<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-11-26T01:08:29+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Wines By Jeremy</title><subtitle>Wines by Jeremy offers an educative and enjoyable personalized wine experience. Located in the DC metro area, Wines by Jeremy provides a number of services including in-home exclusive tastings, highly curated event tastings, educational events, and wine cellar consulting.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Larkmead Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/24/larkmead_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Larkmead Public Tasting" /><published>2018-11-24T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-24T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/24/larkmead_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/24/larkmead_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Another winery with a storied history longer than most (dating back to the late 1800s) that continues to produce top notch wines is Larkmead.  Though unlike many others with the same length of history, Larkmead continues to be a small production winery, choosing to concentrate on quality over quantity as its 2013 The Lark (100pt by Wine Advocate) demonstrates.  Its smaller size and simple-but-bright tasting room provides quite the contrast to Frank Family, which is right across the street.  Both are located in Calistoga off the main highway, so there’s no reason not to visit either or both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/1-1050by788-c0baba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/1-700by525-c0baba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/1-675by506-c0baba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/1-450by338-c0baba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/1-525by394-c0baba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/1-350by263-c0baba.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/1-350by263-c0baba.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Peaceful, but not for long&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The winery getting ready to start the day.  The winemaking facilty is on the right and the wine tasting building is on the left.  You can take the wine tour and visit both buildings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a reason why both wineries are so close together.  Larkmead sold its original winery building to Frank Family back in the day, but kept their vineyards and continued to produce wine, later constructing its new tasting room that I had the pleasure of visiting.  It is very refreshing with a white/light theme that is very fashionable but relaxing.  There are many reasons why this small family winery produces excellent wines, but I think the level of interaction with their vines is the most important one.  They hand prune and hand harvest everything in addition to walking the vineyards every day observing their development and making adjustments as needed.  As it was close to harvest time, I got to wander the vineyards with them and tasted some of the grapes - I’ve never tasted a Sauvignon Blanc grape that good before - ripe but with high acid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/2-1050by788-cfb649.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/2-700by525-cfb649.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/2-675by506-cfb649.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/2-450by338-cfb649.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/2-525by394-cfb649.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/2-350by263-cfb649.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/2-350by263-cfb649.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Wine loves Art&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The private tasting room for larger reservations.  The family loves and creates art, which makes for great decorations around a tasting table.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shout-out to Deanna Basham for taking me on a tour of the vineyards, for letting the wine sell itself while demonstrating a vast depth of knowledge, and for off-roading a little bit on the tasting menu - I had a couple more than the published menu.  Though, if you also show respect for the great wines they produce, I’m sure they will treat you like family and expand the tasting menu.  It’s just too bad that “The Lark” is nearly impossible to get ahold of; they only produce 4-6 barrels of this rockstar each vintage.  Below are the wines I was able to sample:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.larkmead.com/wine/lillie&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Lillie&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;285 cases made of these 500ml bottles of 100% Sauvignon Blanc.  Sur Lie aging, nicely rounded, really nice high acidity, a 3-to-1 ratio of foudre to partially new French oak barrels used for aging, with notes of subdued melon/honeysuckle and jasmine that give it a pretty nose.  On the palate, you see similar notes with a creamy feel on the finish thanks to the sur lie aging.  So smooth for a Sauv Blanc and not heavy by any means.  14% ABV.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.larkmead.com/wine/firebelle&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Firebelle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($125)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;71% Old Vine Merlot, 21% Cab Sauv, 8% Petit Verdot, grown in gravel.  14.5% ABV.  18 months in 65% new French Oak barrels.  Ripe cherry and rose on the nose.  It’s so bright – just smelling the wine is enough to make my mouth water from the acidity.  The wine finishes crisp as well with a bunch of tannin (though not mouthfilling).  The palate is dusty and very dry (high acid/tannin), with cherry and cocoa powder flavors.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.larkmead.com/wine/cabernet-sauvignon&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($100)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;14.7% ABV.  18 months in 65% new French Oak.  Blend of grapes from gravel, sand, and clay terroirs, making ~2700 cases.  97% Cab Sauv and 3% Cab Franc.  Dusty, deeper black fruit with a sweet tinge on the nose.  On the palate, the tannins are not overpowering but they are definitely grippy.  The body is medium but may get heavier when everything integrates and settles down.  It finishes drier because of the tannin and the high acid.  Need to lay this down for a few years to melloe the tannins and allow the earthy/savoury character to come out more.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.larkmead.com/wine/dr-olmo&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Dr. Olmo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($150)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Not nearly as bright on the nose as the Firebelle or even the Cabernet Sauvignon from above.  This bottle of 100% Cabernet Sauvignon is much deeper, brooding even.  The black fruit on the nose opens up more over time and does feel a little cooked.  Grown in all gravel, the savoury quality is also clearer.  This serves as a good contrast to the Cabernet from earlier - this degree of complexity is my style.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.larkmead.com/wine/lmv-salon&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 LMV Salon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($150)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;60/40 Cabernet Sauvignon and Franc.  A little less bright than the 2015 Cabernet, but still has a good intensity of red fruit on the nose.  The mouthfeel and body feel a bit more ready for consumption than the 2015 Cabernet as well, but it still finishes with very fine and present tannin.  This is a lighter wine in general and is much more primary (fruit) in its aromas and flavors than the others.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Proprietary Red Blend&lt;/strong&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A nice, enjoyable wine that is 50/50 Cabernet Sauvignon and Malbec.  The nose is lighter, like a perfume fragrance that you are trying to suss out.  Serve this one a little more chilled than the others, but it’s also very smooth.  A light white rock dust on the nose adds to the complexity and the interest.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.larkmead.com/wine/cabernet-sauvignon&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2002 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I don’t know what the price is, but it’s definitely worth at least $100 more than the others.  That is what happens when the right wine ages well.  The nose is still very nice, fresh, fragrant, and light with a raisin quality that is starting to come out.  But the body/mouthfeel/acid/tannin are in perfect balance.  I wish I had a mirror to see my reaction when drinking this wine…  And it still has a great clean finish with its brick red color.  If I were to buy any wine I tasted today, it would be this one - I don’t know if I could wait 10+ years hoping for the other wines to reach this level.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is definitely balance between the old world style and new world style with these wines as the terroir really comes through along with medium(+) acidity that keeps the wines vibrant while achieving a ripeness found in the best Bordeaux vintages.  The price point of these wines might be a little higher than you may be used to, but they also demonstrate the little nuances that distinguish a $150 bottle from a $75 bottle.  I also think there is clear personality to the wines which make them seem unique as well.  My only concern is that most of these wines require a good amount of decanting if they are to be enjoyed right away.  Except that last bottle of course!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I did not walk away with any bottles or a membership, I do have a clear picture of where they rank next to other vineyards like Frank Family, Round Pond, and others whose Cabernets have hints of that dusty, Rutherford feel.  Even if you do not have the resources to purchase a case of the wine in the event you like it, I still recommend that you visit for a tasting to understand what is waiting for you when you can afford the nicer wines out there.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="calistoga" /><summary type="html">Another winery with a storied history longer than most (dating back to the late 1800s) that continues to produce top notch wines is Larkmead. Though unlike many others with the same length of history, Larkmead continues to be a small production winery, choosing to concentrate on quality over quantity as its 2013 The Lark (100pt by Wine Advocate) demonstrates. Its smaller size and simple-but-bright tasting room provides quite the contrast to Frank Family, which is right across the street. Both are located in Calistoga off the main highway, so there’s no reason not to visit either or both.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/larkmead/2.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Wine Membership Discussion</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/22/wine_membership_tips.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wine Membership Discussion" /><published>2018-11-22T14:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-22T14:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/22/wine_membership_tips</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/22/wine_membership_tips.html">&lt;p&gt;Happy Thanksgiving everyone!!!  I hope everyone is with family and/or friends celebrating over a nice, hot meal and a good bottle of wine.  Since this is a time for giving thanks, thank you, the readers, for following along on this deep dive into Napa wineries with a dose of Willamette Valley as well.  Soon, we will have a look at some in France, in case anyone is thinking of vacationing there at some point.  Some topics have continuously come up in feedback from you, so I’d like to take some time to write about one of them today: Wine Memberships.  Wine memberships is a broad topic and could be discussed in the context of several different segments of the wine industry - e.g. Wine Bars, Distributors/Wine Stores, Wineries.  Today we will focus the conversation on memberships as they pertain to wineries, but much of the same logic applies for other membership types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full discloser: I have been or recently became a member at several of the wineries I’ve written about so far.  This is not a coincidence - what better way to start writing than to write about things you really like?  My situation is a bit unusual though - I consume wine at a faster rate than most and use some of my membership wines for tastings with customers as well.  The normal consumer can likely handle around 3 memberships for various reasons discussed below, though if you handle 7 or more, I’d love to hear from you!!  We’ll discuss the pros/cons below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/wine-memberships/1-1050by788-e0df7c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/wine-memberships/1-700by525-e0df7c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/wine-memberships/1-675by506-e0df7c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/wine-memberships/1-450by338-e0df7c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/wine-memberships/1-525by394-e0df7c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/wine-memberships/1-350by263-e0df7c.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/wine-memberships/1-350by263-e0df7c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;I would live here&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It wouldn’t be a post about wine without a picture of a winery or vineyard in it. I decided to include one of my favorite shots of the Douro Valley in Portugal that wasn’t used in another post!  Don’t worry - we will discuss the wineries of the Douro at some point.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what are wine memberships and why do they exist?  Wine membership is a contract of sorts - it is a commitment from you (the consumer) to purchase a certain number of bottles at each allocation point during the year in return for benefits and other privileges that non-members do not have access to.  It’s obvious to understand why consumers participate, but why do wineries have these programs?  It’s all about the economics.  Each year, wineries invest a significant portion (for smaller ones, it can be all) of their available capital to produce the current vintage - the breakdown of these costs deserves its own article…  This is a huge risk - if all their capital is tied up in wine and they can’t sell that wine, or even if they can’t sell it at the rate that they need to in order to pay their bills, they will go under.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the basis of the “En Primeur” system in France, where large/famous estates (e.g. Lafite-Rothschild, Cheval Blanc) will sell futures in wine (you pay now for a bottle in 2-4 years) that is a lower price than what the wines will cost on release (when the wines are actually ready).  To some, this may seem like an ancient version of the “derivative” financial instrument and they would be right.  This is practiced much more efficiently today in the Agriculture industry (e.g. Corn Futures), but derivatives may never work for the wine industry as a whole.  That’s because no two wines taste the same or cost the same to produce.  If each product is slighly different, how can you manage to track the cost/value of each one to price the derivative?  Wine would need its own stock market!!  (That might be an idea…  Haha).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, that’s enough background from me - I always seem to excitedly dig into the history of wine.  Now that we know why membership programs benefit both the consumer and producer (and therefore know why they exist), let’s actually dig into more of the details for consumers.  Generally, the membership benefits at a given winery are a combination of the following.  Wineries may have incremental membership programs too where the more bottles you commit to buying, the greater the number of benefits and the degree of those benefits (e.g. price discount) are in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;list-of-potential-benefits-from-a-winery-membership&quot;&gt;List of Potential Benefits from a Winery Membership&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price Discount on Purchases&lt;/strong&gt; - Who doesn’t want to pay less for wine?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Free or Discounted Tours and Tastings at the Winery&lt;/strong&gt; - Again, who doesn’t want to pay less for wine?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Access to Limited Production Wines, Library Wines, and Larger Formats)&lt;/strong&gt; - This benefit is tailored to the wine collector types.  Those who crave the rare, highly rated, hard-to-access wines.  This definitely includes me to a degree, especially since I don’t want to wait 10 years when I buy a wine to drink it at its optimal point.  So I purchase library wines that have already undergone that aging in an optimal environment and are ready for consumption when I buy it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guaranteed Availability of Wines for Purchase&lt;/strong&gt; - Some wineries become so popular that their entire inventory is spoken for, even before they release the wine.  Sometimes in order to even get access to purchase they wine they produce, you need to join their wine club.  The most popular small producers, sometimes referred to as cult producers, may have waiting lists that last years before they have room for your allocation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discounted Shipping&lt;/strong&gt; - If you live far enough away from the winery, you’ll know that shipping isn’t cheap.  In addition, many things can go wrong during ground shipping and the storage they use that maybe you want to use 2-day or overnight shipping to make sure your expensive wine arrives in pristine condition.  This can cost its own small fortune.  Discounted/Free Shipping can sometimes be a bigger savings than the discounts they give you on their wines…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Access to Private Areas at the Winery&lt;/strong&gt; - In Napa, most larger wineries have special access areas that are available only to wine club members.  Some even may have different areas for different member levels.  If you are lucky enough to have a tasting in the owner’s tent out in the vineyards, you’ll know what I am talking about when I say this benefit means something (see my Chappellet Review for an example).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ability to Reserve the Winery for Private Events&lt;/strong&gt; - You and your friends probably need to live close to the winery to take advantage of this benefit.  Still, I can imagine having a great birthday party or wedding at one of my favorite wineries!  After all, it seems like the views from every winery is great and relaxing.  Though, imagining the cost of holding such events may be more nightmarish.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Invitation to Winery Events&lt;/strong&gt; - No event is more exciting at a winery than the annual release party.  It’s a chance to thank the wine gods for a good harvest, thank all of the winery’s employees for their hard work, and thank the consumers for purchasing the wine and making this annual cycle possible.  Access to this and other events (e.g. Some may host a summer bbq, a birthday party for the winery, etc.) is one of the lesser celebrated perks of being a winery member.  What I would give to not just get a picture with my winemaking idols, but to get one at a party with unbridled joy on both of our faces.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Less Thinking, More Drinking&lt;/strong&gt; - Do you have a problem choosing new wines every time you go to the store?  Do you just want to drink your favorite wine whenever you feel like it?  Do you forget to purchase that wine or find it’s not in your local stores?  A winery membership takes care of those problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;list-of-potential-drawbacks-from-a-winery-membership&quot;&gt;List of Potential Drawbacks from a Winery Membership&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commitment to Purchasing Bottles&lt;/strong&gt; - Remember, the reward for the winery is that you purchase a minimum amount of their wine.  While many winery memberships can be cancelled at any given time, if you want to continue to enjoy the perks, you will need to continue buying.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Winery Co-Location&lt;/strong&gt; - If you don’t live close to the winery, taking advantage of a majority of the membership benefits can be tough.  Living in DC, I can only take advantage of my membership benefits a couple times a year (e.g. free/discounted tastings), and some not at all (e.g. winery events).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decreased Desire/Ability to Explore&lt;/strong&gt; - Some people might not consider this a drawback but I do.  Part of what I love about the wine world is you never know what amazing wine you might drink tomorrow.  But if you are always going to the same wineries to take advantage of your membership benefits, you may not ever discover the amazing wine that is just down the street.  If you keep getting their shipments too, you may not have the money nor space in your wine rack to explore other places either…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexibility of Allocation Shipments&lt;/strong&gt; - It may be that you joined a winery to get access to their Cabernet Sauvignon, but come springtime, you will also receive the Sauvignon Blanc that you may not be fond of.  Many wineries are flexible in what gets shipped as part of your allocation, but some are not.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficult Discontinuing the Membership&lt;/strong&gt; - This may also be a drawback that only I feel, but I have cancelled a few winery memberships over the years and it was not easy.  It wasn’t that the winery made the process hard, but it felt very personal to do it.  When you discontinue a winery membership, depending on its size, it can feel like you are divorcing a friend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As long as the winery isn’t outside your price range (it’ll likely be more expensive than your local grocery store’s selection, but may be the right price point for nice dinners or celebrations), the drawbacks don’t really seem to impact you until you hit that third winery.  By then, you might be considering another winery membership, but may feel the need to discontinue a previous membership to make room in your budget and your cabinet.  In addition, you may find yourself needing to plan a schedule of which wineries to visit which weekends to take advantage of the membership perks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, there is no right answer.  Or put more accurately, there may be different answers for different people.  Just remember that when you drink that bottle of wine, many people contributed to getting that great juice into the bottle (and making the bottle too!).  As long as you are paying hommage to that fact and treat those people and their products with respect, you are entitled to desiring that they put every effort forward to getting you the best bottle of wine they can manage at that price point.  So get out there, visit some wineries, drinks some wines, give thanks to all of the people that contributed to those wines, and let the good times roll.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="tips" /><summary type="html">Happy Thanksgiving everyone!!! I hope everyone is with family and/or friends celebrating over a nice, hot meal and a good bottle of wine. Since this is a time for giving thanks, thank you, the readers, for following along on this deep dive into Napa wineries with a dose of Willamette Valley as well. Soon, we will have a look at some in France, in case anyone is thinking of vacationing there at some point. Some topics have continuously come up in feedback from you, so I’d like to take some time to write about one of them today: Wine Memberships. Wine memberships is a broad topic and could be discussed in the context of several different segments of the wine industry - e.g. Wine Bars, Distributors/Wine Stores, Wineries. Today we will focus the conversation on memberships as they pertain to wineries, but much of the same logic applies for other membership types.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/wine-memberships/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Cristom’s “The Cristom Experience” Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/17/cristom_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cristom's &quot;The Cristom Experience&quot; Private Tasting" /><published>2018-11-17T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-17T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/17/cristom_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/17/cristom_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;There are many exciting wineries to visit in the Portland / Willamette Valley area.  Although not as famous as Domaine Drouhin nor Argyle, Cristom is undoubtedly one of my favorites in the region, if not my absolute favorite.  Everything about Cristom screams family – from the shape/structure of the tasting room, to their candor and joy while conducting their tastings, to the accessible prices of their wines and your ability to taste anything (with the right appointment), to even the way they named the winery (named after the co-owners - Christine and Thomas).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/1-1050by788-201740.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/1-700by525-201740.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/1-675by506-201740.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/1-450by338-201740.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/1-525by394-201740.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/1-350by263-201740.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/1-350by263-201740.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Chainsaw Massacre&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Taking a chainsaw to the previously grafted section.  This way, they can re-plant a different varietal or a new clone of the same varietal on the rootstock.  It will be a couple years before they can harvest grapes from the new vines.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/2-1050by1400-37527d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/2-700by933-37527d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/2-675by900-37527d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/2-450by600-37527d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/2-525by700-37527d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/2-350by467-37527d.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/2-350by467-37527d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;TV Antennae&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A picture of the newly grafted vines.  The sealant used at the grafting point and the top of the new vines is to protect them from disease, since the point of the wounds can get easily infected.  Very cool to watch as everything was happening.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I happened to visit Cristom at a busy time too as they were in the middle of re-grafting a large section of their vineyard.  They were generous enough to bring me out into the field and explain their rationale for why they were changing their varietals and clones.  After walking through the fields and their storage facilities with their estate Viognier and Pinot in hand, we finally got to the main tasting event inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/3-1050by788-8a2763.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/3-700by525-8a2763.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/3-675by506-8a2763.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/3-450by338-8a2763.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/3-525by394-8a2763.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/3-350by263-8a2763.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/3-350by263-8a2763.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;VSP&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A great example of a vine planted for vertical shoot positioning (VSP).  A branch from last year’s growth is preserved through the winter where new vines will grow vertically from.  They will be tied to the trellis wires (above) and trained upwards to ensure good sun exposure and space for wind to blow through (after rain and lingering fog.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or so I thought.  We were interrupted by the owner of the winery himself who heard that I was dropping wine knowledge to my cousin and her husband.  He introduced himself, asked how I heard about Cristom (blind Pinot Noir tasting with WSET students), and asked what I thought about their operation.  I forgot my resume at home, but needless to say that we got along swimmingly.  We even took a picture together (see below).  There was no pretentiousness at this winery whatsoever, which is not to say other places I visited were - it’s just that everyone felt so relaxed and happy just drinking the wine.  This was only possible because the wine was that good…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/4-1050by1400-5ab802.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/4-700by933-5ab802.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/4-675by900-5ab802.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/4-450by600-5ab802.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/4-525by700-5ab802.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/4-350by467-5ab802.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/4-350by467-5ab802.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Lucky Me!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I was lucky enough to run into the owner and winegrower of Cristom: Tom Gerrie.  We shared a conversation for 15 minutes on our obsession with wine, our respect for Burgundy, and our outsized expectations for Willamette Valley’s future.  As much as I love exploring new places, I will definitely be visiting Cristom again when I return to Oregon!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if this was the actual lineup, or I got a few extra bottles because of the picture above, but I got to taste basically the entire inventory that Cristom had available at the time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2016-Estate-Viognier&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Estate Viognier&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($30)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2016-Mt--Jefferson-Cuv-e-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Mt. Jefferson Cuvée Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($35)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2014-Estate-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Estate Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($50)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2015-Eileen-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Eileen Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($65)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/14-Louise-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir-750ml&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Louise Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($60)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/14-Jessie-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir-750ml&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Jessie Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($60)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2015-Marjorie-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Marjorie Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($70)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2014-Carter-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Carter Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2014-Hirschy-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Hirschy Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2014-Canary-Hill-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Canary Hill Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2015-Estate-Syrah&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Estate Syrah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($50)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I lost a lot of tasting notes from my trip to Oregon this past year.  But my biggest regret is losing the tasting notes for Cristom, because the Pinot Noirs were all so wonderfully diverse.  The best were the four ladies - Eileen Vineyard, Jessie Vineyard, Louise Vineyard, and Marjorie Vineyard.  With vines that average over 20 years in age and are rooted in mostly 10M+ year old Basalt soils, there is just so much complexity that develops on the vines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combining that with whole-cluster fermentation techniques observed in Burgundy, the Pinot Noirs here have character that is unique in the Willamette Valley.  The flavors are more traditional (e.g. red fruit that is lighter than cherry, but not unripe by any means) but different compared to Burgundy (e.g. on one of the wines, I clearly observed tomato leaf as an aroma).  As someone who enjoys cerebral wines, this had me running around in circles.  Though I know others with an open mind could just enjoy the wines as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/5-1050by788-6a06f5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/5-700by525-6a06f5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/5-675by506-6a06f5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/5-450by338-6a06f5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/5-525by394-6a06f5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/5-350by263-6a06f5.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/5-350by263-6a06f5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Lucky Me!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Obligatory picture of the beautiful vineyards.  Luckily, my cousin Jennifer was asking really good questions, which allowed me to hang back at points and just enjoy the experience.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wine &amp;amp; Spirits Magazine found that Cristom is the “#1 Pinot Noir on restaurant wine lists in America” for two years running.  I’m not lucky enough to have restaurants near me with this on the menu, but I do imagine they would be fun to pair foods with.  To be safe, I walked away with a case of their wine - choosing several bottles of the Jessie and one of each of the rest I liked.  If you are in the area, Cristom needs to be on your list of wineries to visit.  It may be 15-20min south of the larger group of wineries, but you need to make this trip.  If you do and enjoy the wines as much as I do, be sure to tell them that Jeremy sent you.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="oregon" /><category term="willamette-valley" /><category term="eola-amity-hills" /><summary type="html">There are many exciting wineries to visit in the Portland / Willamette Valley area. Although not as famous as Domaine Drouhin nor Argyle, Cristom is undoubtedly one of my favorites in the region, if not my absolute favorite. Everything about Cristom screams family – from the shape/structure of the tasting room, to their candor and joy while conducting their tastings, to the accessible prices of their wines and your ability to taste anything (with the right appointment), to even the way they named the winery (named after the co-owners - Christine and Thomas).</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/cristom/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Domaine Drouhin Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/10/domaine_drouhin_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Domaine Drouhin Public Tasting" /><published>2018-11-10T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/10/domaine_drouhin_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/10/domaine_drouhin_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Starting a new winery is hard.  There are so many things to do on the operations side such as clearing out the field, adjusting the soil, planting and caring for the vines, etc.  But just as important as making the product is building a brand and fostering a consumer base that will purchase your product.  This is even harder when you are entering an established market like Willamette Valley.  Thankfully for Domaine Drouhin, they had the branding piece covered already when they established the winery in 1987 and have continued to add to their reputation and legacy from Burgundy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/1-1050by788-8be9e2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/1-700by525-8be9e2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/1-675by506-8be9e2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/1-450by338-8be9e2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/1-525by394-8be9e2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/1-350by263-8be9e2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/1-350by263-8be9e2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Doorway to France&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The doorway to Oregon soil and French Soul&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I visited their tasting room in Beaune, France (capital of the Burgundy area) last year and had a great time.  Their Clos de la Roche Grand Cru from a magnum was crazy good, but more on that in its own review, haha.  Needless to say, I left impressed with their wines.  So when I heard that they had a sister winery in Willamette, you know I had to visit.  I didn’t quite know what to expect as I was driving to the vineyard.  But when I saw the winery, I just shook my head and told myself “of course it would be like this”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/2-1050by788-65f21e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/2-700by525-65f21e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/2-675by506-65f21e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/2-450by338-65f21e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/2-525by394-65f21e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/2-350by263-65f21e.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/2-350by263-65f21e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;A look to the vines&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Wine is only as good as the vines/soil they come from.  A view off the patio into some of their nearby vines&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Owner of 225 acres in the heart of the Dundee Hills area, the winery itself is surrounded by seemingly endless rows of vines with no other structures in sight besides the road you took.  Inside, the place was packed with people.  Many picking up their bottle allocations, many there to sample the wines, and more people than I expected just enjoying a day at the vineyard with their family.  The wines themselves were an interesting mix of new world power with old world flavor profiles and acidity.  This tasting was right after lunch, so my palate was a little off-center, but I would firmly place the tasting in the good category.  The tasting consisted of the following wines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.domainedrouhin.com/2016_Arthur_Chardonnay&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 DDO Chardonnay Arthur&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($35)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The white flowers, balanced body and solid acidity reminded me of Burgundian whites, but the fruit profile was definitely riper (e.g. stonefruit) than what you would find at their French estate.  Not too over-the-top, this is a nice Chardonnay to casually drink.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.domainedrouhin.com/2015_Roserock_Pinot_Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Roserock Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($35)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Roserock covered a higher range of flavors than I normally encounter at this price point in America, meaning you can drink this young or let it evolve a bit with a few years of aging.  Though I wouldn’t wait more than 3 or so.  Balanced with structure and levity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.domainedrouhin.com/2015_Pinot_Noir_Dundee_HIlls&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 DDO Pinot Noir Dundee Hills&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($45)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;There is a noticeable difference of structure and intensity between the Roserock and DDO Dundee Hills.  More red fruit here that is still young in the bottle, balanced, and a noticeably longer finish.  Some wood spice character is also starting to come out - you can age this for 5 years if you wanted.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.domainedrouhin.com/2015_Roserock_Zephirine&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Roserock Zephirine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($60)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;While the previous wines focused on the balance and fruit, the Zephirine takes you on a bit of a turn towards more complexity, particularly terroir driven notes (more vivid floral notes, lighter red fruit, but some wood spice and just a hint of cacao.  This can age even longer than the Dundee Hills (up to 8-10).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.domainedrouhin.com/2015_Laurene&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 DDO Pinot Noir Laurene&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($70)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This is where the complexity hits its peak in the tasting.  To the floral, light red fruit, and light spice character, now add riper fruit (e.g. Cherry) and more dusty character from the terroir.  This felt like the best expression of French and Oregon flavors and concepts of the bunch.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of their French roots, if I my schedule had allowed, I would’ve really liked to have done the “French Soul, Oregon Soil” tasting ($40) instead.  Conducted only at 10AM, they taste wines from their French and Oregon Estates to compare and contrast the Chardonnay and Pinot Noir flavors and characteristics.  Looking back at the tastings, I personally still prefer their French wine - there’s just a level of nuance they achieve with those wines that make them that much more cerebral and enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the $15 fee is very reasonable - The membership pricing and benefits (20% off or free shipping on 6 or more bottles for new memeber) are also pretty solid.  I did not bring back any bottles with me since there are so many good wineries in the area and my luggage was only so big.  However, I encourage you to put this place in your Top 5 of wineries to visit when in the region.  They definitely provide a unique perspective of the terroir in the area and the views are too good to ignore.  Just be prepared to wade through a mass of humanity on the weekend, haha.  Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="oregon" /><category term="willamette-valley" /><category term="dundee-hills" /><summary type="html">Starting a new winery is hard. There are so many things to do on the operations side such as clearing out the field, adjusting the soil, planting and caring for the vines, etc. But just as important as making the product is building a brand and fostering a consumer base that will purchase your product. This is even harder when you are entering an established market like Willamette Valley. Thankfully for Domaine Drouhin, they had the branding piece covered already when they established the winery in 1987 and have continued to add to their reputation and legacy from Burgundy.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/domaine-drouhin/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Argyle “Masters of Sparking” Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/03/argyle_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Argyle &quot;Masters of Sparking&quot; Private Tasting" /><published>2018-11-03T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-03T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/03/argyle_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/03/argyle_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;When people think of Oregon wine, they normal think of red still wine that ranges from the finesse of Burgundy Pinot Noir to the power of Russian River Valley Pinot Noir.  They don’t necessarily think of Sparkling wine, which is a key product of Pinot Noir all around the world, not just Champagne.  And when it comes to Oregon Sparkling Wine, there is no place more established than Argyle; heck, it’s even called out specifically in my Wine and Spirits Education Trust (WSET) Sparkling Wine Class!  The reputation alone is enough to entice even seasoned wine professionals, but when I discovered there was a special Sparkling tasting that also lets you to disgorge a bottle by hand, I made Argyle my first call during my itinerary construction.  I brought along my cousin and her husband for a full weekend of tastings in Willamette as their wedding gift, but this visit was definitely a gift to myself, haha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/1-1050by788-182328.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/1-700by525-182328.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/1-675by506-182328.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/1-450by338-182328.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/1-525by394-182328.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/1-350by263-182328.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/1-350by263-182328.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;beautiful tasting room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view of Argyle’s tasting room as your enter the winery.  Clean, rustic and just feels like a place I would want to drink good wine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winery itself is spacious and gorgeous, polished yet rustic, and has parts from its old barrel storage facility incorporated into different aspects of the new building.  Argyle’s tasting area could hold 100 people without issue and there’s even enough room for kids to run around outside.  Upon entering the facility, we were greeted with a sparkling Riesling that resembled Deutcher Sekt (German Sparkling Wine), but was a little drier and lower in acidity.  After we finished exploring the tasting area, the manager of the winery picked us up and took us to the back for a private tour and tasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/2-1050by788-a75c39.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/2-700by525-a75c39.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/2-675by506-a75c39.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/2-450by338-a75c39.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/2-525by394-a75c39.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/2-350by263-a75c39.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/2-350by263-a75c39.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;just nod&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Learning about the unique terroir of the Willamette Valley and why Pinot Noir is so delicious here.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We first walked through the back space of the storage area, where it was the coolest and darkest.  There we saw unspeakable things, like wines that had been aging on their lees for nearly 10 years, long enough to make even great Champagne Negociant houses blush; the prestige cuvees (best wines) of a Champagne Negociant (e.g. Moet Chandon) is normally aged on the lees for 5-7 years.  Although the bottles didn’t have the iconic black mold growing on the bottles (this was a warehouse, not an underground cave after all), you could tell that these were cared for greatly before they made it to the gyropalates for riddling and eventual disgorgement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One curious thing - there was a pupitre in a corner that someone had been manually riddling.  Turns out, this is for perspective customers of this tasting!  Our host grabbed a bottle and a cap-popping tool and we all headed outside.  The weekend was my cousin’s wedding present, so I let her husband do the disgorging – it was actually well-done…  Once we cleaned up and geeked out a bit more on the production process, it was time to head inside for the tasting.  Our lineup consisted of the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sparkling Wine - Zero Dosage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sparkling Wine - Dosage A&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sparkling Wine - Dosage B&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sparkling Wine - Dosage C&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sparkling Wine - Final Blend&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.argylewinery.com/2014SpiritHillBlancdeBlancs&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Spirit Hill Blanc de Blancs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($50)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This 100% Chardonnay sparkling wine from Eola-Amity Hills has great acidity, minerality, and enough creaminess to balance the lemon flavors.  This is a high energy sparkling that doesn’t seem tamed at all by the time it has spent in neutral oak barrels.  Worth getting at the membership price point.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.argylewinery.com/2014KnudsenVineyardBrut&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Knudsen Vineyard Brut&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($50)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Old vine plot, so you know it’s going to be complex.  Higher elevation helps to preserve the high acidity and lighter citrus flavors.  But this wine is about the barrel aging, which brought out some smoke character to pair with the red fruit (from the Pinot Noir) and citrus.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.argylewinery.com/product/2014-Argyle-Brut-Ros-&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Brut Rose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($50)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Another sparkling wine from the Eola-Amity Hills, so you know its going to have some degree of minerality.  But it’s the lighter, unripened red fruit that play the most prominent role here.  You can feel a little tannin, but this is a delicate wine for drinking chilled on a hot summer day.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.argylewinery.com/2007ExtendedTirageBrut&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2007 Extended Tirage Brut&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;My favorite from the tasting as discussed further below.  The bright acidity, creamy texture, ripe fruit (stonefruit, citrus), and aged character (toast, nuts) are all well integrated into this sparkling wine.  The complexity and character are off the charts and the novelty of its production is also fun to show off.  Buy and try this wine - you will not regret it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2007 Extended Tirage Brut Rose&lt;/strong&gt; ($120)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If this wine was priced similarly to the Extended Tirage Brut, I would have also picked up a bottle.  There is similar character to the Brut Rose and the Extended Tirage Brut with some additional fleshiness on the palate as well.  However it’s priced a little too high for my taste.  Definitely still worth tasting at the winery if you get the chance!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/4-1050by788-62224f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/4-700by525-62224f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/4-675by506-62224f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/4-450by338-62224f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/4-525by394-62224f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/4-350by263-62224f.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/4-350by263-62224f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;delicious&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Argyle’s linup of Sparkling Wines&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, there are 10 wines in this tasting that are broken up into two sets, so come prepared.  The first set is purely for educational purposes - both for you and the winery.  You receive the same sparkling wine with four different dosage levels (including Zero Dosage) and are asked which is your preference.  After all, it’s important the winery produces wines that consumers like!  Next you can try to guess the dosage levels of each sparkling wine and then which of the four the Final Blend is.  Hint: It’s not the Zero Dosage wine.  But getting it right is actually much harder than you might think as they all feel pretty similar on the palate.  After discussing Argyle’s approach to sparkling wine, you’ll then taste the next set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/5-1050by788-6c70ba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/5-700by525-6c70ba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/5-675by506-6c70ba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/5-450by338-6c70ba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/5-525by394-6c70ba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/5-350by263-6c70ba.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/5-350by263-6c70ba.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;captivated&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Discussing Argyle’s methodology when it comes to producing its Sparkling wines and how the dosage affects more than just taste.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of all these wines, I was absolutely captivated by the 10 Year Old Sparkling Wine, which I found out later was the highest rated of the group.  Unlike Champagne where fertilization of the soil every few years is necessary, Oregon has more fertile soil by comparison, which in turn leads to wines with greater flavors.  Normally, this is greatly desired, but in Sparkling wine, you want a more neutral base wine so that the flavors which result from the lees aging are more prominent (e.g. brioche, cream).  To deal with this stronger fruit flavor in the base wine, Argyle makes a wine that ages on the lees for ~10 years to increase the strength of those flavors.  What results is a strong, but subtle wine of great flavor that seemingly could explode at any moment, favoring one flavor (fruit) or the other (lees aging).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/6-1050by788-c59bcb.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/6-700by525-c59bcb.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/6-675by506-c59bcb.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/6-450by338-c59bcb.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/6-525by394-c59bcb.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/6-350by263-c59bcb.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/6-350by263-c59bcb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;every day I'm hustling&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;You know why I am smiling right?  Guess who ranked all of the dosage levels correctly and then guessed the final blend?  This guy…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tasting itself though was a very educational experience.  Tasting four wines of the exact same blend, from the same vintage, and from the same vineyards, differing only in the dosage was a real treat.  So many things I learned about in class that are hard to taste/test practically became much more clear.  The room used for the tasting itself was a small room enclosed by glass, surrounded by racks holding some of their rarest/oldest wines.  I couldn’t quite convince the manager to open one of the bottles, but I was able to get a 6-pack of the 10 Year Old Sparkling Wine at a members discount with free shipping, which isn’t bad.  My cousin and her husband ended up becoming members on the winery, so I probably got the discount transitively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in Sparkling wines, but don’t want to pay for that ticket to Europe, Argyle is a great alternative that stands among the best in America.  And do take advantage of the food truck outside or eat lunch before your tasting appointment.  You will thank yourself, haha.  Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="oregon" /><category term="willamette-valley" /><category term="dundee-hills" /><summary type="html">When people think of Oregon wine, they normal think of red still wine that ranges from the finesse of Burgundy Pinot Noir to the power of Russian River Valley Pinot Noir. They don’t necessarily think of Sparkling wine, which is a key product of Pinot Noir all around the world, not just Champagne. And when it comes to Oregon Sparkling Wine, there is no place more established than Argyle; heck, it’s even called out specifically in my Wine and Spirits Education Trust (WSET) Sparkling Wine Class! The reputation alone is enough to entice even seasoned wine professionals, but when I discovered there was a special Sparkling tasting that also lets you to disgorge a bottle by hand, I made Argyle my first call during my itinerary construction. I brought along my cousin and her husband for a full weekend of tastings in Willamette as their wedding gift, but this visit was definitely a gift to myself, haha.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/argyle/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Archery Summit Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/27/archery_summit_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Archery Summit Public Tasting" /><published>2018-10-27T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-27T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/27/archery_summit_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/27/archery_summit_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;One of the toughest questions I’ve been asked about my Oregon travels is “where do I find good Pinot?”  The reason this is tough is because it’s everywhere, especially with Willamette Valley being a short 1-hour drive from Portland.  But when people ask me where the best Oregon Pinot Noir can be found, I normally respond with Archery Summit in my Top 3.  As its name implies, the winery can be found on the top of a hill not far from Domaine Drouhin, Sokol Blosser, and others.  I love their planting pattern too - you almost need to weave through the vines while driving up to the tasting room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tasting room itself is small, holding only ~20 people at a time, and their entrance to the storage level from the tasting room area is a small hidden entrance down some stairs.  All of this gives it a homely, friendly feel until you start the tasting.  Don’t let the modest exterior and tasting room fool you - Archery Summit is a powerhouse in Willamette that produces exceptional wines.  Although they are only ~25 years old, they own 6 vineyards encompassing 120 acres, have some of the oldest Pinot vines in the valley (40+ years), maintain the only cave system in Oregon, and consistently deliver high-scoring wines, especially for Pinot Noirs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Wine Advocate usually scores them in the 90-92 range while the Wine Enthusiast and Wine Spectator usually score them in the 93-95 range, meaning that the wines are less about power (Wine Advocate gives higher scores for that) and more about finesse and balance (what WE and WS hone in on more).  If you asked me to rate the wines, I would lean toward the 93-95 range.  Not because I prefer finesse over power, but because the purity of the wines cover any shortcomings with regards to power.  Another reason I scored the Archery Summit visit well is their tasting fee ($30) is very reasonable for the number of wines (and their quality) included in the tasting.  Certainly better than many places in Napa.  Without further ado, below are the wines on their tasting menu:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.archerysummit.com/product/2016-Pinot-Noir-Ros-&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Rose of Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($32)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Much more color in this rose than its counterparts from other vineyards, likely due to a longer maceration with the skins or there is more press juice that is used for the wine.  This additional richness is clear on the palate as well, but can be balanced by serving at a colder temperature if that’s your preference.  I found it hard to discern the flavors since the wine was very different than other Roses I’ve had and can’t put it better than the winery themselves: “aromas of fresh guava, starfruit, blood orange juice and rosewater. The palate is layered with notes of raspberry, grapefruit peel and juicy cranberry with lingering hints of delicate orange blossom.”&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.archerysummit.com/product/2016-Archer-s-Edge-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Archer’s Edge Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($90)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Probably the wine I am most conflicted about.  It has such great potential, but didn’t show as well today as I would’ve liked.  Candied red fruits and grapey in its flavor profile and lighter in body thanks to its younger vines.  I hope that some secondary flavors develop in the future, but right now, this is mainly a nice, easy-drinking wine.  I don’t quite get the cocoa powder as described in the winery’s tasting notes, but the basalt soil does begin to come into play.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.archerysummit.com/product/2015-Renegade-Ridge-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Renegade Ridge Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($90)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Renegade Ridge definitely had more intensity to it.  Lighter red/blue fruit notes and even some hints of citrus.  There is a slight dusty cocoa as well that adds a bit of complexity.  The tannins, acid, and body were all very balanced and in line with the intensity of the wine.  Definitely better to enjoy this wine while it’s younger rather than trying to age it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.archerysummit.com/product/2015-Arcus-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Arcus Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($125)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wonderful nose – a lot more floral than the other wines.  Violets and roses, with bright red juicy fruit on both the nose and palate, with just a touch of spice adding complexity.  Great mouthfeel with enough tannins to age it a bit as well.  The spice from the wood is bigger in this wine than the others, but it blends well with the dusty cocoa and red fruit.  The red fruit was a complex mix and very cerebral - I ended up buying a bottle of this wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.archerysummit.com/product/2015-Red-Hills-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Red Hills Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($100)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Blue fruit is more prominent than red fruit (but there is rose petal on the nose).  The most interesting flavors though were the black tea and the sweet spices in the wine.  Though, they certainly did not feel out of place or overly intense - everything was still smoothly integrated in the wine.  There are several Pinots in the area that fit into this flavor profile (black tea, sweet spice) - I find them fascinating, but it may not be to everyone else’s tastes.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.archerysummit.com/product/2015-Premier-Cuv-e-Pinot-Noir1111&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Premium Cuvee Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($54)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Probably the best quality-to-price ratio (QPR) wine from Archery Summit.  The ripeness and richness is more like the Arcus (though more black fruit here) than any of the other wines we tasted, making it very competitive with a lot of other similarly priced wines from the area.  I liked the coffee hints that were there with the dusty cocoa.  It’s very hard not to take two bottles of this over a bottle of one of the other bottles in the tasting lineup…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The membership benefits for Archery Summit are very appealing as well - in addition to significant discounts on the wines, you are invited to winery events and can bring guests with you multiple times for free tastings.  At their non-discounted prices, the cost is a little steep / reminds you of Russian River Valley (RRV), but are still worth it if you can afford it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theme of the wines from Archery Summit reminds me of Kapcsandy.  Not nearly the complexity or price, but that purity of fruit without much candied notes in the wine that is often seen elsewhere.  And although the tasting room is on the smaller side, they can still handle larger groups - a bachelorette party I sent there a couple of months ago had no problems and thoroughly enjoyed their visit.  I highly recommend visiting for a tasting before purchasing their single-vineyard wines, but if you find the 2015 Premium Cuvee at a wine store that you trust, buy a bottle and share with friends a taste of what Willamette has to offer.  Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="oregon" /><category term="willamette-valley" /><category term="dundee-hills" /><summary type="html">One of the toughest questions I’ve been asked about my Oregon travels is “where do I find good Pinot?” The reason this is tough is because it’s everywhere, especially with Willamette Valley being a short 1-hour drive from Portland. But when people ask me where the best Oregon Pinot Noir can be found, I normally respond with Archery Summit in my Top 3. As its name implies, the winery can be found on the top of a hill not far from Domaine Drouhin, Sokol Blosser, and others. I love their planting pattern too - you almost need to weave through the vines while driving up to the tasting room.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Au Sommet Private Tasting with Amuse Bouche and Coup de Foudre</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/20/au_sommet_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Au Sommet Private Tasting with Amuse Bouche and Coup de Foudre" /><published>2018-10-20T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-20T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/20/au_sommet_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/20/au_sommet_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;The last winery for one of our weekend trips to Napa and it was indeed a good one.  Once you contact the winery to setup an appointment, you’ll have a couple of options for the tasting: the Amuse Bouche building in downtown Napa or the Au Sommet vineyard on Atlas Peak.  We obviously chose Atlas Peak, but if you are pressed for time (it is a 20min drive from Napa) or are a nervous driver (it’s unpaved roads only 1.5 lanes wide going up a mountain), I recommend you stay in Napa.  Once you do make it to the winery though, like so many others, the view is worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/1-1050by1065-8a6559.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/1-700by710-8a6559.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/1-675by685-8a6559.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/1-450by457-8a6559.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/1-525by533-8a6559.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/1-350by355-8a6559.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/1-350by355-8a6559.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;It really was a great view&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Enjoying the view from of the vineyards from the tower on the property&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you drive up the mountain, you can still see the devastating effects of the forest fires from last year: some houses completely burnt down, others nearby amazingly unscathed, and blackened plots of land that are starting to show signs of life again.  I hope it wasn’t disrespectful, but multiple times, we slowed down to take pictures because of the impressions the sights left on us.  When we finally made it to the winery, we took a moment to reflect on the power and unpredictability of nature, then proceeded to listen to the story the wines had to tell us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/2-1050by700-98e493.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/2-700by467-98e493.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/2-675by450-98e493.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/2-450by300-98e493.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/2-525by350-98e493.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/2-350by233-98e493.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/2-350by233-98e493.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;I told you it was a great view&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view of the vineyards from the watchtower as I am explaining something that is probably important&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/3-1050by700-21d263.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/3-700by467-21d263.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/3-675by450-21d263.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/3-450by300-21d263.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/3-525by350-21d263.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/3-350by233-21d263.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/3-350by233-21d263.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;I may talk with my hands a bit&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view from the ground as I continue to explain something that is probably important&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tasting room itself is almost a side house/renovated shed next to the main property (I think the family lives in the main building).  There was a watchtower-like structure that we could climb to get a view of the valley below and also catch a glimpse of the helipad that Heidi Barrett uses to land her helicopter when she comes here.  Oh, did I mention that Heidi is a collaborator with some of the wines?  After some more pictures and breathing in the mountain air with no sounds but the birds chirping, we were ready to taste the wines.  &lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; We also had wines from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amusebouchewine.com/index.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amuse Bouche&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coupdefoudrewine.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coup de Foudre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; while at Au Sommet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amusebouchewine.com/pret-a-boire/index.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Pret a Boire&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A rose composed of 66% Grenache and 33% Syrah.  This wine was a balancing act of ripeness, freshness, acidity and body.  There are few roses that command this type of price point, but I think it’s warranted.  It will assuredly test your palate’s limits when it comes to subtlety.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amusebouchewine.com/richard-g-peterson/richard-g-peterson-pinot-noir.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Richard Peterson Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;One of the most purchased wines by our group at this tasting.  The only varietal that Heidi Barrett does not work with is the one that her father (Richard Peterson) specializes in: Pinot Noir.  And this Pinot Noir is very good.  Stylistically, it reminds me of Burgundy Pinots that cost much more than this bottle.  This is a great price point too when you consider the other Pinot Noirs grown in the Russian River Valley nearby.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coupdefoudrewine.com/lesbouquinistes.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Les Bouquinistes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($58)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A complicated blend of Syrah, Merlot, Petit Verdot, Zinfandel.  This is definitely not a typical blend of varietals that you’ll see elsewhere.  And because of that, you know that I bought a few bottles…  The price point also makes it very attractive.  The wine is also quite enjoyable in addition to being cerebral - wine experts and newbies alike should be able to enjoy this one.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ausommetwine.com/au-sommet/index.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Au Sommet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($250)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The estate Cabernet Sauvignon produced from the vines on this Atlas Peak property.  Very drinkable now, as is Heidi’s style, but you can taste that there is potential for aging.  The wine is also reflective of the Atlas Peak terroir and how it differs from the other mountain AVAs around Napa Valley.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amusebouchewine.com/amuse-bouche/index.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Amuse Bouche&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($225)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This is the wine for which a reporter once asked where the grapes came from and Heidi responded she would have to kill him if she told him.  This Merlot from an undisclosed site was just something special; I couldn’t quite put my finger on what though in this right-bank Bordeaux style wine.  Both the Au Sommet and this were wonderful, but I walked away with bottles of this because of that extra something.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amusebouchewine.com/vin-perdu/index.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Vin Perdu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I also walked away with bottles of this.  The second label Merlot to the Amuse Bouche, this wine has great perfume, ripeness and balance on the palate.  If the Amuse Bouche is quality play, this is the value play as it will stand up nicely against other estates’ premium Merlot offering.  This is capable of some aging too, so don’t drink it all right away!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coupdefoudrewine.com/cabernetsauvignon.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Coup de Foudre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($95)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I love the concept of this bottle; you can peel off the label and then document where/when you had it and how it made you feel.  But that is window dressing as the wine is plenty good without the trick to the label.  It’s also priced at the right level - it should not be compared to the Au Sommet nor Amuse Bouche, but to other estates’ $100 Cabernet.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/4-1050by788-111bf5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/4-700by525-111bf5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/4-675by506-111bf5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/4-450by338-111bf5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/4-525by394-111bf5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/4-350by263-111bf5.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/4-350by263-111bf5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;So much good wine in the storage room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The wine tasting bar and inventory storage.  We did our tasting outside to enjoy the weather&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theme of the wines is similar to that of other Heidi Barrett style wines - great quality, fruit, midpalate, balance and the wines are approachable early in their development.  The breadth of varietals and AVAs used for these wines makes it a great visit too if you want something more than just the typical Chardonnay/Sauvignon Blanc + Cabernet Sauvignon offering.  The view, clean cool air and the drive up to Atlas Peak are nothing to scoff at either, even though it was hard to stomach at times.  If you have the time, consider making a reservation for a tasting!  Though, be warned, the wines are available for purchase only via 6-packs (or 3-packs in the case of the Au Sommet), so make sure you go as a group to the tasting!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="atlas-peak" /><summary type="html">The last winery for one of our weekend trips to Napa and it was indeed a good one. Once you contact the winery to setup an appointment, you’ll have a couple of options for the tasting: the Amuse Bouche building in downtown Napa or the Au Sommet vineyard on Atlas Peak. We obviously chose Atlas Peak, but if you are pressed for time (it is a 20min drive from Napa) or are a nervous driver (it’s unpaved roads only 1.5 lanes wide going up a mountain), I recommend you stay in Napa. Once you do make it to the winery though, like so many others, the view is worth it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/au_sommet/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Shafer Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/13/shafer_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shafer Private Tasting" /><published>2018-10-13T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-13T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/13/shafer_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/13/shafer_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s hard for me to recall another winery with as large a production, well-known reputation, but as reclusive from the public eye as Shafer.  But I totally understand and appreciate it - especially since we had the whole place to ourselves during our visit.  Although the estate appears large and the tasting room is gorgeous, there are actually not many people onsite.  Besides ourselves, the Shafer wine educator and the father/son proprietors, I don’t recall seeing anyone else on the property at the time.  There were three workers in the field grafting vines, but that’s it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people don’t make it past Stags Leap Cellars (which is also great) when they visit the Stags Leap AVA.  Besides driving past the 1976 Judgement of Paris winner for red wines, there are other obstacles to visiting Shafer, such as it’s only open on weekdays and by tasting appointment only.  But once you make it there, your realize the journey was well worth it…  Quite a number of fantastic wines to taste, fantastic views of the hillside from the winery with grapevines completely surrounding the building, and a great educational experience with a takeaway notebook detailing their wines, origins and process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/shafer/1-1050by723-df8a57.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/shafer/1-700by482-df8a57.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/shafer/1-675by465-df8a57.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/shafer/1-450by310-df8a57.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/shafer/1-525by362-df8a57.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/shafer/1-350by241-df8a57.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/shafer/1-350by241-df8a57.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;some good looking folks there&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Group picture along the gravel road in front of the winery&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harden yourselves before you partake in this tasting, because the pours are generous and these wines will both chip away and melt you at the same time.  The tasting menu looks like the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shafervineyards.com/wine/red-shoulder-ranch-chardonnay.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Red Shoulder Chardonnay (Carneros)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($52)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;14 mths in 75% new French Oak.  Ripe fruit that produces aromas from floral to tropical.  Similar to the Fantesca Chardonnay, this wine is produced without MLF, but undergoes lees aging for 14mths which gives it a great creamy mouthfeel, additional complexity, but without sacrificing the great acidity.  The natural yeast (from the grape skins) used for the fermentation also adds to the complexity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shafervineyards.com/wine/td9.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TD-9 (Cabernet Sauvignon, Merlot, Malbec)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($60)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;20 mths in 100% new French Oak.  Made with fruit from the southern Vaca Mountains.  This wine reminds me a bit of Bordeaux blends, though the use of Merlot and Malbec in greater proportions together is unusual.  Again, good fruit and phenolic development while maintaining good acidity and freshness thanks to the cooler southern climate.  A good intro to Shafer wines.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shafervineyards.com/wine/one-point-five.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One Point Five (Cabernet Sauvignon)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($95)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;20mths in 100% new French Oak.  After graduating from the TD-9, this should be your next wine.  Some Hillside Select fruit makes it into this bottle and you can tell it’s the beginning of something special.  It hints at some of the secondary/tertiary notes that the Hillside Select is famous for, without overwhelming the senses.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shafervineyards.com/wine/relentless.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relentless (Syrah and Petit Sirah)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($92)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;30 mths in new French Oak.  If you want a Syrah to blow you away, this is that wine.  Unctuous color and overwhelming body that is still smooth on the palate, with black fruit, smoke, tiny bit of meat juice, some cacao and a long finish.  Instead of Relentless, I might have named this wine Shameless, because that’s what it feels like.  Everyone in the group purchased at least one bottle of this wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shafervineyards.com/wine/hillside-select.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hillside Select (Cabernet Sauvignon)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($285)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;32 mths in new French Oak.  What a wine…  And with the pour you get, you could spend 20 minutes just with this wine alone.  Volcanic, poor nutrient soil leads half the normal amount of grapes per acre, leading to a wine that is as intense as the Relentless, but more complex flavors than the One Point Five, with great aging potential.  Bottle purchases are limited to two per person, so grab as many as you can and prepare for the long haul.  You’ll be glad you did!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The converation with our wine guide was also very enjoyable and unhurried - I think we spent 2.5 hours on the property.  And although their website limits the number of guests to 8, there is room enough at the table for more - it just gets roudier and harder to hear the wine guide, which is why they like to impose that limit.  Not surprisingly though, our group quieted down when we dug into the wines, as if the seriousness of the wines made us serious when tasting them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/shafer/2-1050by700-7b3867.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/shafer/2-700by467-7b3867.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/shafer/2-675by450-7b3867.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/shafer/2-450by300-7b3867.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/shafer/2-525by350-7b3867.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/shafer/2-350by233-7b3867.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/shafer/2-350by233-7b3867.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;rolling hills make some smooth wine&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Some of their softer rolling hills that make some softer, more rounded wines that can be drunk early&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The converation with our wine guide was also very enjoyable and unhurried - I think we spent 2.5 hours on the property.  And although their website limits the number of guests to 8, there is room enough at the table for more - it just gets roudier and harder to hear the wine guide, which is why they like to impose that limit.  Not surprisingly though, our group quieted down when we dug into the wines, as if the seriousness of the wines made us serious when tasting them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/shafer/3-1050by788-dba061.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/shafer/3-700by525-dba061.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/shafer/3-675by506-dba061.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/shafer/3-450by338-dba061.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/shafer/3-525by394-dba061.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/shafer/3-350by263-dba061.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/shafer/3-350by263-dba061.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;steeper hills make the interesting stuff&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Some of their rougher hills that make the Hillside Select, an enormous wine that needs so time in the cellar but will reward patience handsomely…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On that note, I think Shafer’s theme is its commitment to producing serious wines that are cerebral, different (see: Relentless), powerful, and moving.  We lost track of time and were late to our next appointment because of how touching the wine and scenery were.  Wear some nice clothes, because you are going to want to take some pictures on this property.  If you are in the area on a weekday, I highly recommend trying to setup an appointment.  But be warned, Shafer usually books up 2-4 weeks out, especially Thurs, Fri, and Mon (for good reason).  And if you are thinking about becoming a collector or just laying down some bottles for a future special occasion, the Hillside Select is not a bad choice, especially since you’ll likely only be able to buy it when you visit the winery and it’s limited to 2 per person.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="stags-leap" /><summary type="html">It’s hard for me to recall another winery with as large a production, well-known reputation, but as reclusive from the public eye as Shafer. But I totally understand and appreciate it - especially since we had the whole place to ourselves during our visit. Although the estate appears large and the tasting room is gorgeous, there are actually not many people onsite. Besides ourselves, the Shafer wine educator and the father/son proprietors, I don’t recall seeing anyone else on the property at the time. There were three workers in the field grafting vines, but that’s it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/shafer/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Favia Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/06/favia_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Favia Private Tasting" /><published>2018-10-06T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-06T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/06/favia_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/06/favia_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Besides Bo and Heidi Barrett, there may not be another couple in the valley that has the background, experience and reputation of Annie and Andy Erickson.  Both have worked for their share of cult wineries that produced highly acclaimed wines wines and the price tags that go along with them.  But now, they work for themselves at their family winery in Coombsville.  The new up-and-coming AVA of the Napa Valley, Coombsville is still not on many people’s radar and wasn’t on mine until this visit.  Though, knowing Annie and Andy, I knew this was going to be an incredible experience.  I later found out that Coombsville winemakers like the make the anology of Coombsville is to Napa as Brooklyn is to NYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Located near Napa proper, it almost feels like you are driving to someone’s house when you arrive - no hills, no isolation, just another house with vineyards surrounding it.  The grapevines that you see are actually the property of another winery nearby.  The vines Favia owns are on sloped hills behind the house and across the way.  The tasting is very intimate, by appointment only and only available on weekdays.  And though there is no tasting fee, there is a minimum bottle purchase requirement that they ask you to meet while scheduling your appointment.  My group didn’t have a problem with this but I encourage you to find a bottle of their wines in a shop, try it out, then decide if the style and price range are to your liking before making your own appointment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andy and Annie were kind enough to take time from their busy workday to come speak with our group and opened themselves up to questions.  I acted like a schoolboy talking to his high school crush and locked up a bit, but did manage to ask for a picture with Andy.  Though I am kicking myself that I missed the opportunity to get one with Annie…  As for the wines, they were very different in style than the ones we had so far that weekend:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.faviawine.com/product/2015-Favia-Suize-Viognier-Amador-County?pageID=298543A9-B2DD-8454-41A3-067A79EC92F5&amp;amp;sortBy=DisplayOrder&amp;amp;maxRows=20&amp;amp;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Suize Viognier Amador County&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Viognier was one of the most complex I have ever had without being overly intense and gives the great estates of Condrieu a run for their money.  Needless to say, it surpasses Napa and Virginia Viogniers with ease.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.faviawine.com/product/2014-Favia-La-Magdalena-Red-Wine-Napa-Valley?pageID=298543A9-B2DD-8454-41A3-067A79EC92F5&amp;amp;sortBy=DisplayOrder&amp;amp;maxRows=20&amp;amp;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 La Magdelena&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($175)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A blend of Cabernet Sauvignon and Cabernet Franc.  The Magdelena is still very young and needs time to integrate and develop its identity.  Very fresh with high acidity, but already is showing some terroir character.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.faviawine.com/product/2014-Favia-Coombsville-Cabernet-Sauvignon-Napa-Valley?pageID=298543A9-B2DD-8454-41A3-067A79EC92F5&amp;amp;sortBy=DisplayOrder&amp;amp;maxRows=20&amp;amp;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Coombsville Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($175)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Again, very young and needs time before it can truly be enjoyed.  This wine does not try to pretend to be a valley wine - probably one of the most compelling examples of the Coombsville terroir that I have had (besides the Cerro Sur).  The wine felt a little closed, so I’d like to reserve full judgment until it’s near its optimal point.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.faviawine.com/product/2014-Favia-Cerro-Sur-Red-Wine-Napa-Valley?pageID=298543A9-B2DD-8454-41A3-067A79EC92F5&amp;amp;sortBy=DisplayOrder&amp;amp;maxRows=20&amp;amp;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Cerro Sur (Cabernet Franc)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($175)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The bottle I am most excited for - it also happens to be Andy and Annie’s favorite varietal (Cabernet Franc) and according to them, it’s also the bottle that best represents the vineyard’s sense of place.  100% Varietal Cabernet Franc is gaining traction in Napa and I think this bottle will help with that.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the wine tasting list was short, each bottle was a hit, which works for me!  If I had to qualify Favia with a theme, it would be doing what the terroir and grapes want with precise execution and not messing anything up from the human intervention perspective.  It’s a little ironic too, given the level of talent both Annie and Andy have to shape the wine to what will score well and what Napa consumers want.  But I really respect this approach and will continue to give this methodology careful consideration.  The red wines are all very young though and won’t hit their sweet spot for a while.  And it’s not because of the tannin like other Napa wine - it is more because the wines are in hiberation and are closed in their flavors.  Once they do come out of their shells though, they are going to be quite something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you are looking for a little zen behind your wine, consider making a reservation at Favia!  I highly recommend a morning reservation when your palate is fresh and isn’t weighed down by a heavy lunch, especially since the intensity of the wines aren’t as high as others in the valley.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="coombsville" /><summary type="html">Besides Bo and Heidi Barrett, there may not be another couple in the valley that has the background, experience and reputation of Annie and Andy Erickson. Both have worked for their share of cult wineries that produced highly acclaimed wines wines and the price tags that go along with them. But now, they work for themselves at their family winery in Coombsville. The new up-and-coming AVA of the Napa Valley, Coombsville is still not on many people’s radar and wasn’t on mine until this visit. Though, knowing Annie and Andy, I knew this was going to be an incredible experience. I later found out that Coombsville winemakers like the make the anology of Coombsville is to Napa as Brooklyn is to NYC.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hall Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/09/29/hall_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hall Public Tasting" /><published>2018-09-29T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-29T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/09/29/hall_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/09/29/hall_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in earlier articles, Napa can be both the ultimate educational experience and ultimate relaxation getaway - it all depends on what you are looking for.  Hall Winery is predominantly for those that are looking for the later, though you can definitely purchase 100 point quality wine there too if you wish.  For being both a purveyor of fine wine and tastings with a beautiful landscape, it’s surprisingly easy to find.  Right off the main highway (Route 29), the giant metal rabbit out in front of the winery is hard to miss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you park and approach this St. Helena winery, you’ll see both the beautiful, neo-architectural winery and the 1800s historic barn next to it.  Prepare yourself, because the inside is just another level compared to the exterior.  You may feel like you are entering a blend of a futuristic winery and art gallery.  If you are brave enough to take the Ultimate Cabernet Experience instead of the traditional tasting, you will be led to the barn where all of the technology and art fade away and all that is left is you and amazing wine.  If you are feeling especially fancy, you can arrange for a special personalized tasting at their Rutherford Estate as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/1-1050by700-c62164.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/1-700by467-c62164.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/1-675by450-c62164.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/1-450by300-c62164.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/1-525by350-c62164.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/1-350by233-c62164.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/1-350by233-c62164.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Vineyards of Hall&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Vineyards at Hall after a spring rain in the morning&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally think that the public tasting is a great deal that exposes you to some really high quality wine without a $75+ tasting fee; two of the wines are over $130 each and scored 98 Points or better with The Wine Advocate.  So if powerful and ageable wines are your preference, you are going to be very happy here.  In addition, while you are tasting the wine in the main area, you’ll get a glimpse of the gorgeous view behind the winery.  But best of all, there is no reservation required for the regular tasting!  So if you happen to find yourself in Napa with no plan, feel free to drop by here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/2-1050by700-262d69.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/2-700by467-262d69.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/2-675by450-262d69.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/2-450by300-262d69.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/2-525by350-262d69.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/2-350by233-262d69.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/2-350by233-262d69.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Makeup is hard&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Getting ready for my close up.  Or maybe caught getting caught off-guard during it?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the wines, the tasting list generally looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ultimate-cabernet-sauvignon-experience-150&quot;&gt;Ultimate Cabernet (Sauvignon) Experience ($150)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hallwines.com/shop-90-point-wines-14/2014-hall-kathryn-hall-cabernet-sauvignon.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Kathryn Hall&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($175)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hallwines.com/shop-90-point-wines-14/2014-hall-bergfeld-st-helena-cabernet-sauvignon.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Bergfeld&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($175)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Almost as important as the flavors of this wine (floral, fruitcake, sweet spice, tea, with bright red fruit) is the texture and weight on the palate.  How wine feels in your mouth is obviously important, but until you have a wine that blows you away, you won’t truly appreciate how important it is.  This wine was one of those that opened my eyes to what amazing texture and weight feel like.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Their choice of any two of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hallwines.com/shop-90-point-wines-14/2014-hall-mount-veeder-cabernet-sauvignon.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mt. Veeder&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hallwines.com/winery-exclusive-wines/2014-hall-howell-mountain-cabernet-sauvignon.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Howell Mountain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hallwines.com/winery-exclusive-wines/2014-hall-stags-leap-cabernet-sauvignon.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stag’s Leap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hallwines.com/winery-exclusive-wines/2015-hall-diamond-mountain-cabernet-sauvignon.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diamond Mountain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($175 each)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Unfortunately, I misplaced my notes for the wines I tasted, but do remember that the tasting notes were pretty much what I got from the wines.  In addition to Beringer, Hall is another great location to taste single AVA Cabernets and observe the nuances.  The wines here are a bit riper and warmer in style, but are also more accessible earlier in their life.  They also score very well with Robert Parker on a consistent basis.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One of the 2014 Platinum Collection: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hallwines.com/2014-the-bishop&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bishop&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hallwines.com/2014-rainin&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rainin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hallwines.com/2014-sacrashe&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sacrashe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($325 each)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I’m partial to Howell Mountain wines (The Bishop) and Rainin gets near 100pt scores, so of course we got the Sacrashe at our tasting.  Although I was initially disappointed, that feeling disappeared as quickly as the wine from my glass.  Really great integration of black fruit, creme de cassis, cedar and terroir notes.  The difference between Hall’s Platinum Series and their Signature wines is an additional degree of purity and complexity.  That might sound like a contradiction on the surface, but once you taste these wines, it will make sense.  The price point and rarity make it hard to obtain bottles, so tasting at the winery is recommended.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;normal-tasting-40&quot;&gt;Normal Tasting ($40)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.waltwines.com/pinot-noir-14/2016-walt-clos-pepe-sta-rita-hills-pinot-noir.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 WALT Clos Pepe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Santa Rita Hills Pinot Noir.  As with all their wines, there’s an extra degree of ripeness and spice notes from the wood aging.  For this Pinot, red cherry and blackberries are the dominant fruits.  In the summertime, the wood spice and alcohol warmth might seem a bit much for a Pinot - this wine is at its best during the fall and winter when you don’t want to drink something as heavy as a Cabernet.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hallwines.com/shop-90-point-wines-14/2014-hall-terra-secca-cabernet-sauvignon.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Terra Secca&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($65)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;For Napa Cabernet, it’s hard to beat the quality-to-price ratio (QPR) of the Hall Terra Secca.  Really great concentration/intensity of black fruit with the hallmark spices that you expect from Hall.  A bit richer in body than the Hall Cabernet Sauvignon with an extra layer of flavor that’s earthy in character.  But make no mistake - this is a nicely balanced wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hallwines.com/winery-exclusive-wines/2014-hall-ellies-cabernet-sauvignon.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Ellie’s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Terra Secca utilizes earthiness to provide complexity, while Ellie’s leverages herbal flavors to provide complexity in the wine.  Again, because of the flavors of sage and clove, this wine is best enjoyed in the Fall time instead of reaching for some heavy mulled wine.  In addition, while the Terra Secca lies on the powerful side of balanced, Ellie’s lies on the elegant side of balanced.  Having both back-to-back provided a good contrast, though I would’ve served the Ellie’s first.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hallwines.com/shop-90-point-wines-14/2014-hall-jack-s-masterpiece-cabernet-sauvignon.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Jack’s Masterpiece&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($135)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Although the Kathryn Hall and Platinum series receive most of the marketing attention, Jack’s Masterpiece quietly outscores some of those wines year after year with a better price point.  The 2014 reminded me of Howell Mountain with its crushed rocks / graphite notes, but of course it had great rich fruit character as well, like black currant and cassis.  The body was lighter than I was expecting though - great finesse for those than prefer that style.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hallwines.com/shop-90-point-wines-14/2014-hall-kathryn-hall-cabernet-sauvignon.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Kathryn Hall&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($175)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If the Jack’s reminded me of Howell Mountain, then the Kathryn Hall reminded me of Rutherford.  This wine is richer and bigger in body, but the detail that grabbed me was a dustiness that you see a lot in Rutherford.  Still, this wine is so smooth and approachable, even in its youth, but it could definitely age 10-20 years effortlessly.  This is another one of those wines that you can enjoy without thinking, but then drink again while paying attention and point out 4-6 distinct flavors.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/3-1050by788-ffed69.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/3-700by525-ffed69.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/3-675by506-ffed69.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/3-450by338-ffed69.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/3-525by394-ffed69.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/3-350by263-ffed69.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/3-350by263-ffed69.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Picnic Time&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The outdoor picnic area available to winery members.  Who wouldn’t want to enjoy a bottle out here?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like the membership benefits of Hall.  There is a separate area where wine club members can conduct their tasting (much quieter) and you can purchase bottles, go outside, and enjoy the view of the mountains from a lawn chair.  They even have fire pits for the fall time!  The lawn in the back is well manicured as well, leaving you with the impression that you are a member of a high class country club.  Definitely one of the best views from the valley floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/4-1050by700-0f001e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/4-700by467-0f001e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/4-675by450-0f001e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/4-450by300-0f001e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/4-525by350-0f001e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/4-350by233-0f001e.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hall/4-350by233-0f001e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Napa scenery is always beautiful&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Another angle of the picnic area from nature’s point of view.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theme of the wines is similar to that of other Napa Valley wineries in that it promotes fruit, wood spice, and power.  However, I’ve found that most of Hall’s wines have much more rounded tannins than other places and are already approachable in their youth.  No need to wait any requisite amount of time to enjoy the wines.  Also, candied fruit and white flower are common notes that seem to come up for me throughout the tasting, though I didn’t explicitly call them out above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you follow critics like Robert Parker or Jeb Dunnuck, you’ll notice that some of the Hall wines score very highly on a consistent basis - the Kathryn Hall and Jack’s Masterpiece received potential 100 point scores for the 2015 vintage.  I’m not one to chase scores, but I can see why people do as these wines are great and ready now.  Visit Hall, buy a bottle or two and sit outside with a group of friends when you get the chance.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="st-helena" /><summary type="html">As I mentioned in earlier articles, Napa can be both the ultimate educational experience and ultimate relaxation getaway - it all depends on what you are looking for. Hall Winery is predominantly for those that are looking for the later, though you can definitely purchase 100 point quality wine there too if you wish. For being both a purveyor of fine wine and tastings with a beautiful landscape, it’s surprisingly easy to find. Right off the main highway (Route 29), the giant metal rabbit out in front of the winery is hard to miss.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/hall/1.jpg" /></entry></feed>