<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-12-16T17:31:31+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Wines By Jeremy</title><subtitle>Wines by Jeremy offers an educative and enjoyable personalized wine experience. Located in the DC metro area, Wines by Jeremy provides a number of services including in-home exclusive tastings, highly curated event tastings, educational events, and wine cellar consulting.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Nickel and Nickel Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/15/nickel_and_nickel_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nickel and Nickel Private Tasting" /><published>2018-12-15T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-15T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/15/nickel_and_nickel_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/15/nickel_and_nickel_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Nickel and Nickel is another winery right next to the Highway 29 in Napa.  In fact it’s right across the street from Robert Mondavi and next to Opus One, both of which have storied histories, so you know they set up shop in the right place.  The styling used for Nickel and Nickel’s logo is also very similar to Far Niente, which isn’t to far away.  That’s not a coincidence - the two are sister wineries.  While Far Niente is known for its rounded portfolio, Nickel and Nickel has built its reputation through its vast number of single vineyard Cabernet Sauvignons.  Even the single vineyard tasting gives you a preview of less than half (6 out of 15) of the single vineyard Cabernet Sauvignons on their menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/1-1050by788-40cb0b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/1-700by525-40cb0b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/1-675by506-40cb0b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/1-450by338-40cb0b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/1-525by394-40cb0b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/1-350by263-40cb0b.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/1-350by263-40cb0b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Follow the red brick walkway&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The wine tasting building is actually a house that functions as the wine tasting location.  The wine tastings are conducted inside as well as on the back patio.  Because the house isn’t that big, reservations are required to throttle visitor throughput.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a previous article discussing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/09/08/beringer_private_tasting.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beringer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I mentioned that Beringer was a great location to explore single vineyard Cabernet Sauvignons.  If I were to contrast these two and their interpretations of premium Cabernet Sauvignon, it would be that Beringer makes its Cabernets heavier and with more tannin for aging, while the Cabernets from Nickel and Nickel are softer and ready to drink earlier.  As far as educative experiences go, this Cabernet tasting was very helpful in isolating the characteristics of the different terroir along the valley floor (e.g. Oakville, Yountville, Rutherford, and St. Helena).  Even if you don’t have the most discerning wine palate yet, this is a fun experience to see if you can taste anything different between the wines.  Once you are able to take that first step, the rest follows.  Also, you will impress your sommelier at dinner if you know what AVA you want your Napa Cabernet from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/2-1050by788-a9e080.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/2-700by525-a9e080.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/2-675by506-a9e080.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/2-450by338-a9e080.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/2-525by394-a9e080.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/2-350by263-a9e080.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/2-350by263-a9e080.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Where's the wedding?&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A look into the house.  This is the waiting area your wine ambassador will escort you to as they setup your tasting.  A nice, classy room to enjoy a glass of Chardonnay and share some laughs with fellow wine drinkers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Approaching the building, it feels like you are visiting a friend’s house.  This house must have been around for some time; once inside, you can tell that the house and furniture all have some age on them.  As you look around and wait for your wine ambassador to come fetch you for your tasting, you are given a glass of their Stiling Chardonnay to enjoy in the meantime.  Once they are ready for you, you’ll be led on a tour of the grounds, through the back patio, and into the white triangular-shaped building in the picture above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/3-1050by788-fd4e21.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/3-700by525-fd4e21.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/3-675by506-fd4e21.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/3-450by338-fd4e21.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/3-525by394-fd4e21.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/3-350by263-fd4e21.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/3-350by263-fd4e21.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Where's the wedding?&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view of the grounds from the back patio of the house.  With this much space, you’d think that there would be a wedding hosted here every weekend, but alas there is not.  Seems like the space could be used for something fun.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting the tour of the winemaking facility and asking any questions you might have of their philosophy and production process, it’ll be time to taste some wines!  As with every winery, the wine ambassador can make or break the tasting experience.  Luckily, I had a great one who also allowed me to taste the Syrah that is not normally on the menu and entertained me with great detail about the wines here.  If you do the single vineyard Cabernet tasting, your list will also look like the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.farniente.com/product/2015-Nickel---Nickel-Stiling-Vineyard-Chardonnay--Russian-River-Valley--Sonoma&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Stiling Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Chardonnay from the Russian River Valley.  Good balance between the acidity, fruit, and secondary/tertiary flavors.  I also liked the intensity and finish.  I was surprised that I would have such a good white wine with my all-red tasting.  I am definitely interested in finding a bottle of this and buying one in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.farniente.com/product/2015-Nickel---Nickel-Branding-Iron-Vineyard-Cabernet-Sauvignon--Oakville&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Branding Iron&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($120)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cabernet from Oakville.  Deep blue fruit but also some red fruit present with a levity to the nose.  The initial impact on the palate is a bit more subtle than the nose suggests.  Not enough intensity or complexity for me to choose this wine over the others, but if you want a subtle wine that is driven by primary flavors (e.g. fruit notes), then this is the wine you want.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.farniente.com/product/2015-Nickel---Nickel-C-C--Ranch-Cabernet-Sauvignon--Rutherford&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 CC Ranch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($120)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cabernet from Rutherford.  Better to drink this earlier in its life as I don’t know how it will age.  The acid is very nice and even though it’s 15%+ alcohol, I can’t really smell the heat at all.  It has good viscosity and length on the palate but with a lower intensity of fruit, hence why I don’t know how the mid-palate will develop and recommend trying an older bottle of this before deciding to age it yourself.  The CC Ranch is still an easy drinking wine now without a tertiary component.  If you like the Branding Iron, you may also like this.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.farniente.com/product/2015-Nickel---Nickel-Hayne-Vineyard-Cabernet-Sauvignon--St--Helena&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Hayne Vineyard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($120)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cabernet from St. Helena.  A really pretty nose with ripe red fruit that feels a little ethereal with some flowers and roses.  It has a lighter body and is brighter than the previous wines with more acidity that also cleans the palate on the finish.  The intensity again is a bit light for my taste (this contrasts the Corison Cabernet which as a light body, but intense flavor), but may be up other people’s alley!  If you want a wine similar to the Branding Iron / CC Ranch but with more acid, look no further.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.farniente.com/product/2015-Nickel---Nickel-State-Ranch-Cabernet-Sauvignon--Yountville&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 State Ranch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($120)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cabernet from Yountville.  Take the notes from the Hayne Vineyard Cabernet, but make them a bit deeper, thicker, more pronounced and you get this wine.  The high acid is prominent too on the palate.  Comparing the two, I would take the State Ranch, but again it’s all about your preferences!  There’s also definitely room for several years of aging too.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.farniente.com/product/2015-Nickel---Nickel-Element-28-Cabernet-Sauvignon--Napa-Valley&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Element 28&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($150)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Subtle with the fruit, emphasizing instead violet/floral notes and vanilla on the nose.  The Element 28 seems like a polished version of the State Ranch and takes the wine to the next level.  There’s also more earthiness on the palate that balances with the fruit and adds to the complexity.  This wine is probably my favorite of all the Nickel and Nickel Cabernets I tasted because of that balance and its intensity, though it won’t overpower you palate either.  The tannins are high and present, affecting the perceived length of the finish and making sure the wine can age 10+ years if it wants to.  Of course it’s also the most expensive wine on the tasting menu…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.farniente.com/product/2015-Nickel---Nickel-Rock-Cairn-Vineyard-Cabernet-Sauvignon--Oakville&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Rock Cairn Vineyard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($120)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cabernet from Oakville.  The nose is so powerful with bright black fruit.  The palate pulls the intensity back a bit but has a solid body, enough acid/tannin to hold up the wine but not get in the way, and medium+ length on the mid-palate and finish.  This wine is probably my second favorite after the Element 28 but doesn’t have the same level of tertiary notes and focuses on the black fruit instead.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.farniente.com/product/2014-Nickel---Nickel-Darien-Vineyard-Syrah--Russian-River-Valley--Sonoma&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Syrah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($65)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Syrah from the Russian River Valley.  They planted two acres of Syrah in the Pinot Noir block they purchased some time ago.  Having rosemary-rubbed lamb with this wine would be sooo good.  Made from cooler fruit that has quite a bit of character - the wild flavors of Syrah and black pepper is well integrated into the wine, making this cerebral and yet easy drinking at the same time.  A really good value buy here for an interesting Syrah that reminds you of the Rhone Valley in France.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would be remiss if I didn’t give a shout-out to Ian Stout who was my wine ambassador for the visit.  Ian hails from Texas and is following in the footsteps of his father, who is a Master Sommelier and owns a Syrah vineyard back in Texas.  Ian’s tasting setup was great - it was both a progression of intensity and fruit flavor types (start with light blue/red to deep red to finishing with black).  He was very knowledgable about the wines and the terroirs; I think the tasting ran over by 30 minutes because of the discussion we would have after each wine.  The cheeses used for the paired tasting were very good as well (I can’t believe I didn’t mention that earlier!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/4-1050by788-329f2f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/4-700by525-329f2f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/4-675by506-329f2f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/4-450by338-329f2f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/4-525by394-329f2f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/4-350by263-329f2f.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/4-350by263-329f2f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;I love getting dirty&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Inside the white triangular-shaped building, you will walk past the different fermentation tanks and also this little area: soil samples from the different single vineyard sites of their Cabernet Sauvignon.  It’s good to have an image of the soil as you taste the wine so you can remember the influence of the terroir&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned before, I enjoyed this tasting very much.  If I had to name a theme for their wines, I would use one of the anologies they used to describe themselves.  The winemakers at Nickel and Nickel think of winemaking like sculpting with marble in that you should start with a single piece and shave it down to its form.  In their case, they only make 100% varietal wine and use winemaking techniques to adjust and achieve what the wine wants to be, rather than blend several varietals together to get what the winemakers want.  It’s an interesting way to look at winemaking, especially since blending is considered a traditional technique and is used by most wineries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally enjoyed the last three bottles and thought the first few (besides the Chardonnay) were just a bit too light/pretty without enough character.  I still think that if you are looking to refine your palate and enjoy a different take (or many different takes) on Cabernet Sauvignon, you should give Nickel and Nickel a look.  And while you are at it, pay its sister vineyard a visit as well - hopefully, I will in the future.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="oakville" /><summary type="html">Nickel and Nickel is another winery right next to the Highway 29 in Napa. In fact it’s right across the street from Robert Mondavi and next to Opus One, both of which have storied histories, so you know they set up shop in the right place. The styling used for Nickel and Nickel’s logo is also very similar to Far Niente, which isn’t to far away. That’s not a coincidence - the two are sister wineries. While Far Niente is known for its rounded portfolio, Nickel and Nickel has built its reputation through its vast number of single vineyard Cabernet Sauvignons. Even the single vineyard tasting gives you a preview of less than half (6 out of 15) of the single vineyard Cabernet Sauvignons on their menu.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/nickel-nickel/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Brian Arden Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/08/brian_arden_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Brian Arden Public Tasting" /><published>2018-12-08T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-08T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/08/brian_arden_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/08/brian_arden_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;As more investment pours into Napa Valley and the large conglomerates (e.g. Constellation Brands) continue to purchase more property and consolidate the industry, it’s getting harder to find quality smaller wineries with that family feel (e.g. Clark-Claudon).  Luckily, there is one right off the Silverado Trail that has been growing, slowly but surely these past 5-10 years.  This recent visit to Brian Arden was a coming of age for both of us - the last time I visited several years ago, they had just opened their facility on the Silverado Trail and I was just discovering how amazing wine could be.  The only thing I can say is “look at us now!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/1-1050by788-27a8a2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/1-700by525-27a8a2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/1-675by506-27a8a2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/1-450by338-27a8a2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/1-525by394-27a8a2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/1-350by263-27a8a2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/1-350by263-27a8a2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;beautiful winery&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I really do like the architecture of the winery.  If I had to design one for myself, I hope it comes out looking as good as this one.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even after some years, Brian Arden still looks like an architectural novelty as you enter the driveway.  Though, it isn’t like Hall where the novelty seems artistically driven - the novelty here is they aimed for a clean design that seems classy and homely at the same time.  The abundance of windows makes the tasting room a little warm during the afternoon, but also allows you to enjoy the incredible views from inside the tasting room.  Inside the tasting room there was constant traffic, but it never got to the point of crowded nor too loud.  The proprietor Brian Harlan, who is also the winemaker, made it a point to come inside and thank every group for their patronage and get their feedback on the wines.  This wasn’t an easy thing for him to do as he was simultaneously receiving delivery of the bottles that will be used for this upcoming vintage - a lot of delicate work to balance, for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/2-1050by788-c2ef70.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/2-700by525-c2ef70.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/2-675by506-c2ef70.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/2-450by338-c2ef70.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/2-525by394-c2ef70.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/2-350by263-c2ef70.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/2-350by263-c2ef70.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;peaceful tasting&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;There’s nothing like sitting at a table enjoying good wine and people watching…  Well, the view outside those windows might have been even more captivating…  Have to love the Napa Valley!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many other small producers, Brian first got his start with a larger winery (Terra Valentine) and has met / worked with others who are in the premium wine category.  Incorporating all of that knowledge into his winemaking style, but keeping things very approachable (like his winery), Brian produces enjoyable wines that can be drunk immediately, are still complex, while also being value deals at their price points.  In addition, all of his single varietal wines are actually 100% (and not just 75% as required by California Law to label your bottle with a varietal).  To keep things interesting though, the only continuous grape contracts they have are for their Chardonnay and the Zinfandel (they own their Zin vines).  The source of all their other fruit can and does change year-to-year, depending on what’s available for purchase from others.   This means that each vintage will likely taste very different from their previous ones.  They also have more fun wines coming down the pipe (e.g. Sparkling Rose, Rose, Riesling, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His dogs also roam the winery (did I mention they were dog friendly?), distracting all serious tasters with their demand for attention.  But I have a duty to my readers…  So without further ado, the wines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.brianardenwines.com/product/2015-Sauvignon-Blanc&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Sauvignon Blanc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($34)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Made from Calistoga grapes.  Brian’s wife, Amanda, likes New Zealand Sauvignon Blanc with its higher acidity and green flavors like gooseberry. Brian does not.  And like every good husband, he made the wine the way she likes it - dubbing the wine “In Amanda Style”, which is also how all of the pourers refer to it.  Medium+ acid, lemon, lime, and a zesty flint on the nose and palate.  Medium body and a roundness to the structure, acidity, and intensity makes this very approachable.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Sangiovese&lt;/strong&gt; ($45)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Warm red cherry/rhubarb pie and sweet spice permeate the nose.  Swirling the glass kicks up the intensity and brings out the alcohol.  The alcohol is still warm on the palate, but there is a sweet/candied fruit richness that’s there as well.  Reminds me of a Pinot Noir in texture but the flavor profile of a toned down version of the Del Dotto Sangiovese.  The grapes are sourced from Vincent Arroyo for this vintage, while the previous two have come from elsewhere.  Pale rose and plum color.  According to Brian, “it was just too good” to use in a blend and needed to be a varietal wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.brianardenwines.com/product/2012ZinNV&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Zinfandel, Burton Ranch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($45)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Made from vines that have been around since the late 1800s (think 130+ years old).  The logo on the Brian Arden bottles was made in tribute to their 55 acres of Zinfandel that is up in Lake County (near Kelseyville, which luckily avoided the Summer 2016 fires in Lake County).  Even more pungent than the Sangiovese, there is cooked/stewed raisin, a little rhubarb, sweet spice, and a solid warming core on the body with a lingering raisin finish.  Almost a bit port-ish in quality, though much warmer.  It has a surprising amount of acidity as well.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.brianardenwines.com/product/2012BARED&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 B.A. Red&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($45)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The only blend that they make.  2012 was 45% Sangiovese, 35% Syrah, 15% Cabernet Sauvignon, and 5% Zinfandel.  Every year, the blend changes – not just the percentages, but even the varietals used in the blend change.  I don’t know how to describe the nose as there are lots of different things happening which are hard to attribute/summarize.  Sweet spice and cooked pie character are still there though with some black pepper from the Syrah.  Not as fruit driven as the other wines, but the nose seems brighter and the palate has more acid.  Definitely a good wine for the winter time…  Pairing with different foods will bring out different characteristics of the wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.brianardenwines.com/product/2012-Cabernet-Sauvignon&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The 2011 Cabernet Sauvignon came from Howell Mountain but this year’s came from the valley floor in Coombsville, which is east of the town of Napa.  This is a good easy drinking Napa Cabernet.  The nose is deep with black fruit, red fruit (plum), and spices.  The tannins are very smooth; you hardly notice them, but the acidity is definitely present.  Medium body, high alcohol, medium+/high intensity.  It’s probably best to serve this a little chilled to bring out the acidity a bit more..&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Malbec&lt;/strong&gt; ($50)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The first and only Malbec that they’ve done so far.  In fact, it’s actually the first wine “made” at the winery when they opened the doors in 2014.  Great fragrant nose with alcohol that integrates with the spice, but the blue and black fruit are really strong and hold up the wine.  Good acidity, body and smooth chewy tannin with spice still stimulating the palate.  The fruit flavors are a bit more restrained on the palate, but not in a bad way.  I might take this wine over the Cabernet Sauvignon because they are similar in style.  Made with fruit from Trefethen.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because Brian does not grow the grapes for many of these wines, more effort needs to go into the wine production process to ensure he gets the results he is looking for, as there is no blending besides the B.A Red.  There were cooked/stewed fruit and spice notes that was present in several of the wines, so if you prefer lighter wines with higher acidity and cranberry flavors, you may want to look elsewhere.  The heat (alcohol), spice, and bigger body qualities were similar to Frank Family, but the fruit is riper/deeper while the Frank Family wines had more cranberry and tertiary pieces.  If you are like me and need wines that will keep you going during the winter months at a reasonable price, it’s hard to do better than this in Napa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, the prospect of a nice, leisurely atmosphere with a great view outside and the chance to talk wine with the owner of the winery and his wine ambassadors is hard to turn down.  And who knows - many of the wines described above may taste totally different next year.  Does that mean I might need to go again next year to check them out - it may!  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="calistoga" /><summary type="html">As more investment pours into Napa Valley and the large conglomerates (e.g. Constellation Brands) continue to purchase more property and consolidate the industry, it’s getting harder to find quality smaller wineries with that family feel (e.g. Clark-Claudon). Luckily, there is one right off the Silverado Trail that has been growing, slowly but surely these past 5-10 years. This recent visit to Brian Arden was a coming of age for both of us - the last time I visited several years ago, they had just opened their facility on the Silverado Trail and I was just discovering how amazing wine could be. The only thing I can say is “look at us now!”</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/brian-arden/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Frank Family Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/01/frank_family_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Frank Family Public Tasting" /><published>2018-12-01T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-01T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/01/frank_family_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/01/frank_family_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Frank Family is one of those vineyards that aren’t hyped by the major wine reviewers, but you continue to hear its name talked about on the wine apps (e.g. Vivino and Delectable) and see its bottles in stores, as their wines are nationally distributed.  I finally had enough and decided to find out for myself what the fuss was all about.  Like many other wineries, it was founded with capital earned in another industry.  In the case of Frank Family, it was Hollywood.  But not as actors - the owner was President of Disney and the son is currently the President of Dreamworks Studios.  And what person in the movie business wouldn’t appreciate good vino?  Better yet, what person in any industry wouldn’t appreciate good vino?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/1-1050by788-006b98.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/1-700by525-006b98.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/1-675by506-006b98.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/1-450by338-006b98.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/1-525by394-006b98.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/1-350by263-006b98.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/1-350by263-006b98.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Where's Waldo&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It’s a little hard to miss Frank Family while driving by…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Found off Highway 29 in Calistoga, the Frank Family winery is very traditional in the design of its buildings and landscape.  After all, the winery portion was purchased from Larkmead some years back.  The interior is very polished with a darker, old fashioned wood theme.  After taking a picture on their red carpet (of course they had one), I was led inside and joined by two other groups for the tasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/2-1050by1400-7a45f3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/2-700by933-7a45f3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/2-675by900-7a45f3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/2-450by600-7a45f3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/2-525by700-7a45f3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/2-350by467-7a45f3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/2-350by467-7a45f3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Red Carpet Rollin&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Enjoying my time on the red carpet.  I must admit, I look very asian in this photograph, but definitely not up to the crazy rich asian standard.  That movie changed the game.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The five others that were seated with me at the tasting were relatively new to wine, so the hostess adjusted the tasting to their experience level.  And though she didn’t have any formal training or a wine background, she was very engaging and very good at recalling her facts!  It’s nice to enjoy tastings like this because it serves as a reminder that not everyone will develop a passion or an intellectual curiosity for all things wine.  But that doesn’t mean that they can’t enjoy it for what it is as much as I do.  And instead of serious talk about wine chemistry, we enjoyed sharing stories about the biggest bloopers we’ve all made with wine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/3-1050by788-18aca9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/3-700by525-18aca9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/3-675by506-18aca9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/3-450by338-18aca9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/3-525by394-18aca9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/3-350by263-18aca9.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/3-350by263-18aca9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Storytelling and Laughs&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Sharing some stories and some laughs over sparkling wine in the tasting room.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While lots of fun, the pace and conversation at the table did distract me a bit from analyzing the wines and I couldn’t really ask questions regarding some of the more intricate details of their wine production process.  It may very well be that my rating of the wines/wineries would’ve been higher on a different day with different circumstances.  Though, if you are looking for a winery to bring a party of 6-8 people, Frank Family could be a very nice choice for the price point, since your party would likely be seated alone.  Without further ado, the wines on the tasting menu!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frankfamilyvineyards.com/wine/bubbles/blanc-de-blancs13&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blanc de Blanc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Made in the traditional method (like Cremant, Champagne, and Cava) with 36 months on the lees and hand-riddled (remuage with a pupitre).  The nose is clean with traces of lemon, lime, brioche, and definitely a high malic acid note (e.g. green apples) that is powerful.  The high malic acid did overpower the palate a bit, leading to an imbalance in my mind that might have been avoided if the grapes had a brix level that was a little higher (ie. the grapes were more ripe).  Still, it makes for a very refreshing sparkling wine if served cold on a hot day.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frankfamilyvineyards.com/wine/reserve/lewis-vineyard-reserve-chardonnay&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Carneros Lewis Vineyard Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($65)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wow – the melon and malolactic fermentation (MLF) flavors jump right out of the glass with high intensity.  There is a little bit of a terroir influence to it as well.  Medium(+) body, the butter is pretty pronounced on the palate but well blended with the melon and other stonefruit character.  The medium acid means the grapes must have been pretty well developed - the acid was enough though to match the finish that goes on for quite a bit.  The wine is dry, but there is an underlying ripeness that carries the wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frankfamilyvineyards.com/wine/reserve/lewis-vineyard-reserve-pinot-noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Carneros Lewis Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($65)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is initially tight, but when you coax the wine a bit, the fruit and spice come out in force with ripe cranberry and fruitcake leading on the nose.  The mouthfeel was much lighter than I was expecting from a Carneros Pinot this ripe.  The palate has cooked cranberry, toast, spices, a medium body, and a smooth palate.  What makes this wine interesting is the little piece of forest floor / tertiary / savory character in there at such a young age.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frankfamilyvineyards.com/wine/reserve/zinfandel-chiles-valley&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Reserve Zinfandel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Blended with Petit Sirah, this Zinfandel has a very fragrant/strong nose, a good amount of body and tannin, but with lighter fruit flavors (cranberry/strawberry), some sweet spice notes, and higher acid that tingles the cheeks.  This is not your normal Zin – it has some elements that remind me of Turley Zinfandel, which is always a flattering comparison.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frankfamilyvineyards.com/wine/reserve/2014-rutherford-reserve-cabernet-sauvignon&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Rutherford Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($95)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;100% Rutherford Cab.  The blue and red fruit on the nose and palate is almost candied.  And although the wine and acid isn’t that bright (like Corison), the acid is still mouthwatering and the perfume is pretty and light coming off the wine.  Give it a swirl to really open up the fruit, spices, tertiary notes (coffee/cedar), and high acid that wafts the flavors up.  Super smooth on the palate, a med(+) body, and a light but persistent finish.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The price points of the first four wines are at the upper-end for solid Napa wines (the Rutherford Cabernet is even with peers).  The profiles of the wines are appealing to a large portion of the population (e.g. their candied notes), especially those that want something a little lighter bodied than traditional Napa Valley, with good fragrance and some tertiary development too.  And while the wines are not “ripe” by some people’s Napa valley standards (cranberry notes in a few of them), they are definitely not underripe.  The wines taste like they undergo a slighly colder fermentation to preserve that floral prettiness and acid.  I can definitely see why this vineyard is popular with many people, but some of the wines seem like they focus on complexity and intensity at a cost to integration and balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frank Family definitely has one of the more relaxed atmospheres in the valley (even more so than Hall), which is very inviting for people that don’t yet know much about wine and want to fit in with the crowd at the winery.  I personally like my wines with a bit more natural personality at the risk of being something that some patrons will love and others not so much.  Still, deft hands make these wines and I definitely recommend Frank Family as a nice stop if it’s your first visit to Napa and you want something more relaxing.  Even if you don’t stop by, try buying one of their wines the next time you see it at your local wine store!  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="calistoga" /><summary type="html">Frank Family is one of those vineyards that aren’t hyped by the major wine reviewers, but you continue to hear its name talked about on the wine apps (e.g. Vivino and Delectable) and see its bottles in stores, as their wines are nationally distributed. I finally had enough and decided to find out for myself what the fuss was all about. Like many other wineries, it was founded with capital earned in another industry. In the case of Frank Family, it was Hollywood. But not as actors - the owner was President of Disney and the son is currently the President of Dreamworks Studios. And what person in the movie business wouldn’t appreciate good vino? Better yet, what person in any industry wouldn’t appreciate good vino?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/frank-family/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Larkmead Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/24/larkmead_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Larkmead Public Tasting" /><published>2018-11-24T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-24T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/24/larkmead_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/24/larkmead_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Another winery with a storied history longer than most (dating back to the late 1800s) that continues to produce top notch wines is Larkmead.  Though unlike many others with the same length of history, Larkmead continues to be a small production winery, choosing to concentrate on quality over quantity as its 2013 The Lark (100pt by Wine Advocate) demonstrates.  Its smaller size and simple-but-bright tasting room provides quite the contrast to Frank Family, which is right across the street.  Both are located in Calistoga off the main highway, so there’s no reason not to visit either or both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/1-1050by788-c0baba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/1-700by525-c0baba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/1-675by506-c0baba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/1-450by338-c0baba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/1-525by394-c0baba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/1-350by263-c0baba.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/1-350by263-c0baba.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Peaceful, but not for long&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The winery getting ready to start the day.  The winemaking facilty is on the right and the wine tasting building is on the left.  You can take the wine tour and visit both buildings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a reason why both wineries are so close together.  Larkmead sold its original winery building to Frank Family back in the day, but kept their vineyards and continued to produce wine, later constructing its new tasting room that I had the pleasure of visiting.  It is very refreshing with a white/light theme that is very fashionable but relaxing.  There are many reasons why this small family winery produces excellent wines, but I think the level of interaction with their vines is the most important one.  They hand prune and hand harvest everything in addition to walking the vineyards every day observing their development and making adjustments as needed.  As it was close to harvest time, I got to wander the vineyards with them and tasted some of the grapes - I’ve never tasted a Sauvignon Blanc grape that good before - ripe but with high acid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/2-1050by788-cfb649.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/2-700by525-cfb649.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/2-675by506-cfb649.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/2-450by338-cfb649.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/2-525by394-cfb649.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/2-350by263-cfb649.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/2-350by263-cfb649.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Wine loves Art&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The private tasting room for larger reservations.  The family loves and creates art, which makes for great decorations around a tasting table.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shout-out to Deanna Basham for taking me on a tour of the vineyards, for letting the wine sell itself while demonstrating a vast depth of knowledge, and for off-roading a little bit on the tasting menu - I had a couple more than the published menu.  Though, if you also show respect for the great wines they produce, I’m sure they will treat you like family and expand the tasting menu.  It’s just too bad that “The Lark” is nearly impossible to get ahold of; they only produce 4-6 barrels of this rockstar each vintage.  Below are the wines I was able to sample:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.larkmead.com/wine/lillie&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Lillie&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;285 cases made of these 500ml bottles of 100% Sauvignon Blanc.  Sur Lie aging, nicely rounded, really nice high acidity, a 3-to-1 ratio of foudre to partially new French oak barrels used for aging, with notes of subdued melon/honeysuckle and jasmine that give it a pretty nose.  On the palate, you see similar notes with a creamy feel on the finish thanks to the sur lie aging.  So smooth for a Sauv Blanc and not heavy by any means.  14% ABV.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.larkmead.com/wine/firebelle&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Firebelle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($125)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;71% Old Vine Merlot, 21% Cab Sauv, 8% Petit Verdot, grown in gravel.  14.5% ABV.  18 months in 65% new French Oak barrels.  Ripe cherry and rose on the nose.  It’s so bright – just smelling the wine is enough to make my mouth water from the acidity.  The wine finishes crisp as well with a bunch of tannin (though not mouthfilling).  The palate is dusty and very dry (high acid/tannin), with cherry and cocoa powder flavors.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.larkmead.com/wine/cabernet-sauvignon&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($100)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;14.7% ABV.  18 months in 65% new French Oak.  Blend of grapes from gravel, sand, and clay terroirs, making ~2700 cases.  97% Cab Sauv and 3% Cab Franc.  Dusty, deeper black fruit with a sweet tinge on the nose.  On the palate, the tannins are not overpowering but they are definitely grippy.  The body is medium but may get heavier when everything integrates and settles down.  It finishes drier because of the tannin and the high acid.  Need to lay this down for a few years to melloe the tannins and allow the earthy/savoury character to come out more.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.larkmead.com/wine/dr-olmo&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Dr. Olmo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($150)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Not nearly as bright on the nose as the Firebelle or even the Cabernet Sauvignon from above.  This bottle of 100% Cabernet Sauvignon is much deeper, brooding even.  The black fruit on the nose opens up more over time and does feel a little cooked.  Grown in all gravel, the savoury quality is also clearer.  This serves as a good contrast to the Cabernet from earlier - this degree of complexity is my style.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.larkmead.com/wine/lmv-salon&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 LMV Salon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($150)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;60/40 Cabernet Sauvignon and Franc.  A little less bright than the 2015 Cabernet, but still has a good intensity of red fruit on the nose.  The mouthfeel and body feel a bit more ready for consumption than the 2015 Cabernet as well, but it still finishes with very fine and present tannin.  This is a lighter wine in general and is much more primary (fruit) in its aromas and flavors than the others.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Proprietary Red Blend&lt;/strong&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A nice, enjoyable wine that is 50/50 Cabernet Sauvignon and Malbec.  The nose is lighter, like a perfume fragrance that you are trying to suss out.  Serve this one a little more chilled than the others, but it’s also very smooth.  A light white rock dust on the nose adds to the complexity and the interest.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.larkmead.com/wine/cabernet-sauvignon&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2002 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I don’t know what the price is, but it’s definitely worth at least $100 more than the others.  That is what happens when the right wine ages well.  The nose is still very nice, fresh, fragrant, and light with a raisin quality that is starting to come out.  But the body/mouthfeel/acid/tannin are in perfect balance.  I wish I had a mirror to see my reaction when drinking this wine…  And it still has a great clean finish with its brick red color.  If I were to buy any wine I tasted today, it would be this one - I don’t know if I could wait 10+ years hoping for the other wines to reach this level.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is definitely balance between the old world style and new world style with these wines as the terroir really comes through along with medium(+) acidity that keeps the wines vibrant while achieving a ripeness found in the best Bordeaux vintages.  The price point of these wines might be a little higher than you may be used to, but they also demonstrate the little nuances that distinguish a $150 bottle from a $75 bottle.  I also think there is clear personality to the wines which make them seem unique as well.  My only concern is that most of these wines require a good amount of decanting if they are to be enjoyed right away.  Except that last bottle of course!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I did not walk away with any bottles or a membership, I do have a clear picture of where they rank next to other vineyards like Frank Family, Round Pond, and others whose Cabernets have hints of that dusty, Rutherford feel.  Even if you do not have the resources to purchase a case of the wine in the event you like it, I still recommend that you visit for a tasting to understand what is waiting for you when you can afford the nicer wines out there.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="calistoga" /><summary type="html">Another winery with a storied history longer than most (dating back to the late 1800s) that continues to produce top notch wines is Larkmead. Though unlike many others with the same length of history, Larkmead continues to be a small production winery, choosing to concentrate on quality over quantity as its 2013 The Lark (100pt by Wine Advocate) demonstrates. Its smaller size and simple-but-bright tasting room provides quite the contrast to Frank Family, which is right across the street. Both are located in Calistoga off the main highway, so there’s no reason not to visit either or both.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/larkmead/2.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Wine Membership Discussion</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/22/wine_membership_tips.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wine Membership Discussion" /><published>2018-11-22T14:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-22T14:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/22/wine_membership_tips</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/22/wine_membership_tips.html">&lt;p&gt;Happy Thanksgiving everyone!!!  I hope everyone is with family and/or friends celebrating over a nice, hot meal and a good bottle of wine.  Since this is a time for giving thanks, thank you, the readers, for following along on this deep dive into Napa wineries with a dose of Willamette Valley as well.  Soon, we will have a look at some in France, in case anyone is thinking of vacationing there at some point.  Some topics have continuously come up in feedback from you, so I’d like to take some time to write about one of them today: Wine Memberships.  Wine memberships is a broad topic and could be discussed in the context of several different segments of the wine industry - e.g. Wine Bars, Distributors/Wine Stores, Wineries.  Today we will focus the conversation on memberships as they pertain to wineries, but much of the same logic applies for other membership types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full discloser: I have been or recently became a member at several of the wineries I’ve written about so far.  This is not a coincidence - what better way to start writing than to write about things you really like?  My situation is a bit unusual though - I consume wine at a faster rate than most and use some of my membership wines for tastings with customers as well.  The normal consumer can likely handle around 3 memberships for various reasons discussed below, though if you handle 7 or more, I’d love to hear from you!!  We’ll discuss the pros/cons below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/wine-memberships/1-1050by788-e0df7c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/wine-memberships/1-700by525-e0df7c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/wine-memberships/1-675by506-e0df7c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/wine-memberships/1-450by338-e0df7c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/wine-memberships/1-525by394-e0df7c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/wine-memberships/1-350by263-e0df7c.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/wine-memberships/1-350by263-e0df7c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;I would live here&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It wouldn’t be a post about wine without a picture of a winery or vineyard in it. I decided to include one of my favorite shots of the Douro Valley in Portugal that wasn’t used in another post!  Don’t worry - we will discuss the wineries of the Douro at some point.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what are wine memberships and why do they exist?  Wine membership is a contract of sorts - it is a commitment from you (the consumer) to purchase a certain number of bottles at each allocation point during the year in return for benefits and other privileges that non-members do not have access to.  It’s obvious to understand why consumers participate, but why do wineries have these programs?  It’s all about the economics.  Each year, wineries invest a significant portion (for smaller ones, it can be all) of their available capital to produce the current vintage - the breakdown of these costs deserves its own article…  This is a huge risk - if all their capital is tied up in wine and they can’t sell that wine, or even if they can’t sell it at the rate that they need to in order to pay their bills, they will go under.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the basis of the “En Primeur” system in France, where large/famous estates (e.g. Lafite-Rothschild, Cheval Blanc) will sell futures in wine (you pay now for a bottle in 2-4 years) that is a lower price than what the wines will cost on release (when the wines are actually ready).  To some, this may seem like an ancient version of the “derivative” financial instrument and they would be right.  This is practiced much more efficiently today in the Agriculture industry (e.g. Corn Futures), but derivatives may never work for the wine industry as a whole.  That’s because no two wines taste the same or cost the same to produce.  If each product is slighly different, how can you manage to track the cost/value of each one to price the derivative?  Wine would need its own stock market!!  (That might be an idea…  Haha).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, that’s enough background from me - I always seem to excitedly dig into the history of wine.  Now that we know why membership programs benefit both the consumer and producer (and therefore know why they exist), let’s actually dig into more of the details for consumers.  Generally, the membership benefits at a given winery are a combination of the following.  Wineries may have incremental membership programs too where the more bottles you commit to buying, the greater the number of benefits and the degree of those benefits (e.g. price discount) are in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;list-of-potential-benefits-from-a-winery-membership&quot;&gt;List of Potential Benefits from a Winery Membership&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price Discount on Purchases&lt;/strong&gt; - Who doesn’t want to pay less for wine?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Free or Discounted Tours and Tastings at the Winery&lt;/strong&gt; - Again, who doesn’t want to pay less for wine?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Access to Limited Production Wines, Library Wines, and Larger Formats)&lt;/strong&gt; - This benefit is tailored to the wine collector types.  Those who crave the rare, highly rated, hard-to-access wines.  This definitely includes me to a degree, especially since I don’t want to wait 10 years when I buy a wine to drink it at its optimal point.  So I purchase library wines that have already undergone that aging in an optimal environment and are ready for consumption when I buy it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guaranteed Availability of Wines for Purchase&lt;/strong&gt; - Some wineries become so popular that their entire inventory is spoken for, even before they release the wine.  Sometimes in order to even get access to purchase they wine they produce, you need to join their wine club.  The most popular small producers, sometimes referred to as cult producers, may have waiting lists that last years before they have room for your allocation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discounted Shipping&lt;/strong&gt; - If you live far enough away from the winery, you’ll know that shipping isn’t cheap.  In addition, many things can go wrong during ground shipping and the storage they use that maybe you want to use 2-day or overnight shipping to make sure your expensive wine arrives in pristine condition.  This can cost its own small fortune.  Discounted/Free Shipping can sometimes be a bigger savings than the discounts they give you on their wines…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Access to Private Areas at the Winery&lt;/strong&gt; - In Napa, most larger wineries have special access areas that are available only to wine club members.  Some even may have different areas for different member levels.  If you are lucky enough to have a tasting in the owner’s tent out in the vineyards, you’ll know what I am talking about when I say this benefit means something (see my Chappellet Review for an example).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ability to Reserve the Winery for Private Events&lt;/strong&gt; - You and your friends probably need to live close to the winery to take advantage of this benefit.  Still, I can imagine having a great birthday party or wedding at one of my favorite wineries!  After all, it seems like the views from every winery is great and relaxing.  Though, imagining the cost of holding such events may be more nightmarish.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Invitation to Winery Events&lt;/strong&gt; - No event is more exciting at a winery than the annual release party.  It’s a chance to thank the wine gods for a good harvest, thank all of the winery’s employees for their hard work, and thank the consumers for purchasing the wine and making this annual cycle possible.  Access to this and other events (e.g. Some may host a summer bbq, a birthday party for the winery, etc.) is one of the lesser celebrated perks of being a winery member.  What I would give to not just get a picture with my winemaking idols, but to get one at a party with unbridled joy on both of our faces.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Less Thinking, More Drinking&lt;/strong&gt; - Do you have a problem choosing new wines every time you go to the store?  Do you just want to drink your favorite wine whenever you feel like it?  Do you forget to purchase that wine or find it’s not in your local stores?  A winery membership takes care of those problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;list-of-potential-drawbacks-from-a-winery-membership&quot;&gt;List of Potential Drawbacks from a Winery Membership&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commitment to Purchasing Bottles&lt;/strong&gt; - Remember, the reward for the winery is that you purchase a minimum amount of their wine.  While many winery memberships can be cancelled at any given time, if you want to continue to enjoy the perks, you will need to continue buying.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Winery Co-Location&lt;/strong&gt; - If you don’t live close to the winery, taking advantage of a majority of the membership benefits can be tough.  Living in DC, I can only take advantage of my membership benefits a couple times a year (e.g. free/discounted tastings), and some not at all (e.g. winery events).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decreased Desire/Ability to Explore&lt;/strong&gt; - Some people might not consider this a drawback but I do.  Part of what I love about the wine world is you never know what amazing wine you might drink tomorrow.  But if you are always going to the same wineries to take advantage of your membership benefits, you may not ever discover the amazing wine that is just down the street.  If you keep getting their shipments too, you may not have the money nor space in your wine rack to explore other places either…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexibility of Allocation Shipments&lt;/strong&gt; - It may be that you joined a winery to get access to their Cabernet Sauvignon, but come springtime, you will also receive the Sauvignon Blanc that you may not be fond of.  Many wineries are flexible in what gets shipped as part of your allocation, but some are not.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficult Discontinuing the Membership&lt;/strong&gt; - This may also be a drawback that only I feel, but I have cancelled a few winery memberships over the years and it was not easy.  It wasn’t that the winery made the process hard, but it felt very personal to do it.  When you discontinue a winery membership, depending on its size, it can feel like you are divorcing a friend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As long as the winery isn’t outside your price range (it’ll likely be more expensive than your local grocery store’s selection, but may be the right price point for nice dinners or celebrations), the drawbacks don’t really seem to impact you until you hit that third winery.  By then, you might be considering another winery membership, but may feel the need to discontinue a previous membership to make room in your budget and your cabinet.  In addition, you may find yourself needing to plan a schedule of which wineries to visit which weekends to take advantage of the membership perks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, there is no right answer.  Or put more accurately, there may be different answers for different people.  Just remember that when you drink that bottle of wine, many people contributed to getting that great juice into the bottle (and making the bottle too!).  As long as you are paying hommage to that fact and treat those people and their products with respect, you are entitled to desiring that they put every effort forward to getting you the best bottle of wine they can manage at that price point.  So get out there, visit some wineries, drinks some wines, give thanks to all of the people that contributed to those wines, and let the good times roll.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="tips" /><summary type="html">Happy Thanksgiving everyone!!! I hope everyone is with family and/or friends celebrating over a nice, hot meal and a good bottle of wine. Since this is a time for giving thanks, thank you, the readers, for following along on this deep dive into Napa wineries with a dose of Willamette Valley as well. Soon, we will have a look at some in France, in case anyone is thinking of vacationing there at some point. Some topics have continuously come up in feedback from you, so I’d like to take some time to write about one of them today: Wine Memberships. Wine memberships is a broad topic and could be discussed in the context of several different segments of the wine industry - e.g. Wine Bars, Distributors/Wine Stores, Wineries. Today we will focus the conversation on memberships as they pertain to wineries, but much of the same logic applies for other membership types.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/wine-memberships/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Cristom’s “The Cristom Experience” Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/17/cristom_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cristom's &quot;The Cristom Experience&quot; Private Tasting" /><published>2018-11-17T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-17T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/17/cristom_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/17/cristom_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;There are many exciting wineries to visit in the Portland / Willamette Valley area.  Although not as famous as Domaine Drouhin nor Argyle, Cristom is undoubtedly one of my favorites in the region, if not my absolute favorite.  Everything about Cristom screams family – from the shape/structure of the tasting room, to their candor and joy while conducting their tastings, to the accessible prices of their wines and your ability to taste anything (with the right appointment), to even the way they named the winery (named after the co-owners - Christine and Thomas).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/1-1050by788-201740.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/1-700by525-201740.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/1-675by506-201740.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/1-450by338-201740.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/1-525by394-201740.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/1-350by263-201740.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/1-350by263-201740.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Chainsaw Massacre&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Taking a chainsaw to the previously grafted section.  This way, they can re-plant a different varietal or a new clone of the same varietal on the rootstock.  It will be a couple years before they can harvest grapes from the new vines.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/2-1050by1400-37527d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/2-700by933-37527d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/2-675by900-37527d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/2-450by600-37527d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/2-525by700-37527d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/2-350by467-37527d.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/2-350by467-37527d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;TV Antennae&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A picture of the newly grafted vines.  The sealant used at the grafting point and the top of the new vines is to protect them from disease, since the point of the wounds can get easily infected.  Very cool to watch as everything was happening.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I happened to visit Cristom at a busy time too as they were in the middle of re-grafting a large section of their vineyard.  They were generous enough to bring me out into the field and explain their rationale for why they were changing their varietals and clones.  After walking through the fields and their storage facilities with their estate Viognier and Pinot in hand, we finally got to the main tasting event inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/3-1050by788-8a2763.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/3-700by525-8a2763.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/3-675by506-8a2763.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/3-450by338-8a2763.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/3-525by394-8a2763.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/3-350by263-8a2763.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/3-350by263-8a2763.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;VSP&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A great example of a vine planted for vertical shoot positioning (VSP).  A branch from last year’s growth is preserved through the winter where new vines will grow vertically from.  They will be tied to the trellis wires (above) and trained upwards to ensure good sun exposure and space for wind to blow through (after rain and lingering fog.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or so I thought.  We were interrupted by the owner of the winery himself who heard that I was dropping wine knowledge to my cousin and her husband.  He introduced himself, asked how I heard about Cristom (blind Pinot Noir tasting with WSET students), and asked what I thought about their operation.  I forgot my resume at home, but needless to say that we got along swimmingly.  We even took a picture together (see below).  There was no pretentiousness at this winery whatsoever, which is not to say other places I visited were - it’s just that everyone felt so relaxed and happy just drinking the wine.  This was only possible because the wine was that good…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/4-1050by1400-5ab802.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/4-700by933-5ab802.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/4-675by900-5ab802.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/4-450by600-5ab802.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/4-525by700-5ab802.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/4-350by467-5ab802.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/4-350by467-5ab802.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Lucky Me!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I was lucky enough to run into the owner and winegrower of Cristom: Tom Gerrie.  We shared a conversation for 15 minutes on our obsession with wine, our respect for Burgundy, and our outsized expectations for Willamette Valley’s future.  As much as I love exploring new places, I will definitely be visiting Cristom again when I return to Oregon!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if this was the actual lineup, or I got a few extra bottles because of the picture above, but I got to taste basically the entire inventory that Cristom had available at the time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2016-Estate-Viognier&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Estate Viognier&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($30)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2016-Mt--Jefferson-Cuv-e-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Mt. Jefferson Cuvée Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($35)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2014-Estate-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Estate Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($50)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2015-Eileen-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Eileen Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($65)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/14-Louise-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir-750ml&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Louise Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($60)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/14-Jessie-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir-750ml&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Jessie Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($60)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2015-Marjorie-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Marjorie Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($70)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2014-Carter-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Carter Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2014-Hirschy-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Hirschy Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2014-Canary-Hill-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Canary Hill Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2015-Estate-Syrah&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Estate Syrah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($50)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I lost a lot of tasting notes from my trip to Oregon this past year.  But my biggest regret is losing the tasting notes for Cristom, because the Pinot Noirs were all so wonderfully diverse.  The best were the four ladies - Eileen Vineyard, Jessie Vineyard, Louise Vineyard, and Marjorie Vineyard.  With vines that average over 20 years in age and are rooted in mostly 10M+ year old Basalt soils, there is just so much complexity that develops on the vines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combining that with whole-cluster fermentation techniques observed in Burgundy, the Pinot Noirs here have character that is unique in the Willamette Valley.  The flavors are more traditional (e.g. red fruit that is lighter than cherry, but not unripe by any means) but different compared to Burgundy (e.g. on one of the wines, I clearly observed tomato leaf as an aroma).  As someone who enjoys cerebral wines, this had me running around in circles.  Though I know others with an open mind could just enjoy the wines as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/5-1050by788-6a06f5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/5-700by525-6a06f5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/5-675by506-6a06f5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/5-450by338-6a06f5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/5-525by394-6a06f5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/5-350by263-6a06f5.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/5-350by263-6a06f5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Lucky Me!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Obligatory picture of the beautiful vineyards.  Luckily, my cousin Jennifer was asking really good questions, which allowed me to hang back at points and just enjoy the experience.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wine &amp;amp; Spirits Magazine found that Cristom is the “#1 Pinot Noir on restaurant wine lists in America” for two years running.  I’m not lucky enough to have restaurants near me with this on the menu, but I do imagine they would be fun to pair foods with.  To be safe, I walked away with a case of their wine - choosing several bottles of the Jessie and one of each of the rest I liked.  If you are in the area, Cristom needs to be on your list of wineries to visit.  It may be 15-20min south of the larger group of wineries, but you need to make this trip.  If you do and enjoy the wines as much as I do, be sure to tell them that Jeremy sent you.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="oregon" /><category term="willamette-valley" /><category term="eola-amity-hills" /><summary type="html">There are many exciting wineries to visit in the Portland / Willamette Valley area. Although not as famous as Domaine Drouhin nor Argyle, Cristom is undoubtedly one of my favorites in the region, if not my absolute favorite. Everything about Cristom screams family – from the shape/structure of the tasting room, to their candor and joy while conducting their tastings, to the accessible prices of their wines and your ability to taste anything (with the right appointment), to even the way they named the winery (named after the co-owners - Christine and Thomas).</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/cristom/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Domaine Drouhin Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/10/domaine_drouhin_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Domaine Drouhin Public Tasting" /><published>2018-11-10T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/10/domaine_drouhin_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/10/domaine_drouhin_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Starting a new winery is hard.  There are so many things to do on the operations side such as clearing out the field, adjusting the soil, planting and caring for the vines, etc.  But just as important as making the product is building a brand and fostering a consumer base that will purchase your product.  This is even harder when you are entering an established market like Willamette Valley.  Thankfully for Domaine Drouhin, they had the branding piece covered already when they established the winery in 1987 and have continued to add to their reputation and legacy from Burgundy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/1-1050by788-8be9e2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/1-700by525-8be9e2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/1-675by506-8be9e2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/1-450by338-8be9e2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/1-525by394-8be9e2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/1-350by263-8be9e2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/1-350by263-8be9e2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Doorway to France&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The doorway to Oregon soil and French Soul&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I visited their tasting room in Beaune, France (capital of the Burgundy area) last year and had a great time.  Their Clos de la Roche Grand Cru from a magnum was crazy good, but more on that in its own review, haha.  Needless to say, I left impressed with their wines.  So when I heard that they had a sister winery in Willamette, you know I had to visit.  I didn’t quite know what to expect as I was driving to the vineyard.  But when I saw the winery, I just shook my head and told myself “of course it would be like this”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/2-1050by788-65f21e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/2-700by525-65f21e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/2-675by506-65f21e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/2-450by338-65f21e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/2-525by394-65f21e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/2-350by263-65f21e.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/2-350by263-65f21e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;A look to the vines&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Wine is only as good as the vines/soil they come from.  A view off the patio into some of their nearby vines&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Owner of 225 acres in the heart of the Dundee Hills area, the winery itself is surrounded by seemingly endless rows of vines with no other structures in sight besides the road you took.  Inside, the place was packed with people.  Many picking up their bottle allocations, many there to sample the wines, and more people than I expected just enjoying a day at the vineyard with their family.  The wines themselves were an interesting mix of new world power with old world flavor profiles and acidity.  This tasting was right after lunch, so my palate was a little off-center, but I would firmly place the tasting in the good category.  The tasting consisted of the following wines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.domainedrouhin.com/2016_Arthur_Chardonnay&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 DDO Chardonnay Arthur&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($35)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The white flowers, balanced body and solid acidity reminded me of Burgundian whites, but the fruit profile was definitely riper (e.g. stonefruit) than what you would find at their French estate.  Not too over-the-top, this is a nice Chardonnay to casually drink.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.domainedrouhin.com/2015_Roserock_Pinot_Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Roserock Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($35)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Roserock covered a higher range of flavors than I normally encounter at this price point in America, meaning you can drink this young or let it evolve a bit with a few years of aging.  Though I wouldn’t wait more than 3 or so.  Balanced with structure and levity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.domainedrouhin.com/2015_Pinot_Noir_Dundee_HIlls&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 DDO Pinot Noir Dundee Hills&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($45)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;There is a noticeable difference of structure and intensity between the Roserock and DDO Dundee Hills.  More red fruit here that is still young in the bottle, balanced, and a noticeably longer finish.  Some wood spice character is also starting to come out - you can age this for 5 years if you wanted.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.domainedrouhin.com/2015_Roserock_Zephirine&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Roserock Zephirine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($60)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;While the previous wines focused on the balance and fruit, the Zephirine takes you on a bit of a turn towards more complexity, particularly terroir driven notes (more vivid floral notes, lighter red fruit, but some wood spice and just a hint of cacao.  This can age even longer than the Dundee Hills (up to 8-10).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.domainedrouhin.com/2015_Laurene&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 DDO Pinot Noir Laurene&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($70)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This is where the complexity hits its peak in the tasting.  To the floral, light red fruit, and light spice character, now add riper fruit (e.g. Cherry) and more dusty character from the terroir.  This felt like the best expression of French and Oregon flavors and concepts of the bunch.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of their French roots, if I my schedule had allowed, I would’ve really liked to have done the “French Soul, Oregon Soil” tasting ($40) instead.  Conducted only at 10AM, they taste wines from their French and Oregon Estates to compare and contrast the Chardonnay and Pinot Noir flavors and characteristics.  Looking back at the tastings, I personally still prefer their French wine - there’s just a level of nuance they achieve with those wines that make them that much more cerebral and enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the $15 fee is very reasonable - The membership pricing and benefits (20% off or free shipping on 6 or more bottles for new memeber) are also pretty solid.  I did not bring back any bottles with me since there are so many good wineries in the area and my luggage was only so big.  However, I encourage you to put this place in your Top 5 of wineries to visit when in the region.  They definitely provide a unique perspective of the terroir in the area and the views are too good to ignore.  Just be prepared to wade through a mass of humanity on the weekend, haha.  Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="oregon" /><category term="willamette-valley" /><category term="dundee-hills" /><summary type="html">Starting a new winery is hard. There are so many things to do on the operations side such as clearing out the field, adjusting the soil, planting and caring for the vines, etc. But just as important as making the product is building a brand and fostering a consumer base that will purchase your product. This is even harder when you are entering an established market like Willamette Valley. Thankfully for Domaine Drouhin, they had the branding piece covered already when they established the winery in 1987 and have continued to add to their reputation and legacy from Burgundy.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/domaine-drouhin/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Argyle “Masters of Sparking” Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/03/argyle_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Argyle &quot;Masters of Sparking&quot; Private Tasting" /><published>2018-11-03T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-03T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/03/argyle_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/03/argyle_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;When people think of Oregon wine, they normal think of red still wine that ranges from the finesse of Burgundy Pinot Noir to the power of Russian River Valley Pinot Noir.  They don’t necessarily think of Sparkling wine, which is a key product of Pinot Noir all around the world, not just Champagne.  And when it comes to Oregon Sparkling Wine, there is no place more established than Argyle; heck, it’s even called out specifically in my Wine and Spirits Education Trust (WSET) Sparkling Wine Class!  The reputation alone is enough to entice even seasoned wine professionals, but when I discovered there was a special Sparkling tasting that also lets you to disgorge a bottle by hand, I made Argyle my first call during my itinerary construction.  I brought along my cousin and her husband for a full weekend of tastings in Willamette as their wedding gift, but this visit was definitely a gift to myself, haha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/1-1050by788-182328.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/1-700by525-182328.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/1-675by506-182328.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/1-450by338-182328.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/1-525by394-182328.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/1-350by263-182328.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/1-350by263-182328.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;beautiful tasting room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view of Argyle’s tasting room as your enter the winery.  Clean, rustic and just feels like a place I would want to drink good wine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winery itself is spacious and gorgeous, polished yet rustic, and has parts from its old barrel storage facility incorporated into different aspects of the new building.  Argyle’s tasting area could hold 100 people without issue and there’s even enough room for kids to run around outside.  Upon entering the facility, we were greeted with a sparkling Riesling that resembled Deutcher Sekt (German Sparkling Wine), but was a little drier and lower in acidity.  After we finished exploring the tasting area, the manager of the winery picked us up and took us to the back for a private tour and tasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/2-1050by788-a75c39.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/2-700by525-a75c39.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/2-675by506-a75c39.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/2-450by338-a75c39.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/2-525by394-a75c39.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/2-350by263-a75c39.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/2-350by263-a75c39.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;just nod&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Learning about the unique terroir of the Willamette Valley and why Pinot Noir is so delicious here.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We first walked through the back space of the storage area, where it was the coolest and darkest.  There we saw unspeakable things, like wines that had been aging on their lees for nearly 10 years, long enough to make even great Champagne Negociant houses blush; the prestige cuvees (best wines) of a Champagne Negociant (e.g. Moet Chandon) is normally aged on the lees for 5-7 years.  Although the bottles didn’t have the iconic black mold growing on the bottles (this was a warehouse, not an underground cave after all), you could tell that these were cared for greatly before they made it to the gyropalates for riddling and eventual disgorgement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One curious thing - there was a pupitre in a corner that someone had been manually riddling.  Turns out, this is for perspective customers of this tasting!  Our host grabbed a bottle and a cap-popping tool and we all headed outside.  The weekend was my cousin’s wedding present, so I let her husband do the disgorging – it was actually well-done…  Once we cleaned up and geeked out a bit more on the production process, it was time to head inside for the tasting.  Our lineup consisted of the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sparkling Wine - Zero Dosage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sparkling Wine - Dosage A&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sparkling Wine - Dosage B&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sparkling Wine - Dosage C&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sparkling Wine - Final Blend&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.argylewinery.com/2014SpiritHillBlancdeBlancs&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Spirit Hill Blanc de Blancs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($50)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This 100% Chardonnay sparkling wine from Eola-Amity Hills has great acidity, minerality, and enough creaminess to balance the lemon flavors.  This is a high energy sparkling that doesn’t seem tamed at all by the time it has spent in neutral oak barrels.  Worth getting at the membership price point.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.argylewinery.com/2014KnudsenVineyardBrut&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Knudsen Vineyard Brut&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($50)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Old vine plot, so you know it’s going to be complex.  Higher elevation helps to preserve the high acidity and lighter citrus flavors.  But this wine is about the barrel aging, which brought out some smoke character to pair with the red fruit (from the Pinot Noir) and citrus.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.argylewinery.com/product/2014-Argyle-Brut-Ros-&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Brut Rose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($50)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Another sparkling wine from the Eola-Amity Hills, so you know its going to have some degree of minerality.  But it’s the lighter, unripened red fruit that play the most prominent role here.  You can feel a little tannin, but this is a delicate wine for drinking chilled on a hot summer day.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.argylewinery.com/2007ExtendedTirageBrut&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2007 Extended Tirage Brut&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;My favorite from the tasting as discussed further below.  The bright acidity, creamy texture, ripe fruit (stonefruit, citrus), and aged character (toast, nuts) are all well integrated into this sparkling wine.  The complexity and character are off the charts and the novelty of its production is also fun to show off.  Buy and try this wine - you will not regret it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2007 Extended Tirage Brut Rose&lt;/strong&gt; ($120)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If this wine was priced similarly to the Extended Tirage Brut, I would have also picked up a bottle.  There is similar character to the Brut Rose and the Extended Tirage Brut with some additional fleshiness on the palate as well.  However it’s priced a little too high for my taste.  Definitely still worth tasting at the winery if you get the chance!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/4-1050by788-62224f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/4-700by525-62224f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/4-675by506-62224f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/4-450by338-62224f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/4-525by394-62224f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/4-350by263-62224f.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/4-350by263-62224f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;delicious&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Argyle’s linup of Sparkling Wines&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, there are 10 wines in this tasting that are broken up into two sets, so come prepared.  The first set is purely for educational purposes - both for you and the winery.  You receive the same sparkling wine with four different dosage levels (including Zero Dosage) and are asked which is your preference.  After all, it’s important the winery produces wines that consumers like!  Next you can try to guess the dosage levels of each sparkling wine and then which of the four the Final Blend is.  Hint: It’s not the Zero Dosage wine.  But getting it right is actually much harder than you might think as they all feel pretty similar on the palate.  After discussing Argyle’s approach to sparkling wine, you’ll then taste the next set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/5-1050by788-6c70ba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/5-700by525-6c70ba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/5-675by506-6c70ba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/5-450by338-6c70ba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/5-525by394-6c70ba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/5-350by263-6c70ba.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/5-350by263-6c70ba.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;captivated&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Discussing Argyle’s methodology when it comes to producing its Sparkling wines and how the dosage affects more than just taste.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of all these wines, I was absolutely captivated by the 10 Year Old Sparkling Wine, which I found out later was the highest rated of the group.  Unlike Champagne where fertilization of the soil every few years is necessary, Oregon has more fertile soil by comparison, which in turn leads to wines with greater flavors.  Normally, this is greatly desired, but in Sparkling wine, you want a more neutral base wine so that the flavors which result from the lees aging are more prominent (e.g. brioche, cream).  To deal with this stronger fruit flavor in the base wine, Argyle makes a wine that ages on the lees for ~10 years to increase the strength of those flavors.  What results is a strong, but subtle wine of great flavor that seemingly could explode at any moment, favoring one flavor (fruit) or the other (lees aging).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/6-1050by788-c59bcb.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/6-700by525-c59bcb.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/6-675by506-c59bcb.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/6-450by338-c59bcb.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/6-525by394-c59bcb.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/6-350by263-c59bcb.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/argyle/6-350by263-c59bcb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;every day I'm hustling&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;You know why I am smiling right?  Guess who ranked all of the dosage levels correctly and then guessed the final blend?  This guy…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tasting itself though was a very educational experience.  Tasting four wines of the exact same blend, from the same vintage, and from the same vineyards, differing only in the dosage was a real treat.  So many things I learned about in class that are hard to taste/test practically became much more clear.  The room used for the tasting itself was a small room enclosed by glass, surrounded by racks holding some of their rarest/oldest wines.  I couldn’t quite convince the manager to open one of the bottles, but I was able to get a 6-pack of the 10 Year Old Sparkling Wine at a members discount with free shipping, which isn’t bad.  My cousin and her husband ended up becoming members on the winery, so I probably got the discount transitively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in Sparkling wines, but don’t want to pay for that ticket to Europe, Argyle is a great alternative that stands among the best in America.  And do take advantage of the food truck outside or eat lunch before your tasting appointment.  You will thank yourself, haha.  Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="oregon" /><category term="willamette-valley" /><category term="dundee-hills" /><summary type="html">When people think of Oregon wine, they normal think of red still wine that ranges from the finesse of Burgundy Pinot Noir to the power of Russian River Valley Pinot Noir. They don’t necessarily think of Sparkling wine, which is a key product of Pinot Noir all around the world, not just Champagne. And when it comes to Oregon Sparkling Wine, there is no place more established than Argyle; heck, it’s even called out specifically in my Wine and Spirits Education Trust (WSET) Sparkling Wine Class! The reputation alone is enough to entice even seasoned wine professionals, but when I discovered there was a special Sparkling tasting that also lets you to disgorge a bottle by hand, I made Argyle my first call during my itinerary construction. I brought along my cousin and her husband for a full weekend of tastings in Willamette as their wedding gift, but this visit was definitely a gift to myself, haha.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/argyle/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Archery Summit Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/27/archery_summit_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Archery Summit Public Tasting" /><published>2018-10-27T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-27T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/27/archery_summit_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/27/archery_summit_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;One of the toughest questions I’ve been asked about my Oregon travels is “where do I find good Pinot?”  The reason this is tough is because it’s everywhere, especially with Willamette Valley being a short 1-hour drive from Portland.  But when people ask me where the best Oregon Pinot Noir can be found, I normally respond with Archery Summit in my Top 3.  As its name implies, the winery can be found on the top of a hill not far from Domaine Drouhin, Sokol Blosser, and others.  I love their planting pattern too - you almost need to weave through the vines while driving up to the tasting room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tasting room itself is small, holding only ~20 people at a time, and their entrance to the storage level from the tasting room area is a small hidden entrance down some stairs.  All of this gives it a homely, friendly feel until you start the tasting.  Don’t let the modest exterior and tasting room fool you - Archery Summit is a powerhouse in Willamette that produces exceptional wines.  Although they are only ~25 years old, they own 6 vineyards encompassing 120 acres, have some of the oldest Pinot vines in the valley (40+ years), maintain the only cave system in Oregon, and consistently deliver high-scoring wines, especially for Pinot Noirs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Wine Advocate usually scores them in the 90-92 range while the Wine Enthusiast and Wine Spectator usually score them in the 93-95 range, meaning that the wines are less about power (Wine Advocate gives higher scores for that) and more about finesse and balance (what WE and WS hone in on more).  If you asked me to rate the wines, I would lean toward the 93-95 range.  Not because I prefer finesse over power, but because the purity of the wines cover any shortcomings with regards to power.  Another reason I scored the Archery Summit visit well is their tasting fee ($30) is very reasonable for the number of wines (and their quality) included in the tasting.  Certainly better than many places in Napa.  Without further ado, below are the wines on their tasting menu:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.archerysummit.com/product/2016-Pinot-Noir-Ros-&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Rose of Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($32)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Much more color in this rose than its counterparts from other vineyards, likely due to a longer maceration with the skins or there is more press juice that is used for the wine.  This additional richness is clear on the palate as well, but can be balanced by serving at a colder temperature if that’s your preference.  I found it hard to discern the flavors since the wine was very different than other Roses I’ve had and can’t put it better than the winery themselves: “aromas of fresh guava, starfruit, blood orange juice and rosewater. The palate is layered with notes of raspberry, grapefruit peel and juicy cranberry with lingering hints of delicate orange blossom.”&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.archerysummit.com/product/2016-Archer-s-Edge-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Archer’s Edge Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($90)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Probably the wine I am most conflicted about.  It has such great potential, but didn’t show as well today as I would’ve liked.  Candied red fruits and grapey in its flavor profile and lighter in body thanks to its younger vines.  I hope that some secondary flavors develop in the future, but right now, this is mainly a nice, easy-drinking wine.  I don’t quite get the cocoa powder as described in the winery’s tasting notes, but the basalt soil does begin to come into play.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.archerysummit.com/product/2015-Renegade-Ridge-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Renegade Ridge Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($90)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Renegade Ridge definitely had more intensity to it.  Lighter red/blue fruit notes and even some hints of citrus.  There is a slight dusty cocoa as well that adds a bit of complexity.  The tannins, acid, and body were all very balanced and in line with the intensity of the wine.  Definitely better to enjoy this wine while it’s younger rather than trying to age it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.archerysummit.com/product/2015-Arcus-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Arcus Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($125)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wonderful nose – a lot more floral than the other wines.  Violets and roses, with bright red juicy fruit on both the nose and palate, with just a touch of spice adding complexity.  Great mouthfeel with enough tannins to age it a bit as well.  The spice from the wood is bigger in this wine than the others, but it blends well with the dusty cocoa and red fruit.  The red fruit was a complex mix and very cerebral - I ended up buying a bottle of this wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.archerysummit.com/product/2015-Red-Hills-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Red Hills Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($100)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Blue fruit is more prominent than red fruit (but there is rose petal on the nose).  The most interesting flavors though were the black tea and the sweet spices in the wine.  Though, they certainly did not feel out of place or overly intense - everything was still smoothly integrated in the wine.  There are several Pinots in the area that fit into this flavor profile (black tea, sweet spice) - I find them fascinating, but it may not be to everyone else’s tastes.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.archerysummit.com/product/2015-Premier-Cuv-e-Pinot-Noir1111&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Premium Cuvee Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($54)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Probably the best quality-to-price ratio (QPR) wine from Archery Summit.  The ripeness and richness is more like the Arcus (though more black fruit here) than any of the other wines we tasted, making it very competitive with a lot of other similarly priced wines from the area.  I liked the coffee hints that were there with the dusty cocoa.  It’s very hard not to take two bottles of this over a bottle of one of the other bottles in the tasting lineup…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The membership benefits for Archery Summit are very appealing as well - in addition to significant discounts on the wines, you are invited to winery events and can bring guests with you multiple times for free tastings.  At their non-discounted prices, the cost is a little steep / reminds you of Russian River Valley (RRV), but are still worth it if you can afford it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theme of the wines from Archery Summit reminds me of Kapcsandy.  Not nearly the complexity or price, but that purity of fruit without much candied notes in the wine that is often seen elsewhere.  And although the tasting room is on the smaller side, they can still handle larger groups - a bachelorette party I sent there a couple of months ago had no problems and thoroughly enjoyed their visit.  I highly recommend visiting for a tasting before purchasing their single-vineyard wines, but if you find the 2015 Premium Cuvee at a wine store that you trust, buy a bottle and share with friends a taste of what Willamette has to offer.  Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="oregon" /><category term="willamette-valley" /><category term="dundee-hills" /><summary type="html">One of the toughest questions I’ve been asked about my Oregon travels is “where do I find good Pinot?” The reason this is tough is because it’s everywhere, especially with Willamette Valley being a short 1-hour drive from Portland. But when people ask me where the best Oregon Pinot Noir can be found, I normally respond with Archery Summit in my Top 3. As its name implies, the winery can be found on the top of a hill not far from Domaine Drouhin, Sokol Blosser, and others. I love their planting pattern too - you almost need to weave through the vines while driving up to the tasting room.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Au Sommet Private Tasting with Amuse Bouche and Coup de Foudre</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/20/au_sommet_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Au Sommet Private Tasting with Amuse Bouche and Coup de Foudre" /><published>2018-10-20T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-20T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/20/au_sommet_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/20/au_sommet_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;The last winery for one of our weekend trips to Napa and it was indeed a good one.  Once you contact the winery to setup an appointment, you’ll have a couple of options for the tasting: the Amuse Bouche building in downtown Napa or the Au Sommet vineyard on Atlas Peak.  We obviously chose Atlas Peak, but if you are pressed for time (it is a 20min drive from Napa) or are a nervous driver (it’s unpaved roads only 1.5 lanes wide going up a mountain), I recommend you stay in Napa.  Once you do make it to the winery though, like so many others, the view is worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/1-1050by1065-8a6559.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/1-700by710-8a6559.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/1-675by685-8a6559.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/1-450by457-8a6559.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/1-525by533-8a6559.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/1-350by355-8a6559.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/1-350by355-8a6559.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;It really was a great view&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Enjoying the view from of the vineyards from the tower on the property&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you drive up the mountain, you can still see the devastating effects of the forest fires from last year: some houses completely burnt down, others nearby amazingly unscathed, and blackened plots of land that are starting to show signs of life again.  I hope it wasn’t disrespectful, but multiple times, we slowed down to take pictures because of the impressions the sights left on us.  When we finally made it to the winery, we took a moment to reflect on the power and unpredictability of nature, then proceeded to listen to the story the wines had to tell us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/2-1050by700-98e493.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/2-700by467-98e493.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/2-675by450-98e493.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/2-450by300-98e493.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/2-525by350-98e493.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/2-350by233-98e493.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/2-350by233-98e493.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;I told you it was a great view&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view of the vineyards from the watchtower as I am explaining something that is probably important&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/3-1050by700-21d263.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/3-700by467-21d263.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/3-675by450-21d263.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/3-450by300-21d263.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/3-525by350-21d263.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/3-350by233-21d263.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/3-350by233-21d263.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;I may talk with my hands a bit&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view from the ground as I continue to explain something that is probably important&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tasting room itself is almost a side house/renovated shed next to the main property (I think the family lives in the main building).  There was a watchtower-like structure that we could climb to get a view of the valley below and also catch a glimpse of the helipad that Heidi Barrett uses to land her helicopter when she comes here.  Oh, did I mention that Heidi is a collaborator with some of the wines?  After some more pictures and breathing in the mountain air with no sounds but the birds chirping, we were ready to taste the wines.  &lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; We also had wines from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amusebouchewine.com/index.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amuse Bouche&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coupdefoudrewine.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coup de Foudre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; while at Au Sommet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amusebouchewine.com/pret-a-boire/index.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Pret a Boire&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A rose composed of 66% Grenache and 33% Syrah.  This wine was a balancing act of ripeness, freshness, acidity and body.  There are few roses that command this type of price point, but I think it’s warranted.  It will assuredly test your palate’s limits when it comes to subtlety.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amusebouchewine.com/richard-g-peterson/richard-g-peterson-pinot-noir.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Richard Peterson Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;One of the most purchased wines by our group at this tasting.  The only varietal that Heidi Barrett does not work with is the one that her father (Richard Peterson) specializes in: Pinot Noir.  And this Pinot Noir is very good.  Stylistically, it reminds me of Burgundy Pinots that cost much more than this bottle.  This is a great price point too when you consider the other Pinot Noirs grown in the Russian River Valley nearby.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coupdefoudrewine.com/lesbouquinistes.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Les Bouquinistes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($58)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A complicated blend of Syrah, Merlot, Petit Verdot, Zinfandel.  This is definitely not a typical blend of varietals that you’ll see elsewhere.  And because of that, you know that I bought a few bottles…  The price point also makes it very attractive.  The wine is also quite enjoyable in addition to being cerebral - wine experts and newbies alike should be able to enjoy this one.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ausommetwine.com/au-sommet/index.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Au Sommet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($250)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The estate Cabernet Sauvignon produced from the vines on this Atlas Peak property.  Very drinkable now, as is Heidi’s style, but you can taste that there is potential for aging.  The wine is also reflective of the Atlas Peak terroir and how it differs from the other mountain AVAs around Napa Valley.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amusebouchewine.com/amuse-bouche/index.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Amuse Bouche&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($225)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This is the wine for which a reporter once asked where the grapes came from and Heidi responded she would have to kill him if she told him.  This Merlot from an undisclosed site was just something special; I couldn’t quite put my finger on what though in this right-bank Bordeaux style wine.  Both the Au Sommet and this were wonderful, but I walked away with bottles of this because of that extra something.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amusebouchewine.com/vin-perdu/index.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Vin Perdu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I also walked away with bottles of this.  The second label Merlot to the Amuse Bouche, this wine has great perfume, ripeness and balance on the palate.  If the Amuse Bouche is quality play, this is the value play as it will stand up nicely against other estates’ premium Merlot offering.  This is capable of some aging too, so don’t drink it all right away!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coupdefoudrewine.com/cabernetsauvignon.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Coup de Foudre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($95)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I love the concept of this bottle; you can peel off the label and then document where/when you had it and how it made you feel.  But that is window dressing as the wine is plenty good without the trick to the label.  It’s also priced at the right level - it should not be compared to the Au Sommet nor Amuse Bouche, but to other estates’ $100 Cabernet.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/4-1050by788-111bf5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/4-700by525-111bf5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/4-675by506-111bf5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/4-450by338-111bf5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/4-525by394-111bf5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/4-350by263-111bf5.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/au_sommet/4-350by263-111bf5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;So much good wine in the storage room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The wine tasting bar and inventory storage.  We did our tasting outside to enjoy the weather&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theme of the wines is similar to that of other Heidi Barrett style wines - great quality, fruit, midpalate, balance and the wines are approachable early in their development.  The breadth of varietals and AVAs used for these wines makes it a great visit too if you want something more than just the typical Chardonnay/Sauvignon Blanc + Cabernet Sauvignon offering.  The view, clean cool air and the drive up to Atlas Peak are nothing to scoff at either, even though it was hard to stomach at times.  If you have the time, consider making a reservation for a tasting!  Though, be warned, the wines are available for purchase only via 6-packs (or 3-packs in the case of the Au Sommet), so make sure you go as a group to the tasting!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="atlas-peak" /><summary type="html">The last winery for one of our weekend trips to Napa and it was indeed a good one. Once you contact the winery to setup an appointment, you’ll have a couple of options for the tasting: the Amuse Bouche building in downtown Napa or the Au Sommet vineyard on Atlas Peak. We obviously chose Atlas Peak, but if you are pressed for time (it is a 20min drive from Napa) or are a nervous driver (it’s unpaved roads only 1.5 lanes wide going up a mountain), I recommend you stay in Napa. Once you do make it to the winery though, like so many others, the view is worth it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/au_sommet/1.jpg" /></entry></feed>