<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-06-14T17:49:37+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Wines By Jeremy</title><subtitle>Wines by Jeremy offers an educative and enjoyable personalized wine experience. Located in the DC metro area, Wines by Jeremy provides a number of services including in-home exclusive tastings, highly curated event tastings, educational events, and wine cellar consulting.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Hanzell Vineyards Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2020/02/08/hanzell_vineyards_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hanzell Vineyards Private Tasting" /><published>2020-02-08T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-08T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2020/02/08/hanzell_vineyards_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2020/02/08/hanzell_vineyards_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Hanzell Vineyards is the most comprehensive farming tour I have ever received from any vineyard.  And I am very grateful for that experience.  Every single detail about the vineyard and wines have layers upon layers of thought to them.  Almost as if a team were given a crazy engineering problem and they iterated with many different tools to get the balance of everything just right.  It’s one thing to discuss the philosophy of Organic farming.  It’s another to implement it meticulously and be able to explain all of your decisions.  If all you want is a wine tasting, you certainly get that too, but if you come with a thirst for knowledge, you will significantly enjoy all that Hanzell has to offer.  High class wine that comes with an even better experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Above the Fog Line&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/hanzell/1-800-19f0b6.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/hanzell/1-350-19f0b6.jpg 350w, /assets/images/hanzell/1-450-19f0b6.jpg 450w, /assets/images/hanzell/1-700-19f0b6.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;One of the reasons California is uniquely suited to grow high quality grapes is the high diurnal temperature swings between day and night.  At night, fog drifts inland from off the ocean and cools temperatures, while the sun burns off the moisture and heats up quite a bit in the afternoon.  It’s one thing to read about this phenomenon in a book.  It’s another to see the fog first hand from Sonoma’s highest elevation vineyard.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Door to Paradise&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/hanzell/2-800-80167f.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/hanzell/2-350-80167f.jpg 350w, /assets/images/hanzell/2-450-80167f.jpg 450w, /assets/images/hanzell/2-700-80167f.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;No winery is complete without an underground wine cave for storing and aging their wines.  It’s great for tax reasons and its natural coolest and humid environment.  I did get a quick tour (picture is seen later below), but wanted to mention how much I love how rustic it looks.  Rather than being huge and obviously blasted into the side of mountain, the wine cave looks handcrafted with care.  Given how old the winery is, I’m not surprised.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hanzell was first started in the 1950s and the original designs have remained in place to balance both the land and the desired agriculture.  In fact, if you walk over to the business offices onsite, you can see the plans for the estate framed on the walls.  It’s tough to argue that you should spend anytime indoors though because the view is absolutely stunning.  I 100% endorse making Hanzell the first wine tasting of your day in Sonoma so that you can see the fogline first hand as illustrated by my picture above.  When they talk in wine classes about the fog helping to preserve the acidity in grapes with its cool temperatures, you’ll be able to attest to this in person.  And yeah, it is a bit chilly up there so bring a jacket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Pigs&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/hanzell/3-800-da30d1.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/hanzell/3-350-da30d1.jpg 350w, /assets/images/hanzell/3-450-da30d1.jpg 450w, /assets/images/hanzell/3-700-da30d1.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Many wineries talk a big game with their organic/biodynamic practices, but this is the first wine tour I’ve had which really drove home the culture.  In fact, Hanzell isn’t technically compliant with Biodynamic practices because they actually micromanage the vineyards more strictly than what the guidelines prescribe.  When discussing the pigs, one neat thing I learned is that before they are introduced to the vineyard for feeding and fertilizing, they are fed organic material from the area to ensure that their body chemistry is already adjusted, so nitrogen and other organic material left behind match the other pigs (ie. The are calibrated for the land).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Sheep&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/hanzell/4-800-e76f0f.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/hanzell/4-350-e76f0f.jpg 350w, /assets/images/hanzell/4-450-e76f0f.jpg 450w, /assets/images/hanzell/4-700-e76f0f.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Further down the way, we saw the dogs and sheep they keep as well.  Because the pigs and sheep produce different organic material when feeding, they take measurements of the soil all around the vineyard, which drives their decision making of what sets of animals roam which plots and when.  It was a really fascinating tour covering details I never really considered in that level of detail.  When people say you grow wine, this is what I imagine they meant…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in the introduction, Hanzell places a lot of effort and emphasis on its farming methodology and techniques.  But I would say it’s unfair to label them with Organic or Biodynamic because Hanzell aims to do what they think is correct, not just adhere to some regulations for a certification.  In fact, I think they are stricter with themselves than what the certifications specify…  They have multiple animals onsite that together produce the right balance of acidity, nitrogen and other products in the vineyard (they fence off 6 rows at a time and let them wander together).  They plant root vegetables for the nitrogen and because the pigs will dig them up, turning over the land to oxygenate it as well.  And all of the food the animals are fed with are grown onsite to keep the microbiology of their gut consistent with what is in the vineyard.  Everything is ridiculously detailed and their reputation is fantastic within the wine community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Winemaking Barn&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/hanzell/5-800-f12861.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/hanzell/5-350-f12861.jpg 350w, /assets/images/hanzell/5-450-f12861.jpg 450w, /assets/images/hanzell/5-700-f12861.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;We walked through the barn where their winemaking equipment is setup.  We saw much less oak than I would have imagined.  It’s interesting that they use both steel and concrete - for white wines, the steel keeps the acidity crisp and enables precise temperature control while the concrete accentuates the minerality while rounding out the feel of the wine.  Their wines do have that “bit of everthing” feel to them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;That Barrel Light Above...&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/hanzell/6-800-6f457a.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/hanzell/6-350-6f457a.jpg 350w, /assets/images/hanzell/6-450-6f457a.jpg 450w, /assets/images/hanzell/6-700-6f457a.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Obligatory picture inside the wine cave, but I do want to point out the wine barrel that they turned into a chandelier above.  I really like the background effect it has on pictures and its an interesting way to reuse barrels when they are done fermenting wines.  Just a note to future me in case I ever get to design a wine cave someday…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have Advanced Sommeliers that beg to work here because of the attention to detail and the amount you learn about wine farming from the best experts in the land.  I would love to take people on a tour and tasting at Hanzell.  In fact, I added it to an itinerary I am planning for a group in the near future because they’ve expressed the desire to go a bit deeper into the winemaking and philosophy, not just drink amazing wines.  The quality of the land and people are top-notch and it’s a no-brainer why their wines are very good as well.  I hope that you get the opportunity to discuss all of their practices and taste that effort in your glass.  It means that much more knowing the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Wines&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/hanzell/7-800-4925c7.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/hanzell/7-350-4925c7.jpg 350w, /assets/images/hanzell/7-450-4925c7.jpg 450w, /assets/images/hanzell/7-700-4925c7.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;In addition to the introductory Chardonnay they pour you while giving you a tour of the estate, these are the four wines that come with the tasting.  I know that they no longer produce the Cabernet Sauvignon, or if they do, it is in very small quanitities - so I consider that a bonus to the experience.  It is definitely unique, but still in the style of Moon Mountain, if you’ve had some Cabernets from there before.  First tasting of the morning so I was by myself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Cats Always be Judging You...&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/hanzell/8-800-e3999f.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/hanzell/8-350-e3999f.jpg 350w, /assets/images/hanzell/8-450-e3999f.jpg 450w, /assets/images/hanzell/8-700-e3999f.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;And you thought I wasn’t going to mention the conspicuous feline in the previous picture.  Hanzell has a cat that roams the winery and is very cute / attention seeking.  As I was the only person tasting at the time, he honed on me pretty quickly.  It was difficult to say the least trying to taste the wine and write about it with a cat in my lap.  And the mental stress of him reading my tasting notes was not helping…  Luckily, I have great mental fortitude and found a way to persevere!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see in my last picture above, when I got around to tasting the wines, I was disadvantaged to say the least.  Staring out into the Sonoma Valley while tasting excellent terroir-driven wines and having my lap was warmed by a very friendly cat.  I arrived a half-hour early and left a half hour late…  But it was totally worth it and I hope you would agree (if you don’t have cat allergies).  Below is a sneak peek of what you have to look forward to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.hanzell.com/2018-hanzell-winemakers-selection-sebella-chardonnay-p468.aspx&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Hanzell Farm Chardonnay, Vintners Selection Sebolla Vineyard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($36)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;From grapes harvested in the front-site of their vineyard.  Ripe green and yellow fruit of medium intensity with acidity that tingles your cheeks, even before you taste the wine.  The acidity feels medium(+) on the palate and spices up the flavors profile.  The lemon and lime feel soft but linger on the finish.  Very well balanced, integrated, fresh, but not underripe in its flavors.  Given the minerality present too, I’d say this is Hanzell’s greatest QPR wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.hanzell.com/chardonnay-c28.aspx&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Hanzell Farm Chardonnay, Ramos Selection&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($68)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bright, fresh, ripe green apple, yellow apple, pear, and apricot open on the nose, but does feel a bit candied compared to the other chardonnays in the lineup.  Medium(+) intensity with the alcohol peeking out a bit as the flavors thin out on the finish.  Very bright, acidic (the minerality contributes to this) palate that makes you think of Sonoma Coast and the saltiness of those wines, but with more ripe lemon and alcohol.  A very good chardonnay, but feels a little imbalanced compared to the Sebolla and Flagship.  With age, I hope this wine evolves towards Chablis in style.  If you don’t want to wait, this could pair with some stronger flavored meals – an interesting option to consider.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.hanzell.com/2017-hanzell-vineyards-chardonnay-p451.aspx&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Hanzell Vineyards Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($78)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Their flagship Chardonnay.  It takes three years and 2 aging cycles (one in tank, one for 6 months in neutral oak) to produce this wine.  The difference between this and the Ramos is staggering.  The acidity feels high, but only tickles your cheeks with its nose.  The aromas are more yellow apple and stonefruit rather than lemon with cream and brioche thanks to lees aging (no MLF).  On the palate, this wine is just harmony.  The calm yellow fruit hits you first, then the weight of the cream/brioche, and then ends with the crisp lemon, acid and minerality that has your mouth watering for more.  Although both the Ramos and this have high acid and are bright, the acid in this wine is not seering in nature.  Balance, balance, balance.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.hanzell.com/2017-hanzell-vineyards-pinot-noir-p476.aspx&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Hanzell Vineyards Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($98)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Their flagship Pinott displays aromas of riper cranberry, strawberry, some cherry and that medicinal candied red plum that is typical of Pinot Noirs.  On the palate, the fruit hits at medium intensity, the acid is medium(+) and keeps the wine bright without interfering, and the medium(+) alcohol gives it weight, texture and a little heat on the finish in a good way.  The medium tannins are soft but definitely present and the red fruit flavors are a bit more brooding and spicy than the nose.  There is even some savory notes on the palate that pave the path from the fruit to the finish.  Like Burgundians, they use whole cluster fermentation without perceptible unripe flavors because the stalks ripen to a sweeter level in the vineyard.  If you are a fan of Burgundian Pinot, you owe it to yourself to try this wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.hanzell.com/cabernet-sauvignon-c50.aspx&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Hanzell Vineyards Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($125)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is so pretty.  Bright red and black fruit that integrate very well and give off the perception of mountain fruit.  There is a depth to the candied black fruit on the nose that pulls you in and begs for a taste.  The palate turns all of those preconceived notions on their head a bit.  The high acidity turns everything up a notch and surpasses the medium(+) powdered, chewy tannins on the palate.  The flavors orient to blended fresh and cooked red fruit with baking spices, but the story here is the palate structure.  Give this wine 5 years to integrate and you’ll have a great wine for those that prefer lighter Cabernets to the very ripe and long aging types.  This wine is made from only four rows of Cabernet vines in the vineyard as well as Petit Verdot and Cabernet Franc grown on the grounds.  As the 4 rows of Cabernet form 75% of the blend, the math tells you that there aren’t many bottles made each year.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Hanzell Vineyards Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt; ($100)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I had the chance to sample the flagship Chardonnay after 7 years of aging to observe its development.  The nose is medium(-) intensity of mellow yellow fruit, brioche, and straw, inviting you to dig your nose in deeper.  The palate’s structure is medium(+) acid with a soft but larger body and a finish that keeps going for 20 seconds.  Soft yellow apple, pear, apricot, and a little peach with cream, straw, and a flinty, white spice minerality saturate your palate.  The texture, mouthfeel and flavors make you want to continously sip the wine until the bottle is empty.  This is one of those rare wines that can connect the wine drinkers that love smooth and delicious with the wine enthusiasts that like to analyze.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend a visit to Hanzell and again strongly suggest that you make this the first stop of your day in Sonoma.  You’ll be glad you took that day-long break from Napa and may even find that you prefer Sonoma Chardonnays over those from Napa!  Regardless of which way you lean, it’s hard to pass up good Pinot when you can find it.  And make sure to bring a notebook to document all of the knowledge your wine ambassador will drop on you, haha.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="sonoma" /><category term="moon-mountain" /><summary type="html">Hanzell Vineyards is the most comprehensive farming tour I have ever received from any vineyard. And I am very grateful for that experience. Every single detail about the vineyard and wines have layers upon layers of thought to them. Almost as if a team were given a crazy engineering problem and they iterated with many different tools to get the balance of everything just right. It’s one thing to discuss the philosophy of Organic farming. It’s another to implement it meticulously and be able to explain all of your decisions. If all you want is a wine tasting, you certainly get that too, but if you come with a thirst for knowledge, you will significantly enjoy all that Hanzell has to offer. High class wine that comes with an even better experience.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/hanzell/1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/hanzell/1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Cornerstone Cellars Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2020/02/01/cornerstone_cellars_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cornerstone Cellars Public Tasting" /><published>2020-02-01T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-01T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2020/02/01/cornerstone_cellars_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2020/02/01/cornerstone_cellars_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Walking around the different wine bars in 850 Bordeaux Way is like being Charlie in the Chocolate Factory; sampling all of the different types of wines and hearing their stories leading to wine overload (theoretically).  Cornerstone is another winery that has a couple of tasting venues (their other is in the town of Napa), but not a large estate to visit and tour.  If you are looking for decent Cabernets for under $100, Cornerstone will fit in your category, but I recommend going after their Rhone blends instead which deliver outsized value for their modest $30 price points.  That and you’ll also be able to take an Instagram photo like everyone else holding their empty Melchior-sized bottle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cornerstone got it’s start in the early 90s thanks to two Memphis Doctors and a winemaker.  While the winemaker would split off and start other brands such as Highlands, the two Docs continued to fund Cornerstone and hired another winemaker.  After a stint by Celia Welch (of Scarecrow fame) in the 2000s, Cornerstone’s trajectory has gone up and not looked back.  Today, Kari Auringer holds the reins to the winemaking operation.  Having made wine for Keever and Lindstrom as well as serving as Celia Welch’s assistant winemaker at Cornerstone for 7 years, Kari has picked up the mantle and continued to carry the brand forward.  It’s no wonder the prices for the wines exceed that of Caymus and other similar producers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend visiting 850 Bordeaux Way for a tasting.  While the tasting fee is non-refundable with bottle purchases (unlike Mi Sueno), the wine ambassadors are very generous and will give your additional pours and tastings of bottles not on the menu if you show interest and excitement.  I ooze a lot of both while tasting (as much as one can while furiously typing notes onto a laptop), so I was able to turn a 4-5 bottle tasting into 7 (with a couple revisits).  The tasting room is slightly smaller than Mi Sueno and Trinitas, but at times felt like it had more people coming through the door for tastings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing I appreciate about Cornerstone is that they procure most of their fruit from other producers.  Meaning that they make many different bottlings of wine from many different Napa AVAs and therefore have a good breadth of bottles to try and flavors to enjoy.  Being able to try Merlot and Cabernet Franc from a hallowed place like Oakville Station, and then turn around and taste Cabernet Sauvignons from different places on the valley floor is not something to take for granted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had to put a theme on the wines from Cornerstone, it’s the drinkability of the wines at a young age, the lighter tannin extraction, and how smooth/mellow the wines are, especially the single varietal reds.  You could easily imagine drinking multiple bottles in a single evening around a campfire or relaxing with friends on a patio.  Perhaps that is the attraction of this winery.  It also helps that the medical community is small and whenever Cornerstone needs to hit a quota, the owners just bring a group of doctors through for a tasting of everything and ship wines out by the truckload.  Like they say, doctors are good with people, but bad with money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My notes on the $40 traditional tasting below.  And all of the wines discussed can be found and purchased online at their website: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cornerstonecellars.com/Wines/Best-Sellers&quot;&gt;https://www.cornerstonecellars.com/Wines/Best-Sellers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Sauvignon Blanc Sonoma County&lt;/strong&gt; ($32)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Grown at 1700 feet elevation on the other side of Mt. Veeder in Sonoma county.  On the nose, you get ripe yellow and green fruit (e.g. apples/pears) and even a little stonefruit.  A tiny bit of gooseberry adds complexity.  On the palate, the ripeness reaches stonefruit levels and beyond with the high acidity characteristic of Sauvignon Blanc.  The ripe apples and pears paired with the mouthwatering acidity make you think you are biting into fresh fruit.  The ripeness almost approaches a level that makes the ending a little unpleasant.  For the fruit-driven wine lovers.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 GSM El Dorado&lt;/strong&gt; ($30)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Grown at 2500 feet elevation in the Sierra Foothills.  Yeah, this nose…  Ripe red fruit, cheese rind, pepper, and some garrigue that is just starting to show.  The finish is fairly short, but while the wine is on your palate, you get notes of just ripened red fruit, black pepper, and a smooth body that has medium(+) acid and medium tannins.  An enjoyable form of Grenache, Syrah, and Mouvedre that does not require any aging.  Finishes dry and mouthwatering, making you want more and suggesting it could pair well with meat dishes.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Pinot Noir, Santa Rita Hills&lt;/strong&gt; ($60)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wow, this wine really does have the nose of a Santa Rita Hills Pinot.  It’s medium intensity with mostly sweet spice, tobacco and wood instead of red fruit.  Same on the palate with the red fruit playing a supporting role at best.  Still, smooth, integrated, and soft on the palate as Pinot Noir traditionally is.  I think this style of Pinot will have its lovers and detractors, but for now, count me in the former category.  This wine will improve with a little age.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Merlot Oakville Station&lt;/strong&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I remember the term “mellow merlot” from my early wine studies - medium everything.  Exploring this wine brings me back to that time.  A pretty, red fruited, medium intensity nose with some sweet spices.  On the palate, that mellow, middle-of-the-road structure and intensity is perfectly fine with me.  Strawberry, cranberry, some cherry, sweet spice, and bright acidity just glide along the tongue but has a surprisingly long finish.  This bottle is classic easy-drinking while letting you know of its quality on the finish.  This is a long weekend, hammock wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Cabernet Sauvignon, Kairos Vineyard&lt;/strong&gt; ($95)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This Cabernet is the spiritual successor to the Merlot above in how it’s mellow, smooth, and delicious.  On the nose and palate, you observe predominantly ripe red fruit, sweet spice, high (but very smooth) tannins, and high acid that dances on the cheeks.  It’s surprising how ready to drink this wine is, given that it’s from the Oak Knoll AVA.  This is the type of wine you could easily drink by yourself because it’s not too strong/overpowering.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Cabernet Sauvignon, Benchlands&lt;/strong&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Is this as smooth as the Kairos?  Yes.  Is the complexity at a whole different level?  Oh heck yes.  A blend of multiple varietals from multiple sites in Napa.  Not quite the puzzle that Sixteen Appellations is from Italics, but I think it’s better integrated and drinking much better at this point.  The acidity is high and vibrant and the flavors span the red spectrum and already display tertiary notes.  If I had to pick a wine to drink today among the reds, this would be it.  I see why it has received the critical acclaim that it has.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Cabernet Franc, Oakville Station&lt;/strong&gt; ($85)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;75% Cab Franc, 15% Merlot, 10% Cabernet Sauvignon - all from the Oakville Station.  The red fruit perfume on the nose comes at you in high intensity.  The acidity and tannin are vibrant and structured, making this enjoyable right now.  The wine almost forces you to continue taking sips of it…  The palate is a little disjointed (mostly the structure is), but you can tell how good this is going to be.  It’s not quite at the same QPR level as the Paradigm Cabernet Franc, but it’s pretty close.  I understand why Cornerstone sells out of this wine so quickly every year.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a long day and a great tasting to end it on.  Unfortunately, I forgot to take pictures of the wine bar at the time.  If you make a visit and don’t mind me posting one of your photos for this blog entry, please let me know!  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><summary type="html">Walking around the different wine bars in 850 Bordeaux Way is like being Charlie in the Chocolate Factory; sampling all of the different types of wines and hearing their stories leading to wine overload (theoretically). Cornerstone is another winery that has a couple of tasting venues (their other is in the town of Napa), but not a large estate to visit and tour. If you are looking for decent Cabernets for under $100, Cornerstone will fit in your category, but I recommend going after their Rhone blends instead which deliver outsized value for their modest $30 price points. That and you’ll also be able to take an Instagram photo like everyone else holding their empty Melchior-sized bottle.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mi Sueno Winery Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2020/01/25/mi_sueno_winery_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mi Sueno Winery Public Tasting" /><published>2020-01-25T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-25T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2020/01/25/mi_sueno_winery_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2020/01/25/mi_sueno_winery_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;If you asked me to name one person in Napa who has a truly inspiring story of achieving his or her dreams, Rolando Herrera is one of the first names that comes to mind.  From immigrating to California from Mexico at age 15, to washing dishes at night while in High School, to starting at the bottom as a harvest laborer at Stag’s Leap Wine Cellars, to eventually making it to Cellarmaster, to winemaking at Vine Cliff and eventually becoming Director of Winemaking at Paul Hobbs Consulting (Paul Hobbs is a very famous name in the wine world), Rolando has always made the best of his situation and continued to grow.  It is only natural that he started his own label (Mi Sueno means “My Dream” in Spanish) with his wife Lorena and continues to tackle new challenges.  The wine quality is excellent and well worth the visit.  It’s so good that you’ll forget about the fact that you aren’t at some grand estate.  Heck, I didn’t even remember to take a picture!  But I did remember to buy some wine…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Village&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/mi-sueno/1-800-e74a68.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/mi-sueno/1-350-e74a68.jpg 350w, /assets/images/mi-sueno/1-450-e74a68.jpg 450w, /assets/images/mi-sueno/1-700-e74a68.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I really like what the Vista Collina Resort, Meritage Resort, and the wineries have done here.  875 Bordeaux Way is like a mini wine-mall that makes several good wineries easy to access (literally a walk away from each other).  If you are looking for a way to taste many different wines in a short period of time, you can try wine bars in the town of Napa or come here.  Even though this place seems huge, it’s usually not that crowded.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d heard of Rolando Herrera in the background at wineries I’ve visited (e.g. he consults for Baldacci Vineyards), but it wasn’t until I had a bottle of his Mi Sueno Cabernet that I decided I needed to pay this man’s winery a visit.  After all, every famous winemaker I know who started their own winery has always put out good product (e.g. La Sirena, Favia, Rivers-Marie, Arcudi, etc.).  Luckily for me, I didn’t have to drive all the way into Napa to enjoy his wines.  The winemaking facility and his tasting room at 875 Bordeaux Way are only a mile from each other and both offer tastings.  Since I was in the mood to walk and try other wines this evening, I decided on the 875 location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Directory&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/mi-sueno/2-800-7f6bdf.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/mi-sueno/2-350-7f6bdf.jpg 350w, /assets/images/mi-sueno/2-450-7f6bdf.jpg 450w, /assets/images/mi-sueno/2-700-7f6bdf.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I thought the directory would have the listing of wineries that setup tasting rooms here (e.g. Cornerstone, Trinitas, Mi Sueno, Jayson, etc.), but it doesn’t.  It does have an entry for “Our Lady of Grapes Chapel” though, which was way too hilarious for me to ignore.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pulling up to the place, it strikes you as an outside mini-mall for wine drinkers.  There is a rectangular astroturf yard in the center where you can pull up a table to enjoy your purchased bottles and it even has Cornhole set up.  The architecture is well done but relaxed and the atmosphere is neither sluggish or too energetic.  An oasis to enjoy wines away from the crowds and the traffic of Napa.  The number of choices may seem intimidating, but Mi Sueno should be your first visit while your palate is fresh - no question.  Just walk right in, grab a table, and pick the tasting you are interested in.  Mi Sueno is the larger production brand while Herrera are his elevated bottlings.  Regardless of which tasting you pick, it is free with a two-bottle purchase, which isn’t hard because both tasting menus are really good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to treat myself with the Herrera tasting and it was totally worth it.  Those bottles can be purchased onsite or you can sign up on their website to purchase them as well: &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.misuenowinery.com/Wines/Herrera&quot;&gt;https://store.misuenowinery.com/Wines/Herrera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Herrera Perla Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt; ($70)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Lemon-green in appearance, high acid, mellow yellow fruit, straw, and brioche on the nose.  The acidity is high, the body is medium(+) with good weight, and the palate is complex with notes of lemon, orange zest, white flowers, some butter (makes me think partial MLF) and vanilla.  It’s funny how the ripeness doesn’t hit the stonefruit and tropical fruit levels of its peers though it has similar ABV and intensity.  I really liked this Chardonnay and walked away with a bottle to blind taste friends on $75-range Chardonnays.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Herrera Seleccion Victoria Malbec&lt;/strong&gt; ($95)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This smells like a top-class Argentinian Malbec.  The nose is so pretty in both its aromatics and its flavors.  Everything is floral, candied, red fruit, high acid, and really smooth.  If you don’t like candied character in your wine, this is likely not the wine for you, but if you do and don’t want the sugar hangover, you are really going to love this wine.  I just cannot stop gushing over how pretty this wine is.  If it didn’t stain your neck with its inky color, you could use it as perfume…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Herrera Valeria Petit Verdot 2015&lt;/strong&gt; ($95)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;To me, the Italics Petit Verdot has set the bar for this varietal in Napa.  But this wine is on par with that bottling.  I’d love a blind tasting with both to choose my favorite.  The fruit and body are powerful, the earthiness of the varietal is clear, and everything integrates so smoothly, with high volume tannins that are very smooth at this young age.  This wine will age beautifully, but is also drinking near a peak right now.  I got a bottle because it’s a rarer varietal wine in the area and has been executed so well by Rolando.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Herrera Seleccion Rebecca Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt; ($140)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This is a great, structured, but easy drinking Cabernet Sauvignon that has flavors between black fruit, red fruit, cinnamon, cocoa, and leather.  All of that is integrated very smoothly and drinks really well right now.  Among the best balanced Cabernets I’ve had in terms of its flavor profile and its finish, which just seems to go on…  I do still think that this could use some more time to integrate, but once it does, watch out.  This bottle is going to surprise some people in the premium wine category.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Herrera Seleccion Lorena Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt; ($155)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A blend of sites that the winemaker won’t reveal.  A little closed on the nose and palate right now; it will need some years in the bottle to unwind.  The acid/tannin profile is complex as you can tell there are components with different feels to them.  It has a lot of potential, but I can’t really see where it’s going at this point, unlike the Rebecca.  I’d want to revisit this wine in a few years, but I know it’ll be impossible to find this bottle at that point.  The tannins are a bit more present too and need time to mellow.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading through my notes and remembering the experience, Mi Sueno was very impressive to me.  I would love to revisit, only this time at their winemaking facility so I can get a tour, ask more questions, and gain more insight as to what drove Rolando’s winemaking style.  Until then, I will just have to enjoy the wines I purchased and live vicariously through you if you decide to visit them as well.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><summary type="html">If you asked me to name one person in Napa who has a truly inspiring story of achieving his or her dreams, Rolando Herrera is one of the first names that comes to mind. From immigrating to California from Mexico at age 15, to washing dishes at night while in High School, to starting at the bottom as a harvest laborer at Stag’s Leap Wine Cellars, to eventually making it to Cellarmaster, to winemaking at Vine Cliff and eventually becoming Director of Winemaking at Paul Hobbs Consulting (Paul Hobbs is a very famous name in the wine world), Rolando has always made the best of his situation and continued to grow. It is only natural that he started his own label (Mi Sueno means “My Dream” in Spanish) with his wife Lorena and continues to tackle new challenges. The wine quality is excellent and well worth the visit. It’s so good that you’ll forget about the fact that you aren’t at some grand estate. Heck, I didn’t even remember to take a picture! But I did remember to buy some wine…</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/mi-sueno/1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/mi-sueno/1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Rocca Family Vineyards Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2020/01/18/rocca_vineyards_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rocca Family Vineyards Private Tasting" /><published>2020-01-18T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-18T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2020/01/18/rocca_vineyards_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2020/01/18/rocca_vineyards_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Everyone has those days when they prefer to interact with as little people as possible and aren’t in the mood for taking Instagram-worthy photos.  On those days, they want to settle at home and drink good wine that doesn’t ask too much from them in terms of analyzing and appreciating complexity.  But for those that don’t have good wine lying around at home, you can just make an hour drive to Rocca Family Vineyards and settle down there instead.  The Hospitality Manager will serve you good, enjoyable wine and you may even pick up a few high QPR bottles to bring home with you like me (HINT: Get the Syrah).  Just relax and enjoy your day off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Tasting House&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/rocca/1-800-77439e.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/rocca/1-350-77439e.jpg 350w, /assets/images/rocca/1-450-77439e.jpg 450w, /assets/images/rocca/1-700-77439e.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A picture of the Rocca Wine Tasting House.  It is located at the southernmost tip of the Napa Valley, so if you are flying into SFO from the east coast that same morning (like me), it’s nice to save yourself a 30min drive into the heart of Napa and instead enjoy some of the smaller family wineries to the south (only an hour drive from the airport on a Saturday afternoon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Backyard&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/rocca/2-800-291073.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/rocca/2-350-291073.jpg 350w, /assets/images/rocca/2-450-291073.jpg 450w, /assets/images/rocca/2-700-291073.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;As I mentioned earlier, this is a house and not a tasting estate.  You won’t see any tremendous views or take and fantastic pictures here.  It’s also close to the highway, so you may hear cars while standing outside too.  Save your camera for other places and just relax with some wine here.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rocca Family Vineyards is another visit I have to credit Vivino for.  Every now and again, I like to try peruse Vivino and purchase some bottles I don’t recognize that are on-sale because (1) it keeps me trying new wines; (2) the deals are sales deals are normally good; and (3) the free shipping.  I remember trying the Tesorina at some point through one of these sales and put Rocca Family Vineyards on my map of places to visit, especially when I don’t want to drive all the way into the heart of Napa.  And on this Saturday afternoon when I had taken a 5+ hour flight from DC and driven an hour from SFO, I did not want to drive another 30min-1hr.  Luckily I had planned ahead and made a reservation as Rocca does not accept walk-in tastings due to its smaller size and staffing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Private Tasting Room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/rocca/3-800-b38fc2.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/rocca/3-350-b38fc2.jpg 350w, /assets/images/rocca/3-450-b38fc2.jpg 450w, /assets/images/rocca/3-700-b38fc2.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;If you come with a larger tasting group, this is the setup that you can expect for your tasting.  It really feels like you are tasting in someone’s house.  I much prefer the couches as seen from my pictures below, but just know what you are walking into if you come with a group.  When the weather is nicer, they can also set you up outside where there is more space to spread out.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hospitality Manager (Christy McDonald) was great throughout the experience.  I was the only person tasting at the time (until my friends arrived), but I have a feeling she would have answered my questions the same even if it was busier.  And it was fun deep diving into a family-run winery like Rocca.  It turns out they have vineyards in Yountville and Coombsville (I’m becoming more and more a fan of the Coombsville AVA).  It turns out that they sell about half their grapes while only producing 2000 cases (I understand that sales and distribution must be hard for a smaller winery like them).  And even though they started making wines in 1999, the Roccas continue to work today in their original professional field (Medical practitioners).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Tasting Couches&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/rocca/4-800-0116e3.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/rocca/4-350-0116e3.jpg 350w, /assets/images/rocca/4-450-0116e3.jpg 450w, /assets/images/rocca/4-700-0116e3.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Now this is my tasting scene.  Laid back, but still classy with plenty of sunshine and a view outside if you want it.  After being stuck in a middle seat for 5+ hours, it was nice to stretch the legs and sink back into the couch with some wine.  Getting a good dose of sun was nice as well.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the wines themselves, the only wine they produce with imported grapes is their Sonoma Coast Chardonnay (they really wanted to make a white wine).  And although they mostly produce Cabernet for reds, because of the varietal distribution in their vineyards, they are able to produce a Merlot and Syrah in certain years (I was able to taste the Syrah by chance).  Their winemaker is Paul Colintony who has been with them since 2008 and is a former biochemist that studied under Mondavi.  Both the owners and him have pushed to make the winery certified organic with natural yeast used for fermentation and no fining/filtering at the end to preserve complexity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;More the Merrier&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/rocca/5-800-b159c5.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/rocca/5-350-b159c5.jpg 350w, /assets/images/rocca/5-450-b159c5.jpg 450w, /assets/images/rocca/5-700-b159c5.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Luckily, I had some friends that had already spent their morning in Napa and came back south to meet up for this tasting.  Ryan is an even better storyteller than I am so I love this photo of him pontificating about wine.  Though, you are probably wondering the same thing as me - why are our wine glasses empty?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tasting lineup was very good for the $35 fee as seen below.  To view/purchase the wines, see this link: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.roccawines.com/Wines&quot;&gt;https://www.roccawines.com/Wines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Chardonnay Sonoma Coast&lt;/strong&gt; ($65)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Although they grow no Chardonnay, the owners wanted a light, crisp, acidic chardonnay in their lineup, hence the decision to purchase Sonoma Coast fruit and use neutral oak.  On the nose, there is a little brioche and cream to go along with the yellow fruit.  On the palate, the acidity is strong and tart, making the fruit seem a little less ripe then you expect from the nose.  There is definitely a salty note and cheese rind that reminds me of the Sonoma Coast AVA.  This is not for the ripe yellow fruit or butter lovers but for those that want a crisp wine that is good for a hot day.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Syrah&lt;/strong&gt; ($48)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Made from Syrah in Yountville that is next to Stag’s Leap, near Cliff Lede.  You know what else is near there?  Kapcsandy…  The aromas are very pretty and mellow at the same time.  They only have 1 acre of Syrah planted, hence why it’s not made often as its own varietal (no 2015 vintage).  High acid on the nose that pairs with the strawberry, ripe cranberry, and saline notes.  The palate is full of baking spice that makes the intensity of the red fruit seem softer.  The alcohol is a little hot, but when combined with the spice of the palate, I’m thinking it would make a great pairing for Italian food.  The tannins are noticeable on the finish, but fairly soft on the palate.  I wouldn’t say the wine has Syrah meatiness, but there are some tertiary touches in the flavors.  Definitely not a fruit driven Syrah.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Vespera&lt;/strong&gt; ($50)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;In Latin, it means “Evening”.  The owners wanted a red wine that was easy to drink, food friendly, and a good “evening porch wine”.  It’s a blend of Syrah (5%), Merlot (40%), and Cabernet Sauvignon (55%) every year, but the percentages vary each vintage.  This is their most distributed wine that also appears in restaurants because blends are becoming popular, the price point is good, and the blend is quite unique (the Syrah is unusual).  The alcohol warmth and bite are a bit strong as well as the spiceness.  On the palate, everything blends together to give an impression of warmth, cranberry, lighter cherry, and spice.  There’s quite a bit of green on the palate too from unbalanced ripening.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Grigsby Cabernet (Yountville)&lt;/strong&gt; ($85)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fruit from the valley floor on the border of Stag’s Leap.  The nose is really delightful as it’s very well balanced between the fruit, spice and earth.  The earth, sweet spice, and wood (from neutral oak) own the finish as the fruit receeds.  My friends really enjoyed this bottle because of the balance and the softer tannin structure and drinkability (but also its ability to age).  If you want a blend of old world and new world styles, this is it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Collinetta Cabernet (Coombsville)&lt;/strong&gt; ($95)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;After the Syrah, this was probably my second favorite wine.  The hang time is 2-5 weeks longer than the other wines, giving it more time for phenolic ripeness in the cool Coombsville area.  The nose is very bright with its soft, candied, red fruit, and the palate is primarily soft red fruit with some intensity lost to the aged wood.  This doesn’t have the complexity of the Grigsby, but it’s also a little more drinkable for those that prefer new world to old world.  It still finishes more tertiary with the wood than the fruit, but that’s just the finish.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Tesorina&lt;/strong&gt; ($160)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Their top bottling.  Bright and more ripe red fruit than the other wines.  The palate has complexity if you dig into it, but it requires patience and intentionality to look for it.  The fact it is very easy and smooth on the palate makes that patience harder to come by.  It requires no effort to enjoy and goes down unintentionally fast.  I’m not sure that it justifies its prices point compared to the other wines in the lineup that offered plenty of complexity, but I would definitely not argue against this wine, because if someone opened the bottle, I’d be the first to put my glass out for a pour.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again if you are looking for a nice little getaway from the hustle and bustle of Napa and just want to enjoy some good wine a little closer to SF, give Rocca Family Vineyards a try.  Just be sure to expect a little more European influence to the wines and a little less ripe fruit that what you would find more central to the valley.  Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><summary type="html">Everyone has those days when they prefer to interact with as little people as possible and aren’t in the mood for taking Instagram-worthy photos. On those days, they want to settle at home and drink good wine that doesn’t ask too much from them in terms of analyzing and appreciating complexity. But for those that don’t have good wine lying around at home, you can just make an hour drive to Rocca Family Vineyards and settle down there instead. The Hospitality Manager will serve you good, enjoyable wine and you may even pick up a few high QPR bottles to bring home with you like me (HINT: Get the Syrah). Just relax and enjoy your day off.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/rocca/1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/rocca/1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Kenzo Estate Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2020/01/11/kenzo_estate_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kenzo Estate Private Tasting" /><published>2020-01-11T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-11T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2020/01/11/kenzo_estate_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2020/01/11/kenzo_estate_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Imagine you own 3,800 acres of pristine land in wine country and had the resources to hire world-class experts in every aspect of the winemaking process.  Now open your eyes.  You aren’t standing in front of Screaming Eagle, Harlan, or any other big name in the cult world today.  You are standing in front of Kenzo Estates.  Established by Kenzo Tsujimoto in the mid-1990s, this estate is the equivalent of the Royal Palace of Oz in from a fantasy wine novel…  You know I love it since I am posting nine pictures of our tour and tasting there!  It is quite a drive outside the town of Napa (both to its gates and then from its gates to the winery itself), but well worth it.  If the pictures aren’t enough to entice you, how about these names: Heidi Barrett, David Abreu, and Thomas Keller (assuming you get the food pair option).  The style of wine is very different from its Napa brethren (much more elegant with herbal notes) but carries similar price tags to the best.  But as 80% of the wine is exported and consumed in Japan, don’t expect much availability in the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Winery Entrance&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/1-800-eb97f0.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/1-350-eb97f0.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kenzo/1-450-eb97f0.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kenzo/1-700-eb97f0.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The first thing I noticed driving into the parking lot is that it isn’t paved.  Instead, they utilize cobblestones for their entrance.  A winery that puts that much thought into the design (without regard for cost) is putting its best foot forward and immediately impresses those that have been to many wineries before&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Rock Wall&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/2-800-fa264d.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/2-350-fa264d.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kenzo/2-450-fa264d.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kenzo/2-700-fa264d.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;They even use a beautifully constructed rock wall to form the terrace separating the vines from the parking lot.  Just great design decisions all around the vineyard about the little things.  It may not seem like a big deal, but the impacts of all the little things add up to a big impact…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are reading this and lived through the 1990s-2000s, you’ll know the Japanese game publisher and developer CAPCOM.  Kenzo just so happens to be the founder (most new winery owners made their money outside the wine world).  In 1990, CAPCOM purchased the property that would become Kenzo Estate with the intentions of developing a resort.  Imagine if that had happened…  During his time at CAPCOM, Kenzo developed a burgeoning interest in the Napa Valley after the Judgement of Paris in 1976.  This no doubt led to the purchase of this land and hope to share Napa with visitors of the resort.  Unfortunately, the resort didn’t pan out, so Kenzo personally acquired the property in the mid-1990s and moved on with another plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Their Lineup&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/3-800-8d8895.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/3-350-8d8895.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kenzo/3-450-8d8895.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kenzo/3-700-8d8895.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I’ve seen a similar bar layout for other wineries (note: there is a correlation) and I have to say I am a fan.  I like how the portfolio is laid out so you can recognize later what you didn’t taste (and can ask about it if you are interested).  While we got our pour of Sauvignon Blanc here, we didn’t stay for long.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Our Tasting Table&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/4-800-2879ce.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/4-350-2879ce.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kenzo/4-450-2879ce.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kenzo/4-700-2879ce.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Yeah, I know what you are thinking…  Why doesn’t my patio look like this?  Although all of the tasting tables are outdoors, they make sure no one is baking in the sun while drinking their wines.  The smell in the are, the wind cooling you down and the view of the vineyards - it was great to have the tasting outside.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was only after some people approached him about wanting to plant vines there that he saw the potential for planting a vineyard and producing his own wine.  And it is easy to see why they did.  The land itself has natural flowing slopes, it’s nestled in the hills above 1,500 feet, and still gets the effects of morning fog that burns off during the day.  So what did Kenzo do?  He brought in the best viticulturalist in Napa (David Abreu, who also owns a winery and produces $600 wine), my favorite winemaker (Heidi Barrett of Screaming Eagle fame), and even the best restaurateur in Napa (Thomas Keller of French Laundry fame who also owns his restaurant group).  I don’t know how you beat that all-star lineup…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Vineyards&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/5-800-e1bd76.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/5-350-e1bd76.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kenzo/5-450-e1bd76.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kenzo/5-700-e1bd76.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The road through the vineyards.  You may notice that the rootstocks and vines look young.  That is because they are.  They will need some time to hit peak maturity, but another wine to think about it is that the wines will keep getting better each vintage in the meantime.  I’m excited.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Me with the Vines&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/6-800-ad8425.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/6-350-ad8425.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kenzo/6-450-ad8425.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kenzo/6-700-ad8425.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I definitely could have used some sunglasses out there.  But I was fine - the vineyards are my happy place.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Mapping it out&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/7-800-47d2a6.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/7-350-47d2a6.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kenzo/7-450-47d2a6.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kenzo/7-700-47d2a6.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Friends discussing the architecture of the property with our wine ambassador.  I love the forest backdrop to the vineyards.  It creates this nature screen for wildlife and also just makes for an incredible view.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kenzo started his enterprise in 2008 by selling his wines in Japan, which accounts for 80% of his current sales.  He exports most of the 5,000 cases Kenzo Estate produces to high-end Tokyo restaurants, wine-club members, and fancy hotel bars.  His master plan calls for an annual production of 16,000 cases and sales split 50-50 between the United States and Japan.  That aspirations are high, but so is his devotion, level of resources, and farmable land.  With the quality that Kenzo Estate is putting out, even with the younger age of their vines, I have no doubt that this goal is achieveable, so keep an eye out at you local high-end restaurants!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Up the Rows&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/8-800-4f2096.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/8-350-4f2096.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kenzo/8-450-4f2096.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kenzo/8-700-4f2096.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Looking up the rows of the vineyards.  Beautiful blue sky, forest in the backgroud, a hump to illustrate the terrain.  I really liked walking among the vines in this place.  I hope to visit again someday.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;To the wines!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/9-800-e708fd.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/9-350-e708fd.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kenzo/9-450-e708fd.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kenzo/9-700-e708fd.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The vines were literally next to our tasting table.  I hope this photograph illustrates how close the vines were to where we were sitting for our tasting.  It took a little time to kick off the dust from our shoes.  But once we did, we were ready to taste!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will let my pictures above do the talking about the tour and what visiting the estate was like.  For notes about the wines, see below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kenzoestate.com/wine-items/asatsuyu&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2018 Asatsuyu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A beautiful Sauvignon Blanc that spends 3 months in steel tank and 3 months in neutral oak.  Green and yellow fruit, but also some grass notes.  I like how this wine integrates the varietal character with the ripeness of the Napa Valley, rather than letting one dominate the other.  A terrific example of “sense of place” that pushed me to purchase a couple bottles to share with friends.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kenzoestate.com/wine-items/yui&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2018 Yui&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;32% Malbec with the rest Cabernet Franc and Cabernet Sauvignon.  Beautiful pink salmon color and wonderful texture and mouthfeel that has body, but doesn’t possess overly extracted flavors or aromas.  More grapefruit, peach, and strawberry flavors than other Roses I’ve had in the area.  This is both a smooth enjoyable wine and a serious Rose that is unlike any others in the region.  Really impressed by the flavor complexity, mouthfeel and great acidity.  One of my favorite roses that I’ve tasted, period.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kenzoestate.com/wine-items/rindo&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Rindo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($130)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Left bank Bordeaux Blend (46% Cabernet, 30%+ Merlot, with the rest Cabernet Franc) that is their flagship wine (highest volume produced).  Deep, rich, cooked red fruit with low pitched baking spices.  On the palate, this wine is softly textured and restrained in intensity.  This isn’t your big, heavy traditional left-bank wine as the palate is brighter than the nose (cranberry and strawberry dominate).  In its youth, this wine is soft enough to have alone, but presents enough intensity to pair with food.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kenzoestate.com/wine-items/murasaki&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Murasaki&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($290)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;83% Merlot-dominant blend.  Murasaki means purple in Japanese, in line with the color of the wine.  The nose has brighter red fruit than the Rindo with some black fruit as well, but the baking spice is more accentuated on the nose.  The palate has some electricity thanks to the acid and bright red fruit.  It’s still very soft in body, texture, tannin and it has a medium(+) finish with a little green fennel at the end adding to the complexity.  The finish grows on you as you have more of the wine, but this is both an engaging and relaxing wine at the same time.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kenzoestate.com/wine-items/ai&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Ai&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($280)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;90% Cabernet Sauvignon with 2% each of other Bordeaux varietals filling out the rest of the wine.  The nose on this wine is absolutely wild.  Earthier and spicier than the other reds, the nose on this wine is like minestrone soup - meat, tomato, green pepper, corn, etc.  On the palate, you still get those same notes, except a bit less in intensity with stewed red fruit integrated into the profile as well.  This has to be one of the more unique wines I have ever tasted.  I really hope to try this wine again to confirm that I and the bottle weren’t crazy that day…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kenzoestate.com/wine-items/muku&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2018 Muku&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($50 for 375ml)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This is a really great dessert wine.  95% Sauvignon Blanc and 5% Semillon, this wine has a fragrant nose of rich yellow fruit and stonefruit, and pronounced intensity (they even serve it in a flute draw the nose back).  On the palate, the acidity gradually builds, but doesn’t detract from the medium(+) body and the pronounced flavors that finish long.  The ripeness isn’t overdone like some dessert wines either – this is like drinking nectar from nature.  Very beautiful and pure…  I made sure to buy a few bottles to enjoy myself when Royal Tokaji would be too intense and Sauternes would be too muddled.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the prices of the bottles are intimidating, the price for the tasting is not.  If you can spare the time to do a 1000am tasting before driving back to Napa for lunch, I highly recommend you take the opportunity.  As the brand’s reputation grows, it will become more difficult to secure reservations as the facility isn’t structured to handle large numbers of guests.  And it’s not every day you get the opportunity to visit the Royal Palace of Oz in the real world, haha.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="wild-horse-valley" /><summary type="html">Imagine you own 3,800 acres of pristine land in wine country and had the resources to hire world-class experts in every aspect of the winemaking process. Now open your eyes. You aren’t standing in front of Screaming Eagle, Harlan, or any other big name in the cult world today. You are standing in front of Kenzo Estates. Established by Kenzo Tsujimoto in the mid-1990s, this estate is the equivalent of the Royal Palace of Oz in from a fantasy wine novel… You know I love it since I am posting nine pictures of our tour and tasting there! It is quite a drive outside the town of Napa (both to its gates and then from its gates to the winery itself), but well worth it. If the pictures aren’t enough to entice you, how about these names: Heidi Barrett, David Abreu, and Thomas Keller (assuming you get the food pair option). The style of wine is very different from its Napa brethren (much more elegant with herbal notes) but carries similar price tags to the best. But as 80% of the wine is exported and consumed in Japan, don’t expect much availability in the market.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/kenzo/3.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/kenzo/3.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bevan Cellars Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2020/01/04/bevan_cellars_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bevan Cellars Private Tasting" /><published>2020-01-04T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-04T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2020/01/04/bevan_cellars_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2020/01/04/bevan_cellars_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;You can read up on the background of Bevan Cellars and prior vintage tastings in in this article &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/09/07/bevan_cellars_private_tasting.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HERE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  The first thing you may notice about this article is that I dropped the rating, compared to my last tasting here.  The change is primarily due to the number and quality of the wines used for this tasting; they were not up to the standard that was set during my previous visit.  We were also given the remnants of bottles opened the previous day to taste, rather than being able to taste fresh bottles.  In a couple cases, the pour was smaller than other bottles because the amount available wasn’t enough.  Make no mistake, these are wines of the highest quality, just not served in their best condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Tasting Room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/bevan-cellars-2/1-800-225a08.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/bevan-cellars-2/1-350-225a08.jpg 350w, /assets/images/bevan-cellars-2/1-450-225a08.jpg 450w, /assets/images/bevan-cellars-2/1-700-225a08.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The tasting room used at Brasswood Winery.  I really need to taste their wines too at some point, since I’ve been to the winery twice now…  I like the tasting bar setup and how you can see outside, but the people on the outside cannot see inside, haha.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the wines had their flavors in well-rounded form thanks to being opened the day before, I think they also lost some of their intensity and precision because of that.  I think my tasting group noticed that as well, since they ranked Bevan Cellars their least impressive wines of the day.  In all fairness, we did have a rockstar lineup that day, but I can empathize with their viewpoint on the wines.  It’s really too bad, because we hit it off with the co-owner of the winery (Victoria De Crescenzo) and she invited us to her new winery in Healdsburg, which we accepted and will be visiting on another trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Posing with the Fountain&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/bevan-cellars-2/2-800-4a70aa.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/bevan-cellars-2/2-350-4a70aa.jpg 350w, /assets/images/bevan-cellars-2/2-450-4a70aa.jpg 450w, /assets/images/bevan-cellars-2/2-700-4a70aa.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Two awesome people (Nick and Jess) posing next to the water fountain outside in the center area of the Brasswood patio.  Our tasting was at 1000, which explains the lack of other people at the winery.  When we left our tasting shortly after 1100, the patio was bustling with people.  Luckily, we had already taken the photos we wanted and were on to the next winery!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got word that the previous wine ambassador I had befriended and tasted with (Dan Walsh) had left his position at Bevan Cellars and is now the Hospitality Director at Knights Bridge Winery.  This was the reason Victoria was conducting our tasting.  If you plan to visit Bevan Cellars in the near future, you may want to confirm your tasting lineup before visiting to ensure they break out at least 3 of their Cabernets.  But if you do get a good lineup, you are in for a great tasting…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Entrance to the Winery&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/bevan-cellars-2/3-800-484685.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/bevan-cellars-2/3-350-484685.jpg 350w, /assets/images/bevan-cellars-2/3-450-484685.jpg 450w, /assets/images/bevan-cellars-2/3-700-484685.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A shot of my glass of Chardonnay, with the bottle I was about to try next (the Petaluma Gap Pinot Noir).  I’ve spoken with plenty of people that like the opulence and mouthfeel of Cabernet Sauvignon, but could do without the high tannin.  Both of the Bevan Pinots are definitely for Cabernet-lovers like them.  If you like opulence and richness in your wine, Bevan is difficult to beat in this category.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, Bevan Cellars are for drinkers that really like rich, round texture and mouthfeel to their wines. Bevan does not rack their wines and blends all of the barrels together in a tank, then redistributes to each barrel, ensuring integration of flavors and texture early on.  They ferment the free run and the press juice separately, then top off the free run juice barrels with the press juice during the fermentation to replace the angel’s share.  Some years, they may choose not to use the press juice at all.  They press the juice off the tank while it is still fermenting (anywhere from 8-10 brix of sugar left) and then barrel it while it is finishing the fermentation - most people wait until the fermentation finishes the sugar.  They use a pulsar in tank too to pump gas from the bottom and break up the cap instead of pump over or punch downs (same as Quiceda Creek which is another fantastic winery).  This really softens the tannins and allows them to create high tannin wines that have great mouthfeels in their youth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the wines!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bevancellars.com/store/detail?item=2017-chardonnay-ritchie-vineyard-russian-river-valley&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Ritchie Vineyard Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($70)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;From a vineyard that is shaped like an inverted cone (the volcano collapsed on itself).  The grape sizes are different in each cluster (like hens and chicks) as they produce this Chardonnay by combining a younger block and an older block.  100% new French oak and it is fairly obvious on the nose as there are notes of ripe yellow fruit, butter, cream, and vanilla.  They produce the wine in a reductive style without much SO2, which is only possible in a very clean facility.  The bottle should peak at 3 years of age.  Rich, beautiful, but not as big as the Hudson Ranch.  I think this is super enjoyable right now and doesn’t need the age if you don’t want to wait!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bevancellars.com/store/detail?item=2017-pinot-noir-petaluma-gap&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Petaluma Gap Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The blue and red fruit on the nose is so rich, integrated, and deep.  On the palate, the depth is just remarkable with pretty red (cranberry, cherry) and black fruit, baking spice that integrates with the alcohol and medium(+) body.  The tannins are medium(+), maybe high due to the amount of extraction, but are very fine grained.  The concentration is striking, but the ripeness on the palate is toned back and is also covered a bit by the tannin.  A very approachable, very rich Pinot that is for Cabernet-lovers, not for those that like Burgundian Pinots.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bevancellars.com/store/detail?item=2016-red-wine-ontogeny-napa-valley&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Ontogeny&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($95)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Deep red/blue fruit and crushed candied blackberry with tight integration on the nose.  On the palate, the acid is a little green and strong, the tannin is high but again fine-grained, and flavors are long and concentrated on the palate.  This wine is the “bane of Russell’s existence” as there is so much information to digest to formulate this wine.  This really shows his ability to blend and I hear the 2017 is even better with its large dose of Cabernet Franc (from the Sugarloaf blend that won’t be made that year since the 2017 Merlot was thrown out due to smoke taint).  This wine is the first thing he blends, then he makes the Sugarloaf, Tench, EE, etc.  That alone shows you how much this wine means to him.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bevancellars.com/store/detail?item=2016-bevan-cellars-tench-vineyard-cabernet-sauvignon-oakville&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Tench Vineyard Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($195)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The vineyard for this wine is RIGHT next to Screaming Eagle.  48 acres planted (55 acres total).  The owners and Bevan Cellars formed a 25 year partnership where they manage the vineyard and Russell makes wine from it.  They also sell some of the fruit to Thomas Rivers Brown and Phillipe Melka (two famous consulting winemakers), so you know it’s good fruit.  The pronounced nose is generous, rich, and lively with its red/blue/black fruit.  On the palate, it’s just as rich and generous but mainly red/black fruit with the acidity enhanced by the minerality of Petit Verdot splash in this wine.  The body is a little leaner than Kapcsandy, but make no mistake this wine is top quality.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bevancellars.com/store/detail?item=2015-cabernet-sauvignon-wildfoote-vixen-stags-leap-district&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Wildfoote Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($195)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pronounced red fruit with some candied red fruit in there as well.  It reminds me of a sleeping giant, like many amazing wines that are closed in their youth, but smash their way onto the scene after a few years in hibernation.  Though, as the most feminine of their Cabernets, it has an elegance, weight, and finish that is fierce that doesn’t rely on sheer intensity alone.  I have a couple bottles of the 2016 vintage of this Stags Leap and hope it unveils itself in a few years to be a worthy rival to my Shafer Hillside Selects and Cliff Lede Poetry.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you buy a bottle of their Cabernet Sauvignon, the tasting is free, which is why I highly recommend visiting if the bottle is not out of your price range.  Think of it like paying for a tasting and buying an extremely good bottle of Cabernet for $100.  Just be sure to confirm the wine lineup before visiting to confirm it has the varietals and values you want and you’ll come back a very happy person.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="st-helena" /><summary type="html">You can read up on the background of Bevan Cellars and prior vintage tastings in in this article HERE. The first thing you may notice about this article is that I dropped the rating, compared to my last tasting here. The change is primarily due to the number and quality of the wines used for this tasting; they were not up to the standard that was set during my previous visit. We were also given the remnants of bottles opened the previous day to taste, rather than being able to taste fresh bottles. In a couple cases, the pour was smaller than other bottles because the amount available wasn’t enough. Make no mistake, these are wines of the highest quality, just not served in their best condition.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/bevan-cellars-2/1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/bevan-cellars-2/1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Italics Winegrowers Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/28/italics_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Italics Winegrowers Private Tasting" /><published>2019-12-28T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-28T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/28/italics_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/28/italics_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;I’m surprised there aren’t more movies/videos on wine in the world today.  Maybe people are too afraid to rock the market like the movie Sideways did to Merlot and Pinot Noir.  One of the more recent ones to hit Netflix is the special “Decanted”, which follows and interviews a few winemakers from Napa.  It starts with an interview of Heidi Barrett in her helicopter (awesome), but a majority of the movie revolves around the creation of a new winery that I hadn’t heard of before.  Since I had been to almost (if not) all the other places featured or discussed in the special, I decided I needed to make a reservation and visit this new winery.  I’m glad we did as we found some great wines and had a fun tasting experience in their wine cave!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Entrance to the Winery&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/italics/1-800-7e0e10.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/italics/1-350-7e0e10.jpg 350w, /assets/images/italics/1-450-7e0e10.jpg 450w, /assets/images/italics/1-700-7e0e10.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I forget whether or not the entrance is finished in the “Decanted” Netflix special or not - I remember it showing footage of the dug out cave.  But as you can see, Italics does not have a traditional wine tasting facility to handle guests like many others.  The facilities are underground and inside the same cave that they use for their wine tasting.  There are several wineries that do this (e.g. Pine Ridge), but it’s not the norm.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Italics wasn’t just a good tasting.  I think it may have been the most pleasant surprise of our last trip.  And we visited 14 wineries too!  Italics is nestled back in the north-western part of Coombsville, which is a newer AVA in the region that doesn’t have much press or attention yet (except maybe Paul Hobb’s Coombsville Cabernet and Favia which is owned by the Erickson power couple).  Because Coombsville sees cooler temperatures than the valley floor, the wines from the region are fresher, more red fruit than black, and also enables winemakers to make varietal wines that may not turn out as well elsewhere in the valley, such as Viognier and Petit Verdot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Taking in the View&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/italics/2-800-4512ef.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/italics/2-350-4512ef.jpg 350w, /assets/images/italics/2-450-4512ef.jpg 450w, /assets/images/italics/2-700-4512ef.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you made a 180 degree turn from the view in the first picture and walked toward the edge of the parking lot, this is the view you would see.  Italics overlooks not just some of its vines, but the vineyards of other wineries as well.  I’m not sure if it’s the best view in Coombsville, but it has to be at least Top 3.  Just captivating…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Italics is a little tricky to navigate to, but when you make your reservation, you should receive directions along with your email confirmation of the tasting.  Still, you will need to pay attention to the road signs as you get to the last parts of the directions.  Be sure to watch the Decanted Netflix special too since you’ll be able to see what the winery looks like in the video and then make sure the place you arrive at looks the same way.  It definitely helped me out.  After you arrive, you’ll be greeted by your wine ambassador with glasses of Chardonnay for your group.  They’ll explain the history and background of the winery as you enjoy your wine overlooking their vineyards and the road leading to the winery (it is a really nice view).  Afterwords, you’ll be led inside the wine cave for a tasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Our Wine Ambassador&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/italics/3-800-7fe659.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/italics/3-350-7fe659.jpg 350w, /assets/images/italics/3-450-7fe659.jpg 450w, /assets/images/italics/3-700-7fe659.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our Wine Ambassador giving us an explanation of the current state of the winery as well as a look into its history and how it came to be (ie. Filling in the details that the Netflix special didn’t have time to cover).  Still surprised about the Chinese Investment and Wine Cave Tasting Room stories.  Read the rest of the entry to get the details!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the interesting things I learned was a very interesting loophole in the tax law for California vineyards and wineries that Italics and some others (like Pine Ridge) take advantage of.  Now, I may not get this exactly right, so if you are a millionaire looking to start a winery in Napa, please consult someone in the area with more expertise before writing off your taxes.  But if your winemaking/wine sales facility occupies the same land as your grapes (ie. your vineyards grow over the top of your wine cave that you use for tastings and sales), the government can only tax you once for the land - it cannot tax you twice.  So it can tax you once for growing the grapes on the land, but can’t tax you again for the wine sales using the same exact piece of land.  Again, I’m not entirely sure that is an accurate explanation, but I learned enough to know that when I start my own winery one day, I should consult finance professionals that specialize in the wine business.  Because that is a lot of money we are talking about…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Our Tasting Room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/italics/4-800-0ffd00.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/italics/4-350-0ffd00.jpg 350w, /assets/images/italics/4-450-0ffd00.jpg 450w, /assets/images/italics/4-700-0ffd00.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;We signed up for the elevated tasting, so we had a private room in the wine cave for our tasting.  While you can still see the entrance, there’s little reason to look.  The spread that was lined up for us as well as the personalized tasting lists were more than enough to get our attention until the main stars (ie. the wines) showed up.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;No Cheating!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/italics/5-800-f31941.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/italics/5-350-f31941.jpg 350w, /assets/images/italics/5-450-f31941.jpg 450w, /assets/images/italics/5-700-f31941.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A closer look at the entrance to the private room and the spread once it was lined up.  The charcuterie was very good, but the cheeses stole the show.  They were so good that we inquired as to what types they were and where we might be able to buy some.  Finding the right food to pair with wine is important as it can really elevate the experience.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another interesting thing we learned about the winery is that it exists in its form today because of the escalated tensions between the USA and China these last few years.  Apparently, Italics was originally owned and built by a Chinese businessman.  However, he was unable to complete the winery before the tariffs between China and America were instantiated.  Because he was no longer able to infuse more money into the winery (Chinese governement limited investment in US) and everything was unfinished, he had to sell the unfinished winery to the current owners, who appeared on the Netflix special.  This part of the history isn’t really discussed, but it is really interesting how things work out someitimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Tasting Menu&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/italics/6-800-e477b7.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/italics/6-350-e477b7.jpg 350w, /assets/images/italics/6-450-e477b7.jpg 450w, /assets/images/italics/6-700-e477b7.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;We tried a few extra wines that were not on the tasting list because our group is awesome, haha.  Seriously, if you show passion for a wine/varietal or two and the wine ambassador can tell you are serious about purchasing them, they likely will find a way to get you a pour.  This doesn’t always work, but just remember that they want you to be happy and increase their sales.  NOTE: I didn’t write about the Chardonnay and Viognier below, even though we tried them, because I did not have my laptop with me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tasting in the cave was well executed.  The lighting was well done, the cheese and characuterie pairing was fantastic (we hunted down the cheeses afterwards), the tasting cards were personalized for the group, and we got to dip into a few bottles that were not on the tasting menu.  I’m sure the wine ambassador was happy they did that since one of those bottles (the Viognier) was our most purchased bottle!  Our other favorite bottle was the Petit Verdot - both are uncommon to see as varietal bottlings in the Napa area.  The 16 Appelations blend was also unusual - a blend of grapes from every AVA in the Napa region.  This was far from your traditional “Chardonnay, Cabernet, Cabernet Reserve, plus one other varietal” tasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Explaining the Wines&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/italics/7-800-d56ec5.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/italics/7-350-d56ec5.jpg 350w, /assets/images/italics/7-450-d56ec5.jpg 450w, /assets/images/italics/7-700-d56ec5.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Getting our explanation of the wines.  I must say that I was really impressed with the tasting.  The wines I liked the most were varietals I am not used to having from Napa - Petit Verdot and Viognier.  Be sure to stop in and give these wines try yourself.  The 16 Appelations wine is also a fun bottle - a blend using grapes from every AVA in the Napa Valley.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some introductions and side-conversation (our wine ambassador used to live in the DC area before leaving it all behind and coming to Napa), we jumped headfirst into the wines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.italicswinegrowers.com/product/2014-Sixteen-Appellations&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Sixteen Appellations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;More raisined character than the 2015 with deeper red rhubarb and spice notes. On the palate, the super smooth tannin and acid are drinking perfectly, yet would allow for aging. This is a people pleaser that will satisfy everyone.  It also has a deep, underlying layer that has great concentration and length. Vines started growing here in 1990 but with 3309C Bordeaux clones that came around 1970.  Meaning the vines will continue to improve with age and the quality of the wine will increase.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.italicswinegrowers.com/product/2015-Sixteen-Appellations&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Sixteen Appellations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It’s brighter and leaps from the glass because there is no Petit Verdot, letting the Cabernet Franc shine freely. Fresh/slightly perfumed red fruit and white spice on the nose.  More tannin and grip than the ‘14, but the complexity on the palate is intriguing. This wine also has the better aging potential.  Some stem tannin or a green fennel to it as well?  I can’t wait to see this wine in 5 years. Still cerebral now, but you may need to wait if you are looking for a people pleaser.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.italicswinegrowers.com/product/2015-Italics-Cabernet-Sauvignon&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Estate Coombsville&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($95)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I really enjoyed this wine and believe it’s a fantastic representation of the AVA.  The nose has depth and concentration with ripe and dark red fruit. The acid is remarkable for a Cabernet - so bright yet elegant.  The palate is very smooth with high ripe tannin, high acid, red fruit, some oak influence, and tertiary elements starting to develop.  I can imagine this wine being complex and still bright in 10 years.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 St. Helena One of 16&lt;/strong&gt; ($125)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is darker red and black fruit and deeper than the Coombsville Estate Cabernet, but also a bit more restrained (medium+ intensity) with cocoa and vanilla.  The palate is intense, richly concentrated, soft integrated tannin, and high acid.  This wine is drinking really well right now - seductively delicious that is impossible to say no to.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Petit Verdot Coombsville&lt;/strong&gt; ($115)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Restrained and powdery on the nose.  The palate has such soft, very high, but fine grained tannins, great concentration and a variety of flavors that leaves you in a bit of disbelief.  This wine is for those that like having wines that are different / off the beaten path.  This is going to age really well and become very interesting…  Still can’t believe a varietal Petit Verdot could turn out like this in Napa.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.italicswinegrowers.com/product/2016-Italics-Estate-Cabernet-Franc&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Estate Cabernet Franc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($125)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Beautiful pronounced perfume of crushed candied cherry and vanilla.  On the palate, the wine is lighter bodied (medium), but the flavors are still intensely pronounced and a little less ripe than the red fruit displayed on the nose.  Not a complex as I traditionally like my Cabernet Francs, but I could still drink an entire bottle myself.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend a visit to Italics, both for the wine and the story.  For my friends that came on the trip with me, they had a blast getting their families to watch Decanted over winter break and then talk about all the different places that were featured (including Italics) and how they were able to visit all of them.  It’s at least one step up from just showing pictures of the places, haha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even without that claim to fame, the wine is great, different, and the tasting experience is above par.  So what are you waiting for?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="coombsville" /><summary type="html">I’m surprised there aren’t more movies/videos on wine in the world today. Maybe people are too afraid to rock the market like the movie Sideways did to Merlot and Pinot Noir. One of the more recent ones to hit Netflix is the special “Decanted”, which follows and interviews a few winemakers from Napa. It starts with an interview of Heidi Barrett in her helicopter (awesome), but a majority of the movie revolves around the creation of a new winery that I hadn’t heard of before. Since I had been to almost (if not) all the other places featured or discussed in the special, I decided I needed to make a reservation and visit this new winery. I’m glad we did as we found some great wines and had a fun tasting experience in their wine cave!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/italics/4.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/italics/4.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Keplinger Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/21/keplinger_wines_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Keplinger Private Tasting" /><published>2019-12-21T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-21T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/21/keplinger_wines_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/21/keplinger_wines_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;While only 14% of the winemakers in Napa today are female, there are several that I follow who I consider to be in the upper-tier of best winemakers in the country, if not the world.  If you’ve read most of my articles, you’ll know that I have a love affair with the wines of Heidi Barrett.  The wines of Helen Turley (at Marcassin) and Celia Welch (at Scarecrow) are a little out of my price range currently (I want to try them so badly…), but the wines of Cathy Corison and Helen Keplinger are right up my alley.  While I’ve done articles on Heidi and Cathy, I haven’t been able to visit Helen yet.  I’ve had some of her personal label before and really like her wines at Carte Blanche.  She’s even worked with Heidi at Kenzo Estate in the past!  So I decided to take our group for a visit.  Luckily, she has a tasting room in downtown Napa and her husband, who is also the Wine Director for Carte Blanche, helped get us setup for a tasting with their wine ambassador.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;My Friends are Hilarious&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/keplinger/1-800-2e9406.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/keplinger/1-350-2e9406.jpg 350w, /assets/images/keplinger/1-450-2e9406.jpg 450w, /assets/images/keplinger/1-700-2e9406.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keplinger does tastings one group at a time.  That’s because their tasting room in downtime Napa only has one table in it for tastings.  It also turns out that the tasting room is just behind a pane of glass, so people on the streets of Napa can walk up to the building and stare at you while you are tasting.  I used that as an opportunity to get a picture before heading into the room, because the quarters are a little tight when inside.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt bad for the wine ambassador because I have poor planning skills.  We overstayed at Kapcsandy and our lunch took at while to be served, so we packed most of our sushi to go and still were running a few minutes late when we arrived.  The wine ambassador was very gracious - she allowed us to finish our lunch in their small tasting room while going into the history of Keplinger wines before we were ready to try the wines.  And I must say, I was surprised how well the Rhone varietal wines we tried followed the lunch sushi.  I’m not saying you need to do this too, but it was a really good experience.  We also purchased a good amount of wine, so I don’t feel as bad looking back on the situation now, haha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Our Tasting Group Crushed It&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/keplinger/2-800-05d50b.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/keplinger/2-350-05d50b.jpg 350w, /assets/images/keplinger/2-450-05d50b.jpg 450w, /assets/images/keplinger/2-700-05d50b.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A look at the tasting table after our group had finished with it.  As you can see, we take no prisoners and crushed all of the wines in our glasses.  It’s rare to taste so many varietals commonly associated with the Rhone Valley of France while in Napa.  We savored every sip from the glass and walked out with a bunch of bottles&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Helen graduated with her Masters from UC Davis in the 90s and has consulted for several wineries in the past, including the illustrious Bryant Family Winery, she is now concentrating solely on Keplinger Wines.  I’m really happy for her that her production, distribution, and sales are at the point where she can just concentrate on her personal project.  That may not be every winemaker’s dream (ask Paul Hobbs), but that certainly would be my dream.  And while you may find Syrah at some other wineries in Napa (e.g. Darioush), it is not common and the style which Helen uses is much more reminiscent of the Southern Rhone than any other vineyard.  It certainly brought back memories for me when I visited Chateauneuf-du-Pape on my way to Avignon.  Because that, I like to think of Helen’s wines as a blend of new world and old world style winemaking.  Helen also doesn’t filter her wines and predominantly uses neutral oak to not lose the fruit character of her wines (sounds familiar… haha).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Yes, that's our lunch&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/keplinger/3-800-96cbf3.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/keplinger/3-350-96cbf3.jpg 350w, /assets/images/keplinger/3-450-96cbf3.jpg 450w, /assets/images/keplinger/3-700-96cbf3.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This one picture really sums up our whirlwind 4-day trip to Napa.  Even though I planned for 2 hours at Kapcsandy, our tasting bled over making us late for lunch, which made us late for this tasting.  So this is us, eating our sushi out of to-go boxes while the food is still hot before our tasting.  Keplinger was very flexible and we made up time to enjoy a great tasting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you take a look on the Keplinger Wines website, they produce around 10 different bottlings.  Also, tasting reservations are by appointment only and they don’t have a set tasting menu that everyone does.  So when you reach out for a reservation via email, be sure to include any preferences you may have so that they can tailor the tasting to what you prefer.  Our group wanted to taste the Cabernet Sauvignon (since Helen made some famous ones in the past and we knew she was skilled) and we wanted to taste an older vintage in comparison to a younger vintage, so we could see how the wines would age.  If you would just like a greater breadth of the portfolio for your tasting, just let them know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Hands Shaking with Excitement&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/keplinger/4-800-a8425a.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/keplinger/4-350-a8425a.jpg 350w, /assets/images/keplinger/4-450-a8425a.jpg 450w, /assets/images/keplinger/4-700-a8425a.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you ask me, I’ll say that my hands were shaking with excitement, and that’s why this picture is blurry.  In actuality, I was probably just avoiding my glass in front of me and hadn’t lifted weights in a while.  We all enjoyed each of the wines, though the Basilisk Syrah (both the 2013 and 2016) were the ones we purchased the most of.  I got several bottles of the Oakville Ranch Cab too.  Because that just has to be good…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you understand what we asked for, here are the wines that we actually tasted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.carteblanchewine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/2016-Carte-Blanche-Chardonnay-UV.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Carte Blanche Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($65)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wow.  Rich, ripe yellow fruit, cream, brioche, and yellow cake on the nose.  Medium(+) acid, medium(+) body that is as smooth and rich as the nose, not overly alcoholic, concentrated, and mellow but solid.  This wine is priced just under the heavyweights and I think that’s where the quality level is too.  A really nice Chardonnay that’s brighter than most, but all the power that you may want from Napa.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://keplingerwines.com/store/detail?item=2013-keplinger-caldera&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Caldera&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($90)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;60% Mourvèdre with the rest Grenache and Counois, just like the Southern Rhone.  From the Gold Butt vineyard on Apple Hill and dry farmed at 2900 feet.  The Grenache provides red fruit and blood orange on the nose, but the Mourvèdre and Counois combine to display iron, blood, animal fur, and savory notes.  On the palate, the fruit is much more restrained, leaving the tertiary character (iron/savory) to really come out.  This is the style of wine my brother and his wife love - I just wish I purchased a bottle…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://keplingerwines.com/store/detail?item=2013-keplinger-basilisk&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Basilisk&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($90)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;100% Grenache from the Greywacke vineyard in the Russian River Valley area.  The vineyard is in a warm, super steep pocket of land (it looks like a serpents tail).  This is a vibrant Grenache with pretty red fruit on the nose.  It’s surprising how structured this wine is, given how pretty the notes are - it could absolutely age for a longer period because of the medium(+) acid and tannin.  A beautiful single varietal expression that reminds you of the best bottling of a vineyard from Chateauneuf.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt; ($185)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Only 96 cases of this wine was produced from Oakville Ranch.  The nose is so beguiling and seductive with its crushed rose petals and the juicy, deep red fruit at medium(+) intensity.  On the palate, that same beauty just seems to continue on.  The tannin is very soft and the acidity provides freshness while the flavors open on the palate. This is drinking amazing but they only have 11 bottle left, so we couldn’t buy any…  However, I got a friend to go in with me on a 6-pack of the 2016.  So I am extremely excited to try those wines!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://keplingerwines.com/store/detail?item=2016-keplinger-basilisk&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Basilisk&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;We asked to try the Basilisk at a younger age because we were so enthralled by the 2013 and wanted to know how it would taste earlier on in its life.  100% Grenache like the 2013, this wine is an absolute giant.  It’s actually high tannin and acid (very uncommon for Grenache), but is balanced with the intensity of flavors the wine.  This needs a little time to age and integrate but wow, this wine is special.  I also bought a 6-pack of this.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should warn readers that when purchasing bottles, they will only sell the wines to you in 6-packs.  So when visiting Keplinger for a tasting, keep that in mind and try to bring along a group of people that will share a 6-pack purchase with you.  Luckily, I have a fantastic group of wine friends I could do that with, but I know this might be an issue for others, especially if your friends don’t spend similar amounts of money for their wines as you do.  But if this isn’t an issue for you and you love the wines of the Rhone Valley, then you must absolutely visit Keplinger wines and support one of the best female talents of Napa.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><summary type="html">While only 14% of the winemakers in Napa today are female, there are several that I follow who I consider to be in the upper-tier of best winemakers in the country, if not the world. If you’ve read most of my articles, you’ll know that I have a love affair with the wines of Heidi Barrett. The wines of Helen Turley (at Marcassin) and Celia Welch (at Scarecrow) are a little out of my price range currently (I want to try them so badly…), but the wines of Cathy Corison and Helen Keplinger are right up my alley. While I’ve done articles on Heidi and Cathy, I haven’t been able to visit Helen yet. I’ve had some of her personal label before and really like her wines at Carte Blanche. She’s even worked with Heidi at Kenzo Estate in the past! So I decided to take our group for a visit. Luckily, she has a tasting room in downtown Napa and her husband, who is also the Wine Director for Carte Blanche, helped get us setup for a tasting with their wine ambassador.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/keplinger/3.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/keplinger/3.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Mayacamas Wine Bar Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/14/mayacamas_wine_bar_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mayacamas Wine Bar Tasting" /><published>2019-12-14T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-14T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/14/mayacamas_wine_bar_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/14/mayacamas_wine_bar_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;When you think about the historical wineries of Napa, you may think of Beringer, Inglenook, and others.  Cult collectors will surely name Mayacamas near the top of their list.  LeBron James, the wine connoisseur of the NBA, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.espn.com/espn/feature/story/_/id/22358028/the-nba-obsession-wine&quot;&gt;took the Cleveland Cavaliers to Mayacamas&lt;/a&gt; during a bonding weekend to enjoy the wines and educational experience.  But you don’t need to make a reservation for $100pp and drive 30min from the town of Napa to enjoy the wines of Mayacamas.  Thanks to a recent trend of wineries in hard-to-commute locations, you can visit the newly-opened Mayacamas wine bar in downtown Napa for a tasting of their current releases ($35pp).  And if you’d like, you can include some back vintage Chardonnays and Cabernets as well ($60pp).  All while being able to walk to dinner afterwards.  Sounds too good to be true, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First established in 1889, Mayacamas has been producing great, ageworthy wines for over a century.  It’s amazing that they’ve continued to exist until today: reviving after Prohibition, surviving the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sfchronicle.com/wine/article/Mayacamas-winery-still-standing-tasting-room-12273311.php&quot;&gt;Nun’s Fire in October 2017&lt;/a&gt;, and enduring plenty of other obstacles, I’m sure…  Despite their history, cult status, and continued streak of red-hot wine critic scores and the collectability of their wines, their prices have stayed relatively modest compared to the high-end of the Napa market.  When I heard that they had opened their Napa wine bar location, I had to bring my tasting group.  And I must admit, telling the LeBron James story was amusing as the reactions I got were all of the map, haha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things I love about Mayacamas is that they have stayed true to their style through the different phases of the American palate.  There was a time when sweet, white Zinfandel was the most popular drink in the USA.  This “sweet” trend/preference started after Prohibition (I should make a podcast episode on the reason why…) and continued until a decade or two ago, when people’s preferences swung back to dry wines.  Even today, the American palate puts a premium on intense, dark, extracted, highly tannic wines.  I’m guilty of the same thing - just peek at my wine collection.  Luckily, there are wineries and winemakers that do not agree with the current Napa style and intentionally produce wines under 14% ABV with lighter extraction.  Dunn Vineyards on Howell Mountain may be one of the most famous examples, but Mayacamas has been keeping ABV and extraction down (and fresh acid up) for an even longer period of time.  These wines will likely taste nothing like the other wines you will have on your trip to Napa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to take a group of people (6 or more), I recommend making a reservation to guarantee the private table alcove in the back of the bar.  However, if it’s four or less people, feel free to do a walk-in tasting.  Just be prepared for it to be busy during the weekend.  If you do make a reservation though, it helps them to prepare any extra bottles they may want to pour for you and helps them ensure they have library vintages available (if you’d like to add them to your tasting, which I HIGHLY recommend).  When I am able to make it to their vineyard and winery on Mt. Veeder, I’ll write more about the history of the winery and the buildings in that article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the visit was after a long day of tasting and I forgot to take pictures…  Sorry.  But I did manage to take notes on the wines!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mayacamas.com/resources/pdfs/Mayacamas_2017_Chardonnay.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($50)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Grown at 1800 feet on Mt. Veeder where there is a lot of light for sugar development, but not a lot of heat for phenolic development.  The nose is medium(+) intensity with salinity and yellow fruit.  On the palate, the acid is high because they block MLF, but allow 7 months of lees aging.  Lots of vanilla as well that integrates with the yellow fruit, pastry, banana, and lychee character.  On the palate, you get green apple, yellow apple, peach, and apricot – just a lovely medley of fruit.  Mayacamas has a “golf of wine” approach: aim to use the least amount of strokes (winemaker interventions) as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2002 Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt; ($135)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The intensity on the nose is incredible with the nuttiness, marzipan, light butter, cream, brioche, and dried yellow fruit.  It was a bit surreal for everyone to taste this wine since the acidity was so bright and kept the wine very fresh.  This inspired our entire group to purchase young bottles and try to age them in order to try something like this again.  It’s crazy what mountain fruit can become…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2010 Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;They stopped making Pinot in 2013, so this was a real treat.  Red fruit and some funkiness on the nose that makes me think of northern burgundy.  Bright acid and solid fruit - this is like a Gevrey Chambertin Premier Cru, but with a little less black olive in the profile.  I’m interested to see how this wine will continue to age and the acid will allow that to happen gracefully.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mayacamas.com/resources/pdfs/Mayacamas_2014_Merlot.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Merlot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($60)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Lost my notes for this bottle, but I remember it being medium intensity, very bright, unripe red fruit (cranberry, strawberry), with acidity that rings inside your cheeks.  Not the “mellow” Merlot you may be used to.  Again, very different in style to traditional Merlots.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mayacamas.com/resources/pdfs/Mayacamas_2014_Cabernet_Sauvignon.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($125)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bright, ripe red fruit (pomegranate, cherry) on the nose.  The same flavors carry through on the palate and do not show secondary character (no new oak for the Cabernets).  The lighter body and alcohol feel great on the palate and the high acidity makes the wine come alive.  A very different style of Cabernet than what you normally find in Napa.  I would really like to enjoy this during the late spring and early summertime.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mayacamas.com/resources/pdfs/Mayacamas_2003_Cabernet_Sauvignon.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2003 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($250)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is very deep with medicinal red candy, earth and iron.  But there is a ray of brightness that also shines through.  On the palate, you get ripe pomegranate and sour cherry with soft, ripe medium(+) tannin and medium(+) acid.  This wine still has a massive amount of life in it and shows what a vibrant wine can be after 16 years of aging.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mayacamas.com/resources/pdfs/Mayacamas_2004_Cabernet_Sauvignon.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2004 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($250)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Whereas the 2003 showed its age openly, the 2004 shows lots of life and very little age on the nose.  On the palate, the acid is still high and present, the tannin is medium and soft, and the flavors are of medium intensity.  It’s funny - it feels like a baby Amarone because it’s a little raisined in character, but has acid, tannin, and lots of life to age gracefully.  I don’t know when it’ll find its peak, but 15 years isn’t it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tasting the aged Cabernets and especially the aged Chardonnay were rare treats that are hard to find at most wineries in Napa.  If you are in the town of Napa waiting for your dinner reservation, I highly recommend that you walk over to the Mayacamas tasting room and try some of these wines.  NOTE: They will not refund your tasting fee with purchases, so don’t feel compelled to buy a bottle if it doesn’t match your palate.  But you never know if you don’t try this style of wine.  So be adventurous and cheers to your future experience!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="mount-veeder" /><summary type="html">When you think about the historical wineries of Napa, you may think of Beringer, Inglenook, and others. Cult collectors will surely name Mayacamas near the top of their list. LeBron James, the wine connoisseur of the NBA, took the Cleveland Cavaliers to Mayacamas during a bonding weekend to enjoy the wines and educational experience. But you don’t need to make a reservation for $100pp and drive 30min from the town of Napa to enjoy the wines of Mayacamas. Thanks to a recent trend of wineries in hard-to-commute locations, you can visit the newly-opened Mayacamas wine bar in downtown Napa for a tasting of their current releases ($35pp). And if you’d like, you can include some back vintage Chardonnays and Cabernets as well ($60pp). All while being able to walk to dinner afterwards. Sounds too good to be true, right?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kapcsandy Private Tour and Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/07/kapcsandy_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kapcsandy Private Tour and Tasting" /><published>2019-12-07T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-07T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/07/kapcsandy_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/07/kapcsandy_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;You can read up on Kapcsandy’s history and prior vintage tastings in this article &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/07/21/kapcsandy_private_tasting.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HERE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  Although there is no membership club you can sign up for with Kapcsandy, they do have a benefit programs you can qualify for based on your purchases.  Since my tasting group loves and purchases as much Kapcsandy as I do, we try to make a trip once a year to taste the new vintage.  And I can’t say enough about Kapcsandy - it is my favorite winery experience in Napa, if you can afford it and meet the requirements for the tasting (see the previous article for details).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Louis in his happy place&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kapcsandy-2/1-800-c894f7.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kapcsandy-2/1-350-c894f7.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kapcsandy-2/1-450-c894f7.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kapcsandy-2/1-700-c894f7.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last time, we got a tour from the wine ambassador of Kapcsandy.  This trip, Louis Jr. himself gave us the repeat full tour (we had a couple new people on the trip with us).  This tasting almost didn’t happen - we booked our trip to Napa during the same week Louis Jr. and his father were supposed to go on a family vacation.  Luckily for us they happened to cancel/move the trip and Louis was happy to host us again.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;If only I could have a barrel&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kapcsandy-2/2-800-3270d6.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kapcsandy-2/2-350-3270d6.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kapcsandy-2/2-450-3270d6.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kapcsandy-2/2-700-3270d6.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The beautiful barrel room with the 2017 vintage in barrel now.  The barrels still look clean/crisp because they use new French Oak each year when producing their wines.  If only I could have a barrel…  What a happy man I would be.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the Grand Vins, we tasted the 2013 and 2014 vintages last year, so tasting the amazing 2015 and 2016 vintages were in order.  And my word, did we all enjoy the wines…  But we knew that coming in.  When the only female Chief Editor of a major wine magazine calls a wine “sex in a glass”, you know you need to try that wine.  I think I walked away with 6 bottles of the 2016 Grand Vin - it may be the greatest young wine I have ever tasted in my life.  And I have tried many 100pt wines before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Bottles and Bottles&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kapcsandy-2/3-800-d894e6.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kapcsandy-2/3-350-d894e6.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kapcsandy-2/3-450-d894e6.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kapcsandy-2/3-700-d894e6.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some of the bottles that we tasted this year.  It doesn’t include a picture of my favorite (the 2016 Grand Vin), but the ones in the picture were still really good bottles.  We happened to see Tony Arcudi on the property during the tasting too and were sure to say hello before diving in!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2016 also marked the first vintage for Tony Arcudi as the consulting winemaker for Kapcsandy.  Coincidence?  You can read up on my tasting of Tony Arcudi’s personal label and his background here &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/27/tony_arcudi_private_tasting.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HERE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  Suffice it to say that he is one of the newer winemakers in the Napa Valley that I am tracking closely and is someone that comes from the Heidi Barrett Winemaking tree (at Fantesca).  Also, I want to be him when I grow up.  So it wouldn’t be wrong to say that I had two reasons I needed to visit Kapcsandy this past year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Telling Stories&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kapcsandy-2/4-800-dd8ab7.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kapcsandy-2/4-350-dd8ab7.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kapcsandy-2/4-450-dd8ab7.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kapcsandy-2/4-700-dd8ab7.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;There’s my favorite bottle, just waiting to be poured into my empty glass after Louis Jr. finishes telling his story.  2016 was probably the best vintage in Napa this millenium after 2013.  But I think I prefer the 2016 over the 2013 Grand Vin.  I almost felt like I could drink any more wine after the tasting this morning.  But after the bland lunch, I was ready to get back into it…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I noted in my earlier article, the wines of Kapcsandy are not in the normal affordable price segment - their Estate Cuvee starts at ~$125 while their Grand Cru runs to $325/350.  But, if you need a special occasion wine or have done well enough in life that you can afford several bottles, you will be glad you did and all of your wine friends will be jealous of you as soon as they taste a glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also noticed that my pictures were a bit lacking in my previous post, so I made sure to take and include some new ones.  But without further ado, the 2015/2016 vintages!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kapcsandywines.com/wines/2018-Furmint&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2018 Furmint&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($40)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Medium(+) intensity of lemon, lime, white peach, apricot, medium(+) soft acidity, with great concentration, depth, and medium body.  Very fresh, but soft and serious.  Fruit driven, but not overly fruity.  Very balanced wine that drinks very easy but is very serious.  Also a unique varietal like Furmint in Napa?  Very cool.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kapcsandywines.com/wines/2016-Estate-Cuv-e-Cabernet-Sauvignon&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Estate Cuvee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($130)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Deep crushed purple flowers, crushed rocks, all of the red, blue, and black fruit, but very fresh and balanced with the ripeness.  The nose is both serious and fun.  The tannins are so fine and balances with the acid and alcohol.  A little less ripe than the Grand Vin, but drinks very nice immediately out of the bottle.  Very complex.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kapcsandywines.com/wines/2016-Rapszodia&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Rapszodia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($285)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pronounced, perfumed, ripe cranberry, cherry, plum, peach and other stonefruit.  The palate is a bit more restrained with the red/black fruit, but there is a minerality that stands out and is supported by a deep tertiary layer that is just starting to peek out.  Long finish that feels good with the acidity and has a bit of fleshiness.  This is a serious wine that is a very good varietal representation that isn’t too cloying.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kapcsandywines.com/wines/2015-Roberta-s-Reserve&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Roberta’s Reserve&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($300)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pronounced nose of crushed, candied cherry, cranberry, rose petals, violets, other floral notes, and deep fresh red plum that sets a strong and concentrated undertone.  Good structure with medium(+) powdery tannin and acid that still needs time to integrated into the medium body.  Very fresh, young and needs time to smooth and round out.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kapcsandywines.com/wines/2015-Cabernet-Sauvignon-Grand-Vin&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Grand Vin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($325)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The intensity on the nose is ridiculous…  All the floral aromas with red, blue, and black fruit with sweet spices and just a touch of vanilla from the wood.  The palate is all of those things with very good integration, weight, concentration, and length.  The wine feels weighty and concentrated all the way through the palate with a long finish.  The tannin is high, powdery, but it isn’t out of sync like the Roberta’s Reserve currently is.  A little more red fruit than there normally is in the Grand Vins, but a sensational wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kapcsandywines.com/wines/2016-Cabernet-Sauvignon-Grand-Vin&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Grand Vin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($325)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The fruit orients toward the blue and black end of the spectrum on the nose (whereas the 2015 leaned towards red fruit).  Crushed, candied blackberries, blueberries, rocks, and other bright black fruit.  Elegant, concentrated, weighty, balanced black/blue fruit that is intense but not overly opulent on the palate.  The tannin is even finer and more integrated in this wine.  If I thought the 2015 was a perfect 100 point wine, this wine must be 105 points.  I can’t say enough about this wine, so I am not going to even try.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2004 Grand Vin&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose on this wine is unbelievable.  I am literally speechless after smelling this wine.  All I can do is stare blankly with my mouth open at people.  15 years old and there is so much pronounced primary/secondary/tertiary aromas and flavors on the palate.  Dark Jolly Ranchers, mocha, vanilla, and a haunting floral perfume on the nose.  Also, this wine was made from 3 YEAR OLD VINES by Helen Turley at the very beginning of Kapcsandy.  The tannins are still rough and grittier on the finish and still feel high/present on the palate because of the types of barrels used back in the day.  But if this is any indication on how the 2015/2016 will age, oh my goodness!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kapcsandywines.com/wines/2013-Vino-del-Sol&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Vino Del Sol+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Aged 42 months in Cognac barrels and made from the vines at the edge of the vineyard from the amazing 2013 vintage.  The concentration, flavors, length, balance, body, viscosity, etc. is even greater than the Vino Del Sol that we had last time.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing this article, I’m realizing I wrote it more for me (so I could relive the experience) than for readers.  Sorry, not sorry.  You need to try the wines of Kapcsandy too.  That way, when you read this article, you can reminisce with me!  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="yountville" /><summary type="html">You can read up on Kapcsandy’s history and prior vintage tastings in this article HERE. Although there is no membership club you can sign up for with Kapcsandy, they do have a benefit programs you can qualify for based on your purchases. Since my tasting group loves and purchases as much Kapcsandy as I do, we try to make a trip once a year to taste the new vintage. And I can’t say enough about Kapcsandy - it is my favorite winery experience in Napa, if you can afford it and meet the requirements for the tasting (see the previous article for details).</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/kapcsandy-2/4.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/kapcsandy-2/4.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>