<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-10-10T18:51:06+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Wines By Jeremy</title><subtitle>Wines by Jeremy offers an educative and enjoyable personalized wine experience. Located in the DC metro area, Wines by Jeremy provides a number of services including in-home exclusive tastings, highly curated event tastings, educational events, and wine cellar consulting.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Cliff Lede Backstage Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/31/cliff_lede_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cliff Lede Backstage Tasting" /><published>2019-08-31T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-31T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/31/cliff_lede_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/31/cliff_lede_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Christopher Tynan is one of the hottest winemakers in Napa Valley right now.  In addition to propelling wineries like Cliff Lede to centerstage in the wine world, he produces wines under his own label from sourced fruit that wine writers cannot stop gushing over (I think Jeb Dunnuck has given every one of his label’s wines 100pts each vintage).  He and Tony Arcudi are the two newer winemakers I am closely following.  So of course I had to take the opportunity to taste at Cliff Lede when I had the chance.  I thought Shafer and Stags Leap Wine Cellars were the two kings of the AVA.  But both of them better watch out because Cliff Lede is coming on very strong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/1-1050by788-aa284e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/1-700by525-aa284e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/1-675by506-aa284e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/1-450by338-aa284e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/1-525by394-aa284e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/1-350by263-aa284e.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/1-350by263-aa284e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Facility&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Cliff Lede Winery looks like a normal house from the road in the Stags Leap District.  The wines are anything but normal though…  I’ve heard rumors and read the articles about Christopher Tynan, but I don’t think I was quite ready to taste these wines.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/2-1050by788-2055df.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/2-700by525-2055df.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/2-675by506-2055df.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/2-450by338-2055df.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/2-525by394-2055df.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/2-350by263-2055df.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/2-350by263-2055df.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The vineyards&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;From the parking lot, you have a great view to Stags Leap and can begin to understand what makes the wines so special.  I am also very jealous of the people that own the houses on the hillside, next to the plots where grapes for the Poetry come from.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than knowing of the winemaker, I had no background on Cliff Lede before the tasting.  I had neither read any articles about them nor tasted any of their wines before.  Even today, I can’t find much of their wines in DC/Virginia, even though I see bottles of the One Point Five (Shafer) and Artemis (SLWC) everywhere.  But now I am always paying attention to Cliff Lede’s website, waiting for the next sales on their Calistoga and Howell Mountain Cabernets as well as purchasing several bottles of their Beckstoffer To Kalon every new vintage.  That is how much things have changed for me in a year…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/3-1050by788-4aedc3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/3-700by525-4aedc3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/3-675by506-4aedc3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/3-450by338-4aedc3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/3-525by394-4aedc3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/3-350by263-4aedc3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/3-350by263-4aedc3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Inside the Main Tasting Room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;If you sign up for the normal tasting, this is the area where it happens.  If you don’t make an appointment, you can still get a tasting from the standing bar, but if you do get one, you’ll have the chance to relax on some sofas inside or some chairs outside.  It was hot this day, so everyone wanted to stay inside.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/4-1050by788-79d8d4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/4-700by525-79d8d4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/4-675by506-79d8d4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/4-450by338-79d8d4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/4-525by394-79d8d4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/4-350by263-79d8d4.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/4-350by263-79d8d4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Members Only&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;If you sign up for one of the special tasting experiences, they will take you to the members lounge in a building a short walk away.  The owners are very passionate about Rock and Roll and have pretty awesome memorabilia hanging up on the walls.  Sometimes during the year, they will also host art pieces at the front of the area as well.  I really liked the atmosphere and how everyone was enjoying themselves.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Driving up to the winery and entering the front-door, I didn’t really see much that would’ve made me think “Cliff Lede is a winery I need to follow”.  Their tasting list looked fairly average for a Napa Valley winery and the number of customers and ambiance were in line with that.  Luckily, I had signed up for their Backstage Tasting.  And as we entered the building behind the main tasting room, all of my perceptions changed.  The room was filled, the conversations were louder and more serious, people were laughing, and one of the workers was continuously collecting filled-out order and membership forms.  It was like I was at a different winery than before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/5-1050by788-7e5e87.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/5-700by525-7e5e87.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/5-675by506-7e5e87.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/5-450by338-7e5e87.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/5-525by394-7e5e87.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/5-350by263-7e5e87.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/5-350by263-7e5e87.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Wine Ambassador&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;My wine ambassador for the tasting, pouring me some of the FEL Chardonnay (their other label).  I came back a second time with another group of people where the wine wasn’t quite as good as this tasting, so sometimes it’s just luck regarding what type of experience you have.  Our tasting lineup was also a bit different.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I was a group of one (yes, it’s lonely), I got a seat at the bar in the back, setup my laptop, and proceeded to taste through 6 very good to outstanding wines.  I think the High Fidelity is not normally on their tasting menu, but some members had requested a taste earlier, so they were pouring the rest of the bottle for people until it ran out.  Good timing for me indeed.  I am still torn about not signing up for a membership here, but of the wines I were interested in, I’d have to purchase 6 of them each vintage and that would be tough, since I consider each of them special occasion wines (ie. ~$200-$300 a bottle).  Though, you can also sign up for a membership and receive their FEL or normal Cabernets instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/6-1050by1400-69a569.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/6-700by933-69a569.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/6-675by900-69a569.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/6-450by600-69a569.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/6-525by700-69a569.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/6-350by467-69a569.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/6-350by467-69a569.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Beckstoffer&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Beckstoffer vineyards are famous in Napa.  In Napa, many times the vineyard will be more well-known than the producer and is one way different wineries will try to improve their visibility in the market (make a wine from a famous site).  I think this was more a clash of the superpowers that produced a 100pt wine…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of these wines were among the best of their varietal (or blend) category.  But that Beckstoffer left me dreaming of life 10-15 years from now.  Even now, I catch myself staring at the bottles in my wine fridge, wondering how well they will round into form.  Time will tell I guess…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ledefamilywines.com/product/2016-FEL-Chardonnay-Savoy-Vineyard&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEL Savoy Vineyard Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($48)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Light saline aromas on the nose paired with ripe lemon and lime on the palate (the wine was produced in steel tanks).  I’m guessing either none or very little MLF because of the lack of butter/cream notes, but in its place you have a very good medium(+) balanced acid.  This is a very easy drinking Chardonnay that is mellow and smooth.  I’d like a little more character, but besides complexity, there is nothing you could point to as a flaw or imbalance in this wine.  And if you like fruit flavors among all else, this will make you very happy…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 FEL Donnelly Creek Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt; ($38)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;From the Anderson Valley, so there is lots of maritime influence, meaning the weather/temperature is pretty constant where these grapes come from.  The first thing I thought of when I sniffed the wine was HdV (which sells its Pinots for $100+).  On the palate, this wine is very smooth…  Ripe fruit that isn’t candied, some degree of green that seems to be from whole cluster methods, great acidity, and smooth body.  This is for all of those cranberry loves out there that appreciates tingling acidity in their Pinot Noir.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cliffledevineyards.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/2010-Poetry.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2010 Cliff Lede Poetry Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($310)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;One of their two Platinum wines from Stags Leap (other is Songbook).  Ripe and cooked black/red fruit, a bit of green/pyrazine on the tasting profile, and very complex because of the blend percentages in this wine: 75% Cabernet Sauvignon, 16% Merlot, 5% Petit Verdot, 3% Cabernet Franc, and 1% Malbec.  Good structure from the Cab Sauv, tertiary character (espresso, chocolate) and integration from the age, and a long finish.  This is a very cerebral wine that has an expansive profile with tannin/acid levels that allow further aging.  I think it’s drinking perfectly right now, as are most 2010s.  This bottle is not for the traditional Cabernet drinker; this is a wine to ruminate on for an hour.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cliffledevineyards.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/2015-High-Fidelity.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 High Fidelity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($85)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;58% Merlot, 28% Cabernet Franc, 13% Cabernet Sauvignon, and the rest Petit Verdot.  The ripe black fruit, cocoa, espresso and dustiness come out right away from the glass.  There’s a spiciness at the end which is very interesting.  The tannin is very present and needs some time to loosen its grip, which is different for a Merlot-driven wine.  In fact, this bottle could compete with many flagship cabernets elsewhere!  Too bad Merlot gets a bad rap.  This is definitely a wine that could turn people around…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cliffledevineyards.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/2015-Moon-Fantasy.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Moon Fantasy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($110)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Each block of their vineyards is named after a Rock and Roll song rather than being numbered like most places.  Moon Fantasy is a blend of fruit from the “Dark Side of the Moon” plot in the Twin Peaks vineyard and the “Dear Mr. Fantasy” plot in the Poetry vineyard, hence the name Moon Fantasy.  Big, rich blue and black fruit with some dust dominate the nose.  The palate is more of the same with more perfumed fruit and big acid/tannin that could use some years of aging.  There is a dustiness/cocoa/terroir component that is just really smoothly integrated into the wine and added another layer of complexity and deliciousness.  If the High Fidelity shows the potential power of Merlot, this wine is about the big, brooding capability of Cabernet.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cliffledevineyards.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/2015-Cliff-Lede-CS-Beckstoffer-To-Kalon.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Beckstoffer To Kalon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($185)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If one considers the Moon Fantasy “brooding”, the Beckstoffer is a sleeping dragon.  I was almost afraid of swirling the wine for fear of what it might be when it woke up…  The wine explodes from the glass with perfumed blue/black fruit, white flowers, and cocoa.  The palate is just as intense as the nose and emphasizes the fruit and the cocoa.  This is just a brazen, out-of-control wine that needs to be drunk in the winter time.  Also, there is so much acid and tannin that allows for (I take that back – it needs!) 15-25 years of aging.  I don’t know if I can even call this a wine.  I dare not touch this for 10 years (and yes, I bought 5 bottles).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was struggling after this tasting as the Beckstoffer had consumed all of my taste buds.  Overall, this was a very solid tasting that showcased several above average wines and a couple showstoppers.  If you like dark, brooding wines like those of Mt. Veeder or other cult wines, you are really going to enjoy this tasting.  I wonder if it’s coincidence that the winery happens to be next to my favorite winery in Napa (Kapcsandy)…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next time you go out to Napa and think about tasting at Shafer and/or Stags Leap Wine Cellars, I ask that you consider including Cliff Lede as part of your itinerary.  I promise you that you will not be disappointed.  I for one was not…  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="stags-leap" /><summary type="html">Christopher Tynan is one of the hottest winemakers in Napa Valley right now. In addition to propelling wineries like Cliff Lede to centerstage in the wine world, he produces wines under his own label from sourced fruit that wine writers cannot stop gushing over (I think Jeb Dunnuck has given every one of his label’s wines 100pts each vintage). He and Tony Arcudi are the two newer winemakers I am closely following. So of course I had to take the opportunity to taste at Cliff Lede when I had the chance. I thought Shafer and Stags Leap Wine Cellars were the two kings of the AVA. But both of them better watch out because Cliff Lede is coming on very strong.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/cliff-lede/4.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Spire Collection Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/24/spire_collection_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spire Collection Private Tasting" /><published>2019-08-24T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-24T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/24/spire_collection_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/24/spire_collection_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;After my visit to Lokoya a couple years ago, I started following and tasting more of Chris Carpenter’s wines.  I would put him right beside Tony Arcudi as one of the winemakers I would love to work for and learn from.  I highly recommend you check out his podcast interview on “The Taste” with Doug Shafer to get a feel for his career and what’s shaped his style of winemaking.  One night, I happened upon his Mt. Brave and La Jota Cabernets and decided that I needed to taste the rest of the portfolio.  Luckily, each of the labels are all grouped under the Spire Collection brand and can be tasted together at their estate in Calistoga.  I recommend you find bottles sooner rather than later as the prices seem to rise every year…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/1-1050by788-e1003b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/1-700by525-e1003b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/1-675by506-e1003b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/1-450by338-e1003b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/1-525by394-e1003b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/1-350by263-e1003b.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/1-350by263-e1003b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The tasting builiding&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The tasting building for the Spire Collection.  It doesn’t look like much on the outside, but the inside with surprise and impress you.  But even better than the building is the views.  See below…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you visit Calistoga, I strongly recommend that you make an appointment with the Spire Collection.  Not only will you get to taste some excellent wines from the Napa Valley, but you’ll also get to sample great wines from other countries such as Australia, South Africa, Italy, France, etc.  Even better, you can email Spire ahead of time to let them know your preferences, the $$ you are willing to pay for the tasting, and they can adjust the wines they pour to fit what you’d like.  Most of the wines chosen for our tasting came from their international portfolio, while the rest were from Mt. Brave.  The tasting for those 6 wines came in at $75 per person, so that should give you an idea of what to expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/2-1050by788-a7fc10.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/2-700by525-a7fc10.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/2-675by506-a7fc10.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/2-450by338-a7fc10.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/2-525by394-a7fc10.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/2-350by263-a7fc10.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/2-350by263-a7fc10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The vines before trimming&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Not to toot my own horn, but I really like this picture.  You get a glimpse of the beautiful mountain views in the background, but also what the vines look like October, after harvest but before trimming all of the vines to start the winter hibernation.  Just gorgeous…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/3-1050by788-c62c6d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/3-700by525-c62c6d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/3-675by506-c62c6d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/3-450by338-c62c6d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/3-525by394-c62c6d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/3-350by263-c62c6d.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/3-350by263-c62c6d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;So bright...&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It was cold enough that you needed a heavy coat, but the morning sun was as strong as ever.  You also get a better view of the mountains in the background.  The one other thing you notice?  Not another winery in sight.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Putting aside the wines for just a moment, the presentation for the tasting is among the best I’ve experienced in the Napa Valley.  Driving to the tasting room, you drive parallel to the mountains and need to meander on a one lane road through the vines to get to your destination.  The only scary moment is when you arrive and see the building where the tasting is conducted.  It does not look like much from the outside, but once you make your way inside, everything changes.  The room is stylish, elegant, and the views of the mountains outside cannot be beat.  You can just stare at the mountainside while enjoying the wines and ignore everything else that is going on around you.  Though, if you love wine like I do, the view may actually be a distraction to enjoying the wine to their utmost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/4-1050by788-7cb309.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/4-700by525-7cb309.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/4-675by506-7cb309.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/4-450by338-7cb309.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/4-525by394-7cb309.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/4-350by263-7cb309.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/4-350by263-7cb309.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The tasting room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The beautiful tasting room.  Very elegant, lots of natural light (you’ll see why later), but that mirror betrays us, haha.  I loved thhe display of the different wines from the Spire Collection (though no Lokoya…).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/5-1050by788-7ab073.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/5-700by525-7ab073.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/5-675by506-7ab073.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/5-450by338-7ab073.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/5-525by394-7ab073.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/5-350by263-7ab073.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/5-350by263-7ab073.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;What do you think?&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;We had two wines to blind taste during the visit.  The first one gave us all some trouble as you can see by the thinking faces in the room.  Needless to say, we all got the wine origins wrong (the Spire Collection has wineries all over the world).  A very fun tasting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After taking some pictures and wandering the room a bit, it was time for our 10am tasting to begin.  Not only did I appreciate the lineup, but I appreciated the order in which we tasted the wines (the first thing you want to taste in the morning isn’t a Cabernet).  The Chardonnay was especially good, though my favorite had to be the Single Block Cabernet from Mt. Brave.  Just a singular wine that will continue to age well and is very good value at $125, compared to other wines in the same price category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/6-1050by788-0c8d4d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/6-700by525-0c8d4d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/6-675by506-0c8d4d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/6-450by338-0c8d4d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/6-525by394-0c8d4d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/6-350by263-0c8d4d.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/6-350by263-0c8d4d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The view outside&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I will admit to being distracted during the tasting.  This picture is the reason why…  You might think that having a beautiful view while tasting is always a plus, but I appreciate it as much as others.  I’d rather concentrate on the wine while tasting, then enjoy the views separately before/after the tasting.  What do you think?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the wines!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://p.widencdn.net/molqeq/CAP18_23014-15-Chard-WIS-Redesign_r5&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Capensis Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;From Stellenbosch, South Africa.  My first thought smelling this wine was “woah”.  The nose is very rich (like a Burgundian Meursault), but on the palate you can tell that the grapes are picked at a higher acid level.  It surprising to drink a South African Chardonnay that has both richness and structure.  The ripe yellow fruit flavors are pleasant but not too intense on the mid-palate and the salinity/minerality lasts through the finish (I wonder if it’s the effect of the Cape Doctor or reduction).  A very balanced wine that maintains the desired complexity of Chardonnay without overdoing the intensity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://embed.widencdn.net/pdf/plus/jfw/ahinjdwyzy/MGY_WIS_Afleet_2014+acclaim.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2011 Maggy Hawk Pinot Noir “Afleet”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;From the Anderson Valley, close to the ocean.  Each block of Maggy Hawk is dedicated to different clones of Pinot Noir.  Traditional red fruit on the nose (think earthy red cranberries) and some tertiary notes.  Afleet uses a Pommard clone, so mushroom notes are present, but the vibrant acidity covers the length of the palate.  I didn’t get much astringency, so this was picked right as the grapes were ready and still high in acid.  Very much varietally driven in structure and flavor.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://embed.widencdn.net/pdf/plus/jfw/vgob47ztzf/2010Arcanum,Toscana,CabernetFranc-basedblend&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blind Wine – 2011 Arcanum (Super Tuscan IGT)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($100)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The first wine we tasted blind (from a black wine glass).  High acid and medium(+) tannin that is well integrated together and has a heavy effect on the finish.  The nose had depth as it came across as mountain fruit.  Although the wine seemed young, the medium(-) body felt a little disconnected with the acid/tannin and the palate was restrained in intensity.  It did not surprise me that this was an italian wine, but I did not expect it to be 8-year-old Cabernet Franc (with 20% Merlot).  As the nose continues to open, there is more cooked fruit and a tiny bit of white spice on the profile, but nothing like what I would expect reading the label of the bottle..&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://embed.widencdn.net/pdf/plus/jfw/cptf1qn3ey/2014Mt.Brave,Mt.Veeder,CabernetSauvignon.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Mt. Brave Single Block Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($125)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;After being vexed from blind tasting the previous wine, I immediately regained my composure and good mood smelling and tasting this wine.  This wine is made from the highest block of Cabernet Sauvignon in the vineyard.  Crushed rocks, purple flowers, perfume, pretty red fruit, high acid and high tannin that isn’t rough, but very present in the wine.  This wine strikes me as a more elegant/feminine expression of Cabernet, yet contains massive structure that requires some aging.  I would be very comfortable calling this the younger brother of the Lokoya Mt. Veeder.  And at a third of the price…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://embed.widencdn.net/pdf/plus/jfw/porl6hsc80/2014Mt.Brave,Mt.Veeder,Malbec.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Mt. Brave Malbec&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mt. Brave grows some interesting varietals on Mt. Veeder: Cabernet Franc, Merlot, Syrah, etc.  We had the chance to taste the Malbec which really excited me because I’ve had world-class renditions from Argentina that had similar terroir.  The nose is explosive with bright red and blue candied fruit that leaps from the glass.  The tannins are not nearly as big as the previous Cabernet and the fruit just owns this glass of wine (there are some blackberries on the palate too, not just red/blue fruit).  Some crushed, powdered purple petals on the nose as well.  The palate goes from a boisterous symphony of bright/candied fruit to finishing a little too quickly…  Still, a huge Malbec that is fun to show off.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://embed.widencdn.net/pdf/plus/jfw/n7ptu6atzp/HCB17_877592015BrooksRoadWIS_Acclaim.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Hickinbotham Clarendon Vineyard Shiraz&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The last wine we tasted was also served blind.  This 100% Shiraz from the McLaren Vale is very reserved on the nose with a medium body that has grippy tannins.  The palate flavors are integrated and don’t really show that much uniqueness, which in itself is unique.  The cherry-cola flavor is a tell-tale sign of Shiraz, but this wasn’t your Barossa Valley (huge) Shiraz.  This was much more reserved and still closed down right now.  I would be interested to see this wine age for 5 years to see if it opens back up.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I had a fun time tasting the different wines and learning about the Jackson Family’s international estates.  I didn’t walk out with any bottles, but I later ordered the set of Mt. Brave wines from their website to do a tasting with since I think they are solid wines at their price point.  Maybe I can visit their winery up on Mt. Veeder someday…  Until then, I will gladly make do tasting their wines and reminiscing about the views.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="calistoga" /><summary type="html">After my visit to Lokoya a couple years ago, I started following and tasting more of Chris Carpenter’s wines. I would put him right beside Tony Arcudi as one of the winemakers I would love to work for and learn from. I highly recommend you check out his podcast interview on “The Taste” with Doug Shafer to get a feel for his career and what’s shaped his style of winemaking. One night, I happened upon his Mt. Brave and La Jota Cabernets and decided that I needed to taste the rest of the portfolio. Luckily, each of the labels are all grouped under the Spire Collection brand and can be tasted together at their estate in Calistoga. I recommend you find bottles sooner rather than later as the prices seem to rise every year…</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/spire-collection/5.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bennett Lane Reserve Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/17/bennett_lane_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bennett Lane Reserve Tasting" /><published>2019-08-17T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-17T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/17/bennett_lane_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/17/bennett_lane_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;The more wineries I visit in Calistoga, the more convinced I become that it’s the hidden value area of Napa.  Bennett Lane was not on my radar before I began planning an itinerary for the weekend; I just happened to notice that it was directly next to where the Spire Collection holds its tastings.  It isn’t as ostentatious as other wineries, but it makes solid wines that balance the fruit development with the weight and acidity on the palate.  And if you are a patient buyer, you may find discounted bottles on distribution sites, such as Vivino, and use the opportunity to stock up!  Having tasted at the winery and enjoyed several bottlings through online purchases, I highly recommend you visit and taste for yourself!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/1-1050by788-f9a7d2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/1-700by525-f9a7d2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/1-675by506-f9a7d2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/1-450by338-f9a7d2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/1-525by394-f9a7d2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/1-350by263-f9a7d2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/1-350by263-f9a7d2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Winery Entrance&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Bennett Lane is a no-frills winery deep into the Calistoga AVA.  It is located right across the street from the building used to taste the Spire Collection wines under the Jackson family.  If you sign up to taste the latter, this is a perfect pitstop right before or after lunch in the area.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/2-1050by788-fb13e6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/2-700by525-fb13e6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/2-675by506-fb13e6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/2-450by338-fb13e6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/2-525by394-fb13e6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/2-350by263-fb13e6.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/2-350by263-fb13e6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The tasting area&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It is a shame that Bennett Lane is not well known.  It has a refined interior, but again, they don’t go over the top.  The wine is on point as well.  Because we had the winery to ourselves on a Sunday afternoon, we were lucky to taste through some of the Reserve bottlings that aren’t normally available.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bennett Lane Winery’s beginnings follow that of many others - the owner(s) were influenced by wine or a wine region at some point in their life and realized that living that dream is the next step after accomplishing what they set out to do in business.  It certainly is my dream.  From both the architecture and their blends (the Maximus brand), you can tell that Italy was the main influence and it translates well to this property.  The pictures above and below hopefully give you some insight on what to expect in the tasting room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/3-1050by788-f0a471.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/3-700by525-f0a471.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/3-675by506-f0a471.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/3-450by338-f0a471.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/3-525by394-f0a471.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/3-350by263-f0a471.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/3-350by263-f0a471.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The tasting bar&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The 180 degree view from the picture above.  I have no idea what my friend Simon is looking at.  I’ve squinted at this picture several times and don’t see a tasting sheet on the bar.  Do you?  Perhaps he is deep in thought, getting ready for the wines to come.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/4-1050by1400-1682b0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/4-700by933-1682b0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/4-675by900-1682b0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/4-450by600-1682b0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/4-525by700-1682b0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/4-350by467-1682b0.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/4-350by467-1682b0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Chardonnay was good&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A picture with their 2016 Reserve chardonnay from the Sangiacomo Vineyard over in Carneros.  I remember being pleasantly surprised by the balance of the wine.  It was neither too heavy, nor too light, and with the right amount of acid.  The flavors between the fruit and wood melded together nicely as well.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to the winery itself, the wine ambassador was courteous and direct about the tasting.  We chose the reserve tasting (and that lineup is reflected below), but one may also choose the traditional tasting to get a better sense of the Maximus wines.  At a previous tasting, I heard about the high quality and decent prices for their Cabernets, but I would also love to visit again to taste their blend of Sauvignon Blanc, Chardonnay and Muscat Canelli (Maximus White) and their Bordeaux blend of Cabernet Sauvignon and Franc, Merlot, Syrah, and Petit Verdot (Maxiumus Red).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/5-1050by788-1183d6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/5-700by525-1183d6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/5-675by506-1183d6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/5-450by338-1183d6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/5-525by394-1183d6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/5-350by263-1183d6.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/5-350by263-1183d6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Soil Samples...&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Yes, I nerded out a bit discussing the different plots that the grapes were farmed from.  These aren’t the most recognizable plots from the Napa Valley, which means that there may be an opportunity to find a bottle that hits above its price range.  I think the Lewelling vineyard was my favorite plot from the tasting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did not spend much time discussing the owners’ nor winemakers’ backgrounds, so I recommend visiting their website if you are interested in learning more, as that will equal the knowledge I have access to.  Instead, we talked much more about the wines and what makes them different than others in the valley.  A summary on each of the available wines can also be found on the winery’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bennettlane.com/napa-valley-calistoga-wines-online-wine-shoping&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Reserve Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($53)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Produced using sourced fruit from Carneros.  10% MLF allowed in order to round out the acid but keep the butter and cream notes as supporting character in the wine.  Fresh primary aromas of lemon and yellow apple.  The palate is medium body, medium(+) acid, and a touch of salinity that stimulates the palate before the crisp yellow apple, pear, vanilla, and hint of melon follows through.  Wine Advocate scored it 90pts (impressive for a white wine) and I’d agree.  The Chardonnay is for the crowd that doesn’t want the full, unctuous wines of Napa but rather a ripe representation of the varietal character.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2011 Cabernet Sauvignon Reserve&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($105)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This wine reminds me slightly of the Left-Bank as it has balanced deep red fruit, but also some green and tertiary notes on the nose.  You’ll want to decant this bottle for an hour or open-and-recork it and leave overnight.  The acid is more present than the tannin, which makes this very drinkable right now.  Medium(-) body with flavors that are a bit more earthy and feels like its at is optimum aging point.  Cherry, blackberry, cocoa and leather.  Again, it doesn’t feel underdeveloped, just very light for the Napa Valley (understandable considering the 2011 vintage).  Many places found it hard to produce wines in 2011 and this is pretty darn drinkable.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Cabernet Sauvignon Reserve&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($105)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Dark cherry, cassis, berries, mocha, cocoa, vanilla, and a caramel sensation on the nose.  Even with all of these aromas, the nose feels bright thanks to the acidity.  The palate is mellow and integrated but with lots of layers and decent complexity.  The 2012 has soft tannins, so it’s ready now, but they won’t hold on for too long - I recommend you finish the bottle the same day that you open it.  And I’m fine with that considering this lighter bodied, fruit-forward wine.  Just a darn good bottle of wine that is fairly rich but not too big.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Lynch Family Vineyard Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($125)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The gem of the lineup as it’s their only single vineyard Cabernet Sauvignon.  I know this sounds very strange, but there is a odd note on the nose that is reminiscent of Denorex Shampoo.  Almost like a herbal mint and caramel blended together.  Once you get past the semi-shock of the nose, the wine is very nice.  There is a cherry cola component that integrates well with the high acid/tannin and it has a medium(-) body that makes it dance across the palate.  Still, I’d describe this as an easy drinking wine (though a really nice one at that) which has a fair bit of complexity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($62)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;They were nice to let me try this wine outside of my tasting menu.  Cherry and cocoa on the nose with similar flavors on the palate.  Although it is less intense and concentrated than the Reserve, it isn’t short by much.  Although it’s a 2013, this is drinking very well right now and a good value buy (I purchased bottles of this to get my tasting free).  Soft and balanced, this wine is medium bodied, medium(+) tannin, and medium(+) acid that is integrated.  You could serve this wine no matter the food pairing at dinner.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Bennett Lane Winery isn’t my favorite winery for its wines, ambiance, nor presentation, it does a pretty solid job in all of the categories and should be a nice, quiet location to enjoy several glasses of wine.  The care and attention to detail are there without the price point nor the need to schedule a tasting in advance.  So meander on through the region and make this a pitstop to rehydrate!  Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="calistoga" /><summary type="html">The more wineries I visit in Calistoga, the more convinced I become that it’s the hidden value area of Napa. Bennett Lane was not on my radar before I began planning an itinerary for the weekend; I just happened to notice that it was directly next to where the Spire Collection holds its tastings. It isn’t as ostentatious as other wineries, but it makes solid wines that balance the fruit development with the weight and acidity on the palate. And if you are a patient buyer, you may find discounted bottles on distribution sites, such as Vivino, and use the opportunity to stock up! Having tasted at the winery and enjoyed several bottlings through online purchases, I highly recommend you visit and taste for yourself!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/bennett-lane/2.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hyde de Villaine Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/10/hyde_de_villaine_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hyde de Villaine Private Tasting" /><published>2019-08-10T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-10T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/10/hyde_de_villaine_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/10/hyde_de_villaine_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;What is in a name?  Well, for some it’s the most effective branding possible.  The name “Villaine” is enough to grab any wine collector’s attention.  Though, they normally associate it with a Burgundian winery that just happens to produce some of the most expensive wine on Earth (Aubert de Villaine of Domaine de la Romanee-Conti).  Though, that association is exactly what the owners don’t want, even though the winery is related to that Villaine!  The character of the terroir between the Cote de Nuit in Burgundy and Carneros in Napa are very different and you should expect very different wine because of that.  And while the wine isn’t as good as DRC, it also doesn’t cost $20K+ a bottle either.  I think what you do get with these wines is old world elegance, finesse, minerality, and a complexity that doesn’t over-index on the fruit character, thanks to the Burgundian traditions applied to Carneros fruit and terroir.  Do I recommend you visit?  You bet I do…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/1-1050by788-afcd6f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/1-700by525-afcd6f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/1-675by506-afcd6f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/1-450by338-afcd6f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/1-525by394-afcd6f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/1-350by263-afcd6f.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/1-350by263-afcd6f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Springtime&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A look at the vineyard before spring officially starts.  While it’s the mountains in the background that may grab your attention, just wait for these Chardonnay vines to bloom and grow their fruit.  These vines produce some of the best white wine in the Napa area today.  And don’t underestimate their red wines either…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The families of Villaine and Hyde each got their start in wine separately.  Larry Hyde has worked in the vineyards since the 70s and you can likely find multiple books on Aubert’s life story in Burgundy.  So what would bring two very different families together?  Love, of course!  Aubert married Larry’s cousin (Pamela Fairbanks) in 1970 and after 30 years of pursuing their own craft, Larry and Aubert decided to start a venture together in Carneros.  In 2002, they brought onboard their current winemaker (Stéphane Vivier) who studied at the the Université de Bourgogne.  And with a vision in mind, they built HdV!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/2-1050by788-000b44.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/2-700by525-000b44.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/2-675by506-000b44.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/2-450by338-000b44.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/2-525by394-000b44.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/2-350by263-000b44.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/2-350by263-000b44.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Not the Prettiest Building&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Never judge a book by its cover, especially in the wine world.  Similar to other great wineries like Kapcsandy, you won’t find a grand estate waiting for you at the property.  The facility is 100% tailored to making wine.  And when you are searching for the best wine, isn’t that what you want to see out of a winery?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HdV is primarily focused on Chardonnay which represents over 60% of their production.  Since the expertise of both Aubert and Stéphane lay in Burgundian wines, it makes sense that HdV is focused on the cooler Carneros, allowing them to produce higher acid wines that are similar to what is produced in Burgundy in contrast to the typical ripe Napa Chardonnay.  And because the Chardonnay is sourced from older-vine blocks at the Hyde Vineyard (30+ year old vines), each bottle contains character and concentration.  They produce a Merlot / Cabernet Sauvignon blend (Belle Cousine) and Syrah onsite as well.  It wasn’t until 2012 that they started making Pinot Noir here (remember, they don’t want that “diet-DRC” comparison), but the Burgundian winemaker wanted to make Pinot, so here we are!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/3-1050by788-ee6575.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/3-700by525-ee6575.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/3-675by506-ee6575.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/3-450by338-ee6575.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/3-525by394-ee6575.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/3-350by263-ee6575.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/3-350by263-ee6575.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;I Spy a Concrete Egg&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A look inside the facility.  Again, besides the office to the right of the concrete egg, everything in the place is for making wine.  It was hard to imagine how and where they move the tanks and barrels during harvest and crush.  Maybe some magical elves take care of everything?  That might explain why the Chardonnay is so delicious!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The funniest thing we talked about during the tasting was that Aubert didn’t take the idea of co-founding an American winery seriously until he participated in a blind tasting where one of the wines revealed was a Ramey Chardonnay that was made with fruit from the Hyde Vineyard.  After that tasting, he finally gave the co-venture some serious thought.  Since Aubert is half-the-world away running DRC, he doesn’t have much influence on the day-to-day.  He does make a couple trips to California each year where his biggest contribution is helping decide when to pick the grapes, since that is always the most important decision for a winery.  Where many wineries index on the brix (sugar) level of the grapes, HdV focuses on picking when the Total Acidity (TA) is just right.  And like Burgundy, there is no fining, filtration or additions to any of the wines, ever.  What the land offers is what they use in the winery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/4-1050by788-d6ca41.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/4-700by525-d6ca41.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/4-675by506-d6ca41.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/4-450by338-d6ca41.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/4-525by394-d6ca41.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/4-350by263-d6ca41.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/4-350by263-d6ca41.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Their Red Wines&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Most people are only familiar with the Chardonnay of HdV.  From the background of the co-owners, it is easy to see why.  But do not discount the red wines here.  The Syrahs were both very good and the Vine Cliff Cabernet was really special - it reminded me of the best French wines that have some Brett in their profile and are better / more complex wines for it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reservations are required for a tasting and just note that it’s pretty much a one man operation during most of the year - the one wine ambassador (Nate Olver) handles all of the phone calls, appointments, emails, etc.  This means that everything is done one customer at a time, including the tastings.  Though, they wouldn’t be able to fit more than one group of people in the office for a tasting anyways, haha.  NOTE: I don’t know if they normally pour this many wines for a tasting, so don’t overindex on the list below.  Though, if you show interest and appreciation for the wines, I wouldn’t be surprised if you had the opportunity to taste most of these wines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hdvwines.com/wines/detail?item=2016-le-debut&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Napa Valley Le Debut Carneros&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($50)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Even their young Chardonnay (Colera clone) has a rich minerality on the nose.  Limestone soil is very important for Burgundian Chardonnay, but there isn’t much of it in Napa (e.g. Mt. Harlan).  With the minerality, you also get very fresh ripe-but-light lemon and yellow apple.  The mouthfeel is the same way with really good harmony between the acid and ripeness thanks in part to the use of neutral oak.  No battonage in barrel and only one remuage.  For vines so young, they already display so much character in the wine…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hdvwines.com/wines/detail?item=15chy&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Napa Valley Chardonnay Carneros&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($70)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Their flagship wine as it represents 50% of their entire production.  The average vine age is around 30 years and they only use the Wente clone to enhance the minerality.  More butter on the profile, but still balanced with the acid and the fruit notes.  This wine is noticeably rounder and fuller bodied than the Le Debut.  I have no doubt this wine can age over a decade and can easily be paired with a meal.  I had to purchase a bottle to blind taste with the other greats of Napa.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2009 Napa Valley Chardonnay Hyde Vineyard&lt;/strong&gt; ($100)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It was fun to be able to taste their flagship 10 years into its life.  Still fresh on the nose with ripe lemon, butter, and a bit of nut, but not too oxidative.  It also sports a really nice golden color.  On the palate, the acid has settled down a bit, but the alcohol is 14.2% (it was a riper year), so there is some afterburn on the finish, making this an ideal fall/winter white wine.  There is still plenty of life in the bottle and could easily age another 5-10 years.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hdvwines.com/wines/detail?item=2016-hyde-pinot-noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Ygnacia Carneros Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($115)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fresh and fleshy red cranberry and strawberry that is not overly ripe/candied like many other Pinots from the valley.  20% new French Oak which gives it a hint of vanilla.  The balance between the tannin and body is nice with lift provided by the acidity.  This wine evokes a blend of Willamette and Burgundy Pinot, rather than RRV Pinot.  Easy drinking and complex thanks to the light earthiness in the wine.  I have no doubt that mushroom character will develop with age, making this really attractive.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hdvwines.com/wines/detail?item=11syrah&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2011 Californio Syrah Hyde Vineyard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($100)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A 12.5% ABV Syrah from the Napa Valley - I could hardly believe it…  Lots of fresh red fruit, some earthiness, and a hint of garrigue character on the nose.  The palate leans towards the garrigue character moreso than the red fruit (cranberry).  There is a balance between the complexity and integration of the wine, making it really appealing to wine nerds.  I must admit tasting this wine harkens me back to my travels in the Cote Rotie area.  I wouldn’t be surprised if the garrigue emphasis is due to the vintage conditions of 2011.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2007 Belle Cousine Hyde Vineyard&lt;/strong&gt; ($120)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;2007 was a great vintage for Napa and this blend of Merlot and Cabernet reflects that well.  Explosive nose of red fruit and tertiary character.  The acidity is still very bright, but the palate leans more towards the tertiary and is supported by the remaining red fruit.  I would not age this wine any longer - the balance is at its peak or slightly past it.  I really appreciate them opening this bottle for me though to show what I can expect when the wine is aging.  Sure to be a crowd-pleaser among the French lovers.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hdvwines.com/wines/detail?item=14syrah&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Californio Syrah Hyde Vineyard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What a difference three years and different vintage conditions can have.  Compared to the 2011, the 2014 has more white flowers, deeper red fruit and a perfume to the nose.  Those aromas carry straight through to the palate.  The structure of this wine is much bigger as well; the wine has smooth, ripe high tannin and medium(+) acid that are integrating nicely, but are still very noticeable.  It’ll take several years before the tertiary emerges to balance the fruit.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hdvwines.com/wines/detail?item=06827d8-14&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Belle Cousine Hyde Vineyard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Similarly, the 2014 Belle Cousine showed very differently compared to the 2007.  This wine is so pretty and feminine on the nose - ripe, developed red fruit that is very seductive and not candied.  The balance of tannin/acidity (more acid) leans to the French side and the tertiary notes are just getting started.  I think the optimal point for me will be after two more years, right before the tertiary notes stand out.  It’s really hard not to drink this wine right now though…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hdvwines.com/wines/detail?item=2014-vhr-vineyard-cabernet-sauvignon&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Cabernet Sauvignon Oakville Vine Hill Ranch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($195)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Only produced between 2013 and 2015 while they had access to the fruit.  100% Cabernet Sauvignon aged in 50% new oak.  This wine is just absolutely stunning.  The complexity is amazing for a wine this young.  The little bit of Brett and Pyrazines in the wine are masterfully done and well balanced with the fruit.  This is what good Brett in wine looks like; the French would be proud…  You can drink this right now and trick people into thinking that the wine is 10 years old.  Me, I would just sniff this wine for days…  It was $200 but I felt compelled to buy a bottle - that is how much this wine affected me.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for excellent Chardonnay and a French take on Napa fruit, you must visit HdV.  It’s rare to find a winery where every wine’s description contains the word “balance”, but that is what HdV offers those that visit.  If they serve you as many wines as they did me, the tasting fee will seem like a discounted amount.  HdV is also located very close to the town of Napa, so it is very easy to plan meals around the visit.  Just remember that this is not the place you want to take a group if you are looking for a winery tour or a place to relax outside for a couple hours.  Though the great thing about Napa is that there is a winery for every occasion, so just keep looking!  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="carneros" /><summary type="html">What is in a name? Well, for some it’s the most effective branding possible. The name “Villaine” is enough to grab any wine collector’s attention. Though, they normally associate it with a Burgundian winery that just happens to produce some of the most expensive wine on Earth (Aubert de Villaine of Domaine de la Romanee-Conti). Though, that association is exactly what the owners don’t want, even though the winery is related to that Villaine! The character of the terroir between the Cote de Nuit in Burgundy and Carneros in Napa are very different and you should expect very different wine because of that. And while the wine isn’t as good as DRC, it also doesn’t cost $20K+ a bottle either. I think what you do get with these wines is old world elegance, finesse, minerality, and a complexity that doesn’t over-index on the fruit character, thanks to the Burgundian traditions applied to Carneros fruit and terroir. Do I recommend you visit? You bet I do…</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/hyde-de-villaine/4.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Penfolds Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/03/penfolds_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Penfolds Private Tasting" /><published>2019-08-03T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-03T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/03/penfolds_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/03/penfolds_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s a shame that some of my favorite wine experiences are those that leave me unable to take quality tasting notes.  Traditionally, those are wine festivals and smaller walkaround tastings.  This is an example of the latter.  Most wineries offer member benefits to only their winery/brand/label.  But because Beringer and Penfolds are owned by the same parent (Treasury Wine Estates), Beringer Reserve Club members had a rare opportunity to explore the full portfolio of Penfolds at no cost.  While I can easily point to the Grange as the highlight of the evening, I thoroughly enjoyed tasting the other wines and even purchased some.  Bottom line with Penfolds is that they make really good value wines and their premium bottles are priced that way for a reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/1-1050by788-efc30a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/1-700by525-efc30a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/1-675by506-efc30a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/1-450by338-efc30a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/1-525by394-efc30a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/1-350by263-efc30a.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/1-350by263-efc30a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Tasting Area&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It is a good thing I arrived early, because the crowd came pouring in 20 minutes later.  It gave me enough time to enjoy the Bin wines and get multiple samples of their RWT and St. Henri luxury wines.  I loved the open floor setup and the casual atmosphere of the walk around tasting.  Again, only Reserve Club Members from Beringer were invited.  I even had wine ambassadors from other estates asking if I could bring them as a +1!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Penfolds is one of the larger Australian wine producers and has a large portfolio that spans the spectrum of quality and cost (that reads eerily similar to my description of Beringer - maybe Treasury Wine Estates just has a type they look for).  I’ve read the reviews on Grange before, but besides that wine, I didn’t know much of the Penfolds offering.  So when I received the invitation email as a Beringer member and realized I’d be in town that weekend, my heart skipped a bit.  As with most private events, I was afforded a +1, so I decided to take one of my co-workers with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/2-1050by788-f5007a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/2-700by525-f5007a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/2-675by506-f5007a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/2-450by338-f5007a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/2-525by394-f5007a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/2-350by263-f5007a.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/2-350by263-f5007a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Bins&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Although the Grange, RWT, and St. Henri got most of the attention, I was pleasantly surprised by the quality of the Bin 389 and Bin 407.  Like Darioush, I’d love to see more Cabernet and Shiraz blends as they balance and complement each other well, especially when the bottle is served at a young age when a varietal Cabernet may be inaccessible.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally, I love enjoying the culinary scene of Napa, but I made sure to eat a bland lunch before the tasting.  Trust me, the worst thing you can do is eat spicy food before drinking serious red wine.  I also made sure to wear a polo and khakis, but it turned out to be unnecessary.  Turns out people that like to spend money on wine don’t necessarily like to spend it on clothes, haha.  But seriously, the crowd in attendance were serious wine lovers and I was the youngest person there by 15+ years.  After checking in and starting with a really nice glass of Riesling, we were led inside to an open space with tables set up on the side that each had 3 bottles to taste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/3-1050by788-2f9419.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/3-700by525-2f9419.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/3-675by506-2f9419.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/3-450by338-2f9419.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/3-525by394-2f9419.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/3-350by263-2f9419.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/3-350by263-2f9419.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Fellow Tasters&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I met a fun couple during the tasting and got our picture taken together (my co-worker and friend Simon is on the opposite side).  We all retired to the Private Lounge for Beringer members to unwind from the Grange.  There, I discovered the 2015 Private Reserve was beautifully soft and ready for early drinking as well.  It was a very good day…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As expected, my favorite table was the one with the most expensive bottles of the day: The RWT and St. Henri.  Both go for $150 a bottle on Penfold’s website, which is pretty steep even by Napa standards, but they still need to be tasted.  Although the RWT scored better with critics for being full-bodied, rich, well-rounded and having strong black fruit, I preferred the St. Henri for having a bit of black olive tapenade integrated with the profile in an interesting and delicious way.  And full disclosure - I dislike black olives, so the fact it turned out great even in my opinion is pretty remarkable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/4-1050by788-a8ea06.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/4-700by525-a8ea06.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/4-675by506-a8ea06.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/4-450by338-a8ea06.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/4-525by394-a8ea06.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/4-350by263-a8ea06.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/4-350by263-a8ea06.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Waiting on the Grange&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Here, the Penfolds Brand Ambassador is explaining the history of Grange while simultaneously teasing us.  We did get to pick a glass afterward and have a taste.  That alone was enough to make the day-trip to Napa worth my while.  I especially love the face the lady in the background of the picture is making because I guarantee you I had the same look while taking the picture.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The $80 Bin 407 Cabernet Sauvignon and $100 Bin 389 Shiraz/Cabernet Sauvignon blend were also quite remarkable.  Certain wine regions of Australia boast climatic conditions similar to Napa and therefore produce excellent renditions of Cabernet Sauvignon.  While the varietal Cab sported impeccable structure, the blend had a bit of spice and a rounded mid-palate thanks to the Shiraz.  At these prices, it’s hard to say I strongly recommend them as the other two bottles mentioned earlier show much more at $50 more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/5-1050by788-70b763.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/5-700by525-70b763.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/5-675by506-70b763.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/5-450by338-70b763.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/5-525by394-70b763.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/5-350by263-70b763.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/penfolds/5-350by263-70b763.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Portfolio&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Since this was a walkaround tasting, it was impossible to take tasting notes on my laptop, nor was I able to use my phone.  Because of that, I decided to at least take a picture of their current portfolio in case any of the wines intrigue you enough to seek them out at their price points.  The best QPR wines might be the whites (Bin 51 Riesling and Bin 311 Chardonnay) at $40 a piece.  Both left quite an impression.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which brings us to the end of the tasting when the pièce de résistance was served: the Penfolds Grange.  I would absolutely put this wine on the level of First Growths in quality, balance, impact, and finish.  That is also likely why it has the price of a First Growth as well ($850 for the 2014 vintage on their website, though you can likely find it for closer to $550 if you look around).  I do think that this wine is one of the great expressions of Shiraz/Syrah in the world, alongside Sine Qua Non, the Guigal La-Las, and the greats of Hermitage.  Not many can afford a bottle of this wine, but if you can, you owe it to yourself to try it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, I hope to conduct a proper tasting of Penfolds wines at some point (hopefully during a trip to Australia)!!  But this initial look at the wines leaves me hopeful for the entire portfolio and has piqued my interest in Australian wines even more.  I’ll need to satisfy that urge soon, but will need to wait for a winter trip (to arrive in their summer).  But lesson learned - you never know what benefits you may stumble upon as a wine club member, haha.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="st-helena" /><summary type="html">It’s a shame that some of my favorite wine experiences are those that leave me unable to take quality tasting notes. Traditionally, those are wine festivals and smaller walkaround tastings. This is an example of the latter. Most wineries offer member benefits to only their winery/brand/label. But because Beringer and Penfolds are owned by the same parent (Treasury Wine Estates), Beringer Reserve Club members had a rare opportunity to explore the full portfolio of Penfolds at no cost. While I can easily point to the Grange as the highlight of the evening, I thoroughly enjoyed tasting the other wines and even purchased some. Bottom line with Penfolds is that they make really good value wines and their premium bottles are priced that way for a reason.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/penfolds/4.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Arcudi Wines Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/27/tony_arcudi_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Arcudi Wines Private Tasting" /><published>2019-07-27T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-27T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/27/tony_arcudi_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/27/tony_arcudi_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;This tasting wasn’t supposed to happen.  During a previous trip to Napa, my group and I happened to have the opportunity to try a bottle of Arcudi while at Fantesca because there wasn’t enough of their 2015 Spring Mountain Cabernet to serve for the tasting.  We found out Tony also produces Fantesca’s Pinot Noir and immediately signed up for his mailing list because both wines were delicious.  Soon after our first order, Tony reached out to personally thank us for the support and offered to host a visit whenever we were next in town.  I am sorry, but not sorry, to my friends because as soon as I found out he was recently hired as the consulting winemaker at Kapcsandy, I used any excuse to come to town and take him up on the offer, even if it was by myself…  Let’s just say, we need to make a second trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/1-1050by788-52a54a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/1-700by525-52a54a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/1-675by506-52a54a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/1-450by338-52a54a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/1-525by394-52a54a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/1-350by263-52a54a.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/1-350by263-52a54a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The House&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It is not uncommon for a winemaker to start a personal label while consulting for other wineries (see: Heidi Barrett, Thomas Rivers Brown, etc).  While others may be more established (e.g. larger/more diverse production, have deals to borrow tasting rooms), don’t expect Arcudi Wines to operate out of Tony’s house for long.  The wine is gorgeous and I have a feeling he’s going places…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But things did not start well.  Like a kid on Christmas Eve, I could not fall asleep in my Palo Alto hotel the night before.  I think I got 4 hours of sleep before picking up my rental car early at 7AM and arriving outside his house at 8:30AM.  And then I failed to nap for 90 minutes inside the car.  I’m surprised Tony let me in when I finally decided to knock on his door - I must have looked like a tired, wired, stressed, mess.  But let me in he did.  He sat me at his table, poured some wine, thanked me again for my patronage and then asked “What would you like to know?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/2-1050by1400-d4c34a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/2-700by933-d4c34a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/2-675by900-d4c34a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/2-450by600-d4c34a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/2-525by700-d4c34a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/2-350by467-d4c34a.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/2-350by467-d4c34a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Pour&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;During our talk, Tony was kind enough to offer me a pour of the newly minted 2015 Arcudi from the Black Sears Vineyard on Howell Mountain.  This wine was simultaneously monumental and elegant.  The quality of the grapes was striking, in addition to how  how well the wine was made.  I’d normally assume that 10+ years of aging is required to access this wine, but it was gorgeous and accessible at 4.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to deep dive on Tony’s life as I’m sure there are other resources that capture his history in more detail.  Actually, the real reason is because my attention was equally divided between the amazing wine in front of me and the amazing story I was listening to.  The wine was an absolute home run that lives up to and even surpasses its price tag.  You can read the tasting notes below, but just note that I met a wine ambassador from Black Sears Vineyard (where Tony gets the fruit for Arcudi wines) at the Howell Mountain Festival in Napa later that year and even he admitted that it was the best wine made from that vineyard.  That is really saying something…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/3-1050by788-e5dfbc.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/3-700by525-e5dfbc.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/3-675by506-e5dfbc.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/3-450by338-e5dfbc.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/3-525by394-e5dfbc.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/3-350by263-e5dfbc.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/3-350by263-e5dfbc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Talk&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Again, words cannot express how honored I was to sit down with Tony.  He opened his home to me at 10AM on a Saturday, poured a glass of $150 wine, and spent an hour discussing how he came to be a winemaker in Napa.  There are some parallels between us that made quite an impact on me.  I will get into the wine world one day…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I loved Tony’s story too.  He grew up in the Boston area (I went there for college); he enlisted in the Navy and became a missile navigation engineer (my father was an Army Ordnance Officer in Korea); he was a product manager in the tech sector (basically my current job); he loves Bruno Giacosa wines (also my favorite Italian wine); he worked at Maison M. Chapoutier (I loved visiting them in Hermitage); he works with Heidi Barrett (one of my all-time favorite winemakers); and he now consults at Kapcsandy (probably my favorite US winery).  I was speechless.  He did tell me of all the trials and tribulations it took to get to this point, but I wasn’t listening.  All that mattered at that moment was how can I get into this world?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/4-1050by1400-9da8c1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/4-700by933-9da8c1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/4-675by900-9da8c1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/4-450by600-9da8c1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/4-525by700-9da8c1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/4-350by467-9da8c1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/4-350by467-9da8c1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Store&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I’ve purchased a few bottles of his wines in the past, but after an experience like this, I couldn’t help but fill my wine suitcase with more.  I got a sneak peak at his personal tastes too (he is aging some great Italian wines).  There were quite a few bottles of King Richard’s Pinot Noir as well (the wine he makes for Fantesca).  I might put on a tasting of his wines one day since I have two complete verticals now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could not settle down at all through the tasting, which is why my tasting note on the wine seems less descript / more hand-wave-y than normal.  Maybe when I setup a vertical tasting of his wines, I’ll revist the tasting notes and fill in some vintages.  Til then, this will have to suffice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arcudiwines.com/wines/detail/?item=2016-cabernet-sauvignon-black-sears-vineyard&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Howell Mountain Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($150)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pretty purple flowers, cocoa, and crushed, candied black fruit on the nose.  Although the palate has high tannin, high acid, and high alcohol, the wine already feels rounded and approachable at its young age.  I cannot understate the amazing texture - it feels weighty and elegant simultaneously, similar to Kapcsandy Cabernets.  The flavors are not as opulent as Cabernets from the valley floor, but it still has intense richness that unfolds over time.  I know it can age for 20+ years, but it’s so attractive right now, not unlike Heidi Barrett wines.  Bravo!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gone are the days where a winemaker works at winery they don’t own for their entire career.  Similar to free agency in sports, it’s important to note who the winemaker is as well as the estate a wine comes from.  Because variations between vintages may not just be influenced by the weather, but the qualities of the winemaker and their “style”.  Judging by the wines I’ve had so far, I know Tony Arcudi is someone I want to follow from now on, no matter who he’s making wine for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get the chance to have one of his wines, cheers to you!  If you are lucky enough to meet the man in person, an extra cheers for you.  I hope to visit him again soon and try his new Pritchard Hill release!  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="howell-mountain" /><summary type="html">This tasting wasn’t supposed to happen. During a previous trip to Napa, my group and I happened to have the opportunity to try a bottle of Arcudi while at Fantesca because there wasn’t enough of their 2015 Spring Mountain Cabernet to serve for the tasting. We found out Tony also produces Fantesca’s Pinot Noir and immediately signed up for his mailing list because both wines were delicious. Soon after our first order, Tony reached out to personally thank us for the support and offered to host a visit whenever we were next in town. I am sorry, but not sorry, to my friends because as soon as I found out he was recently hired as the consulting winemaker at Kapcsandy, I used any excuse to come to town and take him up on the offer, even if it was by myself… Let’s just say, we need to make a second trip.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/tony-arcudi/3.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Clos du Mont-Olivet Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/20/clos_du_mont_olivet_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Clos du Mont-Olivet Public Tasting" /><published>2019-07-20T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-20T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/20/clos_du_mont_olivet_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/20/clos_du_mont_olivet_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve enjoyed several bottles of Clos du Mont Olivet in the past, so the trip to Châteauneuf wouldn’t have been complete without stopping by.  And without Google Maps, I never would have because this place is hard to find…  I don’t recall there being a clear sign outside directing visitors, but the door was branded in the same style as their wine labels, so I knew it was the right place when I knocked on the door.  Do not expect much in the way of aesthetics, but be prepared to taste solid wines that are steals at their price points.  And with a production of 50,000+ bottles a year, you should be able to find their wine back in the USA too.  So enjoy the irony between their office and quality/production while sipping on some serious wine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you drink Châteauneuf in the states and read publications like Jeb Dunnuck and his Rhone Report, you’ve likely heard of Clos du Mont Olivet before.  It isn’t in the same production category as Famille Perrin, but the quality and scores are right there.  I had one of their non-appellation wines at lunch in town on an earlier day which excited me even more (I remember it being surprisingly good for the price).  Similar to Pegau and other places in town, I was lucky that the advertising and storefront were subpar.  As you can see in the picture below, the room wouldn’t be able to accomodate more than one or two groups of visitors at a time and I wouldn’t have wanted to wait long for a tasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-du-mont-olivet/1-1050by788-3085be.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-du-mont-olivet/1-700by525-3085be.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-du-mont-olivet/1-675by506-3085be.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-du-mont-olivet/1-450by338-3085be.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-du-mont-olivet/1-525by394-3085be.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-du-mont-olivet/1-350by263-3085be.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-du-mont-olivet/1-350by263-3085be.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Tasting Room and Office&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;This is Clos du Mont Olivet!  I know, not much to look at - their office and tasting room are the same room after all.  Again, don’t let appearances deceive you.  Quality, price, and marketing are not always 100% correlated.  In this case, it works to the benefit of the consumer.  Out of the many wines I tried in Châteauneuf, I would pick their wine for my everyday table wine, considering the quality and price point.  And no matter your income level, everybody needs bottles like that…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my normal fashion, I introduced myself and gave glimpse of my background, especially why I was excited to be visiting with them.  They were going to start me directly on the Châteauneuf-du-Pape, but I asked to see their more affordable wines as well.  And it was a good thing I did.  The first two wines were quite surprising in quality for the prices.  I know I espoused the QPR of Domaine Durieu in an earlier post, but Clos du Mont Olivet may just be the steal of my Châteauneuf-du-Pape trip.  The style of the tasting was also very different - while the tasting at Domaine Durieu had 60s American rock music and energy, Clos du Mont Olivet played soothing string music and sounds, not unlike the music played during a massage.  As I was tasting by myself again, the music contributed to a relaxing experience that was interesting to reflect on.  Did the music make the wine more enjoyable?  Quite possibly.  If I run a winery one day, that might not be a bad idea for a private tasting room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like other great wineries, quality and care go into even their cheapest wines.  All of their non-appellation wines are grown and produced using similar methods as their highest rated wines.  For example, all of their vineyards are hand picked, pruned to low yields, sorted, etc.  One thing to note is that their white wine isn’t distributed yet to the USA as there is a name conflict with an American winery.  Once they change the name and I find out what it is, I will be sure to post it.  For now, it is referenced as “Vin de France Blanc” below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Vin de France Blanc&lt;/strong&gt; (9.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Ugni Blanc and Grenache Blanc from Lirac are blended together with second pressed juice from the Chateauneuf-du-Pape Blanc (Roussane, Bourboulanc and Clairette).  Very ripe and floral on the nose with notes of perfumed starfruit, ripe apricot, melon, and some MLF (butter/cream).  The wine has medium(+) acidity that balances the ripe fruit flavors, keeps the wine very fresh, light, and gives it a clean finish.  Though, that doesn’t impede the pronounced intensity on the palate one bit.  For the price point, this is an excellent wine, though I can see how it might be hard to drink more than two glasses in a sitting.  This wine will also be a bigger hit with California lovers than traditional French lovers.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.closmontolivet.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/20152.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 A Seraphin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (11.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Made from fruit grown 30 kilometers north of Châteauneuf-du-Pape.  Even though it doesn’t come from the AOC, that doesn’t mean the fruit quality poor in comparison.  A blend of 50% Grenache, 40% Syrah, and 10% old vine Carignan (45-60 years old).  Pronounced, ripe red fruit on the nose with a little bit of perfume and underlying spice.  The palate is not quite integrated yet - the light red fruit, spice and wood/earth character are all distinct.  The tannins are a bit rough at this stage of its life as well, so give it 2-3 years to integrate and soften.  I’m curious as to how the flavor profile will evolve during this time.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.closmontolivet.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/20163.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Châteauneuf-du-Pape&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (25.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A blend of 80% Grenache, 10% Syrah, 6% Mouvedre, and other varietals comprising the last 4%.  Served from a 375ml bottle as smaller bottles age faster and offer a look as to how the wines will develop.  Make no mistake, this cuvee is meant for aging and any attempts to enjoy it now will be like measuring the tip of an iceberg…  This wine is the face of their estate; 50,000 bottles are produced each year.  The red fruit is riper than their other wines with a slight candied quality.  The wine also displays undulating tertiary and spice notes in lower intensity.  The palate has medium(+) acid, high tannin, medium body, with flavors similar to the nose except the red fruit has a reduced intensity while the wood/earth come out more.  This wine is already pretty good but give this 4-5 years to start showing its true colors.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.closmontolivet.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/20162.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 La Cuvee du Papet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (45.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Only produced in the best vintages, this wine comes mostly from GSM vines that are all near ancient (80-100 years old).  The jamminess is accentuated on the nose of this wine and the complexity is higher than the Châteauneuf blend with better integration of flavors as well.  Medium(+) acid, high tannin, medium body, with flavors similar to the nose (the fruit is still jammy), but there is a spiciness that tickles the tongue at the end.  The tannins are smooth already and you could easily enjoy this now if you wanted to, though it will only get better.  I am confident that the fruit will hold strong in this wine through 10-15 years of aging.  I personally wouldn’t be able to hold onto the wine that long though, haha.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You never know where you will find great wines.  Luckily for me, I happened to know the quality and potential without having to rely on their branding or presence in town.  I highly recommend that you stop here for a tasting, if only to walk away with 10-25€ wines that you could happily enjoy over lunch or dinner.  If you want to find the Châteauneuf after tasting it for yourself, you shouldn’t have problems searching online, though as with all wines, there will be a markup from the shipping/distribution lifecycle.  So get out there and enjoy some great QPR wines.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="southern-rhone" /><category term="chateauneuf-du-pape" /><summary type="html">I’ve enjoyed several bottles of Clos du Mont Olivet in the past, so the trip to Châteauneuf wouldn’t have been complete without stopping by. And without Google Maps, I never would have because this place is hard to find… I don’t recall there being a clear sign outside directing visitors, but the door was branded in the same style as their wine labels, so I knew it was the right place when I knocked on the door. Do not expect much in the way of aesthetics, but be prepared to taste solid wines that are steals at their price points. And with a production of 50,000+ bottles a year, you should be able to find their wine back in the USA too. So enjoy the irony between their office and quality/production while sipping on some serious wine.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/clos-du-mont-olivet/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Domaine Durieu Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/13/domaine_durieu_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Domaine Durieu Public Tasting" /><published>2019-07-13T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-13T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/13/domaine_durieu_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/13/domaine_durieu_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;The tasting at Domaine Durieu provided a perfect foil to my tasting at Beaurenard in that it served as proof that the wine tasting experience can have as much impact on the customer as the quality of the wines themselves.  And nothing is more important to the wine tasting experience than the quality of the wine ambassador giving it.  It didn’t hurt either that he took me through their entire portfolio while rock music from the 60s set the mood in the background.  And at 20€ to 30€ a bottle, the wines were nice QPR darlings.  The 2012 Traditional CdP also provided a glimpse of what aging would do to these wines (spoiler alert: great times ahead).  Domaine Durieu is worth the stop while in town and may end up surprising you in a great way!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/1-1050by788-c67e12.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/1-700by525-c67e12.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/1-675by506-c67e12.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/1-450by338-c67e12.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/1-525by394-c67e12.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/1-350by263-c67e12.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/1-350by263-c67e12.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Storefront&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The entrance to Domaine Durieu’s tasting room in town and a very unflattering reflection of myself, haha.  It was amazing to me that Châteauneuf-du-Pape, the hub of amazing wines in the south-east of France, could have stores like this that were completely empty in the middle of the summer.  This area is under-appreciated as a wine tourism destination and one can only hope more people recognize that fact.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the majority of wineries in Châteauneuf, Domaine Durieu is family-owned and managed.  It was first started by the grandmother (Lucile Avril) and grandfather (Henri Duriel) several decades ago, but today boasts 40 hectares of land in Châteauneuf-du-Pape and 9 hectares in the greater Cotes du Pape.  Although they produced mostly strict AOC blends in the past, after the two brothers took over in 2004, Domaine Durieu began to produce other blends that are more accessible earlier in the life of the wine (ie. reduced harshness of tannins).  Even still, I’d like to give everyone of their wines a few more years in bottle…  And this is not to say they’ve completely overthrown tradition - they still produce a traditional blend each vintage for those that like to emphasize ageability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/2-1050by788-043cc9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/2-700by525-043cc9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/2-675by506-043cc9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/2-450by338-043cc9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/2-525by394-043cc9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/2-350by263-043cc9.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/2-350by263-043cc9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Tasting Room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Again, the wine tasting room wasn’t anything special.  I did like how the worn floor contrasted the clean walls and emaculate wine glasses.  You’ll notice that there were no spit buckets on the tasting table.  Instead, there were sinks built into the table where you could pour your wines out and it would drain into a container under the table.  But spitting was a dangerous game (#splashback).  I don’t know, I just really liked this space…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although their shop in town is quite small, the selection of wines is vast and goes back several vintages.  There is no need to make a reservation to stop by - just make sure that you go before lunch or wait until 2pm or so.  If you come with questions and curiosity, you will enjoy the tasting even more and the wine ambassador loves to talk and explain the wines.  Though if you are a white wine lover, this is not the place for you.  Like many wineries in the area, Domaine Durieu does not taste any of their white wines as they were either sold out or close to it.  Remember, 95% of the wines produced in Chateauneuf are red, so you really are in the wrong city in general for white wines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/3-1050by788-fcae24.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/3-700by525-fcae24.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/3-675by506-fcae24.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/3-450by338-fcae24.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/3-525by394-fcae24.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/3-350by263-fcae24.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/3-350by263-fcae24.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Wine Ambassador&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;My wine ambassador with his line-up of wines.  I appreciated that we tasted not only the current vintage, but also some past vintages to give the consumer an idea of how the wines will age.  I did pick up a bottle of the 2012 to bring back with me because it had already achieved a nice roundness to the wine with a fair amount of decanting.  It was unfair that all of the wines were so affordable - I had to think of excuses on the spot why I wasn’t buying one of each for my flight home…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some brief introductions, sharing our love of wine, American rock music, and a great discussion on science versus tradition in the “field” of wine, the wine ambassador poured me some wines and let me experience them at my own pace.  That may be what I loved most by this tasting.  Although I was the only patron in the shop, he could have rushed me through everything.  Instead, we enjoyed decent pours of each wine at a leisurely pace and he didn’t let me move on to the next wine until he was satisfied that I took away what I should from each of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.domainedurieu.fr/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/plandedieu.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Plan de Dieu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (9€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;70% Grenache, 10% each of Syrah, Cinsault, and Carignan.  Because of the Carignan, this cannot be classified as an AOC wine, hence the name.  There is a brooding, raisined fruit note blended with bright flowers on the nose with medium intensity.  Medium(+) acid, high tannin, medium body with a lighter intensity palate than the nose hints at.  Ripe, raisined red fruit, wood notes, light spice, and a hint of some unripened cranberry on the finish.  The wine is complex and interesting, though probably not for the easy drinking crowd.  At 9€ a bottle, that’s saying something…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.domainedurieu.fr/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/cdp.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Traditional Chateauneuf-du-Pape&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (19€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;80% Grenache, 10% Syrah, 5% Mouvedre, 3% Cinsault, and 2% Counoise.  Light red fruit and herbs on the nose.  It’s unfair to even attempt to drink this wine right now.  I wouldn’t even bother trying to decant it.  The screaming high, rough tannins make this wine hard to taste, not to mention hard to enjoy.  The red fruit seems to be big enough to stand up to the aging and hopefully evolves on the nose in the future.  The wine ambassador did warn me about this wine, but I wanted to taste it anyways because 2015 is such a heralded vintage…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.domainedurieu.fr/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/lucileavril.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Lucile Avril Chateauneuf-du-Pape&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (24€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;85% old vine Grenache, 10% old vine Mouvedre, and 5% Syrah.  We had an amazing discussion on how Duck Breast and Truffle Risotto would pair perfectly with this wine.  Not the usual conversation for a 24€ wine.  The red fruit is a bit sweeter than the traditional blend (candied cranberry) and the pepper is much more upfront.  Medium acid, high tannin, and medium bodied.  The palate still has the candied cranberry and while the tannin is high, it’s rounded enough to enjoy now.  Earth, spice and a very light wood undertone contribute to the wine feeling grounded.  I could easily drink more than a couple glasses of this wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.domainedurieu.fr/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/henridurieu.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Henri Durieu Plan de Dieu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (11€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;90% old vine Grenache and 5% each of Carignan and Mouvedre.  Even brighter red fruit than the last wine, but still a complex nose.  Feels lighter/brighter on the palate as well with high acid, high tannin but a medium(-) body.  It is harder to feel out more than red fruit of medium(-) intensity thanks to the tannin, medium(-) body, and the closed state of the wine.  As this wine ages (softens/integrates), I think you can expect this to become a complex wine that offers the red spectrum of flavors and maybe even dried fruits at a low intensity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Traditional Chateauneuf-du-Pape&lt;/strong&gt; (21€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Like the 2015, it feels like you can wait an additional 15 years on this wine if you wanted.  The red fruit is present, but there is an earthy perfume already present from aging (weirdly pleasant, almost like freshly shampoo-ed hair) with some spices.  Feels much better on the palate than the 2015 with a complex palate that is mostly tertiary driven, contrasting the nose.  There is enough fruit on the palate that you do not feel as if you are tasting earth and wood, but that is the dominant profile and it’s not unpleasant.  Definitely one of the more terroir-true wines I’ve had from Chateauneuf.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Lucile Avril Chateauneuf-du-Pape&lt;/strong&gt; (26€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This wine also has that weirdly pleasant “freshly shampoo-ed hair” aroma, but with a bit more bright cranberry behind it.  The tannins have softened to make this drinkable and the red fruit has begun to balance with the tertiary flavors as well.  I don’t know if this wine is lower intensity than the others or if the tertiary flavors just make the wine appear that way.  Still, another wine where you can easily drink multiple glasses.  Softest of the wines in the portfolio tasted thus far.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Tradition Chateauneuf-du-Pape&lt;/strong&gt; (30€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This wine was the star of the tasting.  Black plum, licorice, smoke, and black pepper on the nose in high intensity.  On the palate, this wine is incredible.  The secret to making the wine taste this great is opening the bottle and letting it sit overnight before drinking it.  That alone is enough to integrate the tannins even more and bring out the black plum flavor out to the extent that it is.  That flavor flows over the palate and there is a juiciness that supports and integrates with the tertiary flavors.  I had to get a bottle of this, even with my full suitcase.  It was that good and at only 30€…  I just hope I can replicate the process to make the wine open up.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see above, the wines in this lineup were very traditional and a little closed in the beginning.  If you purchase a Durieu wine, be prepared to wait on it until it is ready or to decant it like a Barolo.  But when it is ready, like the 2012 Traditional CdP, the result can be absolutely inspiring.  Even at a cost of 10-15€ a bottle, it may still be worth shipping a case back to the USA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you are in town and in the mood for more rustic Chateauneuf, make sure you stop by and ask them what the oldest vintage is that you are able to taste.  If you can go back further than the 2012, you know I’ll be jealous and asking your thoughts.  In the meantime, I’m going to let my bottle hit 10 years old and give it another go.  I just hope that I can find some more bottles in the US in the meantime…  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="southern-rhone" /><category term="chateauneuf-du-pape" /><summary type="html">The tasting at Domaine Durieu provided a perfect foil to my tasting at Beaurenard in that it served as proof that the wine tasting experience can have as much impact on the customer as the quality of the wines themselves. And nothing is more important to the wine tasting experience than the quality of the wine ambassador giving it. It didn’t hurt either that he took me through their entire portfolio while rock music from the 60s set the mood in the background. And at 20€ to 30€ a bottle, the wines were nice QPR darlings. The 2012 Traditional CdP also provided a glimpse of what aging would do to these wines (spoiler alert: great times ahead). Domaine Durieu is worth the stop while in town and may end up surprising you in a great way!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/domaine-durieu/3.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Domaine de Beaurenard Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/06/domaine_de_beaurenard_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Domaine de Beaurenard Public Tasting" /><published>2019-07-06T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-06T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/06/domaine_de_beaurenard_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/06/domaine_de_beaurenard_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Not every tasting experience is going to be amazing.  The positive way to look at it is that it helps to emphasize the other places that you did like…  All things considered, I think Domaine de Beaurenard was my least favorite tasting in Châteauneuf-du-Pape.  Granted, I did not make an appointment, but I was also the only visitor at the winery when I arrived.  There was a tasting tour group (one of those that you can purchase/schedule online that originates from Avignon) that came in 30 minutes after me, but even then the guide did most of the talking rather than the winery ambassador.  I learned more from him than I did from my tasting and the notes provided about the winery.  The wines were also a bit austere compared to others.  You win some, you lose some!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/1-1050by788-cbdf48.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/1-700by525-cbdf48.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/1-675by506-cbdf48.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/1-450by338-cbdf48.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/1-525by394-cbdf48.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/1-350by263-cbdf48.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/1-350by263-cbdf48.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Sign&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The sign and entrance to the winery.  I hope I caught the winery on an off day, but I honestly wouldn’t visit again to try and find out.  There are too many wineries in the area that blew me away to give other wineries a second shot.  This is very similar to how I feel about wineries in densely populated wine-producing regions in the USA.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Domaine de Beaurenard is right off one of the main streets that runs around Châteauneuf.  It runs south of the town and then east of it, up to Domaine Roger SABON and beyond.  It is also right next to the wine museum in town, so I would expect it to get decent foot and car traffic.  The wine museum was a bit underwhelming compared to those in other regions of France, so I would understand why people may not travel down this way much.  I had just finished reading up on some history of the area at the museum after lunch, so I was ready for more wine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/2-1050by788-a2f569.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/2-700by525-a2f569.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/2-675by506-a2f569.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/2-450by338-a2f569.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/2-525by394-a2f569.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/2-350by263-a2f569.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/2-350by263-a2f569.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Tasting Counter&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I don’t know if I was intimidating with my laptop and use of the spit bucket.  I like to think not.  The tasting counter at Beaurenard is rather small, but did not cause any sort of hindrance.  There is an open area to the right that is large enough to entertain groups.  It was funny how the tour guide went behind the counter grabbed bottles and just started pouring wine for his group, even though I know he didn’t work there, haha.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I visited and tasted through the wines, I was treated with a mild neglect, as each wine was poured without much explanation to the background of the wine, what the winery hoped to achieve with each one, and why each bottling was different/interesting.  I don’t think it was the language barrier either as I am pretty sure that the wine ambassador spoke English well.  I admit that if the wines were fantastic, then I would’ve been glad to be left to my own devices.  But while the blanc was entertaining, the other two reds felt too young, a bit austere, and not ready for tasting.  I understand the 2016 vintage was excellent and these two could be excellent in a few years, but I don’t think it was the best Châteauneuf-du-Pape has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Chateauneuf-du-Pape Blanc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (35€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Majority of Clairette and Rousanne but is blended with all 6 white varieties of the AOC.  On the nose, bright white peaches, white flowers, and some wood aromas as well.  The flavor profile on the palate emulated the aromas, except there was a zestiness present that seemed to come from the minerality.  Medium(+) acid with a shorter finish.  Nice to drink on a hot day, especially when paired with some food because of that zest, but seemed a little lacking on its own for the pricepoint.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Chateauneuf-du-Pape Rouge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (35€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;GSM majority blend with the rest of the 13 AOC-designate varieties appearing in lower quantities, similar to how Clos Des Papes includes the broad spectrum of varieties in their blends.  The grapes here come from clay/sand/stone terroirs that make biodynamic farming possible.  Give this wine at least 3 hours to breath or lay it down for 3-5 years.  Red fruit on the nose (cherry/strawberry) but medium intensity and medium brightness of fruit.  The palate has a lot of hard tannin making the flavors difficult to feel out, but the spice is more white and red than black pepper.  The high, rough tannin and lower intensity of flavors make this wine a little difficult to enjoy now, but it could definitely be interesting given that 3-5 years.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Chateauneuf-du-Pape Boisrenard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (55€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Low quantity production wine made from ancient vines over 100 years old.  The varietal composition is unknown because the vines were co-planted together in the vineyard in those days as a form a risk management to ensure there were at least some yields each year, no matter the conditions.  The nose is bigger, more complex and jammy than the CdP Rouge.  That impression carries over to the palate - more red fruit, but also more complexity from earth, old wood, thyme, and some light spice notes.  Like the first red, this wine needs time to round out and integrate more, but there is definitely potential, especially if you prefer lighter styled wines that reflect the terroir.  At this pricepoint, it was hard for me to take the leap of faith on a bottle without tasting older vintages so see how they’ve traditionally aged.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no doubt that the wines could become much more interesting and approachable in a few years, but it was a little difficult to enjoy them now.  If the wines sound interesting enough to try, please do!  If anyone has older vintages of this wine that have come around beautifully, I would love to know!  Tough in the meantime, I’ll likely stick to places closer aligned to my palate, preferences, and expectations of tasting hospitality.  Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="southern-rhone" /><category term="chateauneuf-du-pape" /><summary type="html">Not every tasting experience is going to be amazing. The positive way to look at it is that it helps to emphasize the other places that you did like… All things considered, I think Domaine de Beaurenard was my least favorite tasting in Châteauneuf-du-Pape. Granted, I did not make an appointment, but I was also the only visitor at the winery when I arrived. There was a tasting tour group (one of those that you can purchase/schedule online that originates from Avignon) that came in 30 minutes after me, but even then the guide did most of the talking rather than the winery ambassador. I learned more from him than I did from my tasting and the notes provided about the winery. The wines were also a bit austere compared to others. You win some, you lose some!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/beaurenard/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Domaine La Barroche Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/06/29/domaine_la_barroche_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Domaine La Barroche Private Tasting" /><published>2019-06-29T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-06-29T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/06/29/domaine_la_barroche_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/06/29/domaine_la_barroche_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;If there is one winery in Châteauneuf-du-Pape that reminds me of Napa Valley, it’s Domaine la Barroche.  And when I say “Napa Valley”, I don’t mean the large wineries that host hundreds of people for walk-in tastings each day.  I mean the top quality estates where you are the only people on the tour, everything about the winery is dedicated to making great wine, and the wine is fantastic…  In addition, the wine here is more fruit driven and pure than many other estates in the area, so it will greatly please the Napa lovers out there.  If Clos Des Papes was my favorite tasting experience, this may have been my favorite overall experience.  Do NOT miss Domaine la Barroche during your exploration of the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/1-1050by788-99cfb0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/1-700by525-99cfb0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/1-675by506-99cfb0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/1-450by338-99cfb0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/1-525by394-99cfb0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/1-350by263-99cfb0.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/1-350by263-99cfb0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The entrance to the winery&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The gate to the new wine facility for Domaine La Barroche.  After operating in their existing facility for decades, the owner decided to invest in a new winery to continue his crusade of making quality wines.  Their older winery continues to operate, but produces less volume than it used to as much of the harvest is brought here now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the early 1700s, the Barrot family have owned the land that the Domaine is built upon in Châteauneuf.  Passed down through the generations, it wasn’t until the late 19th century that plots would be chosen to plant vines.  The motto of the family has always been that of winegrowers - that wines are made in the vineyard, not in the winery.  Finally in 2015, they decided to invest in that part of the process too and opened a new state-of-the-art production facility.  Though, I admit, “state-of-the-art” is the lazy way to describe this winery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/2-1050by788-b0906b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/2-700by525-b0906b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/2-675by506-b0906b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/2-450by338-b0906b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/2-525by394-b0906b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/2-350by263-b0906b.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/2-350by263-b0906b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;A better view of the building&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A better view of the new facility.  You can tell how new it is by how clean the building and sign look.  This made it easy to spot the winery off the street.  It’s a reservation-only winery, so be sure to make one!  And I must say - I am so impressed by that rock wall.  I can only imagine how long it took to build, but it looks gorgeous walking by it…  Clean and rustic - a fair assessment of their wine as well.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the outside, it looks clean cut and simple except for the beautifully assembled stone walls on opposite sides of the main gate.  The inside reminds me of the best wineries that integrate class and function - everything has a purpose, is 100% geared toward making wine, but organized in such a way that it looks like art.  For example, they use gravity flow for moving the grapes, must and eventually wine to their destinations.  Each level has its own feel - the top floor is steel and white, with the next level a darker tan with barrels lined against the walls.  But each step is seamlessly connected to ensure a smooth production process.  This is the type of winery that everyone wants to copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/3-1050by788-f50c4f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/3-700by525-f50c4f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/3-675by506-f50c4f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/3-450by338-f50c4f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/3-525by394-f50c4f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/3-350by263-f50c4f.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/3-350by263-f50c4f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Where we had the tasting&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;We conducted the tasting 1-on-1 in the cellar of their winery.  That table you see is not a table - it’s actually an authentic well that’s been there since before they built the new winery.  It was a little cool down here, but the experience was fantastic and it was fun walking through, seeing the bottles for sale and this year’s harvest in barrels.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their oldest vintage in the new facility is 2016, so all vintages before that are from the other facility.  I personally thought it was fun to compare and contrast the 2015 and 2016.  Both vintages are rated highly with the 2016 scoring slightly better, but I was convinced that the 2016 had a bit more precision to it (or maybe I talked myself into it?).  The price point on their wines is very reasonable; even their best wine (Pure) is under 80 Euros.  Though, make sure you purchase the wines at the winery as the markup is considerable back in the states where high scores and ratings drive up the price of the Pure to ~$150.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/4-1050by788-890b2a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/4-700by525-890b2a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/4-675by506-890b2a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/4-450by338-890b2a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/4-525by394-890b2a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/4-350by263-890b2a.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/4-350by263-890b2a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The vats!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A picture of the wine ambassador with a bottle of Pure while in front of their giant concrete foudres.  I cannot overstate how gorgeous and pristine it was inside the winery.  It would appeal to anyone’s wine and/or architectural sense.  It was also surreal to be at the winery by ourselves.  They opened up just for me - they had no other visitors that day.  Knowing how much Pure goes for in the states, I was foolish not to fill my suitcase with it on the spot…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with other winery tours, we spent time talking about the vines (they have some ancient vine Grenache on the property), their wine production process with the gravity flow, and the style of wines the proprietors hope to achieve.  After walking around their cellar and admiring the collection of Pure on the shelves, we opened a few bottles to taste.  You can find their wine catalog &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.domainelabarroche.com/our-wines/?lang=en&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.domainelabarroche.com/libertyEN.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Vin de France Liberty&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (19€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A blend of Grenache, Syrah, Mouvedre (GSM) with Cinsault and Carignan.  On the nose, violets and a combination of deep red and black fruit.  Because the grapes come from just outside Châteauneuf-du-Pape and the wine has some Carignan, it cannot be an AOC designate wine.  The palate has intensity and is mainly fruit driven and bright, making it drinkable without any aging required to enjoy it.  This wine is for those that like their Châteauneuf a little juicy with slightly less black pepper.  It still has some tertiary flavors towards the finish that will come out more with time, but why wait?  Very nice for the price point…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Chateauneuf-du-Pape Signature – Julien Barrot&lt;/strong&gt; (35€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Poured from a 375ml bottle.  GSM blend with some Cinsault.  Bright and fresh on the nose with seemingly equal amounts of red/blue/black fruit, though not much tertiary influence.  The palate is medium(+) acid, high ripe tannin, medium body, with flavors of fresh black fruit (blackberry.  Although the tannins are ripe, they still need just a year or two more to smooth out even more.  On the finish, the depth of the fruit becomes more apparent, but it’s too easy to fall in love with the freshness on the nose/palate.  Very clean for a Châteauneuf and an upgrade over the Liberty in its balance, depth, and aging potential.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.domainelabarroche.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/SIGNATURE_UK.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Chateauneuf-du-Pape Signature&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (35€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Jammy and cooked fruit flavors on the nose with black pepper being a significant part of the profile.  Medium acid, high tannin, and medium body with flavors of raisined red fruit, kirsch, black pepper, and some black fruit.  The tannins dry out your mouth on the finish, but I’d still consider it having bright red fruit at the end.  This one will definitely require more aging or decanting than the 2016 and is definitely more for those that like a little more “brooding” in their wine.  The 2016 is just so bright and balanced by comparison.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.domainelabarroche.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/FIANCEE_UK.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Fiancee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (55€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Blend of 40% old vine Grenache and 60% young Syrah.  The nose is very pretty thanks to the Syrah - bright red fruit that’s less ripe than cherry but also a bit candied.  Medium acid, high tannin, medium body, with flavors of young, fresh riper-than-cranberry red fruit and some spice.  The tannins are grippy in this young wine and will obviously round out with age.  I’d love to see this wine in 3-5 years when the tannins mellow into the body.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.domainelabarroche.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/PURE_UK.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Pure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (78€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;100% ancient vine (100+ years old) Grenache that comes from a fine-grained sand plot in the northeast of the appellation, right next to Chateau Rayas (cult-status Châteauneuf).  Aged in Foudre, which prevents oxidation of the Grenache while minimize oak flavors.  Great depth on the nose with red (kirsch) and black fruit coming out and light baking spice tickling the nose at the end.  Medium+ acid and tannin with a medium body.  The flavors are ripe, nearly reaching raisined character, and span the breadth of the red/black spectrum with not too much tertiary character yet.  The tannins are very fine but present which makes the wine appear very elegant at a young age.  It’s inspiring how much character is in this single varietal wine.  Bravo!  Best drinking window is 7-9 years according to the wine ambassador running the tasting.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was disappointed that I didn’t get to taste the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.domainelabarroche.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/PURE_blancUK.pdf&quot;&gt;2016 Pure Blanc&lt;/a&gt; because it sold out upon release,  But it is 55€, an 800 bottle production, and scored very well - I think I saw it being resold in the states for $150 as well.  This wine emulates the Pure Rouge in that it is a 100% varietal wine (Clairette) and evidently displays similar complex character.  I was encouraged to track down a bottle to try it, so track it down I will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must say I was extremely impressed how approachable their wines were at such a young age.  The fineness of the tannins were immediately noticeable and are likely a result of their precises winemaking practices.  I purchased a half-case of their Signature Chateauneuf-du-Pape and a few bottles of the Pure Rouge when I returned the states and am very happy with that decision.  If you’d like to track down bottles for yourself, you can try contacting their distributor in the states (David Bowler Wine - bowlerwine.com).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t wait to share these wines with friends in a blind tasting and hope that you get an opportunity to enjoy them too.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="southern-rhone" /><category term="chateauneuf-du-pape" /><summary type="html">If there is one winery in Châteauneuf-du-Pape that reminds me of Napa Valley, it’s Domaine la Barroche. And when I say “Napa Valley”, I don’t mean the large wineries that host hundreds of people for walk-in tastings each day. I mean the top quality estates where you are the only people on the tour, everything about the winery is dedicated to making great wine, and the wine is fantastic… In addition, the wine here is more fruit driven and pure than many other estates in the area, so it will greatly please the Napa lovers out there. If Clos Des Papes was my favorite tasting experience, this may have been my favorite overall experience. Do NOT miss Domaine la Barroche during your exploration of the area.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/domaine-la-barroche/1.jpg" /></entry></feed>