<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-02-17T17:29:41+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Wines By Jeremy</title><subtitle>Wines by Jeremy offers an educative and enjoyable personalized wine experience. Located in the DC metro area, Wines by Jeremy provides a number of services including in-home exclusive tastings, highly curated event tastings, educational events, and wine cellar consulting.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Domaine Albert Seltz Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/16/albert_seltz_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Domaine Albert Seltz Private Tasting" /><published>2019-02-16T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-16T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/16/albert_seltz_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/16/albert_seltz_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;The first stop on my Alsace + Rhone wine vacation.  Straight off the train from Strasbourg, I walked half a mile with all of my luggage to get here.  The backwoods path was beautiful but carrying three bags will put a damper on enjoying that.  Even though I was traveling in the fall and the temperature was relatively cool, the intensity of the sun was fairly strong as the vineyards of Alsace are generally planted on southern facing slopes next to the Vosges Mountain range to absorb as much of the light as possible, leading to ripe fruit development but keeping their acid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/1-1050by788-fbc2f4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/1-700by525-fbc2f4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/1-675by506-fbc2f4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/1-450by338-fbc2f4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/1-525by394-fbc2f4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/1-350by263-fbc2f4.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/1-350by263-fbc2f4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Walking to the Winery&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I decided to make my way through Alsace without renting a car.  Which meant that I had to walk over a mile from the train station with all of my luggage to the winery.  And then I had to walk another mile to my hotel.  Still, the views while walking were like this the whole time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/2-1050by788-6a955a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/2-700by525-6a955a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/2-675by506-6a955a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/2-450by338-6a955a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/2-525by394-6a955a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/2-350by263-6a955a.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/2-350by263-6a955a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Welcome to Mittelbergheim&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I was so happy to finally see this sign.  I didn’t realize that Mittelbergheim had so many wineries within the town.  I wish I knew so I could’ve spent more time exploring…  It’s definitely on my list of things to do if/when I return to Alsace!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking through the town of Mittelbergheim, I saw that there were at least 8 other wineries within walking distance to Albert Seltz.  I did not get the chance to check if they were open / spoke English / were available for tastings, so Albert Seltz ended up being my only stop in Mittelbergheim.  Though after discovering there were that many places in the area, I am emboldened to make a return visit and stay in town for an evening or two.  Though, it will be difficult to live up to Albert Seltz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/3-1050by788-ca2bb2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/3-700by525-ca2bb2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/3-675by506-ca2bb2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/3-450by338-ca2bb2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/3-525by394-ca2bb2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/3-350by263-ca2bb2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/3-350by263-ca2bb2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Written in Stone&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;On the one hand, I wish the sign was easier to see/read.  On the other hand, having a stone sign without any paint is a really classy move.  The cracks showing the age is also pretty cool.  I was really excited to get to tasting…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website has a quote from the owner: “The Sylvaner is a pretty girl from a poor family that does not interest the boy full of money is the disease of the 21st century.”  I totally understand where he is coming from - sometimes selling wine is a popularity contest where name recognition is everything for a consumer and can transitively affect the choices of the Producer.  Chardonnay, Sauvignon Blanc, Riesling… people are more likely to purchase something they have at least some tangential familiarity with.  It’s a good thing I went outside my own comfort zone as I’ve had some unimpressive Sylvaner before, but these wines totally changed my opinion about the varietal.  It made such an impression that I bought a few bottles with hopes of sharing with friends and spreading Albert’s message just a little further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heading into the winery, I was sad to find that there was (literally) no one home upon my arrival.  After waiting 30 minutes in the shade with their dog, a woman returning from the field was startled to discover me standing there - I had not called ahead for an appointment.  After collecting herself and learning I was an American on an Alsacian Wine Crusade, she guided me inside for a tasting.  Their tasting room doubled as their office, which had several desks and a small 4-stool tasting bar where we broke out some of the wines in their inventory.  NOTE: This was a family-run winery and didn’t have the infrastructure of a larger establishment.  It soon didn’t matter to me as the wines were very good and all I could think about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/4-1050by788-8db837.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/4-700by525-8db837.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/4-675by506-8db837.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/4-450by338-8db837.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/4-525by394-8db837.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/4-350by263-8db837.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/4-350by263-8db837.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Quenching the Thirst&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I don’t know if there is a better view.  To be alone in a winery with the undivided attention of the wine ambassador, drinking some amazing white wines and discussing the individuality of the winery and its wines.  The QPR on the wines are sooo good…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the tasting, we focused on their speciality: Sylvaner.  I think they are the only winery in the region that grows Grand Cru Sylvaner (I am likely mistaken there since there are so many producers), but it sure tasted like their specialty.  There was no formal menu, so your menu is likely to be different when you visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albert-seltz.fr/fiche.php?id=32&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Sylvaner de Mittelbergheim&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (9.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Has a lemon/lime and mineral profile, but with strong intensity and some white spice as well.  The aromas are a touch riper than the palate, but this makes a great summertime wine.  No green or vegetal notes, this wine finishes very fresh with that spice.  I know the notes read like a Sancerre and is similar except for the acidity (lower) and the minerality (it isn’t flint-like).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Sylvaner Zotzenberg Grand Cru Sono Contento&lt;/strong&gt; (16.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;There is definitely some petrol on the nose and less spice character than the first wine above, but there is definitely more complexity with the undertones and less reliance on the fruit character.  All of the notes are very subtle, even though the wine ambassador served this wine at the same temperature as a red wine.  Still great acidity and a little more body than the previous wine - I would love to retaste this without the aerobic exercise beforehand.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albert-seltz.fr/fiche.php?id=31&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Sylvaner Grand Cru Zotzenberg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (30.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Like the Zotzenberg except much more fruit/floral fragrance on the nose (e.g. in the honey/honeysuckle range).  This was just an all-around fantastic wine.  Really ripe stonefruit character (peach, honeysuckle) on the palate with great acidity that isn’t too soft/strong and provides structure.  The finish also goes on…  As someone who doesn’t like sweet wine but likes fruit (my American palate) and balance, I am really in love with this wine and would buy more immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Riesling Rebbuehl granite d’Andlau&lt;/strong&gt; (16.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Strong varietal character as I definitely get the petrol and rubber on the nose with the light yellow fruit and strong acidity.  This was served a little warmer than I am used to for Rieslings, but I think that also made the wine open more quickly.  This is a classic example of terroir-driven wine from Alsace - really like the minerality as well.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albert-seltz.fr/fiche.php?id=24&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Riesling Grand Cru Zotzenberg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (16.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;More fruit on the nose than the last Riesling - it’s almost a bit juicier and riper on the nose than the Sylvaner Grand Cru as well.  The palate is not as ripe as the nose, but there is still plenty of fruit and the finish is quite distinctive.  I wouldn’t say it’s flint but there is something terroir/mineral-related happening at the end.  That added complexity really stimulates the mind in a good way…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albert-seltz.fr/fiche.php?id=29&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2007 Sylvaner Veilles Vignes Colline aux Poiriers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (25.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Honey, ripe honeysuckle, beeswax, honeycomb, orange marmalade.  Not overly heavy on the finish like I was expecting; there is much more acidity to keep the balance intact.  That balance with the sweetness is really something something to dwell on as I’ve had many others that go over the top with the sweetness.  This wine may still be a little much for friends that don’t appreciate sweet wine, but I would not classify this as strictly a dessert wine.  I could easily pair this in a meal.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albert-seltz.fr/fiche.php?id=14&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Pinot Gris Grand Cru Zotzenberg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (16.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is not quite as ripe with honey/honeysuckle nor aromatically intense as some of the other wines, but it is definitely the smoothest out of all of them.  The finish just goes on…  You don’t really feel the acidity either, but that is perfectly fine since the wine is not cloying at all.  This is the kind of wine you could drink multiple bottles of in one sitting and not tire of its intensity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albert-seltz.fr/fiche.php?id=10&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Gewurztraminer Mon Ruisseau de Zanzibar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (25.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Very different from other Gewurztraminers in Alsace.  Not too much marmalade, nor too heavy.  The nose is a little less intense than the normal varietal character, but in a pleasurable way.  There is even a tickle of lemon zest too!  The body and finish have a flint-like character to them and do not finish over the top - the fruit is bright and finishes wonderfully with pineapple and stonefruit.  This is also an easy drinking without the feel of a sugar spike that can be utilized in many ways.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/5-1050by1400-b55b4e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/5-700by933-b55b4e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/5-675by900-b55b4e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/5-450by600-b55b4e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/5-525by700-b55b4e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/5-350by467-b55b4e.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/5-350by467-b55b4e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Sweet and Satisfying&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;There were a couple of wines that really struck me and both were of the same varietal that I haven’t liked in the past - Sylvaner.  This Grand Cru is the perfect balance of distinctive terroir, varietal and easy drinking.  I need a case of this.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/6-1050by1400-812bae.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/6-700by933-812bae.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/6-675by900-812bae.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/6-450by600-812bae.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/6-525by700-812bae.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/6-350by467-812bae.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/6-350by467-812bae.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;So good...&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The other wine that really struck me.  Old vines, older wine, and sweeter than the above Grand Cru, this wine is for the special occasion at the end of the night.  I really need to find their distributor!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a shame that I could not taste these great wines with the owner.  Other online reviews tell of an intimate experience, including touring their cellars and getting more into the philosophy of winemaking.  I am not the biodynamic purist that the owner is, but I would’ve really been interested in getting his thoughts on the matter, especially since all of these wines were done very well…  Normally I like to let the wines do the talking, but in this case, I would’ve liked the extra background and how we can achieve the same quality with these methods in the states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/7-1050by788-9c85b5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/7-700by525-9c85b5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/7-675by506-9c85b5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/7-450by338-9c85b5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/7-525by394-9c85b5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/7-350by263-9c85b5.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/7-350by263-9c85b5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Mandatory Selfie&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Obligatory selfie with the vines behind the winery.  It was pretty cool outside, but the sun was also pretty strong.  It’s probably how they have ripe wines with great acidity.  Seems like a great place to live and make wines.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself in Strasbourg and want to make a day trip for wine by train, you could do worse than Albert Seltz and Mittelbergheim in general.  Just be sure to make reservations by email before showing up so that you get the full experience with the winery owner and check whether they speak English for the tour or not.  I definitely recommend that you make your way into Alsace wine country and enjoy some really good white varietals, but especially Sylvaner since you can’t find it in the states!  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="alsace" /><category term="mittelbergheim" /><summary type="html">The first stop on my Alsace + Rhone wine vacation. Straight off the train from Strasbourg, I walked half a mile with all of my luggage to get here. The backwoods path was beautiful but carrying three bags will put a damper on enjoying that. Even though I was traveling in the fall and the temperature was relatively cool, the intensity of the sun was fairly strong as the vineyards of Alsace are generally planted on southern facing slopes next to the Vosges Mountain range to absorb as much of the light as possible, leading to ripe fruit development but keeping their acid.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/albert-seltz/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Paradigm Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/09/paradigm_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Paradigm Private Tasting" /><published>2019-02-09T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-09T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/09/paradigm_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/09/paradigm_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;I know many of you have never heard of Paradigm before, nor seen any of their bottles or signage in Napa.  But what if I said that Paradigm was the first winery that Heidi Barrett ever worked at and even after her long and illustrious career, she is still their winemaker?  If you follow winemakers like me, I hope that grabbed your attention.  If you need more background, read my article on La Sirena (Heidi’s personal label).  To sum up Paradigm, it is a small Oakville-based operation that owns 55 acres of vines and makes very compelling wines by allowing the varietals to express their quality and terroir influences with minimal winemaker intervention, which is only possible when you have great land, vines, and someone who is confident in what they are doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paradigm got started around the time Heidi was in school.  Her father Richard Peterson was (and still is) a famous winemaker specializing in Pinot Noir who worked with several wineries and did consultation work for others.  At the time, Ren (the owner) and Gene (his business partner) ran a lucrative vineyard real estate business together.  After enough time, they both decided to start their own wineries.  Ren called up Richard Peterson and asked for help getting the winery going.  Everything from building the business plan, to pitching financial institutions for the loans he needed, to designing the vineyard and equipping the facility, to being his winemaking consultant.  When you visit Paradigm, you’ll see that the building and winemaking facility are small and non-descript in comparison to others in the area.  They may be small but are very efficiently structured (everything is tight and compact) and isn’t lacking in any equipment.  As the other wineries grew and expanded around them, Paradigm has stayed relatively the same, which includes its small quantity, great quality, and very affordable prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/1-1050by788-4845aa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/1-700by525-4845aa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/1-675by506-4845aa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/1-450by338-4845aa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/1-525by394-4845aa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/1-350by263-4845aa.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/1-350by263-4845aa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The entrance to the winery&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I told you that the winery was non-descript on the outside.  Yes, this is the entrance as seen from the parking lot.  But don’t let this exterior fool you.  The wine quality will pleasantly surprise you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After helping out with the design and getting the winery close to the finish line, it was Richard’s turn to ask a favor.  At about this time, Heidi was just graduating school and needed a job in the winemaking world.  Getting your first gig is always the hardest, but Richard vouched for her skills and asked that she be given a shot as a favor to him.  After the first couple vintages, Ren realized that he actually owed Richard another favor because the wines Heidi was making were more than he could have hoped for.  Soon after, Ren got a call from his old partner Gene, asking if he knew of anyone that could help her with a stuck fermentation (it’s when the yeast doesn’t convert all the grape sugar into alcohol, leaving you with a 11% sweet red wine that you can’t sell).  Naturally, he talked about his rockstar winemaker and so Heidi went and got her first consulting gig fixing the fermentation.  Afterwards, Gene was so impressed that she hired Heidi to be their first full-time winemaker too.  Did I mention that Gene’s winery was called Screaming Eagle (now the most expensive wine made in America)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ren paid off the final loans of the winery 10+ years ago and how the tax laws work in Napa is that you are taxed each year based on how much you paid for the land/winery at the time of purchase.  Since Ren purchased the land back when there were only 30 wineries in Napa and land prices were dirt cheap compared to today, their taxes are very low by comparison to others, meaning they can pass the savings along to the consumer.  And that’s a pro-tip for visiting Napa - the next time you go, try to visit a winery that has been around for a long time and hasn’t changed hands.  They will nearly always be cheaper than everyone else; not because they wines aren’t as good, but because the cost to produce them is lower (and therefore they need to charge less to keep operations going).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/2-1050by788-a61dd0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/2-700by525-a61dd0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/2-675by506-a61dd0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/2-450by338-a61dd0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/2-525by394-a61dd0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/2-350by263-a61dd0.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/2-350by263-a61dd0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Getting lost in the vines&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;We had a chance to walk through the vineyard and see what is responsible for the great wine.  Since it was the brother-in-law on duty that day, we got to hear some great stories about the early history of the winery that I shared earlier in the article.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Heidi left the industry for a spell for family (raising her young daughters), it was Paradigm that was the first to offer her a job again to get back into the swing of things.  There is loyalty and a sense of family here which matches the size of the winery and the staffing (only the brother of the owner was working the Sunday afternoon I visited).  The tastings are one group at a time and you can’t hear anything except for the Napa Wine train that pass by every so often.  They have some equipment from UC Davis interleaved in the winery too (e.g. measuring aspiration to figure out how often to put out sulfur for protection in the vineyards).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After walking through the vineyards, we settled out on a picnic table outside and dug into the wines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Rose of Merlot&lt;/strong&gt; ($29)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Produced via the vin gris method – you press off the rosé once it has the right amount of color that they want, so it has more tannin, fruit and body.  This is different from the free run method of pulling off the wine from the bottom of the tank after crush.  Cold fermentation that lasts for 6 weeks until it reaches bone dry.  Beautiful salmon pink color with a medium+ intensity nose of strawberry and cranberry with a tickle of alcohol.  The palate is high intensity with medium+ acid and medium alcohol, but very little tannic influence.  There are no underripe notes at all.  A very smooth rosé with a little more body and the right amount of acid that can make a red wine lover happy.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.paradigmwinery.com/product/2014-Merlot&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Oakville Merlot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($53)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Rich red fruit on the nose with some spices and very little alcohol.  The same red fruit on the palate that still has medium+ acidity, the smallest green character, lots of plum, medium tannin that could soften a bit more with time, and alcohol/spice you can feel a bit.  It is a strange sensation drinking this wine - the more I sample, the more I want to drink it.  The acidity has a most peculiar mouth-watering effect (it almost feels like a craving) that is very pleasant.  Still, silky mouthfeel with some oak notes and a finish that goes on for quite a while.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.paradigmwinery.com/product/2014-Paravines&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Paravines&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($73)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;80% Merlot, 20% Petit Verdot.  Right off the bat, you can feel the deep juicy/jammy red fruit on the nose.  I don’t get any caramel on the nose like the tasting notes indicate, but that intertwined spruce/cedar is definitely present.  There is more tannin than the Merlot thanks to the Petit Verdot, but a similar level of acidity, though not quite the same sensation as the Merlot.  Really enjoyable red wine that has solid intensity of flavors and body all the way through the palate.  Some spices and tertiary characteristics make this a thinking wine instead of just bright fruit with acid and tannins.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.paradigmwinery.com/product/2014-Cabernet-Sauvignon&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($84)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Contrasting the Paravines, the Cabernet Sauvignon is much brighter on the nose, with predominantly red and black fruit.  There is some alcohol/spice sensation, but it complements the fruit well to create a warming effect.  The palate is medium bodied with medium tannin that feels very smooth but does dry the mouth slightly.  The acidity isn’t as present as the Merlot or Paravines, which makes this an easy drinking, really enjoyable Cabernet.  The intensity nor flavors aren’t anything unusual that will strike you as unique – it’s just very cohesive, well-balanced, and has no negatives to complain about.  At $84, this is a steal compared to a lot of other wines grown on the valley floor.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.paradigmwinery.com/product/2015-Cabernet-Franc&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Cabernet Franc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($71)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Only available to wine club members.  The color on this wine is incredibly deep and the nose is so fragrant with cool red cherry and raspberry that has slight candied notes.  The body is juicy with a medium body, medium tannin and medium acid with good length at the end.  If you like more fruit driven wines, this will blow you away, especially if you like the varietal character of Cabernet Franc.  Cabernet Francs are getting more popular in Napa, but this is definitely on the upper-end of quality for the Napa Valley region.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.paradigmwinery.com/product/2011-Cabernet-Sauvignon&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2011 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($113)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Paradigm did not pick early when the rains came during harvest time in 2011.  Instead they blow-dried the vines and let the last bit of sun get captured by the vines.  This resulted in a deeper richness in the 2011 that isn’t there on the 2014.  That additional hangtime also resulted in more black fruit than red fruit.  The wine definitely warms you up more than the 2014 too, though the higher alcohol is very subtle.  2011 wines gets a bad rap in the valley but those who didn’t panic and picked to early were rewarded for their patience and additional effort.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, the quality-price ratio (QPR) on these wines is very good and I highly recommend you visit.  After all, it’s in Oakville, which is one of the most expensive AVAs, and you can see Harlan just up the hill from your picnic table tasting (Harlan’s Cabernet goes for ~$800).  You can taste the quality of the terroir in these wines.  They have other wines that are not on the tasting menu as well - the Cabernet Franc isn’t normally available for tasting and I hear the Zinfandel is among the best in the entire valley!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tasting fee is among the cheapest in the valley too, so if you’ve read my other reviews and wish you had the capital to try them out, you can start by going here.  Though, once you taste the wines here, it may be very hard to go back to drinking other wines, haha.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="oakville" /><summary type="html">I know many of you have never heard of Paradigm before, nor seen any of their bottles or signage in Napa. But what if I said that Paradigm was the first winery that Heidi Barrett ever worked at and even after her long and illustrious career, she is still their winemaker? If you follow winemakers like me, I hope that grabbed your attention. If you need more background, read my article on La Sirena (Heidi’s personal label). To sum up Paradigm, it is a small Oakville-based operation that owns 55 acres of vines and makes very compelling wines by allowing the varietals to express their quality and terroir influences with minimal winemaker intervention, which is only possible when you have great land, vines, and someone who is confident in what they are doing.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/paradigm/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Inglenook Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/02/inglenook_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Inglenook Public Tasting" /><published>2019-02-02T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-02T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/02/inglenook_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/02/inglenook_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve had (the very affordable) Francis Coppola wines before and was skeptical of Inglenook even before reading the reviews by the major wine publications.  But I think you can officially change my status from skeptic to believer, because everything about this winery is impressive.  For example, when you make your way to the winery, Google Maps bring you to a small building that turns out to be the check-in desk where they confirm your reservation, give you a ticket to scan at the estate gate, and send you on your way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/1-1050by788-b4d3c5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/1-700by525-b4d3c5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/1-675by506-b4d3c5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/1-450by338-b4d3c5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/1-525by394-b4d3c5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/1-350by263-b4d3c5.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/1-350by263-b4d3c5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Where are you taking me?&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;For a while there, it seemed like the road would go on forever.  That’s definitely one way to heighten the expectations of visitors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The driveway is quite long and leads you to a large parking lot that is next to the largest campus I have seen in the Napa Valley so far.  What’s more, it contrasts wineries like Hall in that everything about the campus looks and feels historic.  The backstory of this land seems surreal when you hear about it, but once you explore and read the signs that are everywhere, you really start to understand that this land is special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/2-1050by788-8d83dd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/2-700by525-8d83dd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/2-675by506-8d83dd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/2-450by338-8d83dd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/2-525by394-8d83dd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/2-350by263-8d83dd.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/2-350by263-8d83dd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;So bright outside...&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;After parking in the large lot they have, you’ll walk past a large veranda on the way to the main winery building.  I know why that veranda exists now - it gets really bright outside and makes selfies tough.  And yes, those are grapevines over my shoulder.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/3-1050by788-0f73d2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/3-700by525-0f73d2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/3-675by506-0f73d2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/3-450by338-0f73d2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/3-525by394-0f73d2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/3-350by263-0f73d2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/3-350by263-0f73d2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Too much shade...&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I feel like Goldilocks; this angle has too much shade.  That shade is caused by the massive winery building, while behind me is the large open area that is perfect for mini-picnincs and enjoying bottles outside.  The resolution on my camera phone may be bad, but the view is really nice.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inglenook, or more accurately the winery that existed before it was purchased and named Inglenook, was founded by a Finnish animal fur trader in the 1850s, who had been responsibe for a vast amount of charting along the west coast.  He was a wine conneiseur, his wife a San Francisco socialite.  It’s no surprise that they compromised and moved from fur trading to operating a winery in Napa.  And it certainly wasn’t about the money - he wanted to show the world that he could make wines that could rival the world’s best in France.  This, a 100+ years before the Judgement of Paris.  Just hearing about the passion and history is enough to get you excited about the wines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Francis Coppola purchased the land, Robert Mondavi immediately called him to setup a dinner.  At this dinner, Mondavi proceeded to explain the history and potential to Francis, practically charging Coppola that he had the moral responsibility to restore Inglenook to its former glory.  After digging some 50+ year old wines out of the Inglenook cellar and tasting them with Mondavi, Coppola was convinced and so the dream was born.  And if that isn’t enough to get you excited, the current consulting winemaker (Philippe Bascaules) happens to be the President of Chateau Margaux, who now flies back to California every few months to make sure that Inglenook is producing amazing wines, as nature intended.  Coppola is also Italian – that’s why there is a Zindandel (known in Italy as Primitivo) here.  If you want French styled wine that just has great balance and takes avantage of Napa’s strengths, you need to try these wines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inglenook.com/Purchase/Details/BL16&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Blancaneaux&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($65)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A northern Rhone blend of Viognier, Marsanne, and Roussanne.  The fruit comes from Pritchet Hill (knob / giant hill), which is not to be confused with Pritchard Hill.  Pritchet Hill is the shadiest place in the Napa Valley (I know how that sounds), which is important for these varietals to shine.  There is almost no color at all to the wine and the nose is very light, reminiscent of French wine.  The palate has screaming high minerality, which makes the perception of the acidity maybe higher than it actually is.  There’s also decent fruit and a nice clean finish of yellow fruit (apple) and some stonefruit.  A really nice alternative to the Chardonnay/Sauvignon Blanc typically grown in the Napa Valley.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inglenook.com/Purchase/Details/RC15&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 RC Reserve Syrah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($62)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The RC stands for Roman Coppola, who is the eldest son and created this wine to be a cigar wine.  But obviously Syrah goes well with BBQ and other meats.  Deep red fruit and black pepper on the nose without any alcoholic heat.  The tannin makes the finish seem a little short initially, but on exhale, you still feel the wine.  Good medium+ body with some juicy flavor character.  The wood notes (e.g. cedar) are strong and integrated into the fruit as well.  This wine is very true to what Syrah is (without the wild game notes of the Northern Rhone) and doesn’t try to be overripe/candied to appease American palates.  50/50 aged in French and American oak.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inglenook.com/Purchase/Details/EP09&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2008 Magnum Edizione Pennino&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55 for a 750ml)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;100% Zinfandel and what a wine this is.  There is some much going on here - Fruitcake, forest floor and cedar are what I could pick out on the nose.  The palate is also wonderful with high intensity all the way through the palate and a good medium+ body every step of the way.  Very well balanced with really good integration of each component.  My advanced sommelier running the tasting said that their 2010 Zinfandel was the best Zinfandel ever made on the planet.  Judging by how good their 2008 is, I do not doubt it.  This may be one of the best Zins I have ever had (at least at the same level as Ridge/Turley).  The alcohol does not rear its head and the wine isn’t too candied.  A really amazing effort.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inglenook.com/Purchase/Details/CK15&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($78)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Rutherford (88% Cabernet), 100% French Oak.  The nose has a lot of rich medium bright red fruit with some dust, not unlike a lot of other Rutherford Cabs.  Ends cleanly with a shorter finish than others, but has that mouthwatering tingling acidity that begs you to drink more.  Definitely less fruit on the midpalate than others; it emphasizes a balance of the terroir character rather than dominating fruit, but it’s still really smooth and enjoyable.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inglenook.com/Purchase/Details/EP15&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Edizione Pennino&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($48)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Remove most of the teritary character from the 2008 Pennino described earlier and you get this wine.  Understandably, the fruit and acid are also sharper as the wine has not yet rounded into form, but you can already taste the potential.  I don’t really have much to say after the 2008 other than I’ll try checking in on this wine again in 10 years.  I still can’t believe I am talking about intentionally aging a Zinfandel…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inglenook.com/Purchase/Details/RB14&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Rubicon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($210)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wow, this really does remind me of a First Growth Bordeaux in so many ways.  The lower alcohol, the significant amount of tertiary notes on the mid-to-late palate and the nose that just hints at it.  This wine will probably peak in 20-30 years according to the Advanced Somm, though it can be aged well into its 40s.  It’s hard for me to see that though as it’s just so smooth right now and very approachable while showing off all the characteristics that you might expect from an aged wine.  Insider Tip for the wine collectors out there - the best vintages to look for (in order of greatness) 78, 79, 91, 95, 96, 01, 03, 04.  The Rubicon has a higher price point than many other wineries’ flagship wine, but I think it deserves it due to its complexity.  Though, the wine becomes more affordable with a Winery Membership (20% off!)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/4-1050by1400-dfa73f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/4-700by933-dfa73f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/4-675by900-dfa73f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/4-450by600-dfa73f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/4-525by700-dfa73f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/4-350by467-dfa73f.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/4-350by467-dfa73f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;There was none left for me...&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I feel like I needed to include a picture of this bottle in the post.  If you are wondering why, I’d recommend doing some research on the older Niebaum-Coppola wines that were released.  Then, you will understand…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After tasting the wines and regaining my bearings, I also started to notice details of the amazing building I was sitting in.  The building’s exterior sets your expectations high and the inside does not disappoint.  Before or after the tasting, you can navigate the cellars of the building and take a look at more history.  The tasting room itself feels 200+ years old and is staffed by professional Sommeliers who are dressed as if they were working in a three-star Michelin restaurant.  Their demeanor aside, you can tell that each one doesn’t just consider Inglenook a job - they sincerely believe that each wine is world-class and represents the best its varietal has to offer (e.g. Zinfandel, Cabernet, and the Northern Rhone white blend).  After all, one of the benefits of working at the winery is tasting the wines!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/5-1050by788-e29298.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/5-700by525-e29298.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/5-675by506-e29298.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/5-450by338-e29298.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/5-525by394-e29298.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/5-350by263-e29298.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/5-350by263-e29298.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;So many barrels&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view down the hallway inside their winery building.  As you can see from the walls in the picture, this building has been around for a very long time.  It’s impressive how aligned the doorways were as technology was very different back in the day.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/6-1050by788-fc549f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/6-700by525-fc549f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/6-675by506-fc549f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/6-450by338-fc549f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/6-525by394-fc549f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/6-350by263-fc549f.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/6-350by263-fc549f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;For the bigshots&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;If you are a real big shot, maybe you get to hold your tasting in one of these private rooms off the main hallway.  What interests me even more is do you get to try the bottles that are aging in there?  I wasn’t able to go inside to see, but I can guess they are not recent vintages.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a fantastic location to bring friends and possibly enjoy a picnic outside on the lawn with a bottle or two of their wines.  Though, I think it was nearly as fulfilling to go alone and really take the time to enjoy each one of these unique wines.  Each had a different expression than most Napa wines I’ve had of the same varietal and the value is solid, especially if you become a member and save 20% on each of the wines that you purchase!  The wines also all had an old world vibe to them, without any flaws from being underripe.  If a friend visitng Napa were to ask me for European-styled wines that weren’t all Cabernets, this is where I would send them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will absolutely be visiting again and hopefully will find a way to pick up and lay down a bottle of Rubicon for a future First Growth blind tasting or for a celebration.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="rutherford" /><summary type="html">I’ve had (the very affordable) Francis Coppola wines before and was skeptical of Inglenook even before reading the reviews by the major wine publications. But I think you can officially change my status from skeptic to believer, because everything about this winery is impressive. For example, when you make your way to the winery, Google Maps bring you to a small building that turns out to be the check-in desk where they confirm your reservation, give you a ticket to scan at the estate gate, and send you on your way.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/inglenook/4.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Corison Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/01/26/corison_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Corison Private Tasting" /><published>2019-01-26T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-26T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/01/26/corison_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/01/26/corison_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;One of the very first female winemakers and at 5’1”, Cathy was laughed off by her female professors when she said she wanted to make wine.  But thanks to fortunate circumstances, she got her start at Freemark Abbey, transitioned to working at Chappellet after a while and eventually worked with the vines that became Lokoya on Spring Mountain.  After she accumulated enough experience and capital, she found some great land that spoke to her in St. Helena and the rest is history.  She produces a Gewurztraminer and three different Cabernets at Corison, whose fruit comes from the valley floor and are all dry farmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/1-1050by788-0995c1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/1-700by525-0995c1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/1-675by506-0995c1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/1-450by338-0995c1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/1-525by394-0995c1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/1-350by263-0995c1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/1-350by263-0995c1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Where are my sunglasses?&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Getting ready for my first tasting of the day!  I must have been facing east for the picture because I look like I needed some sunglasses.  The half-asian definitely comes out in this picture…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/2-1050by788-6168ea.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/2-700by525-6168ea.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/2-675by506-6168ea.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/2-450by338-6168ea.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/2-525by394-6168ea.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/2-350by263-6168ea.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/2-350by263-6168ea.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;So much wine...&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view from the entrance to the Corison Winery.  I dare only imagine how many bottles of excellent wine those barrels will turn into&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kronos is her old vine Cabernet that grows on unique loam that is basically gravel after a 1-2 foot layer of clay.  The Napa Valley and Sunbasket wines are old cabernets (planted in the 90s) that don’t quite meet the unofficial “old vine” definition, but are also high quality.  In addition to the dry farming and earlier harvest date, the spacing between the vines is huge because they were planted back in the day when machinery was bulkier and require more spacing between vines.  All of these circumstances combine to produce wines that are very complex, concentrated, intense, elegant, higher in acidity, and consistently have an ABV below 14%, which is almost blasphemy for Napa Cabernet.  No need to worry as there is no residual sugar in the wines.  Cathy also makes sure to soften the tannins so consumers can drink the wines earlier in their life too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/3-1050by788-0fd629.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/3-700by525-0fd629.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/3-675by506-0fd629.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/3-450by338-0fd629.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/3-525by394-0fd629.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/3-350by263-0fd629.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/3-350by263-0fd629.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Paradise&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view of the vineyards from the winery.  Although not the glamourous view of some wineries, those old vine cabernet vines are a beautiful thing to a wine lover.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/4-1050by788-0a9429.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/4-700by525-0a9429.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/4-675by506-0a9429.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/4-450by338-0a9429.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/4-525by394-0a9429.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/4-350by263-0a9429.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/4-350by263-0a9429.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Old Vines&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A look into the Chronos Vineyard.  You can see that the Cabernets are all old vines and the rootstock is extremely knarled.  They also utilize dry farming and wide spacing for their vines which increases the quality even further.  The only negative is the small quantity of grapes those vines produce.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visiting the winery is very personal.  There are no more than 2-3 groups of visitors permitted on the grounds at any time.  When you arrive, you are greeted with the Gewurztraminer, then brought through the barrel storage room and out the back into the vineyard where the wine ambassadors talk about Cathy’s background, her winemaking style and the vineyards.  Once you are finished asking questions, you are brought back into the barrel storage area to your table where you are presented with the wines you will be tasting.  I was lucky and happened to be visiting on a Library Tasting day, meaning that instead of tasting the current release of Kronos, I was able to taste a library vintage (2008 in this case).  The full wine lineup looked like the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.corison.com/store/index.cfm?fuseaction=productdetail&amp;amp;product_id=299&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Corazon Gewurztraminer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($35)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A ripe Gewurztraminer that has all the characteristics you want and also medium acidity, which doesn’t let the wine fall off a cliff or finish flat like many other Gewurztraminers do.  It also avoids that slightly off-putting finish, which basically means that this is a Gewurz with all the things people love about the varietal but with none of its negatives.  That sounds like a winner to me, especially at the price point…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.corison.com/store/index.cfm?fuseaction=productdetail&amp;amp;product_id=248&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Napa Valley Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($95)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bright but with aromas of black/blue fruit, some cocoa, and good minerality that tingles the nose, but still takes a back seat to the juicy fruit.  No hints of alcohol heat on the nose, which is her style.  Medium+ body that gives the wine texture instead of a juicy body.  And the palate has all of the notes described for the nose, but in a subtle fashion.  This withheld intensity differentiates this from other wineries.  The tannins are very subtle again with a tingling medium+ acidity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.corison.com/store/index.cfm?fuseaction=productdetail&amp;amp;product_id=247&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Sunbasket Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($175)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The name of this wine is an homage to Andre Tchelistcheff, the “maestro” who made Beaulieu and the Georges de Latour Private Reserve into household names and who mentored many of Napa’s early winemakers.  Cathy purchased the 9.5 acre parcel this wine is made from and named it “Sunbasket” after how Andre would refer to the plot.  Compared to the Napa Valley Cabernet, this wine has a nose that seems to be a mix of red/blue fruit and is just as fresh with no alcohol heat and the right intensity of fragrance on the nose.  The palate has a bit more acidity and minerality with some light notes of terroir also entering the picture.  The body has just as much texture as the Napa Valley and also a weightlessness that is so intriguing.  The finish goes on for quite a while as well.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.corison.com/store/index.cfm?fuseaction=productdetail&amp;amp;product_id=104&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2008 Kronos Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($260)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose resembles the Sunbasket, but with a little more depth, black fruit, and integration.  The wine is also less bright with lower levels of blue fruit and cocoa.  The palate reminds me of a great Bordeaux – present red/black fruit, tertiary characteristics with some salinity and less spice, but with a finish just goes on forever at a solid intensity.  The lingering feeling of the acidity and integrated alcohol feels amazing too…  At 10 years old, it trades the bright nose for a great mouthfeel and more intense/present flavors on the palate that continues to last.  Similar, but slightly different than other Bordeaux-like reds from the valley, such as the Inglenook Rubicon.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/5-1050by788-55966e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/5-700by525-55966e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/5-675by506-55966e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/5-450by338-55966e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/5-525by394-55966e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/5-350by263-55966e.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/5-350by263-55966e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Tasting is hard&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Evaluating these wines was so fun and difficult at the same time.  A part of me just wanted to enjoy them with friends, but the other part wanted to give the respect these wines deserved.  And boy did they deserve it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a little tired of the intensity and huge fruit of many Napa wineries, you owe it to yourself to give Corison a try.  It is definitely smaller than many other wineries off the main highway and does not have the lavish look or branding of others, but there is some much energy and care put into these wines.  It would be so easy to let these wines be 15% ABV, black fruit, heavy wood spice powerhouses; it takes much more effort, finesse, and expertise to craft wines that are so complex and enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I did not purchase wines on my first visit, I definitely plan on acquiring some in the future to serve as a contrast to other Napa Cabernets at future tastings.  Their library vintages are also available for purchase by non-members which is a pleasant surprise and will definitely have me considering paying $25-$50 more to try the wines after they’ve undergone sufficient aging.  In a way, you need to taste these wines to believe it.  So the next time you are driving up Highway 29 into Napa, consider giving Corison a try.  I guarantee it will be worth your while and may start you along the path to trying Bordeaux Super-Second Growth wines.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="st-helena" /><summary type="html">One of the very first female winemakers and at 5’1”, Cathy was laughed off by her female professors when she said she wanted to make wine. But thanks to fortunate circumstances, she got her start at Freemark Abbey, transitioned to working at Chappellet after a while and eventually worked with the vines that became Lokoya on Spring Mountain. After she accumulated enough experience and capital, she found some great land that spoke to her in St. Helena and the rest is history. She produces a Gewurztraminer and three different Cabernets at Corison, whose fruit comes from the valley floor and are all dry farmed.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/corison/4.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Chappellet Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/01/19/chappellet_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chappellet Private Tasting" /><published>2019-01-19T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-19T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/01/19/chappellet_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/01/19/chappellet_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;One of the first ten wineries established in the Napa Valley, Chappellet has a long and storied history - from Wine Spectator mentioning one of its wines in the top ten of the past &lt;strong&gt;century&lt;/strong&gt;, to naming and copyrighting the location that people think of when they hear Bryant Family, Colgin, etc. (Chappellet copyrighted “Pritchard Hill”), to producing a consistent 97+ pt wine in the Wine Advocate (their Pritchard Hill Cabernet Sauvignon).  Chappellet has a fantastic reputation and for good reason - the quality of their wine is very good.  I just had to visit Chappellet on my most recent trip, though the reasonable tasting fee also helped.  Note that like many other owners in Napa, the proprietar of Chappellet made his money before coming out to Napa and buying land.  In his case, he invented the first coffee vending machines, where you would pay to get a cup of coffee automatically dispensed for you.  No disrespect to coffee lovers, but I am glad he transitioned to wine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/1-1050by788-9d7e78.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/1-700by525-9d7e78.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/1-675by506-9d7e78.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/1-450by338-9d7e78.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/1-525by394-9d7e78.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/1-350by263-9d7e78.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/1-350by263-9d7e78.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Like the pyramids of old&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Inside the Chappellet winery.  It’s too bad that we couldn’t explore it any further.  Maybe next time…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our visit to Chappellet was a little more epic than normal because of a sulphur leakage inside the winery.  Scary, I know, but it was easy to smell that something was wrong in the storage/tasting area.  Instead of cancelling reservation for the day, the owners approved us to have our wine tasting at a great alternative location - their private outdoor tent in the vineyard.  For those that don’t know, many wineries have a special area that is designated for use only by the winery owners, where they can host close friends, VIPs, and others in a more secluded, relaxed setting that is even more beautiful than inside the winery.  Very rarely do common visitors like us get a chance to enjoy their private oasis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/2-1050by788-f6e3bc.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/2-700by525-f6e3bc.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/2-675by506-f6e3bc.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/2-450by338-f6e3bc.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/2-525by394-f6e3bc.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/2-350by263-f6e3bc.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/2-350by263-f6e3bc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;What a power couple&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Getting ready to hop in the Swiss Pinzgauer and head up into the vineyards.  Don’t drink and drive but it’s ok to drink and ride in a winery.  Also, don’t these two make quite the power couple?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/3-1050by788-4902ca.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/3-700by525-4902ca.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/3-675by506-4902ca.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/3-450by338-4902ca.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/3-525by394-4902ca.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/3-350by263-4902ca.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/3-350by263-4902ca.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;First-class seat&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view out of the back of the Swiss Pinzgauer heading up to the owner’s tent.  It was quite the view the whole way up, but the kicked-up dust was a bit much at times.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They didn’t tell us that we were heading to the owner’s tent though - we were told it was a surprise where we were heading.  We were lead to what looked like a miniature version of a military transport truck.  After we all managed to climb in the back, we took off into the winery.  Although it did get dusty (and some people forgot to protect their glass of Chardonnay), we finally made it to the owner’s private tent in the back-left portion of the winery.  We dusted ourselves off, took many pictures of the tent and the surrounding area, then proceeded to sit at the table and enjoy the wines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/4-1050by788-71a69c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/4-700by525-71a69c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/4-675by506-71a69c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/4-450by338-71a69c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/4-525by394-71a69c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/4-350by263-71a69c.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/4-350by263-71a69c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Owner's Box&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Heading into the owner’s tent for the tasting.  I must say - I really hope to befriend some winery owners at some point in my life, haha.  Now that I’ve been to one, I really want to spend the day or have a dinner at another!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chappellet.com/product/2014-Signature-Chardonnay&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Signature Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($45)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The grapes are from family growers in the cooler Carneros, as the winemaker wanted Chablis level acidity for use in a new world style wine.  The fruit is nicely developed past the lemon/lime fruit development into the yellow apple / apricot stage.  The minerality and sweeter spice are deeper in the wine and take some time to dig out.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chappellet.com/product/2014-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Dutton Ranch Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Great fruit development on the nose with bright floral notes and tons of spice.  A Cabernet lover’s style of Pinot at 14.9% ABV.  There is a bunch of earthiness to the wine, a clean finish without lingering alcohol, and a good amount of acid that stimulates the cheeks.  The short finish of the fruit makes me think this would do better as a wine paired with dinner.  Just make sure it’s a bigger dish, since black fruits (cherry/currant) dominates the palate.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chappellet.com/product/2015-Merlot&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Napa Valley Merlot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($45)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;82% Merlot, 5% of Cab Sauv and Franc, with the rest Malbec.  Bright red fruit with lots of spice/alcohol on the nose.  Definitely some tannin that clings through the finish.  The fruit is a bit lighter again, but with med+ body and acid.  Cooked/stewed fruit through the finish as well.  Some tobacco and cedar and maybe some espresso adding complexity to the flavor profile as well.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chappellet.com/product/2014-Malbec&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Napa Valley Malbec&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($65)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Deeper blue/black fruit on the nose, lean, really nice lingering aromas.  The palate is soft, with some black pepper, jam, black fruit, a touch warm, and a med+ finish.  It tastes a little young – seems like it needs to age a bit to round out the tannins a bit more.  The tertiary note in this wine is more coffee than the wood spices of the Merlot.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chappellet.com/product/2015-Signature-Cabernet-Sauvignon-Napa-Valley-1-5&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Signature Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;79% Cab Sauv, 14% Petit Verdot, 4% Merlot, and 3% Cab Franc.  A richness, lighter spice and baby fat comes off the wines as soon as you dig your nose in.  Soft on the palate, it is drinkable right now.  Pretty and sweet red fruit, smooth tannins, and a decent length on the finish.  And at a really decent price - just what I remember when I served six bottles of this to my colleagues at our company event.  I didn’t really get the herbs and cola to the extent our wine guide described, but I did get the hint of licorice.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/5-1050by788-bc0fe3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/5-700by525-bc0fe3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/5-675by506-bc0fe3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/5-450by338-bc0fe3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/5-525by394-bc0fe3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/5-350by263-bc0fe3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/5-350by263-bc0fe3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;What a sight&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view of the vineyards from the owner’s tent.  I know, it is quite a sight…  Why doesn’t my backyard look like that I wonder?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure that if we had the signature tasting (~$95), which includes the Pritchard Hill Cabernet Sauvignon ($225), I would’ve been happier with the wine piece of the experience.  Chappellet was also our final winery of the day and was right after a late lunch, so I would also be interested in making another visit just to enjoy the wines more, though I doubt we will get the same experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the theme of the wines from Chappellet is Pritchard Hill terroir wines at an afforable price; every other place nearby sells wines at $200+ a bottle, though the Gandona Encosta is another good buy.  These wines are also on the heavier / hotter side and display many qualities that are associated with Napa wines.  I also need to call out their Signature Cabernet as a tremendous value buy at $55 that should be tried by everyone, even those that normally don’t care for Napa Cabernets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get away from the valley floor, but not pay the traditional mountain AVA prices of Napa, give Chappellet a try.  And if you are really ambitious, make sure to try the Pritchard Hill Cabernet too.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="pritchard-hill" /><summary type="html">One of the first ten wineries established in the Napa Valley, Chappellet has a long and storied history - from Wine Spectator mentioning one of its wines in the top ten of the past century, to naming and copyrighting the location that people think of when they hear Bryant Family, Colgin, etc. (Chappellet copyrighted “Pritchard Hill”), to producing a consistent 97+ pt wine in the Wine Advocate (their Pritchard Hill Cabernet Sauvignon). Chappellet has a fantastic reputation and for good reason - the quality of their wine is very good. I just had to visit Chappellet on my most recent trip, though the reasonable tasting fee also helped. Note that like many other owners in Napa, the proprietar of Chappellet made his money before coming out to Napa and buying land. In his case, he invented the first coffee vending machines, where you would pay to get a cup of coffee automatically dispensed for you. No disrespect to coffee lovers, but I am glad he transitioned to wine!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/chappellet/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Round Pond Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/01/12/round_pond_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Round Pond Private Tasting" /><published>2019-01-12T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-12T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/01/12/round_pond_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/01/12/round_pond_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;For those who have not yet been to Tuscany (Italy), you need to make plans to visit ASAP.  The gorgeous scenery aside, the wineries of Tuscany feel like you are visiting distant relatives.  In addition to growing grapes and making wine, the Tuscan estates will also grow olives onsite and make olive oil / balsamic vinagrette.  Combined with the family restaurants on the property and it’s easy to see why you could spend an entire day at a winery eating great food and drinking great wine with the families that own the estates.  Of all the current Napa estates that I have been to, Round Pond is the one that reminds me most of Tuscany.  Its 462 continguous acres in Rutherford can also make you feel like you have been transported somewhere else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the Tuscan estates, Round Pond is family owned, everyone (the owners and the children that now run the winery) lives on the property, they produce their own olive oil from their 13 acres of olives (the old tasting room is now their olivery), and it’s very easy to sit outside on their veranda and drink/eat all day long…  The only thing is the family is not Italian!  Though one vacation to Tuscany is all that is needed to fall in love with everything about it.  It’s also the reason why they grow Italian varietals such as Sangiovese and Nebbiolo and not just the traditional Napa varietals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/1-1050by788-16bee3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/1-700by525-16bee3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/1-675by506-16bee3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/1-450by338-16bee3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/1-525by394-16bee3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/1-350by263-16bee3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/1-350by263-16bee3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;outdoor drinkin&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view of Round Pond’s patio that they use for tastings.  If you don’t make a reservation, there is a standing tasting table indoors that you can go to.  But why wouldn’t you want to sit outdoors while enjoying good wine?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But before they started Round Pond, the owners originally owned some land on Pritchard Hill and used that experience to determine whether they would go all in on a winery or not.  They would come up every weekend to take care of their plot of land and camp outside in the vineyard after each long Saturday and Sunday of hard work.  After many months of working in San Francisco during the week and then traveling to Napa every weekend to work in their vineyard, they decided that they wanted to go all-in and moved their family to Rutherford.  Another family that answered its calling to contribute to the great world of wine…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our wine hostess (Erin) was great.  In addition to talking through all of the history I described above, we talked about the old horticultural school they had for boys, how the style of wine seems to blend the fruit and structure of Napa with the rusticity of Tuscany, and why Thomas Rivers Brown is one of the premier celebrity winemakers in the valley.  Looking back, Round Pond would have been a great place to order some food, but we had to get up Pritchard Hill to Chappellet afterwards, so I’ll need to revisit the food another time.  Still, the ambiance of the winery was great - fun, not too crowded or loud, relaxing seating, and no rush through the tasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/2-1050by788-2d53fa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/2-700by525-2d53fa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/2-675by506-2d53fa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/2-450by338-2d53fa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/2-525by394-2d53fa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/2-350by263-2d53fa.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/2-350by263-2d53fa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;indoor drinkin&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view of Round Pond’s indoor wine tasting area.  Though you can stop by this tasting table without a reservation, wouldn’t you rather sit outside instead (like in the first picture above)?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went for the Cabernet Tasting ($75), so the menu will be slightly different if you choose the regular tasting instead.  Also, you normally get to choose one of the Gravel Series wines for your tasting (Secret Garden, Scholar’s Gate, or the Vow), but since I was there with two other friends, we each picked a different wine from the Gravel Series and shared with each other, hence why I have notes for all three.  The wines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.roundpond.com/store/index.cfm?fuseaction=productdetail&amp;amp;product_id=1358&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Nebbiolo Rose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($32)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The fruit is pretty mellow but the acidity is bright on the nose.  Medium body with high acidity and enough tannin to add to the body.  The color is a unique, nearly invisible pink.  The wine is a little warm – you can definitely feel the alcohol at the end, but otherwise is very pleasant.  I love the novelty – it’s not easy to find Nebbiolo Roses around here.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.roundpond.com/store/index.cfm?fuseaction=productdetail&amp;amp;product_id=1237&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Proprietary Red&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($88)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;65% Cabernet, 25% Petit Verdot, the rest is Malbec and Merlot.  Deep red fruit (kirsch) and spice on the nose with some deep black fruit (fig) as well.  The body was much lighter (med) than I was expecting.  Still had a spice bite but smooth otherwise while warming you up a bit thanks to the alcohol.  Some rustic feel too, reminding me of Italy.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.roundpond.com/store/index.cfm?fuseaction=productdetail&amp;amp;product_id=1243&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Reserve Cabernet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($110)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;96% Cabernet, 4% Petit Verdot.  Much deeper in color than the Proprietary red - they also brought us some skewered meat to pair with the wine.  The nose is similar to the Proprietary Red except this had blue/black fruit with the spice and the alcohol was better integrated.  The body and flavors are wonderful in this wine and the tertiary notes are starting their development too.  The tannins are already so fine and the meat pairing helps clear any remaining tannins in the mouth.  Smooth with a solid body and mouthfeel.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Petit Verdot&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;They blind tasted me at the winery on this wine and I totally nailed it.  I did struggle evaluating just the nose because it reminded me of a really ripe Cabernet Franc with the really bright sweet red fruit, hint of black fruit, violets and black pepper on the nose.  But when you taste it, you get the flavors of a ripe Petit Verdot.  This wine had less fruit than the Cabernets, which gives way to earthiness that is characteristic of Petit Verdots.  There is also more tannin that lingers on the finish but is still rounded.  Very drinkable with a bigger body.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.roundpond.com/store/index.cfm?fuseaction=productdetail&amp;amp;product_id=1448&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Secret Garden&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($225)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A single vineyard wine from Oakville.  The vines are grown in a dried-up gravel riverbed, leading to a higher intensity nose than the Reserve Cabernet and about the same set of aromas except a sweet spice is also present.  This brings my brain directly to fruitcake.  Lighter with much more minerality and alcohol on the body.  The heat lasts through the finish for 60+ seconds.  This wine is more distinctive with its character, but I’m not sure it adds enough that I would take over this over two bottles of the the Reserve Cabernet.  This also really dries the mouth out with the tannin and needs more time in the bottle.  Flavors are sweet berry, spice, chocolate, black fruit, violets and lavender.  This plot is more maritime in climate which leads to this wine’s elegance and reduced power.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.roundpond.com/store/index.cfm?fuseaction=productdetail&amp;amp;product_id=1450&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Scholar’s Gate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($225)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This wine is also made from grapes grown along the rock bed of the property.  Very bright with red fruit and blackberry jam, high acid and medium+ tannin making the nose strong and reminiscent of pie.  But this wine is less about the fruit and more about the mineral characteristics with integration that currently surpasses the Secret Garden.  Initially strong alcohol impact, but opens up with cooked/baked fruit flavors on the palate.  Opulent, intense ripe red fruit, thyme, caramel, and other notes round out what I was able to pick up.  Plenty of hydro stress here would explain the intensity in this wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.roundpond.com/store/index.cfm?fuseaction=productdetail&amp;amp;product_id=1452&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 The Vow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($225)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is very similar to the Reserve Cabernet with less intensity due to the better integration (or lower amount) of alcohol and acid.  On the palate, the flavors stay predominantly in the realm of fruit.  There are some muted spices and the tannins are more fine than the other two of the Gravel Series.  This wine also has slightly more fruit than the others as well.  It’s a tie between the Scholar’s Gate and this as to which I liked best.  Having the other two first may have thrown off my perception, but I was told later that this was the biggest of the three because its soil is extremely porous.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pours of the wines (especially the Gravel Series) were a bit smaller than other places and the tasting was also only four wines (the Petit Verdot is not normally a part of the tasting).  $75 was a pretty steep price to pay for that experience, hence the lower experience score.  Besides that note, the wines were all very good and different compared to a lot of places in the valley.  Although I didn’t get to taste the Sangiovese, nor their Super Tuscan, I really appreciated the different wines that had on the menu (e.g. Nebbiolo Rose, Petit Verdot).  The wines of the Gravel Series were a great pleasure to taste too and would make a great addition to any wine collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/3-1050by1400-688aa7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/3-700by933-688aa7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/3-675by900-688aa7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/3-450by600-688aa7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/3-525by700-688aa7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/3-350by467-688aa7.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/3-350by467-688aa7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Through the looking glass&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view out of their fancy window behind the staircase to the second floor.  It made for a good shot, but you can also see the vineyards through the window if you look closely.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the wines strike you and you’d like to take some home, the good news is the membership program discounts the wines by a good bit and the shipping rates are very good: $15 2-day shipping for a case and $25 2-day shipping for 6-11 bottles.  Again, I really appreciated the ambiance and change-of-pace that Round Pond provided.  If I am able to find its Proprietary Red for closer to $60, I’m definitely going to pick up a few.  So if you are looking for somewhere relaxing to spend some time in Napa and prefer an Italian theme over others (e.g. Hall for its neo-architecture theme), then pay a visit to Round Pond and bring some sunscreen!  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="rutherford" /><summary type="html">For those who have not yet been to Tuscany (Italy), you need to make plans to visit ASAP. The gorgeous scenery aside, the wineries of Tuscany feel like you are visiting distant relatives. In addition to growing grapes and making wine, the Tuscan estates will also grow olives onsite and make olive oil / balsamic vinagrette. Combined with the family restaurants on the property and it’s easy to see why you could spend an entire day at a winery eating great food and drinking great wine with the families that own the estates. Of all the current Napa estates that I have been to, Round Pond is the one that reminds me most of Tuscany. Its 462 continguous acres in Rutherford can also make you feel like you have been transported somewhere else.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/round-pond/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Plumpjack Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/01/05/plumpjack_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Plumpjack Public Tasting" /><published>2019-01-05T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-05T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/01/05/plumpjack_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/01/05/plumpjack_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Plumpjack is a great example of a newer winery on historic land that is producing fantastic wines.  Many people in my social wine circle have heard the name, but not much else other than it supposedly makes great wines.  As you may know by now, that is alone is enough to pique my curiosity and schedule a visit.  It turns out that the legend of Plumpjack started in 1992, when the Lt. Governor of California and a music composer got together and opened a wine store in San Francisco.  Those who are Shakespeare lovers may also get the reference to Sir John “Plumpjack” Falstaff from Henry V.  When someone told me the reference, I knew I was really going to like this place because the personality of Sir “Plumpjack” is pretty close to my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/1-1050by788-4fc29d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/1-700by525-4fc29d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/1-675by506-4fc29d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/1-450by338-4fc29d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/1-525by394-4fc29d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/1-350by263-4fc29d.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/1-350by263-4fc29d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;PJW!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The entrance to the Plumpjack Winery!  We arrived close to 10:15 and somehow were the first visitors to the winery that day.  I will admit, sometimes it’s nice to be the only people at a winery and hog all of the attention of the staff…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Plumpjack is relatively young, the history of the estate goes back to the 1880s when it was known as Mount Eden Winery (the brand got moved to what is now Conn Creek Winery to the north).  Some of the buildings onsite are from around that time, although the tasting room has definitely undergone interior renovations.  Plumpjack could have built its brand in that historic/established direction, but instead chose to build a laid-back, inviting image.  It even became one of the first luxury-priced wineries to bottle its wine with screwcaps to combat the growing problem of cork taint at the time.  Combined with the wide appeal of its wine and the higher production volume today, Plumpjack has grown into a powerhouse that appears in many homes and high-end restaurants.  Its 2013 and 2016 Cabernet Sauvignon Reserve also scored 100 points in the Wine Advocate, so you know the quality is top notch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plumpjack made for a great start to the day.  The drive, entrance and the tasting room all had a relaxing effect, as if to say it was ok to show up in a T-shirt and jeans.  Since we arrived close to opening at 1000, we were also the only people at the winery and received lots of attention from everyone there.  We missed Aaron Miller (their winemaker since 2012 and a UC Davis graduate), but were able to share some stories with the wine ambassadors about studying for the WSET exams and wishing we were all just a little smarter…  The Plumpjack group now owns two other wineries: CADE Winery on Howell Mountain and Odette Winery in Stags Leap.  What’s nice is that at each of the wineries, they will serve a wine from one of the other wineries as part of your tasting so you get an idea of the different styles and taste profiles of each place.  It also gives you a nice incentive to visit and try the rest of their portfolio, because as you can imagine those wines are also delicious!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/2-1050by788-c4d299.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/2-700by525-c4d299.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/2-675by506-c4d299.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/2-450by338-c4d299.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/2-525by394-c4d299.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/2-350by263-c4d299.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/2-350by263-c4d299.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;First-Class Wine Ambassadors&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Another benefit of going to the winery early in the day - everyone is available for a photograph!!  Everyone was very nice and they opened a couple extra wines for our tasting, for which we were very grateful.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tasting room itself is a relatively small space with a small patio in the back, hence the recommendation to make tasting reservations.  The bar is a small semi-circular slab of rock (as seen above) and there is also a small gift shop on the right in case you want to purchase any branded wine accessories.  I’m sure there are other interesting details about the building that I missed, but they poured the wine right away and had a couple off-menu wines to share since we were the first visitors of the day.  Also, I immediately felt like I needed to retract that thought of being able to wear a T-shirt and jeans here - the wine made me snap to attention really quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.plumpjackwinery.com/SHOP.AMS?LEVEL=BOT&amp;amp;PART=PJ17CHSC7&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Reserve Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($52)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;1:2 ratio of new to neutral oak and a 1:2 ratio of St. Helena grapes to Carneros.  Light aromas of lemon zest and lime with ripe green apples and acid that tingles the cheeks.  The lemon and lime are also on the palate, but definitely not as pronounced as on the nose.  A nice, crisp finish without a seering amount of acidity.  I didn’t get the almonds and vanilla on the palate from the wood as suggested by the tasting notes, but it could be that I wasn’t looking for it as well as this being the first wine of the day.  Not nearly the minerality of a Chablis, but still some similar characteristics in this wine.  Definitely not your traditional Napa Chardonnay.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.plumpjackwinery.com/SHOP.AMS?LEVEL=BOT&amp;amp;PART=PJ16MEC7&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Merlot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($64)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;96% Merlot from Oak Knoll with the rest Malbec.  Red and black fruit, chocolate, vanilla, and smoke make for a deep nose with a tingling brightness.  You can still feel the acidity, dust and medium smooth tannin on the palate.  Though, the finish does feel a little hot.  This is definitely a Merlot that Cabernet-Lovers will want to take a long look at.  The flavor profile is a little lighter on the palate, but the texture is very Cab-like.  I picked up a bottle of this for the winter-time!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Cade Napa Valley Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt; ($82)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Less or riper tannins that Cade’s Howell Mountain Cabernet make this a very accessible Cabernet in its youth.  Deep and rich red fruit with some brighter blue fruit on the nose as well.  It’s palate also feels very pretty and approachable with slightly candied notes and raspberry jam blended in.  You don’t need to pair this wine with anything; you can just drink it straight out of the bottle.  But make no mistake - it still has enough complexity to keep your interest.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.plumpjackwinery.com/SHOP.AMS?LEVEL=BOT&amp;amp;PART=PJ15CSCM&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Estate Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($130)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Huge grape jam on the nose with black and blue fruit.  The palate is really smooth (similar to the Cade) with ripe tannins that aren’t grippy but are definitely present.  From a texture standpoint, there is more weight on this wine than the previous Cade.  While the aromas are pronounced, the palate isn’t overly ripe with fruit notes and there is added complexity from cocoa powder, vanilla, and dusty notes.  For drinking right now, I prefer this over the Cade Napa Valley Cabernet and the other critics scores reflect that opinion.  Reminds me of really good black cherry pie…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2007 Oakville Estate Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt; ($371)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cherry, spice, cranberry, some herbaceous notes, but it all leaps out of the glass and the finish goes on forever.  I can’t believe this wine is 11 years old.  There is so much complexity on the nose but it all feels bright, fresh, and utterly irresistible.  The palate is a little lighter than the younger wines – I think it’s caused by a difference in style by the previous winemaker.  But the palate is just as intense as the nose and has flavors across all three segments (primary/secondary/tertiary).  If a wine could drop the mic, walk away, and leave the audience in awe, this is one of those wines.  I might pick this in a blind tasting next to Bordeaux First Growths…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.plumpjackwinery.com/SHOP.AMS?LEVEL=BOT&amp;amp;PART=PJ16SYC7&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Napa Valley Syrah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($62)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It’s hard to taste another wine immediately after a showstopper, but this Syrah held up surprisingly well.  A lot of bright, ripe red ripe fruit that explodes out of the glass.  There’s an underlying meat/blood component, but it’s buried underneath the red fruit and would need aging to bring it more to the forefront.  The body is med+/full with good lingering acid and tannin that is present but pretty soft.  The flavors are dominated by the bright, pretty ripe red fruit but should evolve similarly to the nose.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The style of the red wines reminds me of Nickel and Nickel in how pretty they are on the nose, but the flavor intensity and complexity were an added dimension I really liked, especially at the price points of the Merlot and Syrah.  The tannins were not quite as high as Beringer or similar-styled wines, so I would drink any of these earlier rather than later.  Another aspect that I really appreciated was that they included shipping with a case of wine, which if you buy as much wine as I do, you know that free shipping (especially free 2-day shipping here) is about the same as a 15% to 20% discount on the wines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still can remember the 2007 Oakville Estate Cabernet, but know that it will be hard to obtain or try again with that availability and pricepoint.  Instead, it may be worth trying to find a bottle of the 2016 Cabernet Sauvignon Reserve try aging that for 10 years.  Though, I have a feeling the Cabernet Sauvignon Reserve will also be out of my pricepoint after that 100pt score…  Such is life.  Still, this is a great, quality tasting for $40 and who knows, you may be able to try the reserve at the winery too!  So get out there and give it a try.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="oakville" /><summary type="html">Plumpjack is a great example of a newer winery on historic land that is producing fantastic wines. Many people in my social wine circle have heard the name, but not much else other than it supposedly makes great wines. As you may know by now, that is alone is enough to pique my curiosity and schedule a visit. It turns out that the legend of Plumpjack started in 1992, when the Lt. Governor of California and a music composer got together and opened a wine store in San Francisco. Those who are Shakespeare lovers may also get the reference to Sir John “Plumpjack” Falstaff from Henry V. When someone told me the reference, I knew I was really going to like this place because the personality of Sir “Plumpjack” is pretty close to my own.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/plumpjack/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Lokoya Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/29/lokoya_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lokoya Private Tasting" /><published>2018-12-29T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-29T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/29/lokoya_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/29/lokoya_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t get much better than Lokoya…  Not views of the valley below, not the tasting room, not the isolation/attention, and definitely not the wines.  I guess the only things to complain about is that they only make four wines (all Cabernet Sauvignons) and that I don’t make enough money to drink these wines regularly.  Though, I find myself saying that often for all the best wines.  Even with an allocation, I couldn’t get access to the 2015 Mt. Veeder and Howell Mountain, which happen to be my two favorite mountain terroirs of the four they produce from.  The other two are their Spring Mountain and Diamond Mountain wines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tasting room for Lokoya is up on Spring Mountain, past Fantesca but before Pride Mountain Winery.  It’s fairly difficult to find the gate as it’s unbranded and the location isn’t really advertised.  Don’t worry though - it’s neigh impossible to get a reservation for a tasting there, so if finding the place is your issue, consider it a small one.  Once you reach the property though, you’ll see that the views of the valley below are breathtaking, tempting you to sit outside on the patio all day.  Unfortunately though, that’s not on the menu…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/1-1050by788-b98616.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/1-700by525-b98616.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/1-675by506-b98616.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/1-450by338-b98616.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/1-525by394-b98616.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/1-350by263-b98616.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/1-350by263-b98616.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;token group photo&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Group photo with a glimpse of the valley from the Lokoya patio.  It really is quite something…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lokoya was purchased by Jackson Family Wines (one of the large wine conglomerates in the world today) to be the crown jewel of their Spire Collection.  And the entire experience does not disappoint.  From the moment you walk in the door, you are greeted by the wine ambassador and given a glass of excellent sparkling wine; I forget what Grand Cru Champagne we had.  Regardless, it was very good and quite pricey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/2-1050by788-82b819.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/2-700by525-82b819.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/2-675by506-82b819.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/2-450by338-82b819.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/2-525by394-82b819.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/2-350by263-82b819.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/2-350by263-82b819.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;just amazing&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Can you imagine hosting friends for a wine pairing meal here?  Also, lined around the room on both sides were cabinets that contained bottles of past vintages that are not for sale.  Imagine being able to break out some past vintages here.  I don’t think I could put a price on an experience like that…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you are led inside and listen to the history of the winery and winemaker (I am a huge fan of Chris Carpenter’s wines), it’s impossible not to just stare in awe of how pristine everything looks.  Coupled with the fact that only one group is allowed at the property at a time, we all felt like a million bucks.  In fact, everything was so overwhelming that it felt like I didn’t belong.  Definitely my first time ever feeling uncomfortable in a winery, albeit in a good way.  Finally, we were led to our table where the wines for the tasting had already been decanted and poured in our glasses.  I thought I was entering my comfort zone again.  These wines make you feel many things, but comfortable isn’t one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lokoya.com/collection#spring-mountain&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Spring Mountain Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($375)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This was the first wine of the tasting, so that might bias me, but I am pretty sure out of all the wines, this had the most perfumed floral notes on the nose.  Black and red fruit with minerality comes through on the palate.  Purity and integration define this wine with great balance between power and elegance.  Definitely the best Spring Mountain Cabernet I’ve had.  With proper aging, only the Fantesca Cabernet might begin to compare.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lokoya.com/collection#mount-veeder&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Mount Veeder Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($375)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Oh my goodness.  I lost myself in this wine.  If the Spring Mountain was about purity and integration, this wine was powerful, complex and dominated by the terroir’s minerality.  Blue fruit (more than black or red) with some spice in there as well.  There’s a saying that “If God created Cabernet, the Devil created Pinot”.  Of the many Cabernets I’ve had, this might be Cabernet that best fits that piece of hte equation; it just commands your attention and your respect.  Very masculine - please age this for 20-30 years before drinking.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lokoya.com/collection#howell-mountain&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2006 Howell Mountain Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($450)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;They were running low on the 2013 Howell Mountain, so they opened a library vintage instead.  Even though it was 11 years old, it was still brooding with the dark chocolate and black fruit I love so much from this AVA.  The one interesting note was that there wasn’t much tobacco / cigar box, but an herbal tinge (e.g. fennel) that was likely due to the aging.  This wine seemed to change the most over the course of the tasting and was really nice.  A clear example that these wines are going to age very nicely.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lokoya.com/collection#mount-veeder&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2006 Mount Veeder Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($450)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Compared to the 2013, the 2006 had minerality that was just as distinct, but more chocolate/espresso flavors and black fruit rather than blue fruit.  I’m surprised the floral bouquet was still so aromatic and the tannins were still so present (but sweet/rounded).  Still, the piece that captures the attention is the texture and the complexity - the flavors are layered and integrated at the same time.  I can’t tell which one I preferred more: the ‘06 Howell or the ‘06 Mount Veeder.  There is a reason why these two are my favorite mountain AVAs.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll admit, it must have been dumb luck that I was able to schedule a tasting here.  Out of the 10 wineries I visited in three days, this was by far the highlight of that weekend and continues to be one of my most fond memories of Napa Valley.  It’s really too bad that all they have to taste is four wines; this is where I give the edge to places like Kapcsandy who have wines that are also of extreme quality, but you get to walk through the full portfolio and various library vintages.  Still the winery and views are almost enough to make you forget that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/3-1050by1174-8a4f8d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/3-700by783-8a4f8d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/3-675by755-8a4f8d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/3-450by503-8a4f8d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/3-525by587-8a4f8d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/3-350by391-8a4f8d.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/3-350by391-8a4f8d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;missing half the group&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The wine tasting with the meat and cheese board pairing.  If you thinking they are smiling big in this picture, you should’ve seen how much they were smiling after.  I forgot to take an “after” picture because I was so obsessed with the wines.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all walked away with a bottle of the 2013 Mt. Veeder.  In hindsight, I really wish I bought a couple cases given the rating of the vintage by every wine publication and the 2013 Mt. Veeder itself (100pts Wine Advocate).  I’m sure you got this from the tasting notes, but the theme of the wines here is power, character, and terroir.  There are many powerful Cabernets in the Napa Valley, but these wines are just rock solid and don’t rely on the fruit to do the heavy lifting.  And even though these wines will keep for 30-40 years, there is an approachability like all of Chris Carpenter’s wines that allows you to drink this early (if you really want to).  But I like to think of these wines as an investment in oneself, so save it for a special occasion for when you really deserve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to be able to try these wines, but can’t get a reservation at Lokoya on Spring Mountain, make a reservation at Cardinale.  It’s much easier to get a reservation there and it’s also part of the Spire Collection.  When emailing them to confirm your reservation, you can ask for them to add Lokoya to your tasting menu.  It may add a few dollars to your tasting fee, but it is well worth it.  The Cardinale wine is also of high quality and worth the trip on its own merits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alas, I hope the day comes where I can purchase and consume Lokoya wines as freely as I’d like, but I doubt that will ever be the case.  So my advice to the readers - if you see a bottle in someone’s house, befriend them for life and pray you are lucky enough to be around when that bottle gets opened, haha.  For those that have cases of this wine in their cellars: will you be my friend?  Haha, cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="spring-mountain" /><summary type="html">It doesn’t get much better than Lokoya… Not views of the valley below, not the tasting room, not the isolation/attention, and definitely not the wines. I guess the only things to complain about is that they only make four wines (all Cabernet Sauvignons) and that I don’t make enough money to drink these wines regularly. Though, I find myself saying that often for all the best wines. Even with an allocation, I couldn’t get access to the 2015 Mt. Veeder and Howell Mountain, which happen to be my two favorite mountain terroirs of the four they produce from. The other two are their Spring Mountain and Diamond Mountain wines.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/lokoya/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Romeo Vineyards Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/22/romeo_vineyards_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Romeo Vineyards Public Tasting" /><published>2018-12-22T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-22T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/22/romeo_vineyards_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/22/romeo_vineyards_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;I hope everyone is having fun gearing up for Christmas!!  This may be a little late on my part, but I wanted to share some Christmas cheer by publishing articles on some fantastic wineries over the next few weeks.  That way, people will have all the belated Christmas gift ideas that they need!  The first one we are going to start with is Romeo Vineyards.  I’m fairly sure that most people reading this have never heard of Romeo Vineyards before.  Before I stumbled upon this gem in the town of Calistoga, I hadn’t heard of them either, save one or two deals on Vivino.  As one of the few places in the Napa Valley that is open until 5:00pm or later (it’s actually open until 6:30pm!), I thought I would end a day of tasting by visiting this small family-owned winery and trying a few wines.  Needless to say, that is not how it went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, huge props to Nate who ran the tasting for me.  Without his knowledge, friendliness, and genuine passion for the wines he was pouring, the score for the experience would be much different.  He was one of the most knowledgeable ambassadors I have ever tasted with (I could swear he is an Advanced Somm) and was super excited to share how amazing their wines are and how mispriced they are compared to their quality.  But don’t let all that praise fool you - the wines spoke for themselves and what a story they told.  As you can see in the tasting notes below, I tasted pretty much every wine and every vintage that they have stored down in their massive wine cellar.  My notes are also not as fully detailed as they normally are; part of it is I was tired after a long day of tastings and part of it is that tasting 15+ great wines from different vintages without spitting much of it will lead you to enjoying the overall experience rather than nitpicking the details of each wine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/1-1050by1400-ef32f3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/1-700by933-ef32f3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/1-675by900-ef32f3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/1-450by600-ef32f3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/1-525by700-ef32f3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/1-350by467-ef32f3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/1-350by467-ef32f3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Gateway to a hidden treasure&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Romeo is difficult to find in Calistoga.  It took me walking around the block a couple times to find the place.  But trust me, the search is worth it.  Through this passage lies a great tasting experience that will surprise you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The style of the wines was also much different that what I was used to; this novelty also had a positive effect on me while tasting the wines.  I am seriously enamored with their juicy, approachable style of wine that seemingly ages forever, even though the wines don’t seem like they need to.  Some of the wines are a little closed down (e.g. their 2004 Old Vine Cabernet Sauvignon) and require a decanter to coax out the flavors a bit.  But for the most part, every wine seems like it’s at its perfect drinking window.  Just note that the best temperature for storing and serving wine in this style is lower than what you are used to (e.g. 50-51 degrees) so be sure to take note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entrance to the winery is hard to find as there aren’t really any signs and the building it’s in is unassuming; I am pretty sure that they share it with some other business.  But once you find the terrace entrance as seen above, come prepared to have some preconceptions about good wine and expensive wine flipped on their head.  Great wine does not need to be expensive.  Thanks to the economics of supply-and-demand, it normally is.  But when you find a hidden gem that has a good supply but not much demand (it is relatively unknown), it can result in great deals for the consumer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvested from ~50-year-old vines, the grapes are used in small lot wines to ensure quality and distinctive character.  These vines are near a reservoir, which leads to high diurnal temperature swings (hot days, cool nights) that preserve the high acidity of the grapes and allows the vineyard manager to leave the grapes on the vines for an extremely long hangtime to achieve great flavor intensity.  The winemaker then uses a high skin/pulp to juice ratio during a colder maceration/fermentation to gain its intense but balanced flavors, while maintaining high acidity and a lighter body in the wine.  After reading all of that, you would think that you were drinking wines in the $150+ price range.  I am happy to burst your bubble!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/2-1050by1400-ab991a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/2-700by933-ab991a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/2-675by900-ab991a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/2-450by600-ab991a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/2-525by700-ab991a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/2-350by467-ab991a.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/2-350by467-ab991a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Tank-powered Coravin!!!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A shot inside Romeo’s tasting room.  There are so many great things about this picture.  The tasting room is small (fits at most 10 people), the wine ambassador (Nate) is amazing, the fact that he’s using a coravin connected to an Argon tank is awesome, and he was pouring me a 2004 Old Vine Cabernet Sauvignon.  I was so happy when I took this photo, haha.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wines we tasted (and what little I wrote down) is below.  &lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; The best wines, which also happen to be the ones I tasted, are not listed on their website and can only be purchased through the winery directly, so make sure you visit in person!  I know they are running low on inventory for a few of these, so there isn’t that much time left for finding the older vintages!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2007 Miscela Bordeaux Blend&lt;/strong&gt; ($65)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Really nice nose – juicy but not overripe and with some earth.  The alcohol does not come out at all and everything feels well woven together.  Juicy raisins on the palate with a nice medium(-) body that goes down easy.  The tannin and acidity are in good balance.  It is a just a really good wine that is easy to enjoy but has a deeper cerebral aspect if you want to enjoy that aspect too.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2006 Petit Verdot&lt;/strong&gt; ($46)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;100% varietal Petit Verdot.  I don’t know what was more shocking - the fact they attempted it or how good the wine was.  Big and intense but super enjoyable with lighter tannins and body (still juicy) than I was expecting.  A nice representation of the varietal’s characteristics with enough age to let the tertiary character of the PV shine too.  And this was Nate’s least favorite of the Petit Verdots on the menu….&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2004 Petit Verdot&lt;/strong&gt; ($55)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sweet brown sugar mixed with earth and the juiciness of the 2006.  There is also a high pitched acidity (citrus-like in character) on the back of the nose that makes the wine feel alive at 14 years old.  I thought the 2006 was good, but now I see why he said it didn’t compare to the others.  The vibrancy adds a good amount of complexity and makes the mid-palate feel much more interesting.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Petit Verdot&lt;/strong&gt; ($55)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Their youngest Petit Verdot.  Popcorn kernels (weird, right?) jump out at you and the rest of the red fruit just rushes in after it.  There are also notes of blackberry and blueberry in the wine.  Silky smooth for its varietal and age - I could see how people prefer the younger PV.  But give me that 2004 all day.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2003 Napa Valley Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt; ($70)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Seriously, the first note to come out was gerber baby carrot.  With some time, plum, raisin, bright acidity, and an earthiness also come out of the glass.  Like the others before it, this wine is super smooth with a good amount of juiciness and a lighter body than other Cabernets you’ll have in the valley.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2005 Petit Verdot&lt;/strong&gt; ($42)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;After the 2003 Cabernet, we went back to the 2005 PV.  The nose is still a little closed, but in a cloying type of way where it wants you to wait for it to open up.  Much more earthiness and tannin than the other PVs – the tannin is sharp/compact and the body is not as juicy as the others.  This thing could age another 5 to 10 years if it wanted.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2002 Eugenia Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt; ($85)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Strawberry, raspberry, plum, spice, and earth.  All of this combines into a really nice wine that is so smooth, complex and balanced.  This wine may seem feminine, but the tasting notes that progressively open and its intricacies leave you feeling as if you have experienced powerful in a different sense.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1997 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This wine really struck me as something quite spectacular.  Seemingly made in an old world style, but still has plenty amount of fruit left in its life.  This wine balances being enjoyable and cerebral very well.  I didn’t take any notes on the exact flavors because I was just struck by the sensibility and integration of the wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1998 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt; ($70)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Definitively less fruit than the 1997 Cabernet.  Nate mentioned this and I agree - this is a French farmers wine; there is no fruit left on the palate but this would still make for a great cigar wine.  Still, the textural components are all well balanced and while the flavor may not have much fruit, the wine doesn’t feel too old or tired at all.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2004 Old Vine Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt; ($90)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;By local “definition”, this wine is an old vine Cabernet (over 35 years old).  The wine was very closed in the glass, but I was told would have great potential if I had the time to let it open.  I bought a bottle a tried it again later and he was right.  It was probably the favorite bottle of the night.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Old Vine Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt; ($48)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A very different wine than the 2004.  This is a very pretty wine with lots of red/black fruit and with a crushed flower quality to the taste.  Even though this is a young with, it’s still super approachable with a great mouthfeel.  Do not hesitate to open this bottle and drink right away.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2009 Petit Verdot&lt;/strong&gt; ($55)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A balance between juicy and reserved on the nose.  Like the other PVs, this is really smooth for being a 100% varietal wine with a good amount of tannins that can still support aging for another decade if you wanted to.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Petit Verdot&lt;/strong&gt; ($55)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A bit bigger in the acid and tannin category than the other Petit Verdots.  It’s interesting – the juiciness ends a little quickly on the finish thanks to the acid/tannin, but that does not affect the palate at all.  Not much grip, just a really nice texture.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2008 Malbec&lt;/strong&gt; ($42)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Grapes from Calistoga, but the nose reminded me of Knights Valley.  I don’t even think I felt the tannins and the acid is med/med+ but you don’t even notice it until it hits your cheeks.  I haven’t had a 10 year old Malbec before, so this was a treat.  Also juicy and smooth – the color is not dark like other Malbecs and the body is not heavy either.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Soiree Petit Verdot Port&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;18.5% ABV after fortification, I need more of this.  That is all.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How’s everyone feeling after all that wine?  Not only was the wine great, but you will notice that not a single bottle came out to more than $90.  They were also kind enough to give me free shipping on a case (of course I bought a case after a tasting like that…).  So just make sure that you stop by for a tasting.  You will be glad that you did.  Cheers!!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="calistoga" /><summary type="html">I hope everyone is having fun gearing up for Christmas!! This may be a little late on my part, but I wanted to share some Christmas cheer by publishing articles on some fantastic wineries over the next few weeks. That way, people will have all the belated Christmas gift ideas that they need! The first one we are going to start with is Romeo Vineyards. I’m fairly sure that most people reading this have never heard of Romeo Vineyards before. Before I stumbled upon this gem in the town of Calistoga, I hadn’t heard of them either, save one or two deals on Vivino. As one of the few places in the Napa Valley that is open until 5:00pm or later (it’s actually open until 6:30pm!), I thought I would end a day of tasting by visiting this small family-owned winery and trying a few wines. Needless to say, that is not how it went.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/romeo/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Nickel and Nickel Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/15/nickel_and_nickel_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nickel and Nickel Private Tasting" /><published>2018-12-15T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-15T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/15/nickel_and_nickel_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/15/nickel_and_nickel_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Nickel and Nickel is another winery right next to the Highway 29 in Napa.  In fact it’s right across the street from Robert Mondavi and next to Opus One, both of which have storied histories, so you know they set up shop in the right place.  The styling used for Nickel and Nickel’s logo is also very similar to Far Niente, which isn’t to far away.  That’s not a coincidence - the two are sister wineries.  While Far Niente is known for its rounded portfolio, Nickel and Nickel has built its reputation through its vast number of single vineyard Cabernet Sauvignons.  Even the single vineyard tasting gives you a preview of less than half (6 out of 15) of the single vineyard Cabernet Sauvignons on their menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/1-1050by788-40cb0b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/1-700by525-40cb0b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/1-675by506-40cb0b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/1-450by338-40cb0b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/1-525by394-40cb0b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/1-350by263-40cb0b.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/1-350by263-40cb0b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Follow the red brick walkway&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The wine tasting building is actually a house that functions as the wine tasting location.  The wine tastings are conducted inside as well as on the back patio.  Because the house isn’t that big, reservations are required to throttle visitor throughput.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a previous article discussing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/09/08/beringer_private_tasting.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beringer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I mentioned that Beringer was a great location to explore single vineyard Cabernet Sauvignons.  If I were to contrast these two and their interpretations of premium Cabernet Sauvignon, it would be that Beringer makes its Cabernets heavier and with more tannin for aging, while the Cabernets from Nickel and Nickel are softer and ready to drink earlier.  As far as educative experiences go, this Cabernet tasting was very helpful in isolating the characteristics of the different terroir along the valley floor (e.g. Oakville, Yountville, Rutherford, and St. Helena).  Even if you don’t have the most discerning wine palate yet, this is a fun experience to see if you can taste anything different between the wines.  Once you are able to take that first step, the rest follows.  Also, you will impress your sommelier at dinner if you know what AVA you want your Napa Cabernet from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/2-1050by788-a9e080.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/2-700by525-a9e080.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/2-675by506-a9e080.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/2-450by338-a9e080.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/2-525by394-a9e080.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/2-350by263-a9e080.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/2-350by263-a9e080.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Where's the wedding?&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A look into the house.  This is the waiting area your wine ambassador will escort you to as they setup your tasting.  A nice, classy room to enjoy a glass of Chardonnay and share some laughs with fellow wine drinkers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Approaching the building, it feels like you are visiting a friend’s house.  This house must have been around for some time; once inside, you can tell that the house and furniture all have some age on them.  As you look around and wait for your wine ambassador to come fetch you for your tasting, you are given a glass of their Stiling Chardonnay to enjoy in the meantime.  Once they are ready for you, you’ll be led on a tour of the grounds, through the back patio, and into the white triangular-shaped building in the picture above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/3-1050by788-fd4e21.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/3-700by525-fd4e21.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/3-675by506-fd4e21.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/3-450by338-fd4e21.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/3-525by394-fd4e21.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/3-350by263-fd4e21.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/3-350by263-fd4e21.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Where's the wedding?&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view of the grounds from the back patio of the house.  With this much space, you’d think that there would be a wedding hosted here every weekend, but alas there is not.  Seems like the space could be used for something fun.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting the tour of the winemaking facility and asking any questions you might have of their philosophy and production process, it’ll be time to taste some wines!  As with every winery, the wine ambassador can make or break the tasting experience.  Luckily, I had a great one who also allowed me to taste the Syrah that is not normally on the menu and entertained me with great detail about the wines here.  If you do the single vineyard Cabernet tasting, your list will also look like the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.farniente.com/product/2015-Nickel---Nickel-Stiling-Vineyard-Chardonnay--Russian-River-Valley--Sonoma&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Stiling Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Chardonnay from the Russian River Valley.  Good balance between the acidity, fruit, and secondary/tertiary flavors.  I also liked the intensity and finish.  I was surprised that I would have such a good white wine with my all-red tasting.  I am definitely interested in finding a bottle of this and buying one in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.farniente.com/product/2015-Nickel---Nickel-Branding-Iron-Vineyard-Cabernet-Sauvignon--Oakville&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Branding Iron&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($120)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cabernet from Oakville.  Deep blue fruit but also some red fruit present with a levity to the nose.  The initial impact on the palate is a bit more subtle than the nose suggests.  Not enough intensity or complexity for me to choose this wine over the others, but if you want a subtle wine that is driven by primary flavors (e.g. fruit notes), then this is the wine you want.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.farniente.com/product/2015-Nickel---Nickel-C-C--Ranch-Cabernet-Sauvignon--Rutherford&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 CC Ranch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($120)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cabernet from Rutherford.  Better to drink this earlier in its life as I don’t know how it will age.  The acid is very nice and even though it’s 15%+ alcohol, I can’t really smell the heat at all.  It has good viscosity and length on the palate but with a lower intensity of fruit, hence why I don’t know how the mid-palate will develop and recommend trying an older bottle of this before deciding to age it yourself.  The CC Ranch is still an easy drinking wine now without a tertiary component.  If you like the Branding Iron, you may also like this.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.farniente.com/product/2015-Nickel---Nickel-Hayne-Vineyard-Cabernet-Sauvignon--St--Helena&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Hayne Vineyard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($120)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cabernet from St. Helena.  A really pretty nose with ripe red fruit that feels a little ethereal with some flowers and roses.  It has a lighter body and is brighter than the previous wines with more acidity that also cleans the palate on the finish.  The intensity again is a bit light for my taste (this contrasts the Corison Cabernet which as a light body, but intense flavor), but may be up other people’s alley!  If you want a wine similar to the Branding Iron / CC Ranch but with more acid, look no further.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.farniente.com/product/2015-Nickel---Nickel-State-Ranch-Cabernet-Sauvignon--Yountville&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 State Ranch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($120)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cabernet from Yountville.  Take the notes from the Hayne Vineyard Cabernet, but make them a bit deeper, thicker, more pronounced and you get this wine.  The high acid is prominent too on the palate.  Comparing the two, I would take the State Ranch, but again it’s all about your preferences!  There’s also definitely room for several years of aging too.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.farniente.com/product/2015-Nickel---Nickel-Element-28-Cabernet-Sauvignon--Napa-Valley&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Element 28&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($150)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Subtle with the fruit, emphasizing instead violet/floral notes and vanilla on the nose.  The Element 28 seems like a polished version of the State Ranch and takes the wine to the next level.  There’s also more earthiness on the palate that balances with the fruit and adds to the complexity.  This wine is probably my favorite of all the Nickel and Nickel Cabernets I tasted because of that balance and its intensity, though it won’t overpower you palate either.  The tannins are high and present, affecting the perceived length of the finish and making sure the wine can age 10+ years if it wants to.  Of course it’s also the most expensive wine on the tasting menu…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.farniente.com/product/2015-Nickel---Nickel-Rock-Cairn-Vineyard-Cabernet-Sauvignon--Oakville&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Rock Cairn Vineyard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($120)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cabernet from Oakville.  The nose is so powerful with bright black fruit.  The palate pulls the intensity back a bit but has a solid body, enough acid/tannin to hold up the wine but not get in the way, and medium+ length on the mid-palate and finish.  This wine is probably my second favorite after the Element 28 but doesn’t have the same level of tertiary notes and focuses on the black fruit instead.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.farniente.com/product/2014-Nickel---Nickel-Darien-Vineyard-Syrah--Russian-River-Valley--Sonoma&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Syrah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($65)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Syrah from the Russian River Valley.  They planted two acres of Syrah in the Pinot Noir block they purchased some time ago.  Having rosemary-rubbed lamb with this wine would be sooo good.  Made from cooler fruit that has quite a bit of character - the wild flavors of Syrah and black pepper is well integrated into the wine, making this cerebral and yet easy drinking at the same time.  A really good value buy here for an interesting Syrah that reminds you of the Rhone Valley in France.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would be remiss if I didn’t give a shout-out to Ian Stout who was my wine ambassador for the visit.  Ian hails from Texas and is following in the footsteps of his father, who is a Master Sommelier and owns a Syrah vineyard back in Texas.  Ian’s tasting setup was great - it was both a progression of intensity and fruit flavor types (start with light blue/red to deep red to finishing with black).  He was very knowledgable about the wines and the terroirs; I think the tasting ran over by 30 minutes because of the discussion we would have after each wine.  The cheeses used for the paired tasting were very good as well (I can’t believe I didn’t mention that earlier!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/4-1050by788-329f2f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/4-700by525-329f2f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/4-675by506-329f2f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/4-450by338-329f2f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/4-525by394-329f2f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/4-350by263-329f2f.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/4-350by263-329f2f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;I love getting dirty&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Inside the white triangular-shaped building, you will walk past the different fermentation tanks and also this little area: soil samples from the different single vineyard sites of their Cabernet Sauvignon.  It’s good to have an image of the soil as you taste the wine so you can remember the influence of the terroir&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned before, I enjoyed this tasting very much.  If I had to name a theme for their wines, I would use one of the anologies they used to describe themselves.  The winemakers at Nickel and Nickel think of winemaking like sculpting with marble in that you should start with a single piece and shave it down to its form.  In their case, they only make 100% varietal wine and use winemaking techniques to adjust and achieve what the wine wants to be, rather than blend several varietals together to get what the winemakers want.  It’s an interesting way to look at winemaking, especially since blending is considered a traditional technique and is used by most wineries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally enjoyed the last three bottles and thought the first few (besides the Chardonnay) were just a bit too light/pretty without enough character.  I still think that if you are looking to refine your palate and enjoy a different take (or many different takes) on Cabernet Sauvignon, you should give Nickel and Nickel a look.  And while you are at it, pay its sister vineyard a visit as well - hopefully, I will in the future.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="oakville" /><summary type="html">Nickel and Nickel is another winery right next to the Highway 29 in Napa. In fact it’s right across the street from Robert Mondavi and next to Opus One, both of which have storied histories, so you know they set up shop in the right place. The styling used for Nickel and Nickel’s logo is also very similar to Far Niente, which isn’t to far away. That’s not a coincidence - the two are sister wineries. While Far Niente is known for its rounded portfolio, Nickel and Nickel has built its reputation through its vast number of single vineyard Cabernet Sauvignons. Even the single vineyard tasting gives you a preview of less than half (6 out of 15) of the single vineyard Cabernet Sauvignons on their menu.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/nickel-nickel/1.jpg" /></entry></feed>