<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-03-18T22:29:34+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Wines By Jeremy</title><subtitle>Wines by Jeremy offers an educative and enjoyable personalized wine experience. Located in the DC metro area, Wines by Jeremy provides a number of services including in-home exclusive tastings, highly curated event tastings, educational events, and wine cellar consulting.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Cave du Ribeauville Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/03/09/cave_du_ribeauville_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cave du Ribeauville Public Tasting" /><published>2019-03-09T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-09T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/03/09/cave_du_ribeauville_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/03/09/cave_du_ribeauville_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Most people come to Ribeauville to visit Maison Trimbach, which is famous, has a large production each year, and has a good amount of distribution in the USA.  I did too, but unfortunately Maison Trimbach was closed when I arrived in August.  In fact, many wineries in France are closed for vacations between late July and mid-August before the harvest.  Fortunately Cave de Ribeauville, the second largest place in town, was still open and I quickly diverted there out of the drizzling rain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/1-1050by788-ceefd1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/1-700by525-ceefd1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/1-675by506-ceefd1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/1-450by338-ceefd1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/1-525by394-ceefd1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/1-350by263-ceefd1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/1-350by263-ceefd1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Ribeauville!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The largest wine storefront in the town of Ribeauville.  It is pretty amazing what local winegrowers can do when they band together.  I know that it may not look that fancy on the outside, but the inside is a whole other story…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though Cave de Ribeauville has a large production (it its actually Top 5 in the Alsace region), it is not because it is a large winery.  Rather, it is a large cooperative of many small producers that go in together, share equipment and facilities, and bottle wines under the same brand.  Some of the producers will also bottle some wine under their own brand per the cooperative’s guidelines.  It’s rather remarkable that in today’s capitalistic markets, you can still find examples where people work together for everyone’s benefit.  Thankfully for the rest of us, this cooperation also results in better product and amazing prices…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/2-1050by788-4db94b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/2-700by525-4db94b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/2-675by506-4db94b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/2-450by338-4db94b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/2-525by394-4db94b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/2-350by263-4db94b.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/2-350by263-4db94b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;The guts of the building&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Didn’t I say that the inside of the building was much nicer?  In addition to selling wines, the building also has exhibits that talks through the history of the region and its winegrowers.  I highly recommend that you read up and take a look around before heading for the tasting table.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must admit that the exterior of the building had me rather skeptical at first, but that impression changed immediately after stepping foot inside, as you can see above.  It reminded me of the interiors of wineries back home.  Though as a bonus, they also had display cases, exhibits and maps that explained the history of the area as well as the surrounding grand crus to help familiarize folks with the region.  As I had arrived soon after the building opened and on a weekday, I was left to my own devices for a while.  After inhaling a bit of history, it was time to head to the counter and taste some wines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/3-1050by788-30d40c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/3-700by525-30d40c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/3-675by506-30d40c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/3-450by338-30d40c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/3-525by394-30d40c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/3-350by263-30d40c.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/3-350by263-30d40c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Ready when they are&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view from the tasting counter.  There really isn’t a set tasting menu - you mostly just tell them what you are interested in and what you want to taste and they’ll usually pour it for you.  I may have taken it a bit too far as you can see from the number of wines I wrote about&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At most wineries in the area, there is usually a tasting menu or whoever is pouring for you will choose a lineup of the portfolio.  Here, there are so many wines on the list that it’s not really possible to do either.  Since I looked like I knew what I was doing (taking notes on the laptop helped with that impression), they let me taste around on the list until they got busier.  A shout-out to the two people that ran my tasting below - I got to try a number of really interesting wines thanks to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/4-1050by788-0d8f6d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/4-700by525-0d8f6d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/4-675by506-0d8f6d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/4-450by338-0d8f6d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/4-525by394-0d8f6d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/4-350by263-0d8f6d.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/4-350by263-0d8f6d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Thank you for the great tasting!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The kind folks that ran my tasting for the morning.  I was there bright and early, and as a result got a lot of attention and pours until other customers started arriving.  I had made it through a good port of the menu by then though, haha.  It was also impressive how fluent they were in German and English - I wish I was that smart.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, the wines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boutique.vins-ribeauville.com/en/vin-et-cremant-alsace/alsace-sparkling-wine/cremant-giersberger-brut/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cremant Giersberger Brut&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (8.95€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A sparkling blend of Pinot Blanc and Pinot Auxeroiss.  Light green apple aromas on the nose with very high acid and flavors of green apple, lemon, lime and similar notes on the palate.  I didn’t get any minerality, but the high acid could obscure that.  A good choice served cold on a hot day in Alsace.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boutique.vins-ribeauville.com/en/vin-et-cremant-alsace/alsace-sparkling-wine/cremant-la-grande-cuvee/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cremant La Grande Cuvee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (18.70€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Vin de France reviewed this wine at 14.5/20.  A Pinot Noir + Chardonnay blend with more complexity going on aromatically than the Giersberger.  It still leans on the lighter, fruity side rather than secondary/tertiary aromas.  The palate displays that brioche character from lees aging for a significant period, but the wine still has plenty of warm yellow fruit on the palate.  The acid is very high, leading me to believe they skipped MLF before the 72 months in the cellar.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boutique.vins-ribeauville.com/en/vin-et-cremant-alsace/collection-en-2/muscat-collection-sec/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Muscat Collection 2017 SEC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (8.35€
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose on this wine is downright powerful.  Orange, blossoms, and all the other notes you expect from a blend of Muscat Ottonel and d’Alsace.  The body and acid are smooth and hold up the wine wonderfully.  I would love to serve this as an aperitif for meals because of its huge aromatics, dryness and easy drinking.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Pinot Blanc Barriques&lt;/strong&gt; (8.80€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Spends a year in barrel unlike most Pinot Blanc from the region.  Thanks to this aging, the aromatics are exponentially greater than their other traditional Pinot Blanc.  Apple pie, coconut, light spice and vanilla character dominate the nose.  The palate is as or more intense than the nose.  People may not like this wine because it’s so big and different.  But because of its unusual profile, you know I bought a couple bottles…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boutique.vins-ribeauville.com/en/vin-et-cremant-alsace/lieux-dits-et-villages-vin-de-reserve/riesling-haguenau/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Riesling Lieu Dit Haguenau&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (10.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;High pitched intensity aromas of lemon, petrol and maybe some almond oil as well, but the fruit was much more subdued than I was expecting.  High acid and intensity of the same flavors on the palate.  I really enjoyed the complexity and that fact that neither the primary or tertiary flavors were dominant - a nicely balanced wine at 5 years old.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boutique.vins-ribeauville.com/en/vin-et-cremant-alsace/riesling-en/riesling-comtes-de-ribeauville-2010/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2010 Riesling Comtes De Ribeauville&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (9.30€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Similar notes to the Lieu Dit Haguenau on the nose, but the Comtes is a bit deeper and richer with almond milk notes and reveals more petrol plus minerality.  The acidity is quite a bit less which enhances the richness of the coconut, almond, and petrol a bit more.  The lemon and yellow fruit take a backseat here to the tertiary character and that is not a bad thing…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boutique.vins-ribeauville.com/en/vin-et-cremant-alsace/riesling-en/riesling-grand-cru-osterberg/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Riesling Grand Cru Osterberg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (20.20€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bright, light stonefruit and petrol notes on the nose.  The palate is similar in profile with a little white spice on the finish as well.  I need to call out the balance of the acid, body, and alcohol here - they are already integrating very well.  The acid is higher than the Kirhcberg, which makes this more refreshing and easy to pair in a meal, but the balance also means you can easily enjoy this wine by itself.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boutique.vins-ribeauville.com/en/vin-et-cremant-alsace/riesling-en/riesling-grand-cru-kirchberg-2016/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Riesling Grand Cru Kirchberg de Ribeauville&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (19.70€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;High intensity stone fruit with undulating coconut oil, and a light layer of petrol on the nose.  You can pick out the stonefruit but it’s very well integrated.  The palate emphasizes the stonefruit but is balanced by the acid so that is doesn’t taste/feel overly ripe for a Riesling.  Like the Osterberg, this is also very smooth and has a strong medium+ body for a Riesling.  Enjoy this wine by itself - it deserves it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boutique.vins-ribeauville.com/en/vin-et-cremant-alsace/riesling-en/riesling-grand-cru-rosacker/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Rosacker Riesling Grand Cru&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (15.20€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This Riesling is on the lighter/creamier side.  The stonefruit comes right out on both the nose and palate.  This wine is so well rounded, I’m guessing it may have a tiny bit of residual sugar that balances the high acidity and gives that mouthfeel that roundness.  The flavor of the wine is similar to the others with its stonefruit, vanilla, and coconut notes.  But it is the tactile roundness that distinguishes this wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Riesling Vendanges Tardives&lt;/strong&gt; (17€ for 500mL)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Their late harvest Riesling.  The acidity feels just right on the palate and the flavors are balanced between the fruit and the petrol.  The acidity is still high and gives the wine that clean finish which keeping the nose a bit lighter than the other Rieslings.  This is a sweet wine, but it’s not too sweet.  Combining that character with the high acid and medium(+) body, this would make a great dessert wine but I could see myself drinking it by itself too.  Again, the balance here is key…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boutique.vins-ribeauville.com/en/vin-et-cremant-alsace/great-vintage/pinot-gris-grand-cru-kirchberg/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Pinot Gris Grand Cru Kirchberg de Ribeauville&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (17.20€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bright, light, ripe yellow fruit on the nose with medium(-) intensity.  I’m guessing that there is some residual sugar because the palate seems beyond ripe with the stonefuit and melon.  Though I really appreciate the beeswax and honeycomb that is here too.  Medium acid that rounds out the mid/back palate.  This is definitely a ripe, complex wine that US drinkers would like and need more exposure to.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boutique.vins-ribeauville.com/en/vin-et-cremant-alsace/great-vintage/pinot-gris-grand-cru-altenberg-de-bergheim-2015-casher/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2010 Pinot Gris Grand Cru Altenberg de Bergheim&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (18.40€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The deep color on this is almost of a late-harvest wine.  High intensity aromatics of pineapples and other tropical fruit.  This wine had everything working for it: 2010 was a great ripe year, Altenberg is one of their best grand crus, and Pinot Gris is a very aromatic grape.  Put them altogether and its no wonder this smells like a late harvest wine.  Because of the ripeness, the palate seems to lack the acid necessary to age this wine, though the residual sugar may help.  If you want a sweet wine without the thick body or pure sugar flavor, this is a great wine to try.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boutique.vins-ribeauville.com/en/vin-et-cremant-alsace/clos-du-zahnacker-en/clos-du-zahnacker-2012/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Clos du Zahnacker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (23.20€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Clos du Zahnacker wines are from a very special plot of co-planted varietals on very old vines that produce very distinctive wines.  The nose on the 2012 is very soft and integrated.  The palate mirrors that integration with medium(+) acid and a very smooth palate.  This wine is as complex as you want it to be - the deeper you dig into the integrated whole, the more pieces you begin to feel out.  By the same token, you can also sit back and just enjoy this as a easy drinking wine if you don’t want to think about it.  A great wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Clos du Zahnacker&lt;/strong&gt; (29€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The 2013 feels more dominated by the Gewurztraminer in the blend.  There is more intense varietal character here (though still medium intensity) and more acid than the 2012.  Building on that acid is a salinity in the wine as well.  The 2013 doesn’t quite have the integration and just seems a bit more clunky than the 2012, but that probably will smooth out over time.  Another wine that is very interesting to dive deep on and decompose.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Riesling Selection de Grains Nobles&lt;/strong&gt; (25€ for 500mL)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is much lighter than I was expecting, given its Riesling and an SGN at that.  And though the body is medium(+), the acid is still high.  Contrasting those contradictions, the flavors are much more balanced than I thought they would be, and without much petrol character.  Yes the wine is sweet, but it seemingly emphasizes the ripeness of the fruit more than the residual sugar content.  This is probably the first SGN I have had where I think (well, nay, I know) that I could drink more than one glass in a single sitting.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, this was quite a lineup that even I had a hard time getting through.  While all of the wines were solid (and some even more than that), the Clos du Zahnackers were just special.  A 4000 bottle production each year and exclusive property of the “Le Cave de Ribeauville” since 1935, located in the heart of the Grand Cru Osterberg vineyard.  It is said that Louis XIV liked this wine, which is a blend of Riesling, Pinot Gris, and Gewurztraminer that are grown intertwined and are pressed/vinified together.  I walked away with several bottles, which is saying a lot since I only had room for 16-20 wines in my luggage for a 3 week trip.  And when you see vineyards just down the street from the winery (see picture below), how could I not pick up multiple bottles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/5-1050by788-f666ab.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/5-700by525-f666ab.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/5-675by506-f666ab.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/5-450by338-f666ab.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/5-525by394-f666ab.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/5-350by263-f666ab.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/5-350by263-f666ab.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Which way did you think I went?&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;As I mention in other articles, the vines of Alsace are mostly planted on a slope facing south.  You can get a taste of the elevation of the vines and the slope from this selfie.  Which way do you think I decided to walk after checking out the sign?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the greatest surprise of all, even more than the great quality and variety that had at the winery, was the price on these wines.  Normally when you think of “Grand Cru” the price ends with at least two 0s.  But most of the Grand Crus here were under 20€!!  I literally asked multiple times that the prices listed were for 750mL (normal-sized) bottles, which they were.  The Vendange Tardives and Selection de Grains Nobles cost more than the other Grand Cru because they must be picked by hand, and therefore the labor costs / costs to produce the wines are higher.  Over the course of the tasting, I saw at least 20 different people come in, get a sample of a wine, buy a box of it, and walk out.  At these prices, I would too!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the shipping prices to the USA is prohibitively high.  I asked for the names of their distributors; Eastern Wine Distrubutors (NY) and Golden Ram LLC (NY) are the closest to my area.  I will be reaching out to them soon to see where I can find these wines in stores or if I can purchase from them directly because if the prices are anywhere near what I listed above, the quality will be well worth the price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do regret not spending more than a day in Ribeauville and it has been added to the top of my list to visit again.  The wineries in town are all rated very highly by travelers and by the wine ambassadors that work at the wineries.  And when you visit, please do not overlook Cave du Ribeauville.  I promise you will find something you like (as long as its a white wine, haha).  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="alsace" /><category term="ribeauville" /><summary type="html">Most people come to Ribeauville to visit Maison Trimbach, which is famous, has a large production each year, and has a good amount of distribution in the USA. I did too, but unfortunately Maison Trimbach was closed when I arrived in August. In fact, many wineries in France are closed for vacations between late July and mid-August before the harvest. Fortunately Cave de Ribeauville, the second largest place in town, was still open and I quickly diverted there out of the drizzling rain.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/cave-du-ribeauville/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bott Freres Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/03/09/bott_freres_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bott Freres Public Tasting" /><published>2019-03-09T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-09T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/03/09/bott_freres_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/03/09/bott_freres_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;The thing I love about Alsace is that most of the production comes from small, family-owned wineries.  This can be seen as a double-edged sword because while the styles and varieties on the market can be very different, the quality of production can be very different too.  Luckily, that isn’t really an issue in Alsace as the quality is consistently pretty high across the board.  Though you do find some wineries that just seem to be on another level.  Bott Freres may be my favorite winery in all of Alsace when you factor in the that none of the wines I tasted were above 20 Euros.  The Quality-Price Ratio (QPR) here is just astounding.  I know that is a strong statement and I truly hope that gets you to visit the winery if you ever find yourself in the Alsace region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/1-1050by788-3ac8bb.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/1-700by525-3ac8bb.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/1-675by506-3ac8bb.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/1-450by338-3ac8bb.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/1-525by394-3ac8bb.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/1-350by263-3ac8bb.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/1-350by263-3ac8bb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Bott Freres!!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Bott Freres is a short walk outside of the main area in Ribeauville, but you need to make it here.  Like I said earlier, Bott Freres may be my favorite small producer in Alsace, so be sure to stop by if you are in order around town.  The large sign helps it stick out once you get on the correct street!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it hadn’t been for my waiter at lunch, I might not have discovered Bott Freres!  I hadn’t seen the winery during my earlier walk through the city center.  Unlike many wineries in the Alsace region, the storefront for Bott Freres isn’t along the main street in town, nor does it have a huge building or signs in town pointing to it like Cave du Ribeauville or Domaine Trimbach.  You need to walk a little ways (half a mile) off the main street to find the storefront.  During my walk, I was a bit unlucky because the skies opened up and it felt like the city was going to flood for a good ten minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/2-1050by1400-0d9baf.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/2-700by933-0d9baf.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/2-675by900-0d9baf.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/2-450by600-0d9baf.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/2-525by700-0d9baf.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/2-350by467-0d9baf.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/2-350by467-0d9baf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;The wine ambassador&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The wine ambassador with a really instructive map of the region.  As you can see, there are many wineries along the Vosges Mountain range.  Unfortunately, I did not spend enough time in Alsace, nor did I have a car to explore the smaller towns that didn’t have train stations nearby.  I will be back…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a bit of a mess upon my arrival, but Gladys (their wine ambassador) was kind enough to find me a towel so I could clean myself up as much as possible.  Having done so, I started telling her my story and explaining why I had no vehicle with me…  As we chatted, we started nerding out about all things wine and she was happy to share more details about Alsace that I hadn’t picked up from other wineries, hence the picture with the map above.  Gladys hadn’t traveled outside the country yet, but I think she was paying it forward to a wine traveler and took the extra time to discuss why she decided to join Bott Freres over any other winery.  It turns out she had joined the wine business straight out of high school and while her parents own a vineyard, they sell the fruit they cultivate to bigger wineries.  It’s too bad we didn’t swap contact info - her dreams of getting into the production side of the industry are very similar to my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like other wineries in the region, Bott Freres has been family operated for quite a while.  In fact, the Bott family have been winegrowers in the region since 1835!  Back in those days, being a wine grower was a tradecraft passed down from parents to children, with skills and practices developed and honed over the course of time.  These practices include sustainable agriculture (see: Biodynamic/Organic) and respect what nature gives you, rather than exerting your will upon the land.  The tasting room and building share that same vibe/feeling.  Though, Bott Freres can accomodate up to 50+ people at a time - there is lots of room in the back!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the pleasant conversation and no longer feeling like a wet dog, it was time to start the tasting.  I want to point out that there are times when my palate is a little off after a meal where wine (especially sparkling / white wine) is not as enjoyable as they normally are.  I had no issues with that during this tasting after lunch, which I think is further proof to how good these wines were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bott-freres.fr/en/product/muscat-tradition-2017/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Muscat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (11.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A 50/50 blend of Muscat d’Alsace and Muscat Ottonel.  Very fragrant with notes of the usual aromas (e.g. orange, blosson, etc.).  The mouthfeel is very nice with medium(+) acidity, medium body and a long, lingering finish of white flowers and honeysuckle.  The dryness and high acid makes the flower and honeysuckle feel very pronounced on the palate.  A solid Muscat rendition that has no flaws, is very well balanced and dry.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bott-freres.fr/en/product/riesling-reserve-personnelle-2016/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Riesling Reserve Personnelle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (11.60€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is a little restrained for a Riesling.  The palate is driven by green fruit and high-pitched yellow fruit, with little petrol influence.  Adding to the complexity is a minerality and touch of spice.  Because the wine has a lower intensity, I feel like this could be an easy drinking wine on a hot day with its rounded palate and medium(+) acidity for that crisp finish.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bott-freres.fr/en/product/riesling-grand-cru-kirchberg-de-ribeauville-2016/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Riesling Grand Cru Kirchberg de Ribeauville&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (23.30€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;More fragrant than the Reserve Personnelle, the Kirchberg emphasizes stonefruit and some petrol.  The body is also a bit more viscous, but the main differentiator is the salinity (Kirchberg is primarily limestone).  That salinity and yellow fruit linger for 30+ seconds on the finish, which is very impressive.  The rest of the flavor profile and acidity are similar to the Personnelle above.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bott-freres.fr/en/product/riesling-grand-cru-osterberg-2016/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Riesling Grand Cru Osterberg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (21.30€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Similar to the Kirchberg, but more rounded and less pronounced.  According to Gladys, the diurnal range for Kirchberg is greater than Osterberg, which is why you perceive more acidity and greater intensity in the Kirchberg.  While I would serve the Kirchberg to friends with dinner, the Osterberg is the bottle I’d open if I wanted to enjoy a bottle without a food pairing.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bott-freres.fr/en/product/cremant-dalsace-brut-blanc-de-noirs/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NV Blanc de Noirs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (16.10€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Solid body with aggressive, mousy bubbles.  The palate has trace of red fruit, but the high acid and rampant bubble make it tough to feel out the full range of flavors.  I doubt it’s undergone MLF because of the acidity, but some lees aging makes sense.  Not my favorite sparkling wine from the Alsace region.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bott-freres.fr/en/product/gewurztraminer-reserve-personnelle-2016/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Gewurztraminer Reserve Personnelle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (15.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Aromatic and pronounced on the palate, but very smooth.  The full range of flavors from the Gewurztraminer varietal are on display in this wine up to orange marmalade.  The acidity isn’t noticeable until the finish, but it helps shape the round body.  The finish also goes on for 20+ seconds with white spice emerging as well.  The balance on this Gewurztraminer is what impresses me the most - normally something feels out of place but all of the parts fit together perfectly in this wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bott-freres.fr/en/product/riesling-vendanges-tardives-2011/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2011 Riesling Vendanges Tardives&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (31.70€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This wine is just stunning.  I daresay it surpasses all the other VT and Selection Grain Nobles Rieslings that I have had in terms of flavor intensity (ripe peach and stonefruit) and acidity.  The prominent acid leaves you with a tingling sensation that surpasses the duration of the 30+ second finish.  No noticeable petrol notes or they take a back seat to the fruit at least.  This needs to be a dessert wine at a Michelin restaurant.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had to sum up the experience, the style of Bott Freres lies in the purity of expression.  This applies to both the varietal character that their sustainable agriculture nurtures and the sense of place described in the terroir driven tertiary notes.  You hardly notice any human intervention in these wines which is quite the achievement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/3-1050by788-f5db19.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/3-700by525-f5db19.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/3-675by506-f5db19.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/3-450by338-f5db19.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/3-525by394-f5db19.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/3-350by263-f5db19.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/3-350by263-f5db19.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Selfie Time!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It was raining most of the day in Ribeauville, which was a little unusual…  Most of the townspeople were excited for it, so I didn’t mind walking through it.  It’s really hard not to smile when you drink great wine, meet nice people, and just see beautiful history and nature all around you…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I could not purchase all of the wine I wanted thanks to the expensive shipping costs; it’s 202 Euros for shipping and taxes to ship a case to the USA directly from the winery.  Their distributors in the USA (at the time of this writing) are Wine Universe (NY) and DB Wine Selection, who is based in the Northeast USA and is both an importer and distributor.  Of the wines I tried, their Muscat, Reserve Personnelle Gewurztraminer and Riesling Vendages Tardives were the ones I craved multiple bottles of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, if you are in the area, Bott Freres is a must visit.  Please take the opportunity to explore off the beaten path (or in this case, the main road in town) and enjoy!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="alsace" /><category term="ribeauville" /><summary type="html">The thing I love about Alsace is that most of the production comes from small, family-owned wineries. This can be seen as a double-edged sword because while the styles and varieties on the market can be very different, the quality of production can be very different too. Luckily, that isn’t really an issue in Alsace as the quality is consistently pretty high across the board. Though you do find some wineries that just seem to be on another level. Bott Freres may be my favorite winery in all of Alsace when you factor in the that none of the wines I tasted were above 20 Euros. The Quality-Price Ratio (QPR) here is just astounding. I know that is a strong statement and I truly hope that gets you to visit the winery if you ever find yourself in the Alsace region.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/bott-freres/2.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Domaine des Marronniers Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/03/02/domaine_wach_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Domaine des Marronniers Public Tasting" /><published>2019-03-02T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-02T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/03/02/domaine_wach_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/03/02/domaine_wach_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Andlau may be a small town, but its vineyards and views are second to none in the Alsace region.  In addition, it is home to some of the most interesting Grand Crus of Alsace, which make it a must visit when traveling through Alsace.  There are a few wineries to possibly visit for a tasting in Andlau, but none have as comprehensive of a wine tasting menu as Domaine des Marronniers.  Their social media presence and website are also more up-to-date and accessible than many of its peers.  As luck would have it, I was staying in a hotel next door to the winery, so it only made sense for me to arrange a tasting and talk through their portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/1-1050by788-5d4bbd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/1-700by525-5d4bbd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/1-675by506-5d4bbd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/1-450by338-5d4bbd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/1-525by394-5d4bbd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/1-350by263-5d4bbd.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/1-350by263-5d4bbd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Obligatory Selfie&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;An obligatory selfie with some of vines.  The landscape of the Andlau region is quite something to behold.  Many of the vines in the region are planted on a southernly slope to maximize the amount of sunlight they capture with cool temperatures still keeping the acidity high.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many others in the region, Domaine des Marronniers is a family operation.  In fact, many entities (including Google) still refer to the winery as Domaine Wach (its owner Guy Wach changed the name from Domaine Wach in 1980).  But unlike many other wineries in the region, their ties to the world of wine go all the way back to 1748, before there was even a USA!  While their ancestors have long been barrel makers as their trade, more recent generations of the family have transitioned towards wine growing and making.  And they couldn’t have found a better place to settle down; of the quality land that surrounds them, Domaine Wach owns 17.8 acres, of which nearly 3 acres are Grand Cru classified.  Even more impressive is the average age of their vines (40+ years), which you’d more likely find for Old Vine Zinfandel, not Riesling and other white varietals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make sure that my palate was in top shape to enjoy the experience, I made a morning appointment.  Jessica, the wine ambassador, was very generous to open a little early for me so that I could catch my scheduled taxi to Ribeauville.  Jessica is a certified sommelier from Montreal, meaning that she is fluent in English and French.  This of course meant that in addition to talking about our shared love of wine and her chance meeting with the winemaker while working in New Zealand (which is how she ended up in Alsace), we had to talk about my love of hockey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/2-1050by788-ea8a96.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/2-700by525-ea8a96.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/2-675by506-ea8a96.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/2-450by338-ea8a96.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/2-525by394-ea8a96.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/2-350by263-ea8a96.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/2-350by263-ea8a96.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;The Wine Ambassador&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The tasting bar at Domaine Wach.  Just to the side, there is a large room with a grand dinner table that seems like it could hold 8-10 guests for a tasting and meal pairing.  I came in the morning, but the Wine Ambassador was happy to host me and opened a great array of wines that left me more thirsty than when I had arrived!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the fun chat, we both got strangely serious as she poured the first wine.  It was gametime and I was ready:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Andlau Muscat d’Alsace&lt;/strong&gt; (9.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A blend of Muscat d’Alsace and Muscat Ottonel.  The intensity of the nose is light for a Muscat, but its notes are in line with the varietal character.  The interesting thing is the palate, which stays crisp, dry and feels like a light white wine, rather than the traditional renditions of Muscat.  The balance between the aromas and mouthfeel without either feeling too big/heavy are what make this different.  Drink it cool while outside on a hot summer day.  The flavors dwell around the citrus range, leaning towards oranges.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Andlau Riesling&lt;/strong&gt; (9.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Slight petrol on the nose, but the aromas were a bit muted overall.  The flavors are a tad underripe (think grapefruit) with high acidity on the palate.  Their best QPR bottle in the Wine Ambassadors opinion - they opened a bottle of vintage 1998 recently and thought it aged fairly well for a non-Grand Cru bottle.  This is for those that don’t like their Rieslings too ripe.  Or in my mind, a “without wine, it’s just breakfast” type of bottle.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Grand Cru Wiebelsberg Riesling&lt;/strong&gt; (16.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is clearly more fragrant than the Andlau with white flowers and stonefruit coming out.  It also has a tad more flesh on the body, less noticeable acidity and more intensity on the palate.  This was just really smooth and a pleasure to drink; you can have this all year round as it doesn’t need to pair with any particular temperature or meal to get great enjoyment.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Grand Cru Moenchberg Riesling&lt;/strong&gt; (16.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Riesling and Pinot Gris from Moenchberg are the first to be ready for harvest each year where limestone permeates the soil.  This combination results in less fragrance and less fruit on the nose, though more white flower than the Wiebelsberg and tiny amounts of petrol.  The mouthfeel also has more mouthwatering acidity to go with the medium(-) intensity stonefruit.  While this wine is also very easy to drink, I would pair it with fish and enjoy closer to the summertime than the Wiebelsberg.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Grand Cru Kastelberg Riesling&lt;/strong&gt; (18.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The star of the still white wines.  As mentioned above, the limited acreage means only 5 wineries get to work with these grapes that are grown on blue schist.  The QPR for this bottle is off-the-charts.  The salinity and minerality on the nose and palate are quite something and had me craving seafood for lunch…  Those notes paired with the acidity stimulates the cheeks for more than a minute on the finish, like something touched the funnybone of your cheeks.  You can cellar this for 20+ years and it will still be good, though obviously with more petrol notes.  I normally prefer fruit forward wines, but I had to have multiple bottles of this wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NV Cremant d’Alsace&lt;/strong&gt; (9.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Alsace is the largest producer of cremant in France, with cremant representing over 20% of Alsace’s total wine production.  This one is 70% Chardonnay, 30% Pinot Blanc.  The winemaker wanted to produce a bottle that pairs well with meals without relying on high acidity (ie. didn’t want to use Riesling).  This spends 24 months on the lees gaining texture and flavor and is finished at 6 g/L RS (residual sugar), adding to the balance and body.  The nose immediately brings up thoughts of delicate cream and MLF.  The palate is voluminous with creamy mousse and the flavors are consistent with the nose plus flavors of semi-ripe green/yellow fruit and medium(+) acidity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2006 Grand Cru Wiebelsberg Riesling Selection de Grains Nobles&lt;/strong&gt; (32.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Using Riesling for an SGN is unusual - most of the SGNs I came across while in Alsace were either Pinot Gris or Gewurztraminer, so this is was a happy surprise!  I really liked this wine because of the additional acidity provided by the Riesling that helped to balance and cut through the sweetness on the finish.  Also, the nose was very aromatic with the petrol and botrytis notes basically leaping from the glass.  Those flavors carry onto the palate with some honeyed notes as well.  Of note, the body isn’t unctuous like other SGNs.  The varietal character just adds another dimension and balance to this SGN making it hard to resist.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to Marc Kreydenweiss, even though this is one of the larger producers in the area and has a good portion of the coveted plantings in Kastelberg, its production level is still small by American standards (their total production is roughly 45,000 bottles annually).  That is a real shame because the QPR on all of these wines is really good, even for the SGN in my opinion.  But the biggest shame is that I don’t believe there is an American distributor for this winery and the shipping cost per case to the USA is 180€ - nearly 15€ a bottle!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend stopping by Andlau in Alsace for a day if you have the chance.  And make sure you have some space in your luggage, because if you love any of the bottles you taste here, that’s the likely way you’ll be able to bring the bottles you like back home with you, haha.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="alsace" /><category term="andlau" /><summary type="html">Andlau may be a small town, but its vineyards and views are second to none in the Alsace region. In addition, it is home to some of the most interesting Grand Crus of Alsace, which make it a must visit when traveling through Alsace. There are a few wineries to possibly visit for a tasting in Andlau, but none have as comprehensive of a wine tasting menu as Domaine des Marronniers. Their social media presence and website are also more up-to-date and accessible than many of its peers. As luck would have it, I was staying in a hotel next door to the winery, so it only made sense for me to arrange a tasting and talk through their portfolio.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/domaine-wach/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Domaine Marc Kreydenweiss Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/23/marc_kreydenweiss_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Domaine Marc Kreydenweiss Private Tasting" /><published>2019-02-23T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-23T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/23/marc_kreydenweiss_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/23/marc_kreydenweiss_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Without a doubt, there are many wineries along the northern Alsacian trail that serve great wine.  But Domaine Marc Kreydenweiss is near the top of my list for places that you should stop at.  Midway between Mittelbergheim and the center of the Andlau region, this small organic/biodynamic producer churns out great wine, year after year.  Domaine Marc Kreydenweiss has been managing their 14 hectares this way since 1989 - they’ve been doing it for so long that they had input into the actual definition of both organic and biodynamic farming for wine since there were only a few vineyards that were attempting / executing this vision back then.  Organic and Biodynamic wines have been all over the map for me (some great, some bad), but these were definitely some of the better ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/1-1050by788-10b31c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/1-700by525-10b31c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/1-675by506-10b31c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/1-450by338-10b31c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/1-525by394-10b31c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/1-350by263-10b31c.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/1-350by263-10b31c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;On the road to Kreydenweiss!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Walking the back paths off of the highway to Domaine Marc Kreydenweiss.  Again, normally a mile walk is fine, but when you are carrying your luggage with you, it’s a little more difficult.  There are NO ubers out here, so find the phone numbers of the 1-2 taxi drivers in town and make use of them!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/2-1050by788-19bbc1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/2-700by525-19bbc1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/2-675by506-19bbc1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/2-450by338-19bbc1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/2-525by394-19bbc1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/2-350by263-19bbc1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/2-350by263-19bbc1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Selfie time!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It was a tough (and hot) walk, but that doesn’t mean I disliked it…  The views along the path were just stunning and cut right through the vineyards.  There’s a common understanding to not touch the vines, but the level of trust to let people walk through the vineyards is still stunning.  I know, I am practically glowing with excitement…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, because their wine is of such quality, you can sometimes find it in the American market or in restaurants that sport a healthy white wine menu, even though their production isn’t all that high; their annual production comes in around 70,000 bottles.  They have successfully grown over the past 30+ years and now own vineyards in the Rhone Valley as well!  Because the Rhone vineyards are still up-and-coming, Marc’s eldest son manages and produces the wines from his Alsacian holdings (since 2007) while Marc and his younger son live in the south and manage the Rhone Valley vineyards.  Don’t fret for their family though; both sites are separated only by a ~3-hour train ride.  And if you were to ask me, the eldest son got the better part of the deal - it is just gorgeous here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/3-1050by1400-068cd6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/3-700by933-068cd6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/3-675by900-068cd6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/3-450by600-068cd6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/3-525by700-068cd6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/3-350by467-068cd6.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/3-350by467-068cd6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Make sure you have your international data plan on as the entrance can be a little hard to find.  Try to make a reservation ahead of time too if only to confirm that someone is at the building when you will be dropping by.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you make it into the town area, finding the actual winery (it’s more like a wine shop) can be a little tough, but if you stay true to Google Maps, you should be fine.  I highly recommend making reservations to ensure that they are open and have wines available for you to taste on arrival.  Once you check in at the front, you’ll head upstairs with your wine ambassador for the tasting.  The size, experience, and foot-traffic is very different from USA wineries, but is very typical of smaller wineries in the less visited locations of Europe.  I myself enjoy the more personal experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/4-1050by788-d1830a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/4-700by525-d1830a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/4-675by506-d1830a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/4-450by338-d1830a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/4-525by394-d1830a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/4-350by263-d1830a.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/4-350by263-d1830a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It really isn’t a winery as much as their wine tasting room and storefront.  You could easily purchase a bottle and a cheese board and enjoy sitting inside.  Do not expect grand estates along Alsace - most of the wineries are small and family run.  But the wine quality matches up with best so don’t judge a book by its cover.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you take a walk outside with the wine ambassador for a quick overview of the region, you’ll notice that the altitude at the bottom here is ~100m with a hill that goes up to 400m.  You can also see the Kastelberg and Wiebelsberg Grand Crus nearby.  Auxerrois (more fruit, less acid) and Pinot Blanc (more acid, less fruit) are co-planted in the vineyard - a planting style that harkens back to olden times when this was done as a risk-aversion method.  Higher variety in the vineyard meant a greater chance something would survive a challenging growing season.  When you walk through the vineyards, you can clearly see the different rocks/soil-types that the grapes are grown in: pink sandstone in Weibelsberg, black slate in Kastelberg, with marl and limestone in Moenchberg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/5-1050by788-2eb4fa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/5-700by525-2eb4fa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/5-675by506-2eb4fa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/5-450by338-2eb4fa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/5-525by394-2eb4fa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/5-350by263-2eb4fa.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/5-350by263-2eb4fa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A topographical breakdown of the area of Alsace I (and Domaine Marc Kreydenweiss) were in.  As you can see, there are many different Grand Cru and other demarcated areas in the region.  The terroir is very different across small patches of land (similar to Burgundy), so track where you are and where your Alsacian wine is from very carefully.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the introduction to the family, the vineyards, the grapes, and the biodynamic management/production methods, it was time to introduce the wines!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Kritt Pinot Blanc&lt;/strong&gt; (11.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Ripe fruit on the nose that almost hits pineapple, with lots of cooked yellow fruit too.  Meant to be a simple wine for a simple meal with its high acidity and refreshing profile.  Pinot Blanc is 30% their production.  Kritt is a very stoney place with lots of quartz in the ground and cool winds that blow through.  That acidity is crazy for the amount of ripe fruit in the wine, plus the minerality adds complexity too.  I can see why this is their best-seller and why they produce so much of it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt; (14.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The fruit is not from their vineyard as they don’t grow any Pinot Noir.  True to their beliefs though, they purchase the grapes from other biodynamic vineyards in the area.  Aromas of strawberry and terroir/wildness that is indicative of biodynamic wines.  The feet-crushed grapes, rustic winemaking style and low sulfite content, especially for a Pinot Noir, lead to this wild flavor that leaves you in disbelief.  If you are looking for complexity, this has it with high acidity to boot.  I personally don’t prefer the off-taste of biodynamic wines, but this one isn’t as pronounced as the others I’ve had in the past.  You don’t need to twist my arm to offer me a second glass…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Clos Rebberg (Riesling)&lt;/strong&gt; (23.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Clos Rebberg has terroir of blue/gray schist with lots of small layers and is the oldest geological formation in the area.  It’s interesting that Kreydenweiss replanted their Pinot Gris with Riesling because the animals would eat the grapes (Pinot Gris is sweeter with less acid and less petrol).  You can feel the petrol notes here but the yellow fruit and wild flavors are stronger with high acid, a nice hint of white pepper on the finish, and good minerality.  This is not a fruit driven wine - there is too much complexity to classify it that way.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Kritt Gewurztraminer&lt;/strong&gt; (18.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is a bit prettier and higher in acidity than other Gewurztraminers I’ve had.  The palate is very clean – this bottle is one that you pair in a meal as it’s not too intense that it would overwhelm its paired dish.  Though, it is a bit light in intensity on the palate, so I wouldn’t choose this wine over some other Gewurztraminers from the region for enjoying a glass by itself.  Gewurz means “spice” in German and this wine lives up to that with its white pepper.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Wiebelsberg Grand Cru (Riesling)&lt;/strong&gt; (28.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wiebelsberg has a south-facing steep slope with soil made of pink sandstone that doesn’t retain water very well.  The pink sandstone appears everywhere in the village because it’s easy to shape / work with.  Women built the church here in town, which gave the area is its name: hill (berg) of the lady (wiebel).  Again, some petrol varietal character but spice on the nose too.  The fruit is more muted than the Clos Rebberg, though it has decent length with fresh yellow fruit, some stonefruit, and white spice on the palate and finish.  High, refreshing acid gives it a nice crisp finish as well.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Kastelberg Grand Cru (Riesling)&lt;/strong&gt; (45.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Kreydenweiss balances the lack of sulfur used with CO2 in this wine, which is why it sometimes bubbles when you decant it.  Kastelberg is very rocky (black schist) and the soil is poor, so they minimize yields to protect the vineyards.  The Kastelberg Grand Cru is 5 hectares and is only Riesling (Kreydenweiss owns 1 hectare).  I haven’t decanted too many white wines before, so this was a treat.  That decanting does help it open up and gives it a creamier feel on the palate.  Although the acid is high, this wine is still super smooth - it undergoes MLF and 18 mths aging on the lees to smooth out the acid while adding complexity, though the MLF notes were near invisible to me.  There is even some tartaric acid as well from the skins because they gently squeeze the grapes for 10 hours in the pneumatic press.  This wine tastes like it’s their flagship wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Quality-Price Ratio (QPR) for these wines are quite good as high quality white wines in the USA traditionally cost markedly more.  In addition, finding Biodynamic wines of this caliber is not an easy proposition, though it is getting better as more people practice it and get a better feel for it.  I myself walked away with a few bottles, keen to share them with friends that would appreciate the ideals behind the wines in addition to the wines themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For wines that are harder to find, I’ll try to include the distributor information so that you might try to reach out to them directly if you want to pursue purchasing any bottles.  For Marc Kreydenweiss, the closest importer/distributor to the DMV is Williams Corner in Charlottesville, Virginia.  But if you ever find yourself in that part of France, you should absolutely stop by for a visit and some education.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="alsace" /><category term="andlau" /><summary type="html">Without a doubt, there are many wineries along the northern Alsacian trail that serve great wine. But Domaine Marc Kreydenweiss is near the top of my list for places that you should stop at. Midway between Mittelbergheim and the center of the Andlau region, this small organic/biodynamic producer churns out great wine, year after year. Domaine Marc Kreydenweiss has been managing their 14 hectares this way since 1989 - they’ve been doing it for so long that they had input into the actual definition of both organic and biodynamic farming for wine since there were only a few vineyards that were attempting / executing this vision back then. Organic and Biodynamic wines have been all over the map for me (some great, some bad), but these were definitely some of the better ones.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/marc-kreydenweiss/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Domaine Albert Seltz Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/16/albert_seltz_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Domaine Albert Seltz Private Tasting" /><published>2019-02-16T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-16T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/16/albert_seltz_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/16/albert_seltz_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;The first stop on my Alsace + Rhone wine vacation.  Straight off the train from Strasbourg, I walked half a mile with all of my luggage to get here.  The backwoods path was beautiful but carrying three bags will put a damper on enjoying that.  Even though I was traveling in the fall and the temperature was relatively cool, the intensity of the sun was fairly strong as the vineyards of Alsace are generally planted on southern facing slopes next to the Vosges Mountain range to absorb as much of the light as possible, leading to ripe fruit development but keeping their acid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/1-1050by788-fbc2f4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/1-700by525-fbc2f4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/1-675by506-fbc2f4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/1-450by338-fbc2f4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/1-525by394-fbc2f4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/1-350by263-fbc2f4.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/1-350by263-fbc2f4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Walking to the Winery&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I decided to make my way through Alsace without renting a car.  Which meant that I had to walk over a mile from the train station with all of my luggage to the winery.  And then I had to walk another mile to my hotel.  Still, the views while walking were like this the whole time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/2-1050by788-6a955a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/2-700by525-6a955a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/2-675by506-6a955a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/2-450by338-6a955a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/2-525by394-6a955a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/2-350by263-6a955a.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/2-350by263-6a955a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Welcome to Mittelbergheim&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I was so happy to finally see this sign.  I didn’t realize that Mittelbergheim had so many wineries within the town.  I wish I knew so I could’ve spent more time exploring…  It’s definitely on my list of things to do if/when I return to Alsace!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking through the town of Mittelbergheim, I saw that there were at least 8 other wineries within walking distance to Albert Seltz.  I did not get the chance to check if they were open / spoke English / were available for tastings, so Albert Seltz ended up being my only stop in Mittelbergheim.  Though after discovering there were that many places in the area, I am emboldened to make a return visit and stay in town for an evening or two.  Though, it will be difficult to live up to Albert Seltz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/3-1050by788-ca2bb2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/3-700by525-ca2bb2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/3-675by506-ca2bb2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/3-450by338-ca2bb2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/3-525by394-ca2bb2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/3-350by263-ca2bb2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/3-350by263-ca2bb2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Written in Stone&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;On the one hand, I wish the sign was easier to see/read.  On the other hand, having a stone sign without any paint is a really classy move.  The cracks showing the age is also pretty cool.  I was really excited to get to tasting…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website has a quote from the owner: “The Sylvaner is a pretty girl from a poor family that does not interest the boy full of money is the disease of the 21st century.”  I totally understand where he is coming from - sometimes selling wine is a popularity contest where name recognition is everything for a consumer and can transitively affect the choices of the Producer.  Chardonnay, Sauvignon Blanc, Riesling… people are more likely to purchase something they have at least some tangential familiarity with.  It’s a good thing I went outside my own comfort zone as I’ve had some unimpressive Sylvaner before, but these wines totally changed my opinion about the varietal.  It made such an impression that I bought a few bottles with hopes of sharing with friends and spreading Albert’s message just a little further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heading into the winery, I was sad to find that there was (literally) no one home upon my arrival.  After waiting 30 minutes in the shade with their dog, a woman returning from the field was startled to discover me standing there - I had not called ahead for an appointment.  After collecting herself and learning I was an American on an Alsacian Wine Crusade, she guided me inside for a tasting.  Their tasting room doubled as their office, which had several desks and a small 4-stool tasting bar where we broke out some of the wines in their inventory.  NOTE: This was a family-run winery and didn’t have the infrastructure of a larger establishment.  It soon didn’t matter to me as the wines were very good and all I could think about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/4-1050by788-8db837.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/4-700by525-8db837.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/4-675by506-8db837.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/4-450by338-8db837.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/4-525by394-8db837.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/4-350by263-8db837.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/4-350by263-8db837.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Quenching the Thirst&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I don’t know if there is a better view.  To be alone in a winery with the undivided attention of the wine ambassador, drinking some amazing white wines and discussing the individuality of the winery and its wines.  The QPR on the wines are sooo good…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the tasting, we focused on their speciality: Sylvaner.  I think they are the only winery in the region that grows Grand Cru Sylvaner (I am likely mistaken there since there are so many producers), but it sure tasted like their specialty.  There was no formal menu, so your menu is likely to be different when you visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albert-seltz.fr/fiche.php?id=32&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Sylvaner de Mittelbergheim&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (9.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Has a lemon/lime and mineral profile, but with strong intensity and some white spice as well.  The aromas are a touch riper than the palate, but this makes a great summertime wine.  No green or vegetal notes, this wine finishes very fresh with that spice.  I know the notes read like a Sancerre and is similar except for the acidity (lower) and the minerality (it isn’t flint-like).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Sylvaner Zotzenberg Grand Cru Sono Contento&lt;/strong&gt; (16.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;There is definitely some petrol on the nose and less spice character than the first wine above, but there is definitely more complexity with the undertones and less reliance on the fruit character.  All of the notes are very subtle, even though the wine ambassador served this wine at the same temperature as a red wine.  Still great acidity and a little more body than the previous wine - I would love to retaste this without the aerobic exercise beforehand.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albert-seltz.fr/fiche.php?id=31&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Sylvaner Grand Cru Zotzenberg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (30.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Like the Zotzenberg except much more fruit/floral fragrance on the nose (e.g. in the honey/honeysuckle range).  This was just an all-around fantastic wine.  Really ripe stonefruit character (peach, honeysuckle) on the palate with great acidity that isn’t too soft/strong and provides structure.  The finish also goes on…  As someone who doesn’t like sweet wine but likes fruit (my American palate) and balance, I am really in love with this wine and would buy more immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Riesling Rebbuehl granite d’Andlau&lt;/strong&gt; (16.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Strong varietal character as I definitely get the petrol and rubber on the nose with the light yellow fruit and strong acidity.  This was served a little warmer than I am used to for Rieslings, but I think that also made the wine open more quickly.  This is a classic example of terroir-driven wine from Alsace - really like the minerality as well.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albert-seltz.fr/fiche.php?id=24&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Riesling Grand Cru Zotzenberg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (16.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;More fruit on the nose than the last Riesling - it’s almost a bit juicier and riper on the nose than the Sylvaner Grand Cru as well.  The palate is not as ripe as the nose, but there is still plenty of fruit and the finish is quite distinctive.  I wouldn’t say it’s flint but there is something terroir/mineral-related happening at the end.  That added complexity really stimulates the mind in a good way…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albert-seltz.fr/fiche.php?id=29&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2007 Sylvaner Veilles Vignes Colline aux Poiriers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (25.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Honey, ripe honeysuckle, beeswax, honeycomb, orange marmalade.  Not overly heavy on the finish like I was expecting; there is much more acidity to keep the balance intact.  That balance with the sweetness is really something something to dwell on as I’ve had many others that go over the top with the sweetness.  This wine may still be a little much for friends that don’t appreciate sweet wine, but I would not classify this as strictly a dessert wine.  I could easily pair this in a meal.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albert-seltz.fr/fiche.php?id=14&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Pinot Gris Grand Cru Zotzenberg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (16.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is not quite as ripe with honey/honeysuckle nor aromatically intense as some of the other wines, but it is definitely the smoothest out of all of them.  The finish just goes on…  You don’t really feel the acidity either, but that is perfectly fine since the wine is not cloying at all.  This is the kind of wine you could drink multiple bottles of in one sitting and not tire of its intensity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albert-seltz.fr/fiche.php?id=10&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Gewurztraminer Mon Ruisseau de Zanzibar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (25.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Very different from other Gewurztraminers in Alsace.  Not too much marmalade, nor too heavy.  The nose is a little less intense than the normal varietal character, but in a pleasurable way.  There is even a tickle of lemon zest too!  The body and finish have a flint-like character to them and do not finish over the top - the fruit is bright and finishes wonderfully with pineapple and stonefruit.  This is also an easy drinking without the feel of a sugar spike that can be utilized in many ways.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/5-1050by1400-b55b4e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/5-700by933-b55b4e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/5-675by900-b55b4e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/5-450by600-b55b4e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/5-525by700-b55b4e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/5-350by467-b55b4e.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/5-350by467-b55b4e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Sweet and Satisfying&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;There were a couple of wines that really struck me and both were of the same varietal that I haven’t liked in the past - Sylvaner.  This Grand Cru is the perfect balance of distinctive terroir, varietal and easy drinking.  I need a case of this.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/6-1050by1400-812bae.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/6-700by933-812bae.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/6-675by900-812bae.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/6-450by600-812bae.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/6-525by700-812bae.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/6-350by467-812bae.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/6-350by467-812bae.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;So good...&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The other wine that really struck me.  Old vines, older wine, and sweeter than the above Grand Cru, this wine is for the special occasion at the end of the night.  I really need to find their distributor!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a shame that I could not taste these great wines with the owner.  Other online reviews tell of an intimate experience, including touring their cellars and getting more into the philosophy of winemaking.  I am not the biodynamic purist that the owner is, but I would’ve really been interested in getting his thoughts on the matter, especially since all of these wines were done very well…  Normally I like to let the wines do the talking, but in this case, I would’ve liked the extra background and how we can achieve the same quality with these methods in the states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/7-1050by788-9c85b5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/7-700by525-9c85b5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/7-675by506-9c85b5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/7-450by338-9c85b5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/7-525by394-9c85b5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/7-350by263-9c85b5.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/7-350by263-9c85b5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Mandatory Selfie&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Obligatory selfie with the vines behind the winery.  It was pretty cool outside, but the sun was also pretty strong.  It’s probably how they have ripe wines with great acidity.  Seems like a great place to live and make wines.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself in Strasbourg and want to make a day trip for wine by train, you could do worse than Albert Seltz and Mittelbergheim in general.  Just be sure to make reservations by email before showing up so that you get the full experience with the winery owner and check whether they speak English for the tour or not.  I definitely recommend that you make your way into Alsace wine country and enjoy some really good white varietals, but especially Sylvaner since you can’t find it in the states!  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="alsace" /><category term="mittelbergheim" /><summary type="html">The first stop on my Alsace + Rhone wine vacation. Straight off the train from Strasbourg, I walked half a mile with all of my luggage to get here. The backwoods path was beautiful but carrying three bags will put a damper on enjoying that. Even though I was traveling in the fall and the temperature was relatively cool, the intensity of the sun was fairly strong as the vineyards of Alsace are generally planted on southern facing slopes next to the Vosges Mountain range to absorb as much of the light as possible, leading to ripe fruit development but keeping their acid.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/albert-seltz/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Paradigm Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/09/paradigm_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Paradigm Private Tasting" /><published>2019-02-09T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-09T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/09/paradigm_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/09/paradigm_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;I know many of you have never heard of Paradigm before, nor seen any of their bottles or signage in Napa.  But what if I said that Paradigm was the first winery that Heidi Barrett ever worked at and even after her long and illustrious career, she is still their winemaker?  If you follow winemakers like me, I hope that grabbed your attention.  If you need more background, read my article on La Sirena (Heidi’s personal label).  To sum up Paradigm, it is a small Oakville-based operation that owns 55 acres of vines and makes very compelling wines by allowing the varietals to express their quality and terroir influences with minimal winemaker intervention, which is only possible when you have great land, vines, and someone who is confident in what they are doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paradigm got started around the time Heidi was in school.  Her father Richard Peterson was (and still is) a famous winemaker specializing in Pinot Noir who worked with several wineries and did consultation work for others.  At the time, Ren (the owner) and Gene (his business partner) ran a lucrative vineyard real estate business together.  After enough time, they both decided to start their own wineries.  Ren called up Richard Peterson and asked for help getting the winery going.  Everything from building the business plan, to pitching financial institutions for the loans he needed, to designing the vineyard and equipping the facility, to being his winemaking consultant.  When you visit Paradigm, you’ll see that the building and winemaking facility are small and non-descript in comparison to others in the area.  They may be small but are very efficiently structured (everything is tight and compact) and isn’t lacking in any equipment.  As the other wineries grew and expanded around them, Paradigm has stayed relatively the same, which includes its small quantity, great quality, and very affordable prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/1-1050by788-4845aa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/1-700by525-4845aa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/1-675by506-4845aa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/1-450by338-4845aa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/1-525by394-4845aa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/1-350by263-4845aa.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/1-350by263-4845aa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The entrance to the winery&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I told you that the winery was non-descript on the outside.  Yes, this is the entrance as seen from the parking lot.  But don’t let this exterior fool you.  The wine quality will pleasantly surprise you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After helping out with the design and getting the winery close to the finish line, it was Richard’s turn to ask a favor.  At about this time, Heidi was just graduating school and needed a job in the winemaking world.  Getting your first gig is always the hardest, but Richard vouched for her skills and asked that she be given a shot as a favor to him.  After the first couple vintages, Ren realized that he actually owed Richard another favor because the wines Heidi was making were more than he could have hoped for.  Soon after, Ren got a call from his old partner Gene, asking if he knew of anyone that could help her with a stuck fermentation (it’s when the yeast doesn’t convert all the grape sugar into alcohol, leaving you with a 11% sweet red wine that you can’t sell).  Naturally, he talked about his rockstar winemaker and so Heidi went and got her first consulting gig fixing the fermentation.  Afterwards, Gene was so impressed that she hired Heidi to be their first full-time winemaker too.  Did I mention that Gene’s winery was called Screaming Eagle (now the most expensive wine made in America)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ren paid off the final loans of the winery 10+ years ago and how the tax laws work in Napa is that you are taxed each year based on how much you paid for the land/winery at the time of purchase.  Since Ren purchased the land back when there were only 30 wineries in Napa and land prices were dirt cheap compared to today, their taxes are very low by comparison to others, meaning they can pass the savings along to the consumer.  And that’s a pro-tip for visiting Napa - the next time you go, try to visit a winery that has been around for a long time and hasn’t changed hands.  They will nearly always be cheaper than everyone else; not because they wines aren’t as good, but because the cost to produce them is lower (and therefore they need to charge less to keep operations going).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/2-1050by788-a61dd0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/2-700by525-a61dd0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/2-675by506-a61dd0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/2-450by338-a61dd0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/2-525by394-a61dd0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/2-350by263-a61dd0.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/2-350by263-a61dd0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Getting lost in the vines&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;We had a chance to walk through the vineyard and see what is responsible for the great wine.  Since it was the brother-in-law on duty that day, we got to hear some great stories about the early history of the winery that I shared earlier in the article.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Heidi left the industry for a spell for family (raising her young daughters), it was Paradigm that was the first to offer her a job again to get back into the swing of things.  There is loyalty and a sense of family here which matches the size of the winery and the staffing (only the brother of the owner was working the Sunday afternoon I visited).  The tastings are one group at a time and you can’t hear anything except for the Napa Wine train that pass by every so often.  They have some equipment from UC Davis interleaved in the winery too (e.g. measuring aspiration to figure out how often to put out sulfur for protection in the vineyards).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After walking through the vineyards, we settled out on a picnic table outside and dug into the wines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Rose of Merlot&lt;/strong&gt; ($29)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Produced via the vin gris method – you press off the rosé once it has the right amount of color that they want, so it has more tannin, fruit and body.  This is different from the free run method of pulling off the wine from the bottom of the tank after crush.  Cold fermentation that lasts for 6 weeks until it reaches bone dry.  Beautiful salmon pink color with a medium+ intensity nose of strawberry and cranberry with a tickle of alcohol.  The palate is high intensity with medium+ acid and medium alcohol, but very little tannic influence.  There are no underripe notes at all.  A very smooth rosé with a little more body and the right amount of acid that can make a red wine lover happy.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.paradigmwinery.com/product/2014-Merlot&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Oakville Merlot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($53)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Rich red fruit on the nose with some spices and very little alcohol.  The same red fruit on the palate that still has medium+ acidity, the smallest green character, lots of plum, medium tannin that could soften a bit more with time, and alcohol/spice you can feel a bit.  It is a strange sensation drinking this wine - the more I sample, the more I want to drink it.  The acidity has a most peculiar mouth-watering effect (it almost feels like a craving) that is very pleasant.  Still, silky mouthfeel with some oak notes and a finish that goes on for quite a while.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.paradigmwinery.com/product/2014-Paravines&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Paravines&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($73)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;80% Merlot, 20% Petit Verdot.  Right off the bat, you can feel the deep juicy/jammy red fruit on the nose.  I don’t get any caramel on the nose like the tasting notes indicate, but that intertwined spruce/cedar is definitely present.  There is more tannin than the Merlot thanks to the Petit Verdot, but a similar level of acidity, though not quite the same sensation as the Merlot.  Really enjoyable red wine that has solid intensity of flavors and body all the way through the palate.  Some spices and tertiary characteristics make this a thinking wine instead of just bright fruit with acid and tannins.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.paradigmwinery.com/product/2014-Cabernet-Sauvignon&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($84)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Contrasting the Paravines, the Cabernet Sauvignon is much brighter on the nose, with predominantly red and black fruit.  There is some alcohol/spice sensation, but it complements the fruit well to create a warming effect.  The palate is medium bodied with medium tannin that feels very smooth but does dry the mouth slightly.  The acidity isn’t as present as the Merlot or Paravines, which makes this an easy drinking, really enjoyable Cabernet.  The intensity nor flavors aren’t anything unusual that will strike you as unique – it’s just very cohesive, well-balanced, and has no negatives to complain about.  At $84, this is a steal compared to a lot of other wines grown on the valley floor.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.paradigmwinery.com/product/2015-Cabernet-Franc&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Cabernet Franc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($71)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Only available to wine club members.  The color on this wine is incredibly deep and the nose is so fragrant with cool red cherry and raspberry that has slight candied notes.  The body is juicy with a medium body, medium tannin and medium acid with good length at the end.  If you like more fruit driven wines, this will blow you away, especially if you like the varietal character of Cabernet Franc.  Cabernet Francs are getting more popular in Napa, but this is definitely on the upper-end of quality for the Napa Valley region.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.paradigmwinery.com/product/2011-Cabernet-Sauvignon&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2011 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($113)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Paradigm did not pick early when the rains came during harvest time in 2011.  Instead they blow-dried the vines and let the last bit of sun get captured by the vines.  This resulted in a deeper richness in the 2011 that isn’t there on the 2014.  That additional hangtime also resulted in more black fruit than red fruit.  The wine definitely warms you up more than the 2014 too, though the higher alcohol is very subtle.  2011 wines gets a bad rap in the valley but those who didn’t panic and picked to early were rewarded for their patience and additional effort.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, the quality-price ratio (QPR) on these wines is very good and I highly recommend you visit.  After all, it’s in Oakville, which is one of the most expensive AVAs, and you can see Harlan just up the hill from your picnic table tasting (Harlan’s Cabernet goes for ~$800).  You can taste the quality of the terroir in these wines.  They have other wines that are not on the tasting menu as well - the Cabernet Franc isn’t normally available for tasting and I hear the Zinfandel is among the best in the entire valley!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tasting fee is among the cheapest in the valley too, so if you’ve read my other reviews and wish you had the capital to try them out, you can start by going here.  Though, once you taste the wines here, it may be very hard to go back to drinking other wines, haha.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="oakville" /><summary type="html">I know many of you have never heard of Paradigm before, nor seen any of their bottles or signage in Napa. But what if I said that Paradigm was the first winery that Heidi Barrett ever worked at and even after her long and illustrious career, she is still their winemaker? If you follow winemakers like me, I hope that grabbed your attention. If you need more background, read my article on La Sirena (Heidi’s personal label). To sum up Paradigm, it is a small Oakville-based operation that owns 55 acres of vines and makes very compelling wines by allowing the varietals to express their quality and terroir influences with minimal winemaker intervention, which is only possible when you have great land, vines, and someone who is confident in what they are doing.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/paradigm/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Inglenook Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/02/inglenook_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Inglenook Public Tasting" /><published>2019-02-02T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-02T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/02/inglenook_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/02/inglenook_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve had (the very affordable) Francis Coppola wines before and was skeptical of Inglenook even before reading the reviews by the major wine publications.  But I think you can officially change my status from skeptic to believer, because everything about this winery is impressive.  For example, when you make your way to the winery, Google Maps bring you to a small building that turns out to be the check-in desk where they confirm your reservation, give you a ticket to scan at the estate gate, and send you on your way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/1-1050by788-b4d3c5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/1-700by525-b4d3c5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/1-675by506-b4d3c5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/1-450by338-b4d3c5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/1-525by394-b4d3c5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/1-350by263-b4d3c5.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/1-350by263-b4d3c5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Where are you taking me?&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;For a while there, it seemed like the road would go on forever.  That’s definitely one way to heighten the expectations of visitors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The driveway is quite long and leads you to a large parking lot that is next to the largest campus I have seen in the Napa Valley so far.  What’s more, it contrasts wineries like Hall in that everything about the campus looks and feels historic.  The backstory of this land seems surreal when you hear about it, but once you explore and read the signs that are everywhere, you really start to understand that this land is special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/2-1050by788-8d83dd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/2-700by525-8d83dd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/2-675by506-8d83dd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/2-450by338-8d83dd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/2-525by394-8d83dd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/2-350by263-8d83dd.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/2-350by263-8d83dd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;So bright outside...&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;After parking in the large lot they have, you’ll walk past a large veranda on the way to the main winery building.  I know why that veranda exists now - it gets really bright outside and makes selfies tough.  And yes, those are grapevines over my shoulder.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/3-1050by788-0f73d2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/3-700by525-0f73d2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/3-675by506-0f73d2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/3-450by338-0f73d2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/3-525by394-0f73d2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/3-350by263-0f73d2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/3-350by263-0f73d2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Too much shade...&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I feel like Goldilocks; this angle has too much shade.  That shade is caused by the massive winery building, while behind me is the large open area that is perfect for mini-picnincs and enjoying bottles outside.  The resolution on my camera phone may be bad, but the view is really nice.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inglenook, or more accurately the winery that existed before it was purchased and named Inglenook, was founded by a Finnish animal fur trader in the 1850s, who had been responsibe for a vast amount of charting along the west coast.  He was a wine conneiseur, his wife a San Francisco socialite.  It’s no surprise that they compromised and moved from fur trading to operating a winery in Napa.  And it certainly wasn’t about the money - he wanted to show the world that he could make wines that could rival the world’s best in France.  This, a 100+ years before the Judgement of Paris.  Just hearing about the passion and history is enough to get you excited about the wines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Francis Coppola purchased the land, Robert Mondavi immediately called him to setup a dinner.  At this dinner, Mondavi proceeded to explain the history and potential to Francis, practically charging Coppola that he had the moral responsibility to restore Inglenook to its former glory.  After digging some 50+ year old wines out of the Inglenook cellar and tasting them with Mondavi, Coppola was convinced and so the dream was born.  And if that isn’t enough to get you excited, the current consulting winemaker (Philippe Bascaules) happens to be the President of Chateau Margaux, who now flies back to California every few months to make sure that Inglenook is producing amazing wines, as nature intended.  Coppola is also Italian – that’s why there is a Zindandel (known in Italy as Primitivo) here.  If you want French styled wine that just has great balance and takes avantage of Napa’s strengths, you need to try these wines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inglenook.com/Purchase/Details/BL16&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Blancaneaux&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($65)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A northern Rhone blend of Viognier, Marsanne, and Roussanne.  The fruit comes from Pritchet Hill (knob / giant hill), which is not to be confused with Pritchard Hill.  Pritchet Hill is the shadiest place in the Napa Valley (I know how that sounds), which is important for these varietals to shine.  There is almost no color at all to the wine and the nose is very light, reminiscent of French wine.  The palate has screaming high minerality, which makes the perception of the acidity maybe higher than it actually is.  There’s also decent fruit and a nice clean finish of yellow fruit (apple) and some stonefruit.  A really nice alternative to the Chardonnay/Sauvignon Blanc typically grown in the Napa Valley.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inglenook.com/Purchase/Details/RC15&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 RC Reserve Syrah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($62)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The RC stands for Roman Coppola, who is the eldest son and created this wine to be a cigar wine.  But obviously Syrah goes well with BBQ and other meats.  Deep red fruit and black pepper on the nose without any alcoholic heat.  The tannin makes the finish seem a little short initially, but on exhale, you still feel the wine.  Good medium+ body with some juicy flavor character.  The wood notes (e.g. cedar) are strong and integrated into the fruit as well.  This wine is very true to what Syrah is (without the wild game notes of the Northern Rhone) and doesn’t try to be overripe/candied to appease American palates.  50/50 aged in French and American oak.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inglenook.com/Purchase/Details/EP09&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2008 Magnum Edizione Pennino&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55 for a 750ml)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;100% Zinfandel and what a wine this is.  There is some much going on here - Fruitcake, forest floor and cedar are what I could pick out on the nose.  The palate is also wonderful with high intensity all the way through the palate and a good medium+ body every step of the way.  Very well balanced with really good integration of each component.  My advanced sommelier running the tasting said that their 2010 Zinfandel was the best Zinfandel ever made on the planet.  Judging by how good their 2008 is, I do not doubt it.  This may be one of the best Zins I have ever had (at least at the same level as Ridge/Turley).  The alcohol does not rear its head and the wine isn’t too candied.  A really amazing effort.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inglenook.com/Purchase/Details/CK15&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($78)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Rutherford (88% Cabernet), 100% French Oak.  The nose has a lot of rich medium bright red fruit with some dust, not unlike a lot of other Rutherford Cabs.  Ends cleanly with a shorter finish than others, but has that mouthwatering tingling acidity that begs you to drink more.  Definitely less fruit on the midpalate than others; it emphasizes a balance of the terroir character rather than dominating fruit, but it’s still really smooth and enjoyable.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inglenook.com/Purchase/Details/EP15&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Edizione Pennino&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($48)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Remove most of the teritary character from the 2008 Pennino described earlier and you get this wine.  Understandably, the fruit and acid are also sharper as the wine has not yet rounded into form, but you can already taste the potential.  I don’t really have much to say after the 2008 other than I’ll try checking in on this wine again in 10 years.  I still can’t believe I am talking about intentionally aging a Zinfandel…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inglenook.com/Purchase/Details/RB14&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Rubicon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($210)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wow, this really does remind me of a First Growth Bordeaux in so many ways.  The lower alcohol, the significant amount of tertiary notes on the mid-to-late palate and the nose that just hints at it.  This wine will probably peak in 20-30 years according to the Advanced Somm, though it can be aged well into its 40s.  It’s hard for me to see that though as it’s just so smooth right now and very approachable while showing off all the characteristics that you might expect from an aged wine.  Insider Tip for the wine collectors out there - the best vintages to look for (in order of greatness) 78, 79, 91, 95, 96, 01, 03, 04.  The Rubicon has a higher price point than many other wineries’ flagship wine, but I think it deserves it due to its complexity.  Though, the wine becomes more affordable with a Winery Membership (20% off!)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/4-1050by1400-dfa73f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/4-700by933-dfa73f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/4-675by900-dfa73f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/4-450by600-dfa73f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/4-525by700-dfa73f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/4-350by467-dfa73f.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/4-350by467-dfa73f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;There was none left for me...&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I feel like I needed to include a picture of this bottle in the post.  If you are wondering why, I’d recommend doing some research on the older Niebaum-Coppola wines that were released.  Then, you will understand…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After tasting the wines and regaining my bearings, I also started to notice details of the amazing building I was sitting in.  The building’s exterior sets your expectations high and the inside does not disappoint.  Before or after the tasting, you can navigate the cellars of the building and take a look at more history.  The tasting room itself feels 200+ years old and is staffed by professional Sommeliers who are dressed as if they were working in a three-star Michelin restaurant.  Their demeanor aside, you can tell that each one doesn’t just consider Inglenook a job - they sincerely believe that each wine is world-class and represents the best its varietal has to offer (e.g. Zinfandel, Cabernet, and the Northern Rhone white blend).  After all, one of the benefits of working at the winery is tasting the wines!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/5-1050by788-e29298.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/5-700by525-e29298.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/5-675by506-e29298.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/5-450by338-e29298.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/5-525by394-e29298.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/5-350by263-e29298.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/5-350by263-e29298.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;So many barrels&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view down the hallway inside their winery building.  As you can see from the walls in the picture, this building has been around for a very long time.  It’s impressive how aligned the doorways were as technology was very different back in the day.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/6-1050by788-fc549f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/6-700by525-fc549f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/6-675by506-fc549f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/6-450by338-fc549f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/6-525by394-fc549f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/6-350by263-fc549f.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/6-350by263-fc549f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;For the bigshots&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;If you are a real big shot, maybe you get to hold your tasting in one of these private rooms off the main hallway.  What interests me even more is do you get to try the bottles that are aging in there?  I wasn’t able to go inside to see, but I can guess they are not recent vintages.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a fantastic location to bring friends and possibly enjoy a picnic outside on the lawn with a bottle or two of their wines.  Though, I think it was nearly as fulfilling to go alone and really take the time to enjoy each one of these unique wines.  Each had a different expression than most Napa wines I’ve had of the same varietal and the value is solid, especially if you become a member and save 20% on each of the wines that you purchase!  The wines also all had an old world vibe to them, without any flaws from being underripe.  If a friend visitng Napa were to ask me for European-styled wines that weren’t all Cabernets, this is where I would send them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will absolutely be visiting again and hopefully will find a way to pick up and lay down a bottle of Rubicon for a future First Growth blind tasting or for a celebration.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="rutherford" /><summary type="html">I’ve had (the very affordable) Francis Coppola wines before and was skeptical of Inglenook even before reading the reviews by the major wine publications. But I think you can officially change my status from skeptic to believer, because everything about this winery is impressive. For example, when you make your way to the winery, Google Maps bring you to a small building that turns out to be the check-in desk where they confirm your reservation, give you a ticket to scan at the estate gate, and send you on your way.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/inglenook/4.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Corison Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/01/26/corison_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Corison Private Tasting" /><published>2019-01-26T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-26T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/01/26/corison_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/01/26/corison_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;One of the very first female winemakers and at 5’1”, Cathy was laughed off by her female professors when she said she wanted to make wine.  But thanks to fortunate circumstances, she got her start at Freemark Abbey, transitioned to working at Chappellet after a while and eventually worked with the vines that became Lokoya on Spring Mountain.  After she accumulated enough experience and capital, she found some great land that spoke to her in St. Helena and the rest is history.  She produces a Gewurztraminer and three different Cabernets at Corison, whose fruit comes from the valley floor and are all dry farmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/1-1050by788-0995c1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/1-700by525-0995c1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/1-675by506-0995c1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/1-450by338-0995c1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/1-525by394-0995c1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/1-350by263-0995c1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/1-350by263-0995c1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Where are my sunglasses?&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Getting ready for my first tasting of the day!  I must have been facing east for the picture because I look like I needed some sunglasses.  The half-asian definitely comes out in this picture…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/2-1050by788-6168ea.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/2-700by525-6168ea.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/2-675by506-6168ea.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/2-450by338-6168ea.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/2-525by394-6168ea.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/2-350by263-6168ea.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/2-350by263-6168ea.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;So much wine...&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view from the entrance to the Corison Winery.  I dare only imagine how many bottles of excellent wine those barrels will turn into&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kronos is her old vine Cabernet that grows on unique loam that is basically gravel after a 1-2 foot layer of clay.  The Napa Valley and Sunbasket wines are old cabernets (planted in the 90s) that don’t quite meet the unofficial “old vine” definition, but are also high quality.  In addition to the dry farming and earlier harvest date, the spacing between the vines is huge because they were planted back in the day when machinery was bulkier and require more spacing between vines.  All of these circumstances combine to produce wines that are very complex, concentrated, intense, elegant, higher in acidity, and consistently have an ABV below 14%, which is almost blasphemy for Napa Cabernet.  No need to worry as there is no residual sugar in the wines.  Cathy also makes sure to soften the tannins so consumers can drink the wines earlier in their life too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/3-1050by788-0fd629.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/3-700by525-0fd629.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/3-675by506-0fd629.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/3-450by338-0fd629.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/3-525by394-0fd629.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/3-350by263-0fd629.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/3-350by263-0fd629.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Paradise&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view of the vineyards from the winery.  Although not the glamourous view of some wineries, those old vine cabernet vines are a beautiful thing to a wine lover.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/4-1050by788-0a9429.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/4-700by525-0a9429.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/4-675by506-0a9429.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/4-450by338-0a9429.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/4-525by394-0a9429.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/4-350by263-0a9429.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/4-350by263-0a9429.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Old Vines&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A look into the Chronos Vineyard.  You can see that the Cabernets are all old vines and the rootstock is extremely knarled.  They also utilize dry farming and wide spacing for their vines which increases the quality even further.  The only negative is the small quantity of grapes those vines produce.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visiting the winery is very personal.  There are no more than 2-3 groups of visitors permitted on the grounds at any time.  When you arrive, you are greeted with the Gewurztraminer, then brought through the barrel storage room and out the back into the vineyard where the wine ambassadors talk about Cathy’s background, her winemaking style and the vineyards.  Once you are finished asking questions, you are brought back into the barrel storage area to your table where you are presented with the wines you will be tasting.  I was lucky and happened to be visiting on a Library Tasting day, meaning that instead of tasting the current release of Kronos, I was able to taste a library vintage (2008 in this case).  The full wine lineup looked like the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.corison.com/store/index.cfm?fuseaction=productdetail&amp;amp;product_id=299&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Corazon Gewurztraminer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($35)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A ripe Gewurztraminer that has all the characteristics you want and also medium acidity, which doesn’t let the wine fall off a cliff or finish flat like many other Gewurztraminers do.  It also avoids that slightly off-putting finish, which basically means that this is a Gewurz with all the things people love about the varietal but with none of its negatives.  That sounds like a winner to me, especially at the price point…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.corison.com/store/index.cfm?fuseaction=productdetail&amp;amp;product_id=248&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Napa Valley Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($95)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bright but with aromas of black/blue fruit, some cocoa, and good minerality that tingles the nose, but still takes a back seat to the juicy fruit.  No hints of alcohol heat on the nose, which is her style.  Medium+ body that gives the wine texture instead of a juicy body.  And the palate has all of the notes described for the nose, but in a subtle fashion.  This withheld intensity differentiates this from other wineries.  The tannins are very subtle again with a tingling medium+ acidity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.corison.com/store/index.cfm?fuseaction=productdetail&amp;amp;product_id=247&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Sunbasket Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($175)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The name of this wine is an homage to Andre Tchelistcheff, the “maestro” who made Beaulieu and the Georges de Latour Private Reserve into household names and who mentored many of Napa’s early winemakers.  Cathy purchased the 9.5 acre parcel this wine is made from and named it “Sunbasket” after how Andre would refer to the plot.  Compared to the Napa Valley Cabernet, this wine has a nose that seems to be a mix of red/blue fruit and is just as fresh with no alcohol heat and the right intensity of fragrance on the nose.  The palate has a bit more acidity and minerality with some light notes of terroir also entering the picture.  The body has just as much texture as the Napa Valley and also a weightlessness that is so intriguing.  The finish goes on for quite a while as well.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.corison.com/store/index.cfm?fuseaction=productdetail&amp;amp;product_id=104&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2008 Kronos Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($260)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose resembles the Sunbasket, but with a little more depth, black fruit, and integration.  The wine is also less bright with lower levels of blue fruit and cocoa.  The palate reminds me of a great Bordeaux – present red/black fruit, tertiary characteristics with some salinity and less spice, but with a finish just goes on forever at a solid intensity.  The lingering feeling of the acidity and integrated alcohol feels amazing too…  At 10 years old, it trades the bright nose for a great mouthfeel and more intense/present flavors on the palate that continues to last.  Similar, but slightly different than other Bordeaux-like reds from the valley, such as the Inglenook Rubicon.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/5-1050by788-55966e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/5-700by525-55966e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/5-675by506-55966e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/5-450by338-55966e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/5-525by394-55966e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/5-350by263-55966e.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/corison/5-350by263-55966e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Tasting is hard&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Evaluating these wines was so fun and difficult at the same time.  A part of me just wanted to enjoy them with friends, but the other part wanted to give the respect these wines deserved.  And boy did they deserve it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a little tired of the intensity and huge fruit of many Napa wineries, you owe it to yourself to give Corison a try.  It is definitely smaller than many other wineries off the main highway and does not have the lavish look or branding of others, but there is some much energy and care put into these wines.  It would be so easy to let these wines be 15% ABV, black fruit, heavy wood spice powerhouses; it takes much more effort, finesse, and expertise to craft wines that are so complex and enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I did not purchase wines on my first visit, I definitely plan on acquiring some in the future to serve as a contrast to other Napa Cabernets at future tastings.  Their library vintages are also available for purchase by non-members which is a pleasant surprise and will definitely have me considering paying $25-$50 more to try the wines after they’ve undergone sufficient aging.  In a way, you need to taste these wines to believe it.  So the next time you are driving up Highway 29 into Napa, consider giving Corison a try.  I guarantee it will be worth your while and may start you along the path to trying Bordeaux Super-Second Growth wines.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="st-helena" /><summary type="html">One of the very first female winemakers and at 5’1”, Cathy was laughed off by her female professors when she said she wanted to make wine. But thanks to fortunate circumstances, she got her start at Freemark Abbey, transitioned to working at Chappellet after a while and eventually worked with the vines that became Lokoya on Spring Mountain. After she accumulated enough experience and capital, she found some great land that spoke to her in St. Helena and the rest is history. She produces a Gewurztraminer and three different Cabernets at Corison, whose fruit comes from the valley floor and are all dry farmed.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/corison/4.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Chappellet Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/01/19/chappellet_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chappellet Private Tasting" /><published>2019-01-19T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-19T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/01/19/chappellet_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/01/19/chappellet_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;One of the first ten wineries established in the Napa Valley, Chappellet has a long and storied history - from Wine Spectator mentioning one of its wines in the top ten of the past &lt;strong&gt;century&lt;/strong&gt;, to naming and copyrighting the location that people think of when they hear Bryant Family, Colgin, etc. (Chappellet copyrighted “Pritchard Hill”), to producing a consistent 97+ pt wine in the Wine Advocate (their Pritchard Hill Cabernet Sauvignon).  Chappellet has a fantastic reputation and for good reason - the quality of their wine is very good.  I just had to visit Chappellet on my most recent trip, though the reasonable tasting fee also helped.  Note that like many other owners in Napa, the proprietar of Chappellet made his money before coming out to Napa and buying land.  In his case, he invented the first coffee vending machines, where you would pay to get a cup of coffee automatically dispensed for you.  No disrespect to coffee lovers, but I am glad he transitioned to wine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/1-1050by788-9d7e78.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/1-700by525-9d7e78.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/1-675by506-9d7e78.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/1-450by338-9d7e78.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/1-525by394-9d7e78.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/1-350by263-9d7e78.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/1-350by263-9d7e78.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Like the pyramids of old&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Inside the Chappellet winery.  It’s too bad that we couldn’t explore it any further.  Maybe next time…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our visit to Chappellet was a little more epic than normal because of a sulphur leakage inside the winery.  Scary, I know, but it was easy to smell that something was wrong in the storage/tasting area.  Instead of cancelling reservation for the day, the owners approved us to have our wine tasting at a great alternative location - their private outdoor tent in the vineyard.  For those that don’t know, many wineries have a special area that is designated for use only by the winery owners, where they can host close friends, VIPs, and others in a more secluded, relaxed setting that is even more beautiful than inside the winery.  Very rarely do common visitors like us get a chance to enjoy their private oasis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/2-1050by788-f6e3bc.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/2-700by525-f6e3bc.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/2-675by506-f6e3bc.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/2-450by338-f6e3bc.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/2-525by394-f6e3bc.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/2-350by263-f6e3bc.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/2-350by263-f6e3bc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;What a power couple&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Getting ready to hop in the Swiss Pinzgauer and head up into the vineyards.  Don’t drink and drive but it’s ok to drink and ride in a winery.  Also, don’t these two make quite the power couple?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/3-1050by788-4902ca.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/3-700by525-4902ca.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/3-675by506-4902ca.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/3-450by338-4902ca.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/3-525by394-4902ca.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/3-350by263-4902ca.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/3-350by263-4902ca.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;First-class seat&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view out of the back of the Swiss Pinzgauer heading up to the owner’s tent.  It was quite the view the whole way up, but the kicked-up dust was a bit much at times.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They didn’t tell us that we were heading to the owner’s tent though - we were told it was a surprise where we were heading.  We were lead to what looked like a miniature version of a military transport truck.  After we all managed to climb in the back, we took off into the winery.  Although it did get dusty (and some people forgot to protect their glass of Chardonnay), we finally made it to the owner’s private tent in the back-left portion of the winery.  We dusted ourselves off, took many pictures of the tent and the surrounding area, then proceeded to sit at the table and enjoy the wines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/4-1050by788-71a69c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/4-700by525-71a69c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/4-675by506-71a69c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/4-450by338-71a69c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/4-525by394-71a69c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/4-350by263-71a69c.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/4-350by263-71a69c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Owner's Box&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Heading into the owner’s tent for the tasting.  I must say - I really hope to befriend some winery owners at some point in my life, haha.  Now that I’ve been to one, I really want to spend the day or have a dinner at another!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chappellet.com/product/2014-Signature-Chardonnay&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Signature Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($45)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The grapes are from family growers in the cooler Carneros, as the winemaker wanted Chablis level acidity for use in a new world style wine.  The fruit is nicely developed past the lemon/lime fruit development into the yellow apple / apricot stage.  The minerality and sweeter spice are deeper in the wine and take some time to dig out.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chappellet.com/product/2014-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Dutton Ranch Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Great fruit development on the nose with bright floral notes and tons of spice.  A Cabernet lover’s style of Pinot at 14.9% ABV.  There is a bunch of earthiness to the wine, a clean finish without lingering alcohol, and a good amount of acid that stimulates the cheeks.  The short finish of the fruit makes me think this would do better as a wine paired with dinner.  Just make sure it’s a bigger dish, since black fruits (cherry/currant) dominates the palate.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chappellet.com/product/2015-Merlot&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Napa Valley Merlot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($45)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;82% Merlot, 5% of Cab Sauv and Franc, with the rest Malbec.  Bright red fruit with lots of spice/alcohol on the nose.  Definitely some tannin that clings through the finish.  The fruit is a bit lighter again, but with med+ body and acid.  Cooked/stewed fruit through the finish as well.  Some tobacco and cedar and maybe some espresso adding complexity to the flavor profile as well.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chappellet.com/product/2014-Malbec&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Napa Valley Malbec&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($65)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Deeper blue/black fruit on the nose, lean, really nice lingering aromas.  The palate is soft, with some black pepper, jam, black fruit, a touch warm, and a med+ finish.  It tastes a little young – seems like it needs to age a bit to round out the tannins a bit more.  The tertiary note in this wine is more coffee than the wood spices of the Merlot.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chappellet.com/product/2015-Signature-Cabernet-Sauvignon-Napa-Valley-1-5&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Signature Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;79% Cab Sauv, 14% Petit Verdot, 4% Merlot, and 3% Cab Franc.  A richness, lighter spice and baby fat comes off the wines as soon as you dig your nose in.  Soft on the palate, it is drinkable right now.  Pretty and sweet red fruit, smooth tannins, and a decent length on the finish.  And at a really decent price - just what I remember when I served six bottles of this to my colleagues at our company event.  I didn’t really get the herbs and cola to the extent our wine guide described, but I did get the hint of licorice.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/5-1050by788-bc0fe3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/5-700by525-bc0fe3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/5-675by506-bc0fe3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/5-450by338-bc0fe3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/5-525by394-bc0fe3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/5-350by263-bc0fe3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/chappellet/5-350by263-bc0fe3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;What a sight&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view of the vineyards from the owner’s tent.  I know, it is quite a sight…  Why doesn’t my backyard look like that I wonder?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure that if we had the signature tasting (~$95), which includes the Pritchard Hill Cabernet Sauvignon ($225), I would’ve been happier with the wine piece of the experience.  Chappellet was also our final winery of the day and was right after a late lunch, so I would also be interested in making another visit just to enjoy the wines more, though I doubt we will get the same experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the theme of the wines from Chappellet is Pritchard Hill terroir wines at an afforable price; every other place nearby sells wines at $200+ a bottle, though the Gandona Encosta is another good buy.  These wines are also on the heavier / hotter side and display many qualities that are associated with Napa wines.  I also need to call out their Signature Cabernet as a tremendous value buy at $55 that should be tried by everyone, even those that normally don’t care for Napa Cabernets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get away from the valley floor, but not pay the traditional mountain AVA prices of Napa, give Chappellet a try.  And if you are really ambitious, make sure to try the Pritchard Hill Cabernet too.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="pritchard-hill" /><summary type="html">One of the first ten wineries established in the Napa Valley, Chappellet has a long and storied history - from Wine Spectator mentioning one of its wines in the top ten of the past century, to naming and copyrighting the location that people think of when they hear Bryant Family, Colgin, etc. (Chappellet copyrighted “Pritchard Hill”), to producing a consistent 97+ pt wine in the Wine Advocate (their Pritchard Hill Cabernet Sauvignon). Chappellet has a fantastic reputation and for good reason - the quality of their wine is very good. I just had to visit Chappellet on my most recent trip, though the reasonable tasting fee also helped. Note that like many other owners in Napa, the proprietar of Chappellet made his money before coming out to Napa and buying land. In his case, he invented the first coffee vending machines, where you would pay to get a cup of coffee automatically dispensed for you. No disrespect to coffee lovers, but I am glad he transitioned to wine!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/chappellet/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Round Pond Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/01/12/round_pond_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Round Pond Private Tasting" /><published>2019-01-12T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-12T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/01/12/round_pond_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/01/12/round_pond_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;For those who have not yet been to Tuscany (Italy), you need to make plans to visit ASAP.  The gorgeous scenery aside, the wineries of Tuscany feel like you are visiting distant relatives.  In addition to growing grapes and making wine, the Tuscan estates will also grow olives onsite and make olive oil / balsamic vinagrette.  Combined with the family restaurants on the property and it’s easy to see why you could spend an entire day at a winery eating great food and drinking great wine with the families that own the estates.  Of all the current Napa estates that I have been to, Round Pond is the one that reminds me most of Tuscany.  Its 462 continguous acres in Rutherford can also make you feel like you have been transported somewhere else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the Tuscan estates, Round Pond is family owned, everyone (the owners and the children that now run the winery) lives on the property, they produce their own olive oil from their 13 acres of olives (the old tasting room is now their olivery), and it’s very easy to sit outside on their veranda and drink/eat all day long…  The only thing is the family is not Italian!  Though one vacation to Tuscany is all that is needed to fall in love with everything about it.  It’s also the reason why they grow Italian varietals such as Sangiovese and Nebbiolo and not just the traditional Napa varietals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/1-1050by788-16bee3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/1-700by525-16bee3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/1-675by506-16bee3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/1-450by338-16bee3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/1-525by394-16bee3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/1-350by263-16bee3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/1-350by263-16bee3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;outdoor drinkin&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view of Round Pond’s patio that they use for tastings.  If you don’t make a reservation, there is a standing tasting table indoors that you can go to.  But why wouldn’t you want to sit outdoors while enjoying good wine?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But before they started Round Pond, the owners originally owned some land on Pritchard Hill and used that experience to determine whether they would go all in on a winery or not.  They would come up every weekend to take care of their plot of land and camp outside in the vineyard after each long Saturday and Sunday of hard work.  After many months of working in San Francisco during the week and then traveling to Napa every weekend to work in their vineyard, they decided that they wanted to go all-in and moved their family to Rutherford.  Another family that answered its calling to contribute to the great world of wine…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our wine hostess (Erin) was great.  In addition to talking through all of the history I described above, we talked about the old horticultural school they had for boys, how the style of wine seems to blend the fruit and structure of Napa with the rusticity of Tuscany, and why Thomas Rivers Brown is one of the premier celebrity winemakers in the valley.  Looking back, Round Pond would have been a great place to order some food, but we had to get up Pritchard Hill to Chappellet afterwards, so I’ll need to revisit the food another time.  Still, the ambiance of the winery was great - fun, not too crowded or loud, relaxing seating, and no rush through the tasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/2-1050by788-2d53fa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/2-700by525-2d53fa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/2-675by506-2d53fa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/2-450by338-2d53fa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/2-525by394-2d53fa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/2-350by263-2d53fa.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/2-350by263-2d53fa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;indoor drinkin&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view of Round Pond’s indoor wine tasting area.  Though you can stop by this tasting table without a reservation, wouldn’t you rather sit outside instead (like in the first picture above)?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went for the Cabernet Tasting ($75), so the menu will be slightly different if you choose the regular tasting instead.  Also, you normally get to choose one of the Gravel Series wines for your tasting (Secret Garden, Scholar’s Gate, or the Vow), but since I was there with two other friends, we each picked a different wine from the Gravel Series and shared with each other, hence why I have notes for all three.  The wines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.roundpond.com/store/index.cfm?fuseaction=productdetail&amp;amp;product_id=1358&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Nebbiolo Rose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($32)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The fruit is pretty mellow but the acidity is bright on the nose.  Medium body with high acidity and enough tannin to add to the body.  The color is a unique, nearly invisible pink.  The wine is a little warm – you can definitely feel the alcohol at the end, but otherwise is very pleasant.  I love the novelty – it’s not easy to find Nebbiolo Roses around here.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.roundpond.com/store/index.cfm?fuseaction=productdetail&amp;amp;product_id=1237&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Proprietary Red&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($88)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;65% Cabernet, 25% Petit Verdot, the rest is Malbec and Merlot.  Deep red fruit (kirsch) and spice on the nose with some deep black fruit (fig) as well.  The body was much lighter (med) than I was expecting.  Still had a spice bite but smooth otherwise while warming you up a bit thanks to the alcohol.  Some rustic feel too, reminding me of Italy.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.roundpond.com/store/index.cfm?fuseaction=productdetail&amp;amp;product_id=1243&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Reserve Cabernet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($110)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;96% Cabernet, 4% Petit Verdot.  Much deeper in color than the Proprietary red - they also brought us some skewered meat to pair with the wine.  The nose is similar to the Proprietary Red except this had blue/black fruit with the spice and the alcohol was better integrated.  The body and flavors are wonderful in this wine and the tertiary notes are starting their development too.  The tannins are already so fine and the meat pairing helps clear any remaining tannins in the mouth.  Smooth with a solid body and mouthfeel.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Petit Verdot&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;They blind tasted me at the winery on this wine and I totally nailed it.  I did struggle evaluating just the nose because it reminded me of a really ripe Cabernet Franc with the really bright sweet red fruit, hint of black fruit, violets and black pepper on the nose.  But when you taste it, you get the flavors of a ripe Petit Verdot.  This wine had less fruit than the Cabernets, which gives way to earthiness that is characteristic of Petit Verdots.  There is also more tannin that lingers on the finish but is still rounded.  Very drinkable with a bigger body.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.roundpond.com/store/index.cfm?fuseaction=productdetail&amp;amp;product_id=1448&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Secret Garden&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($225)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A single vineyard wine from Oakville.  The vines are grown in a dried-up gravel riverbed, leading to a higher intensity nose than the Reserve Cabernet and about the same set of aromas except a sweet spice is also present.  This brings my brain directly to fruitcake.  Lighter with much more minerality and alcohol on the body.  The heat lasts through the finish for 60+ seconds.  This wine is more distinctive with its character, but I’m not sure it adds enough that I would take over this over two bottles of the the Reserve Cabernet.  This also really dries the mouth out with the tannin and needs more time in the bottle.  Flavors are sweet berry, spice, chocolate, black fruit, violets and lavender.  This plot is more maritime in climate which leads to this wine’s elegance and reduced power.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.roundpond.com/store/index.cfm?fuseaction=productdetail&amp;amp;product_id=1450&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Scholar’s Gate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($225)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This wine is also made from grapes grown along the rock bed of the property.  Very bright with red fruit and blackberry jam, high acid and medium+ tannin making the nose strong and reminiscent of pie.  But this wine is less about the fruit and more about the mineral characteristics with integration that currently surpasses the Secret Garden.  Initially strong alcohol impact, but opens up with cooked/baked fruit flavors on the palate.  Opulent, intense ripe red fruit, thyme, caramel, and other notes round out what I was able to pick up.  Plenty of hydro stress here would explain the intensity in this wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.roundpond.com/store/index.cfm?fuseaction=productdetail&amp;amp;product_id=1452&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 The Vow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($225)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is very similar to the Reserve Cabernet with less intensity due to the better integration (or lower amount) of alcohol and acid.  On the palate, the flavors stay predominantly in the realm of fruit.  There are some muted spices and the tannins are more fine than the other two of the Gravel Series.  This wine also has slightly more fruit than the others as well.  It’s a tie between the Scholar’s Gate and this as to which I liked best.  Having the other two first may have thrown off my perception, but I was told later that this was the biggest of the three because its soil is extremely porous.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pours of the wines (especially the Gravel Series) were a bit smaller than other places and the tasting was also only four wines (the Petit Verdot is not normally a part of the tasting).  $75 was a pretty steep price to pay for that experience, hence the lower experience score.  Besides that note, the wines were all very good and different compared to a lot of places in the valley.  Although I didn’t get to taste the Sangiovese, nor their Super Tuscan, I really appreciated the different wines that had on the menu (e.g. Nebbiolo Rose, Petit Verdot).  The wines of the Gravel Series were a great pleasure to taste too and would make a great addition to any wine collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/3-1050by1400-688aa7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/3-700by933-688aa7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/3-675by900-688aa7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/3-450by600-688aa7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/3-525by700-688aa7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/3-350by467-688aa7.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/round-pond/3-350by467-688aa7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Through the looking glass&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view out of their fancy window behind the staircase to the second floor.  It made for a good shot, but you can also see the vineyards through the window if you look closely.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the wines strike you and you’d like to take some home, the good news is the membership program discounts the wines by a good bit and the shipping rates are very good: $15 2-day shipping for a case and $25 2-day shipping for 6-11 bottles.  Again, I really appreciated the ambiance and change-of-pace that Round Pond provided.  If I am able to find its Proprietary Red for closer to $60, I’m definitely going to pick up a few.  So if you are looking for somewhere relaxing to spend some time in Napa and prefer an Italian theme over others (e.g. Hall for its neo-architecture theme), then pay a visit to Round Pond and bring some sunscreen!  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="rutherford" /><summary type="html">For those who have not yet been to Tuscany (Italy), you need to make plans to visit ASAP. The gorgeous scenery aside, the wineries of Tuscany feel like you are visiting distant relatives. In addition to growing grapes and making wine, the Tuscan estates will also grow olives onsite and make olive oil / balsamic vinagrette. Combined with the family restaurants on the property and it’s easy to see why you could spend an entire day at a winery eating great food and drinking great wine with the families that own the estates. Of all the current Napa estates that I have been to, Round Pond is the one that reminds me most of Tuscany. Its 462 continguous acres in Rutherford can also make you feel like you have been transported somewhere else.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/round-pond/1.jpg" /></entry></feed>