<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-04-06T23:20:51+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Wines By Jeremy</title><subtitle>Wines by Jeremy offers an educative and enjoyable personalized wine experience. Located in the DC metro area, Wines by Jeremy provides a number of services including in-home exclusive tastings, highly curated event tastings, educational events, and wine cellar consulting.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Domaine Weinbach Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/04/06/domaine_weimbach_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Domaine Weinbach Private Tasting" /><published>2019-04-06T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-04-06T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/04/06/domaine_weimbach_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/04/06/domaine_weimbach_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;If you are talking about the quality of the wine and tasting experience, I am not sure there is any other winery in Alsace that surpasses the experience offered by Domaine Weinbach…  Unlike many of the larger producers in the area (e.g. Hugel, Dopff, etc.), you do not go to a storefront for a tasting.  You actually visit their estate in Kayserberg where they usher you into one of the rooms in the house to enjoy your tasting by yourself (or with your group).  You do need to make a reservation for the tasting and therefore need to plan your schedule for the day a bit, but the reward for doing so is entering this sublime state after 90 minutes of tasting, after which you feel as if there is nothing more you really need to accomplish that day.  I know I didn’t!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than Domaine Paul Blanck in Kientzheim, there aren’t really any other renowned wineries in the area, though I am sure there are some wonderful, smaller wineries nearby in Kientzheim, Sigolsheim, and Ammerschwihr.  So if you are coming to Kayserberg, you are likely betting on this experience, the views of the Schlossberg hill, and finding a couple enjoyable places afterwards.  Although the three villages are normally walkable, it’s not quite walkable when you have 80 pounds of luggage to drag around with you.  At the time of my trip (Fall 2018), the sidewalks were non-existant between the towns and there wasn’t a taxi in sight either.  Since I only had a pre-arranged car taking me to Colmar at noon, I had myself put all of my eggs in one basket.  And I was not disappointed…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/1-1050by788-f2552d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/1-700by525-f2552d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/1-675by506-f2552d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/1-450by338-f2552d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/1-525by394-f2552d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/1-350by263-f2552d.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/1-350by263-f2552d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Faller Family&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Although the winery is named Domaine Weinbach, it is purchased by the Faller brother in 1898 and has remained in their family’s possession ever since, hence the name on the wall surrounding their estate.  You can see their home / estate just above the the vines in the picture.  There was a lot of constuction on the road and sidewalks when I visited, so be careful if going on foot!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/2-1050by788-f980af.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/2-700by525-f980af.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/2-675by506-f980af.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/2-450by338-f980af.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/2-525by394-f980af.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/2-350by263-f980af.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/2-350by263-f980af.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The View in Reverse&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Once you make it to the estate and turnaround, you’ll see a gorgeous view of Schlossberg and all of the vines that are planted on it.  Unfortunately, the pixelation on my camera in selfie-mode is kinda bad, but I maintain that you truly cannot appreciate the view unless you are their in person, similar to the Douro and Cote Rotie.  You need to see it to believe it…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look at the map on your mobile device, you’ll notice that there is a house seemingly in the middle of nowhere, just outside of Kayserberg.  That is Domaine Weinbach and it’s not in the middle of nowhere - it’s just surrounded by small part of its planted holdings.  As the largest family producer in all of Alsace (I think around 30 hectares or so), you might expect the quality to dip a little, but I would argue the opposite - the variety of their holdings allows them to craft some singular wines that are fun to taste, similar to Hugel and others.  Walking to the winery from the center of town, you can’t help but notice the incredible view of Schlossberg and the winery is situated at a perfect spot for some incredible pictures, like the one above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to their website, the winery was named after the little stream which runs through the property.  The history of the land is just fascinating though…  Vines have existed on the land for over 1000 years though it wasn’t domesticated for winemaking until the 1600s by Capuchin friars, hence the name of the old walls that surround the property (Clos des Capucins) and the monk on their wine labels.  After being sold as national property during the French revolution, it was acquired by the Faller brothers in 1898 and has been passed along through the generations until today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/5-1050by788-d67b16.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/5-700by525-d67b16.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/5-675by506-d67b16.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/5-450by338-d67b16.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/5-525by394-d67b16.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/5-350by263-d67b16.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/5-350by263-d67b16.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Selfie Time, Part 2&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The entrance to the winery.  Again, not the most impressive on the outside, but the inside is a 180.  This picture was after my tasting, hence the wider grin than normal.  It was a decent walk back into town, but so worth it…  I highly recommend you visit if you are ever in the area.  In my Top 3 of Alsace!!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking up to the estate, it’s not obvious how you should go about entering as there is no marked directions (e.g. Whether you should just walk right in, knock and wait outside, etc.).  Knowing their reputation, I was nervous about walking right in, but my excitement won out.  I was welcomed and guided to a room by a young lady (presumably, the daughter) and left to my own devices while they prepared a tasting menu for my impromptu visit (I highly recommend you make a reservation instead as I was lucky there weren’t many reservations for that morning!!).  For as large as Weinbach’s holdings are, the wine tasting room I found myself in seemed like the study room in their home.  I actually think it was and wondered what the other rooms were like as I saw another couple get ushered in to their room.  The advertising of Weinbach is spot on – although the production is large for a winery in this region, this is all family run, they do not really have the capacity to handle many visitors simultaneously, and I am pretty sure I interrupted their breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/3-1050by788-f67451.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/3-700by525-f67451.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/3-675by506-f67451.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/3-450by338-f67451.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/3-525by394-f67451.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/3-350by263-f67451.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/3-350by263-f67451.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;A room all to myself&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The gorgeous living room I was invited to for the tasting.  My tasting was at 10AM, so you can see the morning sun was very strong coming through the windows behind me.  There were other groups tasting in different parts of the house through the morning (I took a little longer than others).  Being the only person in the room tasting defintely made me feel special, but the singular quality of the wines also played a huge part in the experience.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the course of the tasting, I had the pleasure of meeting three of the four members of the family (I think the father was out cutting the grass).  The family chemistry was also fun to experience - my tasting started with the daughter who was very passionate about the wines, then transitioned to the eldest son who discussed more of the science and farming, and ended slightly rushed with the mother who was high energy (though I admit, I was being very deliberate with each wine I tasted).  With as small an operation that they seemingly have, how do they handle the capacity and the many different wines that they produced (their portfolio is huge each year!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/4-1050by788-2da2cc.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/4-700by525-2da2cc.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/4-675by506-2da2cc.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/4-450by338-2da2cc.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/4-525by394-2da2cc.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/4-350by263-2da2cc.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/4-350by263-2da2cc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;A map of the area&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Some pieces of the map are hard to read - that morning sun made it difficult to even see my computer screen!  Domaine Weinbach owns a large portion of the vineyards in the area.  In fact, I believe they are the largest family producer in all of Alsace!  While the classified areas of Mambourg and Marckrain were the largest, the majority of the wines I tasted were from their vines in Schlossberg and Altenbourg.  Many of which were Grand Crus.  The variety of wines and their uniqueness even when compared to each other made this seem like a day-long tasting.  In fact, it was so good, I didn’t tasting anything else the rest of the day…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most unusual for a tasting, but we started with the Pinot Noir and moved on to the white wines afterwards.  The explanation made sense though - they like to start their tastings with the dry wines and work their way up RS (residual sugar) ladder.  Although the white wines served right after the Pinot Noir have little or no RS, their ripeness level can definitely fool you.  Another unusual fact - there are no fact sheets, descriptions, or prices for their wines listed on their website, so you will need to be like me and do your best to find these wines at wine stores and restaurants in the area.  Without further ado, the wines!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 W - Altenbourg&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Grown in the clay/limestone soil of Altenbourg and spent 12 months in barrique.  Much more red fruit (cranberry and raspberry mostly) on the nose than other Alsacian Pinot Noirs I’ve experienced, with some crushed flower petals on the tail end.  Medium(+) acid and the palate has a lot more of that crushed flower petal flavor with some minerality of the limestone coming into play.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 S - Schlossberg&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Grown in the granite soil of Schlossberg at a production of around 1200 bottles a year.  Weinbach cannot call it a Grand Cru because Schlossberg does not have that designation for Pinot Noir.  It spends 6 months longer in barrique than the Altenbourg, resulting in a more integrated, pretty and floral nose that is a touch lighter in intensity.  If you don’t require cherry in your Pinot profile, then this wine is going to make you very happy.  Everything is in perfect proportion and it is surprisingly much brighter than the Altenbourg.  I walked away with a bottle and am kicking myself for not picking up more, especially at the price point they were selling it at the winery…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Pinot Blanc&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Looking back at my notes, I am confused because I clearly wrote that this wine is 70% Auxeroiss and 30% Pinot Blanc, yet I remember fairly clearly that the wine was labeled “Pinot Blanc”.  Bright white peach on the nose along with a light, juicy, white grapey note.  Despite a little alcohol burn at the end, this is a medium bodied white wine that I think Americans will really like.  The finish goes on for a few seconds too making this is a fruity, easy drinking white wine that is perfect for serving chilled during summertime, but not suitable for aging.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Muscat&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A blend of 70% Muscat Ottonel and 30% Muscat d’Alsace.  They allow a few hours of cold maceration before pressing the juice, resulting in a pronounced and very aromatic nose.  The aromas are a mix of both stonefruit and tropical fruit with the slightest touch of coconut.  I might believe this has some Muscat Blanc a Petits Grains in it.  Again, juicy on the palate but there is medium(+) acid that makes this finish cleanly in the stonefruit range of flavors.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Riesling - Cuvee Theo&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Made from grapes grown in Sandy and Alluvial soil on the estate (same as the Muscat and the Pinot Blanc).  The commanding, bright, ripe peach character and hints of petrol integrate well with the salinity on the finish, which seems to come from the terroir.   The alcohol is well integrated until you hit the salinity, which also brings out some lemon/lime character.  This ending definitely makes the Theo more cerebral than the Colette, which I really appreciated.  It does a little bit of everything.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Riesling - Cuvee Colette&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This is grown on the other side of the road from the estate, just below the Schlossberg Grand Cru limits.  The vines are stil on an angled slope and south facing, mimicing many of the good characteristics of the grand cru plot.  The nose is more perfumed than the Theo and the stonefruit seems even riper.  The palate has a lot of ripe green apple character, which makes it very palatable, to go along with more minerality.  This is probably the more popular of the two Rieslings with drinkers.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Riesling Grand Cru Schlossberg&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;From 40 year old vines at the very top of the AOC.  The nose was a little closed and low in intensity for a Riesling, but it wouldn’t surprise me if it needed a few years in bottle.  The palate is similar in that you can feel the edges of something great, but it’s just not revealing itself yet…  Elegant, medium(-) intensity with stonefruit and minerality, solid acidity, and without much petrol character.  This just feels like it will be a great wine, even though I can’t see it very well at the moment.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Riesling Grand Cru Schlossberg - Cuvee Ste Catherine&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;From 60/70 year old vines on the mid slope in the AOC.  There is much more intensity on the nose than the Schlossberg - a mix of floral and stonefruit aromas, but more floral in character.  The palate reveals stronger stonefruit with plenty of minerality and salinity on the finish.  It’s funny to say about a white wine, but there’s seemingly more baby fat on this wine, though the RS is about the same as the Schlossberg.  I could see this wine aging really well in bottle and hitting its peak in 10-20 years.  I’m just not sure I can wait that long…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 L’Inedit - Riesling Grand Cru Schlossberg&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;From similar 60/70 year old vines as the Ste Catherine, but harvested a little bit later.  Not VT late, but late enough so that they could produced a wine for the evolving culinary world (e.g. a wine for fish with heavy cream sauce).  The palate definitely has a heavier feel and even a bit more minerality to it.  You can also feel a bit more heat (ie. alcohol)  because the wine is fermented to dryness.  I would agree that this feels richer than the previous wine and is a nice counterpoint to the VT style.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Pinot Gris - Cuvee St. Catherine&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;100% Pinot Gris from sand/silt terroir.  Fresh, light white flowers wth lemon/lime on the nose.  The palate is dominated by ripe stonefruit, to the point that the wine is approaching “sweet”.  With the lower acid of the Pinot Gris, that ripness translates into a richness on the palate as well.  For my friends that prefer fruit-driven wine, this is a great wine to try and an interesting one to explore the varietal outside of its Pinot Grigio rendition.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Pinot Gris - Cuvee Laurence&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;From marl and limestone with 20g/L of residual sugar.  Grown just below the Altenbourg Grand Cru designated area, so still high quality even if they can’t call it Grand Cru.  Bright, white peach pith on the nose that doesn’t prepare you for the onslaught of ripeness (sweet stonefruit) on the palate that surpasses the St. Catherine, almost approaching coconut.  This wine does not have an overbearing mouthfeel, but you almost can’t taste the acidity either.  Definitely a wine for the end of a night or meal.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Pinot Gris - Altenbourg&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;From limestone and clay, the nose of this Altenbourg is more yellow/green fruit (e.g. apples) than stonefruit and is more reserved than the Cuvee Laurence.  The palate is has a good amount of ripeness, but is brighter and has more acid/structure, making this a bit more versatile in its uses.  This is my favorite of the Pinot Gris that I tasted - ripe but structured that provide pleasure in both the taste and feel.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Gewurztraminer&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;From marl and limestone.  Less tropical fruit on the nose than other Gewurztraminers, but I like the zest.  The palate has that tropical fruit and this medium(-) intensity coconut creaminess that binds the whole tasting experience and mouthfeel together.  I was very surprised with the restraint on the nose and would not have guessed the palate would have such intensity and complexity.  Definitely an outlier when it comes to Gewurztraminer from the region and I do love outliers!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Gewurztraminer Altenbourg&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;More pronounced on the nose than the earlier Gewurztraminer.  In addition to zest and spice, there are ripe citrus (oranges) and pineapple notes on the forefront.  The palate is very light in body and the flavors are surprisingly restrained as well, though they are also well integrated.  The range of flavors is in line with the aromas, but they are just a bit harder to pull out because the wine is so easy drinking too.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Gewurztraminer Furstentum&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Although the Furstentum has 55g of RS, it tastes like 40 because the sugar is well integrated.  This wine could have been called a VT if they had declared it to Alsacian officials in time to get the official recognition, so the consumer benefits from the high quality but lower price.  From even higher altitude than the Altenbourg, this wine has slight more muted aromas.  But once the wine touches your palate, you understand why it could have gotten a VT designation – the mouthfeel is so smooth, so ripe, and a touched candied.  In other words, delicious.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Riesling Schlossberg SGN&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The petrol covers the light fruit aromas a bit, but you can dig them out with some swirling.  The flavors are not overly intense or candied - everything is well balanced between the fruit, minerality, petrol, and botrytis.  Thanks to the lighter body and medium(+) acidity, this wine finishes very cleanly.  In fact, it feels like this wine has more body, spectrum of flavors and balance than the non-GC Rieslings.  Well done!!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, this was one of my favorite tastings in Alsace.  So make sure you visit and make sure you get to Weinbach.  To give you incentive one more time, I’ll end with another picture of me and Schlossberg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/6-1050by788-e260fe.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/6-700by525-e260fe.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/6-675by506-e260fe.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/6-450by338-e260fe.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/6-525by394-e260fe.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/6-350by263-e260fe.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-weinbach/6-350by263-e260fe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Again, the VIEW!!!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I still can’t say enough about the view of Schlossberg.  This was taken around noon, two hours after the second picture.  You can see the sky has evened out a bit.  What’s also impressive is the stone wall that runs parallel to the vines all the way down to the main road.  Please bring a better camera than I did and send me some copies of your photos, please!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="alsace" /><category term="kaysersberg" /><summary type="html">If you are talking about the quality of the wine and tasting experience, I am not sure there is any other winery in Alsace that surpasses the experience offered by Domaine Weinbach… Unlike many of the larger producers in the area (e.g. Hugel, Dopff, etc.), you do not go to a storefront for a tasting. You actually visit their estate in Kayserberg where they usher you into one of the rooms in the house to enjoy your tasting by yourself (or with your group). You do need to make a reservation for the tasting and therefore need to plan your schedule for the day a bit, but the reward for doing so is entering this sublime state after 90 minutes of tasting, after which you feel as if there is nothing more you really need to accomplish that day. I know I didn’t!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/domaine-weinbach/6.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Dopff au Moulin Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/03/30/dopff_au_moulin_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dopff au Moulin Public Tasting" /><published>2019-03-30T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-30T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/03/30/dopff_au_moulin_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/03/30/dopff_au_moulin_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Before visiting Alsace, I had not heard of Domaine Dopff au Moulin.  I have now…  As much as I was excited to taste the wines at Hugel et Fils, German tourists were as excited (if not moreso) to visit Dopff au Moulin and walk off with a case of wine.  The town of Riquewihr is nestled on a hill that reaches 300 meters in altitude in the shadow of the Vosges mountains, with most of the town being inaccessible by car during the day (since the streets are filled with people).  This means that the foot traffic is greatest at the bottom of the hill, which is accessible by motor vehicles, and decreases as you go up the hill.  Coincidence or not, Dopff au Moulin is located right next to the traffic circle at the bottom of the hill and sees a lot of foot traffic.  It also sees a lot of people exiting their doors carrying boxes of wine…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/1-1050by788-0f6920.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/1-700by525-0f6920.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/1-675by506-0f6920.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/1-450by338-0f6920.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/1-525by394-0f6920.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/1-350by263-0f6920.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/1-350by263-0f6920.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Gate to Dopff&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The front gate to Dopff Au Moulin.  Funny enough, the building straight behind the gate isn’t where the tastings are held.  I know, that totally threw me off too.  Thought I would just warn the reader to not make the same mistake I did (haha) while also showing off their fancy gate.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/2-1050by1400-a8d771.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/2-700by933-a8d771.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/2-675by900-a8d771.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/2-450by600-a8d771.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/2-525by700-a8d771.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/2-350by467-a8d771.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/2-350by467-a8d771.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Real Entrance&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The real entrance to Dopff Au Moulin - you can see the door through the hedges.  I did not think it was the entrance either, but I should have probably known to follow the large contingent of people entering and exiting the facility.  Domaine Dopff Au Moulin is at the bottom of the hill at the edge of town, so if you are driving to Riquewihr by car, this is the easiest winery to access.  It does get more foot traffic than any other winery I saw in town…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Searching for the entrance to the wine shop, I thought to myself that they had to have been around for a long time to get such a premium location for their storefront.  That is an understatement.  It all started in 1574 for the Dopff family, who now have three generations (including the 13th generation) of their family operating the winery.  At 70 hectares, they are the second largest family-owned winery in all of Alsace (behind Domaine Weimbach I believe), producing around a million bottles of sparkling wine and still wines.  I appreciate how they consider themselves wine growers rather than winemakers as it emphasizes their dedication in the vineyards to ensuring that they are producing natural wines, with traditional means, that meet their high standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/3-1050by788-00c35b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/3-700by525-00c35b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/3-675by506-00c35b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/3-450by338-00c35b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/3-525by394-00c35b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/3-350by263-00c35b.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/3-350by263-00c35b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Spill the dirt!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Not the greatest photo of the soil samples from each Grand Cru terroir nearby - the sun was very bright even inside the winery.  Even so, you should still be able to pick out the differences in the glass bottles.  The soil types are also noted on the pieces of slate in each glass.  Schoenenbourg, Sporen and Vorbourg are the places where you see most wine in the region from.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to being part of the fabric of Riquewihr for so long, Dopff au Moulin has achieved much over the years and serves as an example to many other producers.  It’s biggest claim-to-fame is “inventing” Cremant d’Alsace.  In the early 1900s, Julien Dopff attended a practical demonstration of the Champenoise method at the Universal Exhibition in Paris.  Inspired by the demonstration, he went to Epernay (an AOC in the Champagne region) to train for a couple years before returning to Alsace and producing a sparkling wine with Pinot Blanc (the varietal is prone to a natural effervescence too).  Although Cremant d’Alsace didn’t achieve its AOC status until 1976, Dopff au Moulin was the beginning.  It even says so on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cr%C3%A9mant_d%27Alsace&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;!!!  Today, Cremant d’Alsace represents nearly 25% of Alsatian wines - if you haven’t had one before, you need to try it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julien Dopff was also the first person in the region to begin commercially selling their wines in the long stemmed bottles.  Today, these bottles (known as Flûte d’Alsace) are part of the region’s branding effort and is mandatory for all still wines bottled in the region!  As a student of wine history (for my WSET Diploma), I was a bit ashamed that I had not heard of them or their achievements before arriving.  But observing their sheer throughput throughout the day, it all makes sense now.  I also feel like this winery really tailors itself to Germans as much as the French; a vast majority of their wines are varietally named (as is tradition in Germany) and the wine ambassadors speak German fluently (if not also English).  The wine ambassador pouring for me received her French wine certification, which is a three year joint school + internship program, so you know they hire the best people too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/4-1050by788-947d06.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/4-700by525-947d06.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/4-675by506-947d06.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/4-450by338-947d06.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/4-525by394-947d06.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/4-350by263-947d06.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/4-350by263-947d06.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Tasting Counter&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Again, I visited during the peak afternoon sun, which impacted all of my photos.  The lit countertops did not help either…  You can still tell that I got to taste and check out the bottles of many different wines and that the people behind the bar were very busy.  There was a lot of customer turnover as I sat in the corner, enjoying each of the wines.  But hey, if you know what you want, buy quick and head to the next stop!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the tasting room had a high throughput of customers, I was generally left to my own devices in the corner to taste and take notes on the wines.  I believe a normal tasting is the customer’s choice of 4-5 wines.  Since I tasted more than that, I paid double, though the wine ambassador was shocked as if I had tipped her way too much…  I didn’t mind since it was a pleasure to be able to taste a good part of the portfolio.  Now then, to the wines!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boutiquedopff.fr/catalogue/nos-vins-1/cremant-d-alsace-4/cremant-d-alsace-cuvee-julien-brut-60-1.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NV Cuvee Julien&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (9.90€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A young blend of Pinot Blanc and Auxeroiss. In order to integrate the bubbles and flavors better, the sur lie age the wine for 2-3 years in barrel.  Ripe apple on the nose but green/yellow apple on the palate.  Good acidity and length, but the flavors on the palate and finish aren’t my favorite.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boutiquedopff.fr/catalogue/nos-vins-1/cremant-d-alsace-4/2015-cremant-chardonnay-brut-99-81.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Chardonnay Brut&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (12.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;In Alsace, you can’t make a still AOC Chardonnay; it can only be used in Cremant (sparkling wine).  2015 was a really ripe vintage for Alsace, which isn’t great for most varietals going into a Sparkling wine.  But when it happens with Chardonnay, you can get complexity on the palate (like almonds) without lees aging the wine.  Along with some barrel age character, this Brut has lighter green/yellow apple and some almond character on the nose.  The palate is composed of flavors similar to the nose with aggressive but medium-sized mousse and high, mouthwatering acidity on the finish.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boutiquedopff.fr/catalogue/nos-vins-1/propre-recolte-6/2015-chardonnay-150-86.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (15.95€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;3g/L of residual sugar (RS).  As I mentioned in the last note, there is no AOC that allows a still, varietal Chardonnay in Alsace, so this is called a Vin de France.  I believe the Dopff Chardonnay is the first varietal Chardonnay to be produced in Alsace.  The nose is quite light, though definitely has some almond character and minerality.  The acid is medium because 2015 was a hot year.  There is ripe lemon on the palate, but the nut and minerality are what dominate the palate.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boutiquedopff.fr/catalogue/nos-vins-1/grands-crus-8/2014-riesling-grand-cru-schoenenbourg-de-riquewihr-30-28.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Riesling Grand Cru Schoenenberg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (19.20€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;5.5g/L of RS.  White peach, petrol, white flowers and minerality - the first two being the strongest.  The palate emphasizes the minerality more than anything else with ripe yellow fruit and peach coming afterwards (the petrol is absent for the most part).  The acidity continues to tingle the cheeks for 15 seconds on the finish.  Because of the strength of the flavors, I think this could pair well with fish or even light white meat (e.g. Chicken).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boutiquedopff.fr/catalogue/nos-vins-1/propre-recolte-6/2014-pinot-gris-coeur-de-barrique-151-87.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Pinot Gris (Coeur de Barrique)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (21.90€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;2.4g/L of RS.  They cannot call this a grand cru even though it is grown in Schoenenburg Grand Cru soil because barreling the wine is not allowed under the AOC Grand Cru designation.  Do not make the mistake of passing over this wine because of that - the time in the wood has accuentated the smoke that was already part of the varietal flavor for Pinot Gris, though it’s only medium(-) intensity in the glass.  There is also almond and toast in the aromas.  The palate has all of that plus some coconut and the slightest bit of salinity.  Very interesting wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boutiquedopff.fr/catalogue/nos-vins-1/grands-crus-8/2015-pinot-gris-grand-cru-schoenenbourg-de-riquewihr-36-33.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Pinot Gris Grand Cru Schoenenbourg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (19.90€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The only difference from the Coeur de Barrique is that this wine is not done in oak barrels and therefore can carry the AOC Grand Cru designation.  Its nose is much brighter than the barreled rendition - I can almost smell more acid in this wine as well.  The palate feels as if it has a higher RS too, which is probably intentional on the winemaker’s part (during grape selection between the two wines at the very least).  I also get more fruit on this wine, with ripe yellow fruit and some lighter stonefruit the most prominent.  There is salinity in the undertones of the wine, but the story is definitely the ripeness and the fruit (its primary flavors).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boutiquedopff.fr/catalogue/nos-vins-1/grands-crus-8/2011-gewurztraminer-vorbourg-de-rouffach-westhalten-37-34.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Grand Cru Vorberg Gewurztraminer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (19.70€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;34g/L of RS.  Only made in 2011 and 2015 because they wanted a balance between the normal (20 g/L) and the late harvest (60g/L) RS levels of Gewurztraminer and these years were the ones that fit the requirements.  This is one of the first Gewurztraminers I’ve smelled where the primary note wasn’t honeysuckle and other exotic fruit.  It smells predominantly like a dry white wine with white flowers and spice.  On the palate, the honey/honeysuckle comes out in force and moving the wine gets the white flower and spice notes to come out more which is a quality that I really like…  It finishes drier than I was anticipating and I really like the acidity level.  One of my favorite wines from the Vorberg AOC.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boutiquedopff.fr/catalogue/nos-vins-1/grands-crus-8/gewurztraminer-grand-cru-sporen-2015-101-89.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Grand Cru Sporen Gewurztraminer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (26.90€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;50g/L of RS.  This is the wine that scored a perfect 3 stars in a famed German Wine Review Journal.  The nose is similar to the last wine in that the honey is pulled back on the nose, but there is more brightness to this nose.  There is even more ripeness on the palate and indexes more on exotic fruit than pure sugar with orange blossom, starfruit, and lychee leading the way.  I can see why people consider this wine “balanced”; the ripeness and acidity makes this a delicious wine that is smooth all the wine down and lingers on the palate.  I wish the spice was a little more prominent, but this is still really good and I wouldn’t argue with the German journal’s rating.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boutiquedopff.fr/catalogue/nos-vins-1/propre-recolte-6/2015-pinot-noir-de-riquewihr-26-27.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Pinot Noir du Domaine Familial&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (12.90€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;An interesting nose of lighter intensity red fruit, but with a brooding aspect and some spice.  Aged in old/used barrels, there are several earthen and wood-driven notes that come out on the palate more than the fruit  Though the medium(+) acid and medium tannin maintain some freshness, I am surprised that the palate is so tertiary / terroir-driven given the age of the wine.  Admittedly, the bottle was nearly empty when I received my pour and the oxygen exposure over the course of the day probably played a part.  So drink this wine in a single sitting!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.boutiquedopff.fr/catalogue/nos-vins-1/propre-recolte-6/2014-pinot-noir-coeur-de-barrique-27-77.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Pinot Noir Coeur de Barrique&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (21.90€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Coeur de Barrique is similar to the previous wine (again, possibly because of oxidation during the day), except there seems to be more wood tannin and the cedar / other wood flavors are more prominent in this wine.  The lack of vanilla and other character makes me think they re-used older oak barrels.  The palate had more earth-driven flavors as well - very different than the fruit-driven Pinots I am accustomed to.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can tell, there were many wines to taste and I only scratched the surface!  I think I tried maybe a third of the wines on their menu, though I did get to try many of their Grand Crus, which was a real treat.  I love that the portfolio is balanced between classical renditions of varietals and what effects aging, barrels and intervention by the winemaker might have on the wines.  The wines were also not overtly fruit-driven for the most part, letting the wood and terroir do more of the talking, which was very different than many of the places I visited in the area (especially Hugel et Fils, which was right up the hill).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/5-1050by788-3be9b6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/5-700by525-3be9b6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/5-675by506-3be9b6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/5-450by338-3be9b6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/5-525by394-3be9b6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/5-350by263-3be9b6.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/dopff-au-moulin/5-350by263-3be9b6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Obligatory Selfie&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The pixelation on my selfie is pretty bad, but the picture is still good enough to communicate what the vineyards were like.  They just kept going for miles over my back shoulder, which the higher quality grapes coming from the mid-to-top of the slope.  Everything was just so green and lively.  It’s hard not to be happy here, even without a car!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I did not walk away with any bottles, I did come away with an appreciation for their commitment to quality and tradition, as well as a new take on the wines of Alsace.  If you are in Riquewihr for the day, this is also another must-visit location.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="alsace" /><category term="riquewihr" /><summary type="html">Before visiting Alsace, I had not heard of Domaine Dopff au Moulin. I have now… As much as I was excited to taste the wines at Hugel et Fils, German tourists were as excited (if not moreso) to visit Dopff au Moulin and walk off with a case of wine. The town of Riquewihr is nestled on a hill that reaches 300 meters in altitude in the shadow of the Vosges mountains, with most of the town being inaccessible by car during the day (since the streets are filled with people). This means that the foot traffic is greatest at the bottom of the hill, which is accessible by motor vehicles, and decreases as you go up the hill. Coincidence or not, Dopff au Moulin is located right next to the traffic circle at the bottom of the hill and sees a lot of foot traffic. It also sees a lot of people exiting their doors carrying boxes of wine…</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/dopff-au-moulin/4.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hugel et Fils Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/03/23/hugel_et_fils_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hugel et Fils Public Tasting" /><published>2019-03-23T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-23T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/03/23/hugel_et_fils_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/03/23/hugel_et_fils_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;If you are visiting Riquewihr, your first stop should be Hugel et Fils (pronounced UGE-el).  There is no argument to be made here.  Yes, Riquewihr was the first town in my Alsatian travels that had enough foreigners where I would consider it a tourist destination.  Yes, the restaurants were top notch and among the best I visited in Alsace.  Yes, there were many other shops and wineries to visit.  But it’s Hugel.  There is no name that I consider more synonymous with Alsace than Hugel.  A large part of that is due to its vast distribution network in the USA and its solid presence on restaurants’ wine lists.  But like the best producers, it’s the solid quality year-after-year that have them ranked highly in my book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/1-1050by788-eba781.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/1-700by525-eba781.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/1-675by506-eba781.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/1-450by338-eba781.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/1-525by394-eba781.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/1-350by263-eba781.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/1-350by263-eba781.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;The Streets!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The main “street” of Riquewihr.  As with many of the smaller towns in Alsace, the main road is a cobblestone street that is just wide enough for all the foot traffic, leaving no room for trucks to make deliveries or cars to come through.  So you better get used to walking uphill!  Still, any hardship the climb might impose is off-set and then some by the bright, storied architecture of the buildings and the energy of the tourists.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting dropped off by my taxi at the edge of town, I began making my climb up the main street to Hugel.  Luckily, the street wasn’t nearly as crowded 9:30AM in the morning, meaning I had plenty of room to manuever up the street with all of my luggage.  The store is about 2/3 of the way up the hill, meaning I needed to take a few breaks along the way.  I didn’t mind though because as you can see from the picture below, the views of the buildings were quite something.  Along the way, I noticed that a good portion of the people on the street were Germans speaking English with the French villagers.  That was quite the sight to behold, but to my surprise, I learned that many of the villagers could speak both German and English fluently.  One of my regrets from my childhood - not learning more languages…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/2-1050by788-ed333a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/2-700by525-ed333a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/2-675by506-ed333a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/2-450by338-ed333a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/2-525by394-ed333a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/2-350by263-ed333a.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/2-350by263-ed333a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Outside the stronghold&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;While being late might be fashionable, being early means you beat the rush and may have the opportunity to taste more than a few wines!  It also means your palate is fresh and ready to take on the day!  Be sure to plan carefully - the sign on the door notifies customers that Hugel is closed for two hours around lunch time, so don’t plan on coming at noon!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time I made it to the store, most of the shops were beginning to open for the day and buses/cars/taxis started shuttling in more and more people into town.  There was a brief wait until the shop opened and I did have to restrain myself from trying some of the Eaux de Vie across the street in the meantime.  But it was Hugel - I needed to keep my palate clean.  Judging by the storefront, I knew that the tasting area wasn’t going to be large.  That was a slight understatement - the place would (and did) feel packed with 10 people in the room.  The amount of space available is reason number one I recommend making a reservation, otherwise you may find that only part of your party is allowed in the shop at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/3-1050by788-920186.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/3-700by525-920186.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/3-675by506-920186.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/3-450by338-920186.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/3-525by394-920186.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/3-350by263-920186.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/3-350by263-920186.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Small but full of treasures&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Hugel here is their storefront in town - I don’t know where their winery is physically located or how/if you can get a tasting scheduled there.  While the tasting room may be small, it still sports their full inventory (minus their rarities).  Looks can be deceiving, especially in the wine world…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ignoring the size of the space, it felt clean, relaxed and almost homely.  You could spend your time watching a promotional video of the wines, reading literature on the history of the winery and its owners, or inspecting all of the old vintage bottles lined around the room.  I spent some time doing all three while enjoying the effects of the air conditioner and righting myself for the tasting, haha.  As with several other wineries in the region, there was no set tasting list.  If you were there to drink wine and really didn’t know what you were doing, standard procedure would be to take you through several of their easier-to-find-and-purchase wines, with a reserve wine or two mixed in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coralie (the wine ambassador pictured above) was really nice to me.  After explaining my background and the purpose of my trip, as well as my opinion on Hugel et Fils (ie. the “must-visit” place in town), she was kind enough to give me a deeper look into their reserve collection (e.g. the Grossi Laues and Vendange Tardives).  The wines were really good; so good that I had to stop myself from tasting more than I did because my palate was starting to weaken.  I wonder if it was because I was spitting less and less of the wine as the quality increased…  Coralie spoke great English and was very helpful explaining the terroir of the area, the impact it had on the wines, as well as why each of the wines were unique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/4-1050by788-7c153d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/4-700by525-7c153d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/4-675by506-7c153d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/4-450by338-7c153d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/4-525by394-7c153d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/4-350by263-7c153d.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/4-350by263-7c153d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Riquewihr Vineyards!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The vineyards surrounding the town of Riquewihr.  Obviously Schoenenbourg is the largest physical area and does account for the majority of production, but don’t count out Pflostig or Sporen for quality wines.  And while the production from these areas is mostly white wine, I am excited to see Pinot Noir begin to spread more and more.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On initial inspection of the map above, you may get the impression that Riquewihr is just three large areas producing wine.  If you pay attention to the coloring scheme, you’ll notice five varietals (and two special bottlings) are intertwined non-contiguously throughout the three areas, all planted according to the micro-climates and soil compositions that best suit each one.  This attention to detail really shows in all of their wines, not just their pricier bottlings.  And while their Grossi Laue, Vendange Tardives and Selecion Grain Nobles are noticeably more costly at than other wineries, I do believe you owe it to yourself to find a way to taste them and see if the quality is worth the pricepoint.  They certainly were for me, especially the Grossi Laues…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, the wines!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hugel.com/en/desc.php?N=Y8G9TE&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Gentil&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (10.80€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;4g of residual sugar (RS).  A blend of the six white grapes of Alsace: Sylvaner, Pinot Blanc, Pinot Gris, Riesling, Gewurztraminer, and Muscat.  Pure white flower aromas and a body that is fairly light.  An easy drinking wine for sure that isn’t too bright or deep.  And with Riesling being the largest share of the blend (30%), the acid feels crisp on the finish.  The fruit notes are in the citrus range with light orange as the strongest flavor.  The complexity of the blend isn’t communicated on the palate, so don’t let the label overwhelm you.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hugel.com/en/desc.php?N=S8EFKE&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Muscat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (13.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;1.9g of RS.  Due to the age of the wine, the nose isn’t as pronounced nor expressive as other Muscats you may have in Alsace.  Still, though the flower blossom aromas have dissipated, the orange and honeysuckle are firmly present.  The palate is in line with the aromas and the finish is clean with fine acid that is reminiscent of yellow fruit.  The orange flavor lasts for 5-10 seconds on the finish, making this an interesting Muscat indeed.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hugel.com/en/desc.php?N=1G50CE&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Classic Riesling&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (14.40€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;50% of the fruit is from their Pflostig plot, southwest of the village.  The other 50% is purchased fruit from local growers.  The nose has both yellow fruit and petrol notes and is consistent on the palate, with some unripe peach and orange in there as well.  Again, this is mostly an easier drinking wine with high acid for a hot day.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hugel.com/en/desc.php?N=749IRE&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Estate Riesling (Marnes-Marl)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (20.90€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;As the name indicates, this is made using the estate’s fruit that is grown in Marl soil in the northern part of the village in Schoenenbourg and using some fruit north of Sporen.  While the Classic Riesling is a bit more reserved in its intensity and flavor profile, the Estate Riesling is more generous on both accounts.  Peach and other stonefruit drive the wine on both the nose and palate.  The acidity is still very high and lingers on the cheeks.  Definitely worth the extra 6.50€.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hugel.com/en/desc.php?N=JS9T7E&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2011 Riesling Grossi Laue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (42.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;At seven years old, this wine is slightly less intense than the Estate Riesling, but has wonderful complexity and mouthfeel.  White flowers, honeydew, soft honey, flint and a variety of other terroir notes softly integrate in this Riesling.  The acid is still high, but it has a numbing effect on the cheeks, rather than a pulsing or throbbing effect like other wines.  I feel this wine is drinking very good right now and has plenty of life to age for 10 more years.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hugel.com/en/desc.php?N=9WDIDE&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Riesling Grossi Laue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (43.20€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Two years (and I am sure a very different growing season) make a huge difference.  This wine is much more powerful than the 2013 - think of flavors like exotic tropical fruits like mango, pineapple, etc.  As it makes its way to the palate, you can feel the touch of salinity and terroir (slate-like) notes.  The acidity is a bit more throbbing than the 2011, so I would not serve/drink this right away, but in 3-5 years, who knows how good this wine could be then?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hugel.com/en/desc.php?N=FU8NVE&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2009 Schoelhammmer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (98.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The grapes for this wine come from the same general area as the Grossi Laue, except this is a special 0.6 hectare area that has marl, gypsum, limestone, and clay in its profile as well as a steeper slope than the Grossi Laue area.  The nose is just so sublime – a spectrum of stonefruit, white flowers, and the slightest whiff of honey.  The mouthfeel and palate are fantastic.  I can’t think of anything negative to say about the wine.  If I could afford to drink this wine regularly, I would indeed…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hugel.com/en/desc.php?N=LINN7E&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Estate Pinot Gris (Calcaire-Limestone)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (22.90€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The limestone soil that this wine comes from is similar to what you would find in Burgundy.  On the nose, you’ll find lemon, lime, chalk and zesty mineral notes - it’s quite difficult to describe.  The acidity is better than I was anticipating, creating a mouthwatering effect without any throbbing.  The palate is very fresh, but not unripe at all.  A very nice Pinot Gris indeed.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hugel.com/en/desc.php?N=7TKUFE&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2011 Grossi Laue Pinot Gris&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (40.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Out of all the wines I tasted, this is the bottle I brought back to the states (partly because the Schoelhammer was out of my range).  The fruit comes from the same vineyards as the Estate Pinot Gris, except this wine is aged in new oak barrels for 10 months.  For the aromas, take everything I said about the Estate Pinot Gris and turn up the intensity a couple notches and add some citrus zest.  The palate has yellow and stonefruit with a touch of salinity, but it’s still super pleasing to my American palate.  Ready to drink, easy to enjoy and enough going on to keep me interested.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hugel.com/en/desc.php?N=88E6IE&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2010 Gewurztraminer Grossi Laue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (43.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;16g of RS, which is pretty low for a grand cru Gewurztraminer.  From Sporen in the east which has 60% clay soil.  Many people consider 2010 to be the perfect vintage in Alsace because it wasn’t too hot nor too cold throughout the growing season.  For a varietal Gewurztraminer that has naturally lower acidity, that balance is very important.  The nose is intense but has an elegance that many other Gewurztraminers don’t have.  Aromas of honeysuckle and ripe orange are the strongest and that ripe citrus (orange/tangerine) and stonefruit flavors on the palate are so good…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hugel.com/en/desc.php?N=LTM7JE&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2011 Grossi Laue Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (34.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Alongside their Pinot Gris in Pflostig, the Grossi Laue Pinot Noir is also grown in Limestone soil.  Their menu had the 2010 vintage, but the wine ambassador opened the 2011 for tasting instead.  2010 was a cooler vintage, which is good for Gewurztraminers because it adds acidity and structure for them.  Pinot Noirs in the area already have high acidity, so its better to enjoy warmer vintages like the 2011.  The terroir is fully reflected on the nose and is complemented by tart strawberry and cranberry character.  The palate has wood-related flavor with brooding red fruit underneath that.  The flavors, acid and texture remind me a bit of Burgundy (with a slighter lower price point).  If the palate were a tad riper and brighter, you could fool some people into thinking Premier Cru Burgundy, including possibly myself.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hugel.com/en/desc.php?N=N3L82E&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2011 Riesling Vendange Tardives&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (54.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;63g of RS.  There is quite a bit of noble rot character and petrol on the nose, with orange blossom, honey and pineapple rounding it out.  The flavors, intensity and body are all a result of the ripe fruit and noble rot from harvesting late.  Though interestingly, there is very little petrol character on the palate.  You could fool me into thinking that this was an SGN.  And the medium(+) acidity cuts through on the finish, preventing the wine from feeling overly heavy and giving it a electric brightness.  As dessert wines go, this is up there with all the other SGNs/VTs I’ve tasted.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hugel.com/en/desc.php?N=5V02SE&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2009 Gewurztraminer Vendange Tardive&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (35.40€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;98g of RS.  The grapes come from the east side in Sporen.  The nose has all the classic Gewurztraminer notes; it’s the palate that is the differentiator.  It seems like you are drinking sweet nectar with a decent amount of acidity at the end.  To be clear, this wine is very sweet but in a candied manner rather than a “pure sugar” feel.  The viscosity is at a “syrup” level thanks to the RS, glycerol, and alcohol.  It basically screams “I am the end to your meal – forget dessert”.  If you like dessert wines, prepare to be floored by this wine.  If dessert wines aren’t your thing, this is not a wine I would serve to get you aboard that train (see the Riesling Vendange Tardives above instead).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hugel.com/en/desc.php?N=HJ38HE&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2010 Riesling Selection de Grains Nobles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (145.80€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If someone told you they only had three bottles left of a wine and called it “perfection”, what would you do to try some?  As a lover of sweet wine, I resorted to begging and somehow was allowed the pleasure.  The nose starts muted but after a few swirls, the integrated flavors that make SGN Riesling so seductive (e.g. petrol, noble rot, ripe stonefruit, pineapple) start to flourish.  As the wine touches your palate, your  mouth starts to water with ripe citrus fruit and salinity.  When it finally hits your cheeks, your knees get weak thanks to the tinge of ginger that also comes out.  Add in the mouthwatering acidity and you get a unique beast that separates itself from the pack of SGNs.  You just can’t help but smile drinking this wine…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hugel.com/en/desc.php?N=J0ZV5X&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2007 Gewurztraminer Selection de Grains Nobles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (135.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The first thing you notice in this wine is its deep golden color.  The nose is similar to the Vendange Tardives, except that there is a depth to the flavor which also has some honeycomb/beeswax in the profile.  It has the thickest texture / highest viscosity of all the wines I tasted here, and the palate appears to be less candied than the VT.  It’s because those deep flavors rise to the surface and occupy you with med+ acid, ripe stonefruit, and every piece of the honey production process (pollen, honeycomb, honey, etc.).  Another fantastic wine, but I prefer the Riesling for its unmatched complexity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, the Schoelhammmer and SGNs were show-stoppers, but I can’t stop thinking about the Grossi Laues as being the best bang-for-the-buck here.  The grapes for the Grossi Laue’s come from three different plots in Schoenenbourg that are steeply angled north and south.  There are 12 different soil structures encompassed by those three plots, but they do not classify them nor separate them out as such.  The grapes from these plots are blended together into these wines, which give them complexity but make it harder to pull out flavors attributable to those terroirs.  The wines are also vinified in 19th century huge oak barrels (15000 gallons), allowing some oxidization to round the acidity, but imparting little-to-no wood character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/5-1050by788-c6a133.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/5-700by525-c6a133.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/5-675by506-c6a133.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/5-450by338-c6a133.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/5-525by394-c6a133.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/5-350by263-c6a133.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hugel/5-350by263-c6a133.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;The Vines!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Me and the vines out back behind the town.  I just cannot get over how beautiful Alsace is.  Its seemlingly seas of green and blue continue as far as the eye can see (until you hit the Vosges).  I just could not help but take pictures every few feet…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a real shame that the Vendange Tardives, SGNs and the Grossi Laues do not make it to the US.  As much as I adore white Burgundies (ie. Chardonnays), I would definitely mix the Grossi Laue’s into the periodic doses of white wine that I intake.  This tasting was a real treat and made my trip to Riquewihr worthwhile by itself.  I highly recommend that you stop by the town, if only to visit Hugel.  But I guarantee that you will also enjoy the culinary scene as well - the restaurants here were very good…  So get on out there and enjoy some good wine.  Or at least give that bottle of Hugel in your wine store a try!  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="alsace" /><category term="riquewihr" /><summary type="html">If you are visiting Riquewihr, your first stop should be Hugel et Fils (pronounced UGE-el). There is no argument to be made here. Yes, Riquewihr was the first town in my Alsatian travels that had enough foreigners where I would consider it a tourist destination. Yes, the restaurants were top notch and among the best I visited in Alsace. Yes, there were many other shops and wineries to visit. But it’s Hugel. There is no name that I consider more synonymous with Alsace than Hugel. A large part of that is due to its vast distribution network in the USA and its solid presence on restaurants’ wine lists. But like the best producers, it’s the solid quality year-after-year that have them ranked highly in my book.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/hugel/2.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bott Freres Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/03/16/bott_freres_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bott Freres Public Tasting" /><published>2019-03-16T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-16T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/03/16/bott_freres_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/03/16/bott_freres_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;The thing I love about Alsace is that most of the production comes from small, family-owned wineries.  This can be seen as a double-edged sword because while the styles and varieties on the market can be very different, the quality of production can be very different too.  Luckily, that isn’t really an issue in Alsace as the quality is consistently pretty high across the board.  Though you do find some wineries that just seem to be on another level.  Bott Freres may be my favorite winery in all of Alsace when you factor in the that none of the wines I tasted were above 20 Euros.  The Quality-Price Ratio (QPR) here is just astounding.  I know that is a strong statement and I truly hope that gets you to visit the winery if you ever find yourself in the Alsace region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/1-1050by788-3ac8bb.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/1-700by525-3ac8bb.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/1-675by506-3ac8bb.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/1-450by338-3ac8bb.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/1-525by394-3ac8bb.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/1-350by263-3ac8bb.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/1-350by263-3ac8bb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Bott Freres!!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Bott Freres is a short walk outside of the main area in Ribeauville, but you need to make it here.  Like I said earlier, Bott Freres may be my favorite small producer in Alsace, so be sure to stop by if you are in order around town.  The large sign helps it stick out once you get on the correct street!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it hadn’t been for my waiter at lunch, I might not have discovered Bott Freres!  I hadn’t seen the winery during my earlier walk through the city center.  Unlike many wineries in the Alsace region, the storefront for Bott Freres isn’t along the main street in town, nor does it have a huge building or signs in town pointing to it like Cave du Ribeauville or Domaine Trimbach.  You need to walk a little ways (half a mile) off the main street to find the storefront.  During my walk, I was a bit unlucky because the skies opened up and it felt like the city was going to flood for a good ten minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/2-1050by1400-0d9baf.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/2-700by933-0d9baf.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/2-675by900-0d9baf.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/2-450by600-0d9baf.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/2-525by700-0d9baf.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/2-350by467-0d9baf.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/2-350by467-0d9baf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;The wine ambassador&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The wine ambassador with a really instructive map of the region.  As you can see, there are many wineries along the Vosges Mountain range.  Unfortunately, I did not spend enough time in Alsace, nor did I have a car to explore the smaller towns that didn’t have train stations nearby.  I will be back…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a bit of a mess upon my arrival, but Gladys (their wine ambassador) was kind enough to find me a towel so I could clean myself up as much as possible.  Having done so, I started telling her my story and explaining why I had no vehicle with me…  As we chatted, we started nerding out about all things wine and she was happy to share more details about Alsace that I hadn’t picked up from other wineries, hence the picture with the map above.  Gladys hadn’t traveled outside the country yet, but I think she was paying it forward to a wine traveler and took the extra time to discuss why she decided to join Bott Freres over any other winery.  It turns out she had joined the wine business straight out of high school and while her parents own a vineyard, they sell the fruit they cultivate to bigger wineries.  It’s too bad we didn’t swap contact info - her dreams of getting into the production side of the industry are very similar to my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like other wineries in the region, Bott Freres has been family operated for quite a while.  In fact, the Bott family have been winegrowers in the region since 1835!  Back in those days, being a wine grower was a tradecraft passed down from parents to children, with skills and practices developed and honed over the course of time.  These practices include sustainable agriculture (see: Biodynamic/Organic) and respect what nature gives you, rather than exerting your will upon the land.  The tasting room and building share that same vibe/feeling.  Though, Bott Freres can accomodate up to 50+ people at a time - there is lots of room in the back!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the pleasant conversation and no longer feeling like a wet dog, it was time to start the tasting.  I want to point out that there are times when my palate is a little off after a meal where wine (especially sparkling / white wine) is not as enjoyable as they normally are.  I had no issues with that during this tasting after lunch, which I think is further proof to how good these wines were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bott-freres.fr/en/product/muscat-tradition-2017/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Muscat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (11.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A 50/50 blend of Muscat d’Alsace and Muscat Ottonel.  Very fragrant with notes of the usual aromas (e.g. orange, blosson, etc.).  The mouthfeel is very nice with medium(+) acidity, medium body and a long, lingering finish of white flowers and honeysuckle.  The dryness and high acid makes the flower and honeysuckle feel very pronounced on the palate.  A solid Muscat rendition that has no flaws, is very well balanced and dry.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bott-freres.fr/en/product/riesling-reserve-personnelle-2016/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Riesling Reserve Personnelle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (11.60€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is a little restrained for a Riesling.  The palate is driven by green fruit and high-pitched yellow fruit, with little petrol influence.  Adding to the complexity is a minerality and touch of spice.  Because the wine has a lower intensity, I feel like this could be an easy drinking wine on a hot day with its rounded palate and medium(+) acidity for that crisp finish.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bott-freres.fr/en/product/riesling-grand-cru-kirchberg-de-ribeauville-2016/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Riesling Grand Cru Kirchberg de Ribeauville&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (23.30€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;More fragrant than the Reserve Personnelle, the Kirchberg emphasizes stonefruit and some petrol.  The body is also a bit more viscous, but the main differentiator is the salinity (Kirchberg is primarily limestone).  That salinity and yellow fruit linger for 30+ seconds on the finish, which is very impressive.  The rest of the flavor profile and acidity are similar to the Personnelle above.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bott-freres.fr/en/product/riesling-grand-cru-osterberg-2016/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Riesling Grand Cru Osterberg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (21.30€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Similar to the Kirchberg, but more rounded and less pronounced.  According to Gladys, the diurnal range for Kirchberg is greater than Osterberg, which is why you perceive more acidity and greater intensity in the Kirchberg.  While I would serve the Kirchberg to friends with dinner, the Osterberg is the bottle I’d open if I wanted to enjoy a bottle without a food pairing.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bott-freres.fr/en/product/cremant-dalsace-brut-blanc-de-noirs/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NV Blanc de Noirs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (16.10€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Solid body with aggressive, mousy bubbles.  The palate has trace of red fruit, but the high acid and rampant bubble make it tough to feel out the full range of flavors.  I doubt it’s undergone MLF because of the acidity, but some lees aging makes sense.  Not my favorite sparkling wine from the Alsace region.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bott-freres.fr/en/product/gewurztraminer-reserve-personnelle-2016/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Gewurztraminer Reserve Personnelle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (15.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Aromatic and pronounced on the palate, but very smooth.  The full range of flavors from the Gewurztraminer varietal are on display in this wine up to orange marmalade.  The acidity isn’t noticeable until the finish, but it helps shape the round body.  The finish also goes on for 20+ seconds with white spice emerging as well.  The balance on this Gewurztraminer is what impresses me the most - normally something feels out of place but all of the parts fit together perfectly in this wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bott-freres.fr/en/product/riesling-vendanges-tardives-2011/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2011 Riesling Vendanges Tardives&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (31.70€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This wine is just stunning.  I daresay it surpasses all the other VT and Selection Grain Nobles Rieslings that I have had in terms of flavor intensity (ripe peach and stonefruit) and acidity.  The prominent acid leaves you with a tingling sensation that surpasses the duration of the 30+ second finish.  No noticeable petrol notes or they take a back seat to the fruit at least.  This needs to be a dessert wine at a Michelin restaurant.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had to sum up the experience, the style of Bott Freres lies in the purity of expression.  This applies to both the varietal character that their sustainable agriculture nurtures and the sense of place described in the terroir driven tertiary notes.  You hardly notice any human intervention in these wines which is quite the achievement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/3-1050by788-f5db19.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/3-700by525-f5db19.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/3-675by506-f5db19.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/3-450by338-f5db19.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/3-525by394-f5db19.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/3-350by263-f5db19.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bott-freres/3-350by263-f5db19.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Selfie Time!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It was raining most of the day in Ribeauville, which was a little unusual…  Most of the townspeople were excited for it, so I didn’t mind walking through it.  It’s really hard not to smile when you drink great wine, meet nice people, and just see beautiful history and nature all around you…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I could not purchase all of the wine I wanted thanks to the expensive shipping costs; it’s 202 Euros for shipping and taxes to ship a case to the USA directly from the winery.  Their distributors in the USA (at the time of this writing) are Wine Universe (NY) and DB Wine Selection, who is based in the Northeast USA and is both an importer and distributor.  Of the wines I tried, their Muscat, Reserve Personnelle Gewurztraminer and Riesling Vendages Tardives were the ones I craved multiple bottles of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, if you are in the area, Bott Freres is a must visit.  Please take the opportunity to explore off the beaten path (or in this case, the main road in town) and enjoy!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="alsace" /><category term="ribeauville" /><summary type="html">The thing I love about Alsace is that most of the production comes from small, family-owned wineries. This can be seen as a double-edged sword because while the styles and varieties on the market can be very different, the quality of production can be very different too. Luckily, that isn’t really an issue in Alsace as the quality is consistently pretty high across the board. Though you do find some wineries that just seem to be on another level. Bott Freres may be my favorite winery in all of Alsace when you factor in the that none of the wines I tasted were above 20 Euros. The Quality-Price Ratio (QPR) here is just astounding. I know that is a strong statement and I truly hope that gets you to visit the winery if you ever find yourself in the Alsace region.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/bott-freres/2.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Cave du Ribeauville Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/03/09/cave_du_ribeauville_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cave du Ribeauville Public Tasting" /><published>2019-03-09T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-09T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/03/09/cave_du_ribeauville_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/03/09/cave_du_ribeauville_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Most people come to Ribeauville to visit Maison Trimbach, which is famous, has a large production each year, and has a good amount of distribution in the USA.  I did too, but unfortunately Maison Trimbach was closed when I arrived in August.  In fact, many wineries in France are closed for vacations between late July and mid-August before the harvest.  Fortunately Cave de Ribeauville, the second largest place in town, was still open and I quickly diverted there out of the drizzling rain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/1-1050by788-ceefd1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/1-700by525-ceefd1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/1-675by506-ceefd1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/1-450by338-ceefd1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/1-525by394-ceefd1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/1-350by263-ceefd1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/1-350by263-ceefd1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Ribeauville!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The largest wine storefront in the town of Ribeauville.  It is pretty amazing what local winegrowers can do when they band together.  I know that it may not look that fancy on the outside, but the inside is a whole other story…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though Cave de Ribeauville has a large production (it its actually Top 5 in the Alsace region), it is not because it is a large winery.  Rather, it is a large cooperative of many small producers that go in together, share equipment and facilities, and bottle wines under the same brand.  Some of the producers will also bottle some wine under their own brand per the cooperative’s guidelines.  It’s rather remarkable that in today’s capitalistic markets, you can still find examples where people work together for everyone’s benefit.  Thankfully for the rest of us, this cooperation also results in better product and amazing prices…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/2-1050by788-4db94b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/2-700by525-4db94b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/2-675by506-4db94b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/2-450by338-4db94b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/2-525by394-4db94b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/2-350by263-4db94b.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/2-350by263-4db94b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;The guts of the building&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Didn’t I say that the inside of the building was much nicer?  In addition to selling wines, the building also has exhibits that talks through the history of the region and its winegrowers.  I highly recommend that you read up and take a look around before heading for the tasting table.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must admit that the exterior of the building had me rather skeptical at first, but that impression changed immediately after stepping foot inside, as you can see above.  It reminded me of the interiors of wineries back home.  Though as a bonus, they also had display cases, exhibits and maps that explained the history of the area as well as the surrounding grand crus to help familiarize folks with the region.  As I had arrived soon after the building opened and on a weekday, I was left to my own devices for a while.  After inhaling a bit of history, it was time to head to the counter and taste some wines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/3-1050by788-30d40c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/3-700by525-30d40c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/3-675by506-30d40c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/3-450by338-30d40c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/3-525by394-30d40c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/3-350by263-30d40c.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/3-350by263-30d40c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Ready when they are&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view from the tasting counter.  There really isn’t a set tasting menu - you mostly just tell them what you are interested in and what you want to taste and they’ll usually pour it for you.  I may have taken it a bit too far as you can see from the number of wines I wrote about&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At most wineries in the area, there is usually a tasting menu or whoever is pouring for you will choose a lineup of the portfolio.  Here, there are so many wines on the list that it’s not really possible to do either.  Since I looked like I knew what I was doing (taking notes on the laptop helped with that impression), they let me taste around on the list until they got busier.  A shout-out to the two people that ran my tasting below - I got to try a number of really interesting wines thanks to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/4-1050by788-0d8f6d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/4-700by525-0d8f6d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/4-675by506-0d8f6d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/4-450by338-0d8f6d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/4-525by394-0d8f6d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/4-350by263-0d8f6d.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/4-350by263-0d8f6d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Thank you for the great tasting!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The kind folks that ran my tasting for the morning.  I was there bright and early, and as a result got a lot of attention and pours until other customers started arriving.  I had made it through a good port of the menu by then though, haha.  It was also impressive how fluent they were in German and English - I wish I was that smart.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, the wines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boutique.vins-ribeauville.com/en/vin-et-cremant-alsace/alsace-sparkling-wine/cremant-giersberger-brut/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cremant Giersberger Brut&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (8.95€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A sparkling blend of Pinot Blanc and Pinot Auxeroiss.  Light green apple aromas on the nose with very high acid and flavors of green apple, lemon, lime and similar notes on the palate.  I didn’t get any minerality, but the high acid could obscure that.  A good choice served cold on a hot day in Alsace.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boutique.vins-ribeauville.com/en/vin-et-cremant-alsace/alsace-sparkling-wine/cremant-la-grande-cuvee/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cremant La Grande Cuvee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (18.70€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Vin de France reviewed this wine at 14.5/20.  A Pinot Noir + Chardonnay blend with more complexity going on aromatically than the Giersberger.  It still leans on the lighter, fruity side rather than secondary/tertiary aromas.  The palate displays that brioche character from lees aging for a significant period, but the wine still has plenty of warm yellow fruit on the palate.  The acid is very high, leading me to believe they skipped MLF before the 72 months in the cellar.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boutique.vins-ribeauville.com/en/vin-et-cremant-alsace/collection-en-2/muscat-collection-sec/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Muscat Collection 2017 SEC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (8.35€
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose on this wine is downright powerful.  Orange, blossoms, and all the other notes you expect from a blend of Muscat Ottonel and d’Alsace.  The body and acid are smooth and hold up the wine wonderfully.  I would love to serve this as an aperitif for meals because of its huge aromatics, dryness and easy drinking.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Pinot Blanc Barriques&lt;/strong&gt; (8.80€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Spends a year in barrel unlike most Pinot Blanc from the region.  Thanks to this aging, the aromatics are exponentially greater than their other traditional Pinot Blanc.  Apple pie, coconut, light spice and vanilla character dominate the nose.  The palate is as or more intense than the nose.  People may not like this wine because it’s so big and different.  But because of its unusual profile, you know I bought a couple bottles…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boutique.vins-ribeauville.com/en/vin-et-cremant-alsace/lieux-dits-et-villages-vin-de-reserve/riesling-haguenau/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Riesling Lieu Dit Haguenau&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (10.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;High pitched intensity aromas of lemon, petrol and maybe some almond oil as well, but the fruit was much more subdued than I was expecting.  High acid and intensity of the same flavors on the palate.  I really enjoyed the complexity and that fact that neither the primary or tertiary flavors were dominant - a nicely balanced wine at 5 years old.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boutique.vins-ribeauville.com/en/vin-et-cremant-alsace/riesling-en/riesling-comtes-de-ribeauville-2010/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2010 Riesling Comtes De Ribeauville&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (9.30€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Similar notes to the Lieu Dit Haguenau on the nose, but the Comtes is a bit deeper and richer with almond milk notes and reveals more petrol plus minerality.  The acidity is quite a bit less which enhances the richness of the coconut, almond, and petrol a bit more.  The lemon and yellow fruit take a backseat here to the tertiary character and that is not a bad thing…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boutique.vins-ribeauville.com/en/vin-et-cremant-alsace/riesling-en/riesling-grand-cru-osterberg/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Riesling Grand Cru Osterberg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (20.20€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bright, light stonefruit and petrol notes on the nose.  The palate is similar in profile with a little white spice on the finish as well.  I need to call out the balance of the acid, body, and alcohol here - they are already integrating very well.  The acid is higher than the Kirhcberg, which makes this more refreshing and easy to pair in a meal, but the balance also means you can easily enjoy this wine by itself.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boutique.vins-ribeauville.com/en/vin-et-cremant-alsace/riesling-en/riesling-grand-cru-kirchberg-2016/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Riesling Grand Cru Kirchberg de Ribeauville&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (19.70€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;High intensity stone fruit with undulating coconut oil, and a light layer of petrol on the nose.  You can pick out the stonefruit but it’s very well integrated.  The palate emphasizes the stonefruit but is balanced by the acid so that is doesn’t taste/feel overly ripe for a Riesling.  Like the Osterberg, this is also very smooth and has a strong medium+ body for a Riesling.  Enjoy this wine by itself - it deserves it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boutique.vins-ribeauville.com/en/vin-et-cremant-alsace/riesling-en/riesling-grand-cru-rosacker/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Rosacker Riesling Grand Cru&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (15.20€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This Riesling is on the lighter/creamier side.  The stonefruit comes right out on both the nose and palate.  This wine is so well rounded, I’m guessing it may have a tiny bit of residual sugar that balances the high acidity and gives that mouthfeel that roundness.  The flavor of the wine is similar to the others with its stonefruit, vanilla, and coconut notes.  But it is the tactile roundness that distinguishes this wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Riesling Vendanges Tardives&lt;/strong&gt; (17€ for 500mL)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Their late harvest Riesling.  The acidity feels just right on the palate and the flavors are balanced between the fruit and the petrol.  The acidity is still high and gives the wine that clean finish which keeping the nose a bit lighter than the other Rieslings.  This is a sweet wine, but it’s not too sweet.  Combining that character with the high acid and medium(+) body, this would make a great dessert wine but I could see myself drinking it by itself too.  Again, the balance here is key…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boutique.vins-ribeauville.com/en/vin-et-cremant-alsace/great-vintage/pinot-gris-grand-cru-kirchberg/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Pinot Gris Grand Cru Kirchberg de Ribeauville&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (17.20€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bright, light, ripe yellow fruit on the nose with medium(-) intensity.  I’m guessing that there is some residual sugar because the palate seems beyond ripe with the stonefuit and melon.  Though I really appreciate the beeswax and honeycomb that is here too.  Medium acid that rounds out the mid/back palate.  This is definitely a ripe, complex wine that US drinkers would like and need more exposure to.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boutique.vins-ribeauville.com/en/vin-et-cremant-alsace/great-vintage/pinot-gris-grand-cru-altenberg-de-bergheim-2015-casher/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2010 Pinot Gris Grand Cru Altenberg de Bergheim&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (18.40€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The deep color on this is almost of a late-harvest wine.  High intensity aromatics of pineapples and other tropical fruit.  This wine had everything working for it: 2010 was a great ripe year, Altenberg is one of their best grand crus, and Pinot Gris is a very aromatic grape.  Put them altogether and its no wonder this smells like a late harvest wine.  Because of the ripeness, the palate seems to lack the acid necessary to age this wine, though the residual sugar may help.  If you want a sweet wine without the thick body or pure sugar flavor, this is a great wine to try.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boutique.vins-ribeauville.com/en/vin-et-cremant-alsace/clos-du-zahnacker-en/clos-du-zahnacker-2012/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Clos du Zahnacker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (23.20€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Clos du Zahnacker wines are from a very special plot of co-planted varietals on very old vines that produce very distinctive wines.  The nose on the 2012 is very soft and integrated.  The palate mirrors that integration with medium(+) acid and a very smooth palate.  This wine is as complex as you want it to be - the deeper you dig into the integrated whole, the more pieces you begin to feel out.  By the same token, you can also sit back and just enjoy this as a easy drinking wine if you don’t want to think about it.  A great wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Clos du Zahnacker&lt;/strong&gt; (29€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The 2013 feels more dominated by the Gewurztraminer in the blend.  There is more intense varietal character here (though still medium intensity) and more acid than the 2012.  Building on that acid is a salinity in the wine as well.  The 2013 doesn’t quite have the integration and just seems a bit more clunky than the 2012, but that probably will smooth out over time.  Another wine that is very interesting to dive deep on and decompose.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Riesling Selection de Grains Nobles&lt;/strong&gt; (25€ for 500mL)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is much lighter than I was expecting, given its Riesling and an SGN at that.  And though the body is medium(+), the acid is still high.  Contrasting those contradictions, the flavors are much more balanced than I thought they would be, and without much petrol character.  Yes the wine is sweet, but it seemingly emphasizes the ripeness of the fruit more than the residual sugar content.  This is probably the first SGN I have had where I think (well, nay, I know) that I could drink more than one glass in a single sitting.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, this was quite a lineup that even I had a hard time getting through.  While all of the wines were solid (and some even more than that), the Clos du Zahnackers were just special.  A 4000 bottle production each year and exclusive property of the “Le Cave de Ribeauville” since 1935, located in the heart of the Grand Cru Osterberg vineyard.  It is said that Louis XIV liked this wine, which is a blend of Riesling, Pinot Gris, and Gewurztraminer that are grown intertwined and are pressed/vinified together.  I walked away with several bottles, which is saying a lot since I only had room for 16-20 wines in my luggage for a 3 week trip.  And when you see vineyards just down the street from the winery (see picture below), how could I not pick up multiple bottles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/5-1050by788-f666ab.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/5-700by525-f666ab.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/5-675by506-f666ab.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/5-450by338-f666ab.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/5-525by394-f666ab.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/5-350by263-f666ab.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cave-du-ribeauville/5-350by263-f666ab.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Which way did you think I went?&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;As I mention in other articles, the vines of Alsace are mostly planted on a slope facing south.  You can get a taste of the elevation of the vines and the slope from this selfie.  Which way do you think I decided to walk after checking out the sign?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the greatest surprise of all, even more than the great quality and variety that had at the winery, was the price on these wines.  Normally when you think of “Grand Cru” the price ends with at least two 0s.  But most of the Grand Crus here were under 20€!!  I literally asked multiple times that the prices listed were for 750mL (normal-sized) bottles, which they were.  The Vendange Tardives and Selection de Grains Nobles cost more than the other Grand Cru because they must be picked by hand, and therefore the labor costs / costs to produce the wines are higher.  Over the course of the tasting, I saw at least 20 different people come in, get a sample of a wine, buy a box of it, and walk out.  At these prices, I would too!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the shipping prices to the USA is prohibitively high.  I asked for the names of their distributors; Eastern Wine Distrubutors (NY) and Golden Ram LLC (NY) are the closest to my area.  I will be reaching out to them soon to see where I can find these wines in stores or if I can purchase from them directly because if the prices are anywhere near what I listed above, the quality will be well worth the price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do regret not spending more than a day in Ribeauville and it has been added to the top of my list to visit again.  The wineries in town are all rated very highly by travelers and by the wine ambassadors that work at the wineries.  And when you visit, please do not overlook Cave du Ribeauville.  I promise you will find something you like (as long as its a white wine, haha).  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="alsace" /><category term="ribeauville" /><summary type="html">Most people come to Ribeauville to visit Maison Trimbach, which is famous, has a large production each year, and has a good amount of distribution in the USA. I did too, but unfortunately Maison Trimbach was closed when I arrived in August. In fact, many wineries in France are closed for vacations between late July and mid-August before the harvest. Fortunately Cave de Ribeauville, the second largest place in town, was still open and I quickly diverted there out of the drizzling rain.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/cave-du-ribeauville/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Domaine des Marronniers Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/03/02/domaine_wach_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Domaine des Marronniers Public Tasting" /><published>2019-03-02T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-02T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/03/02/domaine_wach_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/03/02/domaine_wach_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Andlau may be a small town, but its vineyards and views are second to none in the Alsace region.  In addition, it is home to some of the most interesting Grand Crus of Alsace, which make it a must visit when traveling through Alsace.  There are a few wineries to possibly visit for a tasting in Andlau, but none have as comprehensive of a wine tasting menu as Domaine des Marronniers.  Their social media presence and website are also more up-to-date and accessible than many of its peers.  As luck would have it, I was staying in a hotel next door to the winery, so it only made sense for me to arrange a tasting and talk through their portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/1-1050by788-5d4bbd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/1-700by525-5d4bbd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/1-675by506-5d4bbd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/1-450by338-5d4bbd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/1-525by394-5d4bbd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/1-350by263-5d4bbd.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/1-350by263-5d4bbd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Obligatory Selfie&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;An obligatory selfie with some of vines.  The landscape of the Andlau region is quite something to behold.  Many of the vines in the region are planted on a southernly slope to maximize the amount of sunlight they capture with cool temperatures still keeping the acidity high.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many others in the region, Domaine des Marronniers is a family operation.  In fact, many entities (including Google) still refer to the winery as Domaine Wach (its owner Guy Wach changed the name from Domaine Wach in 1980).  But unlike many other wineries in the region, their ties to the world of wine go all the way back to 1748, before there was even a USA!  While their ancestors have long been barrel makers as their trade, more recent generations of the family have transitioned towards wine growing and making.  And they couldn’t have found a better place to settle down; of the quality land that surrounds them, Domaine Wach owns 17.8 acres, of which nearly 3 acres are Grand Cru classified.  Even more impressive is the average age of their vines (40+ years), which you’d more likely find for Old Vine Zinfandel, not Riesling and other white varietals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make sure that my palate was in top shape to enjoy the experience, I made a morning appointment.  Jessica, the wine ambassador, was very generous to open a little early for me so that I could catch my scheduled taxi to Ribeauville.  Jessica is a certified sommelier from Montreal, meaning that she is fluent in English and French.  This of course meant that in addition to talking about our shared love of wine and her chance meeting with the winemaker while working in New Zealand (which is how she ended up in Alsace), we had to talk about my love of hockey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/2-1050by788-ea8a96.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/2-700by525-ea8a96.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/2-675by506-ea8a96.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/2-450by338-ea8a96.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/2-525by394-ea8a96.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/2-350by263-ea8a96.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-wach/2-350by263-ea8a96.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;The Wine Ambassador&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The tasting bar at Domaine Wach.  Just to the side, there is a large room with a grand dinner table that seems like it could hold 8-10 guests for a tasting and meal pairing.  I came in the morning, but the Wine Ambassador was happy to host me and opened a great array of wines that left me more thirsty than when I had arrived!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the fun chat, we both got strangely serious as she poured the first wine.  It was gametime and I was ready:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Andlau Muscat d’Alsace&lt;/strong&gt; (9.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A blend of Muscat d’Alsace and Muscat Ottonel.  The intensity of the nose is light for a Muscat, but its notes are in line with the varietal character.  The interesting thing is the palate, which stays crisp, dry and feels like a light white wine, rather than the traditional renditions of Muscat.  The balance between the aromas and mouthfeel without either feeling too big/heavy are what make this different.  Drink it cool while outside on a hot summer day.  The flavors dwell around the citrus range, leaning towards oranges.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Andlau Riesling&lt;/strong&gt; (9.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Slight petrol on the nose, but the aromas were a bit muted overall.  The flavors are a tad underripe (think grapefruit) with high acidity on the palate.  Their best QPR bottle in the Wine Ambassadors opinion - they opened a bottle of vintage 1998 recently and thought it aged fairly well for a non-Grand Cru bottle.  This is for those that don’t like their Rieslings too ripe.  Or in my mind, a “without wine, it’s just breakfast” type of bottle.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Grand Cru Wiebelsberg Riesling&lt;/strong&gt; (16.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is clearly more fragrant than the Andlau with white flowers and stonefruit coming out.  It also has a tad more flesh on the body, less noticeable acidity and more intensity on the palate.  This was just really smooth and a pleasure to drink; you can have this all year round as it doesn’t need to pair with any particular temperature or meal to get great enjoyment.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Grand Cru Moenchberg Riesling&lt;/strong&gt; (16.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Riesling and Pinot Gris from Moenchberg are the first to be ready for harvest each year where limestone permeates the soil.  This combination results in less fragrance and less fruit on the nose, though more white flower than the Wiebelsberg and tiny amounts of petrol.  The mouthfeel also has more mouthwatering acidity to go with the medium(-) intensity stonefruit.  While this wine is also very easy to drink, I would pair it with fish and enjoy closer to the summertime than the Wiebelsberg.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Grand Cru Kastelberg Riesling&lt;/strong&gt; (18.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The star of the still white wines.  As mentioned above, the limited acreage means only 5 wineries get to work with these grapes that are grown on blue schist.  The QPR for this bottle is off-the-charts.  The salinity and minerality on the nose and palate are quite something and had me craving seafood for lunch…  Those notes paired with the acidity stimulates the cheeks for more than a minute on the finish, like something touched the funnybone of your cheeks.  You can cellar this for 20+ years and it will still be good, though obviously with more petrol notes.  I normally prefer fruit forward wines, but I had to have multiple bottles of this wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NV Cremant d’Alsace&lt;/strong&gt; (9.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Alsace is the largest producer of cremant in France, with cremant representing over 20% of Alsace’s total wine production.  This one is 70% Chardonnay, 30% Pinot Blanc.  The winemaker wanted to produce a bottle that pairs well with meals without relying on high acidity (ie. didn’t want to use Riesling).  This spends 24 months on the lees gaining texture and flavor and is finished at 6 g/L RS (residual sugar), adding to the balance and body.  The nose immediately brings up thoughts of delicate cream and MLF.  The palate is voluminous with creamy mousse and the flavors are consistent with the nose plus flavors of semi-ripe green/yellow fruit and medium(+) acidity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2006 Grand Cru Wiebelsberg Riesling Selection de Grains Nobles&lt;/strong&gt; (32.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Using Riesling for an SGN is unusual - most of the SGNs I came across while in Alsace were either Pinot Gris or Gewurztraminer, so this is was a happy surprise!  I really liked this wine because of the additional acidity provided by the Riesling that helped to balance and cut through the sweetness on the finish.  Also, the nose was very aromatic with the petrol and botrytis notes basically leaping from the glass.  Those flavors carry onto the palate with some honeyed notes as well.  Of note, the body isn’t unctuous like other SGNs.  The varietal character just adds another dimension and balance to this SGN making it hard to resist.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to Marc Kreydenweiss, even though this is one of the larger producers in the area and has a good portion of the coveted plantings in Kastelberg, its production level is still small by American standards (their total production is roughly 45,000 bottles annually).  That is a real shame because the QPR on all of these wines is really good, even for the SGN in my opinion.  But the biggest shame is that I don’t believe there is an American distributor for this winery and the shipping cost per case to the USA is 180€ - nearly 15€ a bottle!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend stopping by Andlau in Alsace for a day if you have the chance.  And make sure you have some space in your luggage, because if you love any of the bottles you taste here, that’s the likely way you’ll be able to bring the bottles you like back home with you, haha.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="alsace" /><category term="andlau" /><summary type="html">Andlau may be a small town, but its vineyards and views are second to none in the Alsace region. In addition, it is home to some of the most interesting Grand Crus of Alsace, which make it a must visit when traveling through Alsace. There are a few wineries to possibly visit for a tasting in Andlau, but none have as comprehensive of a wine tasting menu as Domaine des Marronniers. Their social media presence and website are also more up-to-date and accessible than many of its peers. As luck would have it, I was staying in a hotel next door to the winery, so it only made sense for me to arrange a tasting and talk through their portfolio.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/domaine-wach/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Domaine Marc Kreydenweiss Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/23/marc_kreydenweiss_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Domaine Marc Kreydenweiss Private Tasting" /><published>2019-02-23T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-23T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/23/marc_kreydenweiss_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/23/marc_kreydenweiss_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Without a doubt, there are many wineries along the northern Alsacian trail that serve great wine.  But Domaine Marc Kreydenweiss is near the top of my list for places that you should stop at.  Midway between Mittelbergheim and the center of the Andlau region, this small organic/biodynamic producer churns out great wine, year after year.  Domaine Marc Kreydenweiss has been managing their 14 hectares this way since 1989 - they’ve been doing it for so long that they had input into the actual definition of both organic and biodynamic farming for wine since there were only a few vineyards that were attempting / executing this vision back then.  Organic and Biodynamic wines have been all over the map for me (some great, some bad), but these were definitely some of the better ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/1-1050by788-10b31c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/1-700by525-10b31c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/1-675by506-10b31c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/1-450by338-10b31c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/1-525by394-10b31c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/1-350by263-10b31c.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/1-350by263-10b31c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;On the road to Kreydenweiss!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Walking the back paths off of the highway to Domaine Marc Kreydenweiss.  Again, normally a mile walk is fine, but when you are carrying your luggage with you, it’s a little more difficult.  There are NO ubers out here, so find the phone numbers of the 1-2 taxi drivers in town and make use of them!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/2-1050by788-19bbc1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/2-700by525-19bbc1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/2-675by506-19bbc1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/2-450by338-19bbc1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/2-525by394-19bbc1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/2-350by263-19bbc1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/2-350by263-19bbc1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Selfie time!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It was a tough (and hot) walk, but that doesn’t mean I disliked it…  The views along the path were just stunning and cut right through the vineyards.  There’s a common understanding to not touch the vines, but the level of trust to let people walk through the vineyards is still stunning.  I know, I am practically glowing with excitement…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, because their wine is of such quality, you can sometimes find it in the American market or in restaurants that sport a healthy white wine menu, even though their production isn’t all that high; their annual production comes in around 70,000 bottles.  They have successfully grown over the past 30+ years and now own vineyards in the Rhone Valley as well!  Because the Rhone vineyards are still up-and-coming, Marc’s eldest son manages and produces the wines from his Alsacian holdings (since 2007) while Marc and his younger son live in the south and manage the Rhone Valley vineyards.  Don’t fret for their family though; both sites are separated only by a ~3-hour train ride.  And if you were to ask me, the eldest son got the better part of the deal - it is just gorgeous here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/3-1050by1400-068cd6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/3-700by933-068cd6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/3-675by900-068cd6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/3-450by600-068cd6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/3-525by700-068cd6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/3-350by467-068cd6.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/3-350by467-068cd6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Make sure you have your international data plan on as the entrance can be a little hard to find.  Try to make a reservation ahead of time too if only to confirm that someone is at the building when you will be dropping by.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you make it into the town area, finding the actual winery (it’s more like a wine shop) can be a little tough, but if you stay true to Google Maps, you should be fine.  I highly recommend making reservations to ensure that they are open and have wines available for you to taste on arrival.  Once you check in at the front, you’ll head upstairs with your wine ambassador for the tasting.  The size, experience, and foot-traffic is very different from USA wineries, but is very typical of smaller wineries in the less visited locations of Europe.  I myself enjoy the more personal experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/4-1050by788-d1830a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/4-700by525-d1830a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/4-675by506-d1830a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/4-450by338-d1830a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/4-525by394-d1830a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/4-350by263-d1830a.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/4-350by263-d1830a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It really isn’t a winery as much as their wine tasting room and storefront.  You could easily purchase a bottle and a cheese board and enjoy sitting inside.  Do not expect grand estates along Alsace - most of the wineries are small and family run.  But the wine quality matches up with best so don’t judge a book by its cover.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you take a walk outside with the wine ambassador for a quick overview of the region, you’ll notice that the altitude at the bottom here is ~100m with a hill that goes up to 400m.  You can also see the Kastelberg and Wiebelsberg Grand Crus nearby.  Auxerrois (more fruit, less acid) and Pinot Blanc (more acid, less fruit) are co-planted in the vineyard - a planting style that harkens back to olden times when this was done as a risk-aversion method.  Higher variety in the vineyard meant a greater chance something would survive a challenging growing season.  When you walk through the vineyards, you can clearly see the different rocks/soil-types that the grapes are grown in: pink sandstone in Weibelsberg, black slate in Kastelberg, with marl and limestone in Moenchberg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/5-1050by788-2eb4fa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/5-700by525-2eb4fa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/5-675by506-2eb4fa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/5-450by338-2eb4fa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/5-525by394-2eb4fa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/5-350by263-2eb4fa.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/marc-kreydenweiss/5-350by263-2eb4fa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A topographical breakdown of the area of Alsace I (and Domaine Marc Kreydenweiss) were in.  As you can see, there are many different Grand Cru and other demarcated areas in the region.  The terroir is very different across small patches of land (similar to Burgundy), so track where you are and where your Alsacian wine is from very carefully.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the introduction to the family, the vineyards, the grapes, and the biodynamic management/production methods, it was time to introduce the wines!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Kritt Pinot Blanc&lt;/strong&gt; (11.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Ripe fruit on the nose that almost hits pineapple, with lots of cooked yellow fruit too.  Meant to be a simple wine for a simple meal with its high acidity and refreshing profile.  Pinot Blanc is 30% their production.  Kritt is a very stoney place with lots of quartz in the ground and cool winds that blow through.  That acidity is crazy for the amount of ripe fruit in the wine, plus the minerality adds complexity too.  I can see why this is their best-seller and why they produce so much of it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt; (14.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The fruit is not from their vineyard as they don’t grow any Pinot Noir.  True to their beliefs though, they purchase the grapes from other biodynamic vineyards in the area.  Aromas of strawberry and terroir/wildness that is indicative of biodynamic wines.  The feet-crushed grapes, rustic winemaking style and low sulfite content, especially for a Pinot Noir, lead to this wild flavor that leaves you in disbelief.  If you are looking for complexity, this has it with high acidity to boot.  I personally don’t prefer the off-taste of biodynamic wines, but this one isn’t as pronounced as the others I’ve had in the past.  You don’t need to twist my arm to offer me a second glass…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Clos Rebberg (Riesling)&lt;/strong&gt; (23.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Clos Rebberg has terroir of blue/gray schist with lots of small layers and is the oldest geological formation in the area.  It’s interesting that Kreydenweiss replanted their Pinot Gris with Riesling because the animals would eat the grapes (Pinot Gris is sweeter with less acid and less petrol).  You can feel the petrol notes here but the yellow fruit and wild flavors are stronger with high acid, a nice hint of white pepper on the finish, and good minerality.  This is not a fruit driven wine - there is too much complexity to classify it that way.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Kritt Gewurztraminer&lt;/strong&gt; (18.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is a bit prettier and higher in acidity than other Gewurztraminers I’ve had.  The palate is very clean – this bottle is one that you pair in a meal as it’s not too intense that it would overwhelm its paired dish.  Though, it is a bit light in intensity on the palate, so I wouldn’t choose this wine over some other Gewurztraminers from the region for enjoying a glass by itself.  Gewurz means “spice” in German and this wine lives up to that with its white pepper.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Wiebelsberg Grand Cru (Riesling)&lt;/strong&gt; (28.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wiebelsberg has a south-facing steep slope with soil made of pink sandstone that doesn’t retain water very well.  The pink sandstone appears everywhere in the village because it’s easy to shape / work with.  Women built the church here in town, which gave the area is its name: hill (berg) of the lady (wiebel).  Again, some petrol varietal character but spice on the nose too.  The fruit is more muted than the Clos Rebberg, though it has decent length with fresh yellow fruit, some stonefruit, and white spice on the palate and finish.  High, refreshing acid gives it a nice crisp finish as well.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Kastelberg Grand Cru (Riesling)&lt;/strong&gt; (45.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Kreydenweiss balances the lack of sulfur used with CO2 in this wine, which is why it sometimes bubbles when you decant it.  Kastelberg is very rocky (black schist) and the soil is poor, so they minimize yields to protect the vineyards.  The Kastelberg Grand Cru is 5 hectares and is only Riesling (Kreydenweiss owns 1 hectare).  I haven’t decanted too many white wines before, so this was a treat.  That decanting does help it open up and gives it a creamier feel on the palate.  Although the acid is high, this wine is still super smooth - it undergoes MLF and 18 mths aging on the lees to smooth out the acid while adding complexity, though the MLF notes were near invisible to me.  There is even some tartaric acid as well from the skins because they gently squeeze the grapes for 10 hours in the pneumatic press.  This wine tastes like it’s their flagship wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Quality-Price Ratio (QPR) for these wines are quite good as high quality white wines in the USA traditionally cost markedly more.  In addition, finding Biodynamic wines of this caliber is not an easy proposition, though it is getting better as more people practice it and get a better feel for it.  I myself walked away with a few bottles, keen to share them with friends that would appreciate the ideals behind the wines in addition to the wines themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For wines that are harder to find, I’ll try to include the distributor information so that you might try to reach out to them directly if you want to pursue purchasing any bottles.  For Marc Kreydenweiss, the closest importer/distributor to the DMV is Williams Corner in Charlottesville, Virginia.  But if you ever find yourself in that part of France, you should absolutely stop by for a visit and some education.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="alsace" /><category term="andlau" /><summary type="html">Without a doubt, there are many wineries along the northern Alsacian trail that serve great wine. But Domaine Marc Kreydenweiss is near the top of my list for places that you should stop at. Midway between Mittelbergheim and the center of the Andlau region, this small organic/biodynamic producer churns out great wine, year after year. Domaine Marc Kreydenweiss has been managing their 14 hectares this way since 1989 - they’ve been doing it for so long that they had input into the actual definition of both organic and biodynamic farming for wine since there were only a few vineyards that were attempting / executing this vision back then. Organic and Biodynamic wines have been all over the map for me (some great, some bad), but these were definitely some of the better ones.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/marc-kreydenweiss/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Domaine Albert Seltz Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/16/albert_seltz_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Domaine Albert Seltz Private Tasting" /><published>2019-02-16T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-16T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/16/albert_seltz_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/16/albert_seltz_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;The first stop on my Alsace + Rhone wine vacation.  Straight off the train from Strasbourg, I walked half a mile with all of my luggage to get here.  The backwoods path was beautiful but carrying three bags will put a damper on enjoying that.  Even though I was traveling in the fall and the temperature was relatively cool, the intensity of the sun was fairly strong as the vineyards of Alsace are generally planted on southern facing slopes next to the Vosges Mountain range to absorb as much of the light as possible, leading to ripe fruit development but keeping their acid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/1-1050by788-fbc2f4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/1-700by525-fbc2f4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/1-675by506-fbc2f4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/1-450by338-fbc2f4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/1-525by394-fbc2f4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/1-350by263-fbc2f4.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/1-350by263-fbc2f4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Walking to the Winery&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I decided to make my way through Alsace without renting a car.  Which meant that I had to walk over a mile from the train station with all of my luggage to the winery.  And then I had to walk another mile to my hotel.  Still, the views while walking were like this the whole time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/2-1050by788-6a955a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/2-700by525-6a955a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/2-675by506-6a955a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/2-450by338-6a955a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/2-525by394-6a955a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/2-350by263-6a955a.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/2-350by263-6a955a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Welcome to Mittelbergheim&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I was so happy to finally see this sign.  I didn’t realize that Mittelbergheim had so many wineries within the town.  I wish I knew so I could’ve spent more time exploring…  It’s definitely on my list of things to do if/when I return to Alsace!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking through the town of Mittelbergheim, I saw that there were at least 8 other wineries within walking distance to Albert Seltz.  I did not get the chance to check if they were open / spoke English / were available for tastings, so Albert Seltz ended up being my only stop in Mittelbergheim.  Though after discovering there were that many places in the area, I am emboldened to make a return visit and stay in town for an evening or two.  Though, it will be difficult to live up to Albert Seltz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/3-1050by788-ca2bb2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/3-700by525-ca2bb2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/3-675by506-ca2bb2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/3-450by338-ca2bb2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/3-525by394-ca2bb2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/3-350by263-ca2bb2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/3-350by263-ca2bb2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Written in Stone&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;On the one hand, I wish the sign was easier to see/read.  On the other hand, having a stone sign without any paint is a really classy move.  The cracks showing the age is also pretty cool.  I was really excited to get to tasting…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website has a quote from the owner: “The Sylvaner is a pretty girl from a poor family that does not interest the boy full of money is the disease of the 21st century.”  I totally understand where he is coming from - sometimes selling wine is a popularity contest where name recognition is everything for a consumer and can transitively affect the choices of the Producer.  Chardonnay, Sauvignon Blanc, Riesling… people are more likely to purchase something they have at least some tangential familiarity with.  It’s a good thing I went outside my own comfort zone as I’ve had some unimpressive Sylvaner before, but these wines totally changed my opinion about the varietal.  It made such an impression that I bought a few bottles with hopes of sharing with friends and spreading Albert’s message just a little further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heading into the winery, I was sad to find that there was (literally) no one home upon my arrival.  After waiting 30 minutes in the shade with their dog, a woman returning from the field was startled to discover me standing there - I had not called ahead for an appointment.  After collecting herself and learning I was an American on an Alsacian Wine Crusade, she guided me inside for a tasting.  Their tasting room doubled as their office, which had several desks and a small 4-stool tasting bar where we broke out some of the wines in their inventory.  NOTE: This was a family-run winery and didn’t have the infrastructure of a larger establishment.  It soon didn’t matter to me as the wines were very good and all I could think about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/4-1050by788-8db837.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/4-700by525-8db837.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/4-675by506-8db837.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/4-450by338-8db837.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/4-525by394-8db837.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/4-350by263-8db837.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/4-350by263-8db837.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Quenching the Thirst&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I don’t know if there is a better view.  To be alone in a winery with the undivided attention of the wine ambassador, drinking some amazing white wines and discussing the individuality of the winery and its wines.  The QPR on the wines are sooo good…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the tasting, we focused on their speciality: Sylvaner.  I think they are the only winery in the region that grows Grand Cru Sylvaner (I am likely mistaken there since there are so many producers), but it sure tasted like their specialty.  There was no formal menu, so your menu is likely to be different when you visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albert-seltz.fr/fiche.php?id=32&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Sylvaner de Mittelbergheim&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (9.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Has a lemon/lime and mineral profile, but with strong intensity and some white spice as well.  The aromas are a touch riper than the palate, but this makes a great summertime wine.  No green or vegetal notes, this wine finishes very fresh with that spice.  I know the notes read like a Sancerre and is similar except for the acidity (lower) and the minerality (it isn’t flint-like).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Sylvaner Zotzenberg Grand Cru Sono Contento&lt;/strong&gt; (16.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;There is definitely some petrol on the nose and less spice character than the first wine above, but there is definitely more complexity with the undertones and less reliance on the fruit character.  All of the notes are very subtle, even though the wine ambassador served this wine at the same temperature as a red wine.  Still great acidity and a little more body than the previous wine - I would love to retaste this without the aerobic exercise beforehand.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albert-seltz.fr/fiche.php?id=31&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Sylvaner Grand Cru Zotzenberg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (30.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Like the Zotzenberg except much more fruit/floral fragrance on the nose (e.g. in the honey/honeysuckle range).  This was just an all-around fantastic wine.  Really ripe stonefruit character (peach, honeysuckle) on the palate with great acidity that isn’t too soft/strong and provides structure.  The finish also goes on…  As someone who doesn’t like sweet wine but likes fruit (my American palate) and balance, I am really in love with this wine and would buy more immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Riesling Rebbuehl granite d’Andlau&lt;/strong&gt; (16.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Strong varietal character as I definitely get the petrol and rubber on the nose with the light yellow fruit and strong acidity.  This was served a little warmer than I am used to for Rieslings, but I think that also made the wine open more quickly.  This is a classic example of terroir-driven wine from Alsace - really like the minerality as well.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albert-seltz.fr/fiche.php?id=24&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Riesling Grand Cru Zotzenberg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (16.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;More fruit on the nose than the last Riesling - it’s almost a bit juicier and riper on the nose than the Sylvaner Grand Cru as well.  The palate is not as ripe as the nose, but there is still plenty of fruit and the finish is quite distinctive.  I wouldn’t say it’s flint but there is something terroir/mineral-related happening at the end.  That added complexity really stimulates the mind in a good way…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albert-seltz.fr/fiche.php?id=29&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2007 Sylvaner Veilles Vignes Colline aux Poiriers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (25.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Honey, ripe honeysuckle, beeswax, honeycomb, orange marmalade.  Not overly heavy on the finish like I was expecting; there is much more acidity to keep the balance intact.  That balance with the sweetness is really something something to dwell on as I’ve had many others that go over the top with the sweetness.  This wine may still be a little much for friends that don’t appreciate sweet wine, but I would not classify this as strictly a dessert wine.  I could easily pair this in a meal.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albert-seltz.fr/fiche.php?id=14&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Pinot Gris Grand Cru Zotzenberg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (16.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is not quite as ripe with honey/honeysuckle nor aromatically intense as some of the other wines, but it is definitely the smoothest out of all of them.  The finish just goes on…  You don’t really feel the acidity either, but that is perfectly fine since the wine is not cloying at all.  This is the kind of wine you could drink multiple bottles of in one sitting and not tire of its intensity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.albert-seltz.fr/fiche.php?id=10&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Gewurztraminer Mon Ruisseau de Zanzibar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (25.00€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Very different from other Gewurztraminers in Alsace.  Not too much marmalade, nor too heavy.  The nose is a little less intense than the normal varietal character, but in a pleasurable way.  There is even a tickle of lemon zest too!  The body and finish have a flint-like character to them and do not finish over the top - the fruit is bright and finishes wonderfully with pineapple and stonefruit.  This is also an easy drinking without the feel of a sugar spike that can be utilized in many ways.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/5-1050by1400-b55b4e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/5-700by933-b55b4e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/5-675by900-b55b4e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/5-450by600-b55b4e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/5-525by700-b55b4e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/5-350by467-b55b4e.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/5-350by467-b55b4e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Sweet and Satisfying&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;There were a couple of wines that really struck me and both were of the same varietal that I haven’t liked in the past - Sylvaner.  This Grand Cru is the perfect balance of distinctive terroir, varietal and easy drinking.  I need a case of this.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/6-1050by1400-812bae.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/6-700by933-812bae.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/6-675by900-812bae.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/6-450by600-812bae.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/6-525by700-812bae.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/6-350by467-812bae.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/6-350by467-812bae.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;So good...&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The other wine that really struck me.  Old vines, older wine, and sweeter than the above Grand Cru, this wine is for the special occasion at the end of the night.  I really need to find their distributor!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a shame that I could not taste these great wines with the owner.  Other online reviews tell of an intimate experience, including touring their cellars and getting more into the philosophy of winemaking.  I am not the biodynamic purist that the owner is, but I would’ve really been interested in getting his thoughts on the matter, especially since all of these wines were done very well…  Normally I like to let the wines do the talking, but in this case, I would’ve liked the extra background and how we can achieve the same quality with these methods in the states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/7-1050by788-9c85b5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/7-700by525-9c85b5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/7-675by506-9c85b5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/7-450by338-9c85b5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/7-525by394-9c85b5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/7-350by263-9c85b5.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/albert-seltz/7-350by263-9c85b5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Mandatory Selfie&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Obligatory selfie with the vines behind the winery.  It was pretty cool outside, but the sun was also pretty strong.  It’s probably how they have ripe wines with great acidity.  Seems like a great place to live and make wines.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself in Strasbourg and want to make a day trip for wine by train, you could do worse than Albert Seltz and Mittelbergheim in general.  Just be sure to make reservations by email before showing up so that you get the full experience with the winery owner and check whether they speak English for the tour or not.  I definitely recommend that you make your way into Alsace wine country and enjoy some really good white varietals, but especially Sylvaner since you can’t find it in the states!  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="alsace" /><category term="mittelbergheim" /><summary type="html">The first stop on my Alsace + Rhone wine vacation. Straight off the train from Strasbourg, I walked half a mile with all of my luggage to get here. The backwoods path was beautiful but carrying three bags will put a damper on enjoying that. Even though I was traveling in the fall and the temperature was relatively cool, the intensity of the sun was fairly strong as the vineyards of Alsace are generally planted on southern facing slopes next to the Vosges Mountain range to absorb as much of the light as possible, leading to ripe fruit development but keeping their acid.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/albert-seltz/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Paradigm Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/09/paradigm_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Paradigm Private Tasting" /><published>2019-02-09T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-09T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/09/paradigm_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/09/paradigm_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;I know many of you have never heard of Paradigm before, nor seen any of their bottles or signage in Napa.  But what if I said that Paradigm was the first winery that Heidi Barrett ever worked at and even after her long and illustrious career, she is still their winemaker?  If you follow winemakers like me, I hope that grabbed your attention.  If you need more background, read my article on La Sirena (Heidi’s personal label).  To sum up Paradigm, it is a small Oakville-based operation that owns 55 acres of vines and makes very compelling wines by allowing the varietals to express their quality and terroir influences with minimal winemaker intervention, which is only possible when you have great land, vines, and someone who is confident in what they are doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paradigm got started around the time Heidi was in school.  Her father Richard Peterson was (and still is) a famous winemaker specializing in Pinot Noir who worked with several wineries and did consultation work for others.  At the time, Ren (the owner) and Gene (his business partner) ran a lucrative vineyard real estate business together.  After enough time, they both decided to start their own wineries.  Ren called up Richard Peterson and asked for help getting the winery going.  Everything from building the business plan, to pitching financial institutions for the loans he needed, to designing the vineyard and equipping the facility, to being his winemaking consultant.  When you visit Paradigm, you’ll see that the building and winemaking facility are small and non-descript in comparison to others in the area.  They may be small but are very efficiently structured (everything is tight and compact) and isn’t lacking in any equipment.  As the other wineries grew and expanded around them, Paradigm has stayed relatively the same, which includes its small quantity, great quality, and very affordable prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/1-1050by788-4845aa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/1-700by525-4845aa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/1-675by506-4845aa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/1-450by338-4845aa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/1-525by394-4845aa.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/1-350by263-4845aa.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/1-350by263-4845aa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The entrance to the winery&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I told you that the winery was non-descript on the outside.  Yes, this is the entrance as seen from the parking lot.  But don’t let this exterior fool you.  The wine quality will pleasantly surprise you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After helping out with the design and getting the winery close to the finish line, it was Richard’s turn to ask a favor.  At about this time, Heidi was just graduating school and needed a job in the winemaking world.  Getting your first gig is always the hardest, but Richard vouched for her skills and asked that she be given a shot as a favor to him.  After the first couple vintages, Ren realized that he actually owed Richard another favor because the wines Heidi was making were more than he could have hoped for.  Soon after, Ren got a call from his old partner Gene, asking if he knew of anyone that could help her with a stuck fermentation (it’s when the yeast doesn’t convert all the grape sugar into alcohol, leaving you with a 11% sweet red wine that you can’t sell).  Naturally, he talked about his rockstar winemaker and so Heidi went and got her first consulting gig fixing the fermentation.  Afterwards, Gene was so impressed that she hired Heidi to be their first full-time winemaker too.  Did I mention that Gene’s winery was called Screaming Eagle (now the most expensive wine made in America)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ren paid off the final loans of the winery 10+ years ago and how the tax laws work in Napa is that you are taxed each year based on how much you paid for the land/winery at the time of purchase.  Since Ren purchased the land back when there were only 30 wineries in Napa and land prices were dirt cheap compared to today, their taxes are very low by comparison to others, meaning they can pass the savings along to the consumer.  And that’s a pro-tip for visiting Napa - the next time you go, try to visit a winery that has been around for a long time and hasn’t changed hands.  They will nearly always be cheaper than everyone else; not because they wines aren’t as good, but because the cost to produce them is lower (and therefore they need to charge less to keep operations going).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/2-1050by788-a61dd0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/2-700by525-a61dd0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/2-675by506-a61dd0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/2-450by338-a61dd0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/2-525by394-a61dd0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/2-350by263-a61dd0.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/paradigm/2-350by263-a61dd0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Getting lost in the vines&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;We had a chance to walk through the vineyard and see what is responsible for the great wine.  Since it was the brother-in-law on duty that day, we got to hear some great stories about the early history of the winery that I shared earlier in the article.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Heidi left the industry for a spell for family (raising her young daughters), it was Paradigm that was the first to offer her a job again to get back into the swing of things.  There is loyalty and a sense of family here which matches the size of the winery and the staffing (only the brother of the owner was working the Sunday afternoon I visited).  The tastings are one group at a time and you can’t hear anything except for the Napa Wine train that pass by every so often.  They have some equipment from UC Davis interleaved in the winery too (e.g. measuring aspiration to figure out how often to put out sulfur for protection in the vineyards).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After walking through the vineyards, we settled out on a picnic table outside and dug into the wines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Rose of Merlot&lt;/strong&gt; ($29)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Produced via the vin gris method – you press off the rosé once it has the right amount of color that they want, so it has more tannin, fruit and body.  This is different from the free run method of pulling off the wine from the bottom of the tank after crush.  Cold fermentation that lasts for 6 weeks until it reaches bone dry.  Beautiful salmon pink color with a medium+ intensity nose of strawberry and cranberry with a tickle of alcohol.  The palate is high intensity with medium+ acid and medium alcohol, but very little tannic influence.  There are no underripe notes at all.  A very smooth rosé with a little more body and the right amount of acid that can make a red wine lover happy.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.paradigmwinery.com/product/2014-Merlot&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Oakville Merlot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($53)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Rich red fruit on the nose with some spices and very little alcohol.  The same red fruit on the palate that still has medium+ acidity, the smallest green character, lots of plum, medium tannin that could soften a bit more with time, and alcohol/spice you can feel a bit.  It is a strange sensation drinking this wine - the more I sample, the more I want to drink it.  The acidity has a most peculiar mouth-watering effect (it almost feels like a craving) that is very pleasant.  Still, silky mouthfeel with some oak notes and a finish that goes on for quite a while.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.paradigmwinery.com/product/2014-Paravines&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Paravines&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($73)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;80% Merlot, 20% Petit Verdot.  Right off the bat, you can feel the deep juicy/jammy red fruit on the nose.  I don’t get any caramel on the nose like the tasting notes indicate, but that intertwined spruce/cedar is definitely present.  There is more tannin than the Merlot thanks to the Petit Verdot, but a similar level of acidity, though not quite the same sensation as the Merlot.  Really enjoyable red wine that has solid intensity of flavors and body all the way through the palate.  Some spices and tertiary characteristics make this a thinking wine instead of just bright fruit with acid and tannins.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.paradigmwinery.com/product/2014-Cabernet-Sauvignon&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($84)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Contrasting the Paravines, the Cabernet Sauvignon is much brighter on the nose, with predominantly red and black fruit.  There is some alcohol/spice sensation, but it complements the fruit well to create a warming effect.  The palate is medium bodied with medium tannin that feels very smooth but does dry the mouth slightly.  The acidity isn’t as present as the Merlot or Paravines, which makes this an easy drinking, really enjoyable Cabernet.  The intensity nor flavors aren’t anything unusual that will strike you as unique – it’s just very cohesive, well-balanced, and has no negatives to complain about.  At $84, this is a steal compared to a lot of other wines grown on the valley floor.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.paradigmwinery.com/product/2015-Cabernet-Franc&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Cabernet Franc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($71)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Only available to wine club members.  The color on this wine is incredibly deep and the nose is so fragrant with cool red cherry and raspberry that has slight candied notes.  The body is juicy with a medium body, medium tannin and medium acid with good length at the end.  If you like more fruit driven wines, this will blow you away, especially if you like the varietal character of Cabernet Franc.  Cabernet Francs are getting more popular in Napa, but this is definitely on the upper-end of quality for the Napa Valley region.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.paradigmwinery.com/product/2011-Cabernet-Sauvignon&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2011 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($113)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Paradigm did not pick early when the rains came during harvest time in 2011.  Instead they blow-dried the vines and let the last bit of sun get captured by the vines.  This resulted in a deeper richness in the 2011 that isn’t there on the 2014.  That additional hangtime also resulted in more black fruit than red fruit.  The wine definitely warms you up more than the 2014 too, though the higher alcohol is very subtle.  2011 wines gets a bad rap in the valley but those who didn’t panic and picked to early were rewarded for their patience and additional effort.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, the quality-price ratio (QPR) on these wines is very good and I highly recommend you visit.  After all, it’s in Oakville, which is one of the most expensive AVAs, and you can see Harlan just up the hill from your picnic table tasting (Harlan’s Cabernet goes for ~$800).  You can taste the quality of the terroir in these wines.  They have other wines that are not on the tasting menu as well - the Cabernet Franc isn’t normally available for tasting and I hear the Zinfandel is among the best in the entire valley!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tasting fee is among the cheapest in the valley too, so if you’ve read my other reviews and wish you had the capital to try them out, you can start by going here.  Though, once you taste the wines here, it may be very hard to go back to drinking other wines, haha.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="oakville" /><summary type="html">I know many of you have never heard of Paradigm before, nor seen any of their bottles or signage in Napa. But what if I said that Paradigm was the first winery that Heidi Barrett ever worked at and even after her long and illustrious career, she is still their winemaker? If you follow winemakers like me, I hope that grabbed your attention. If you need more background, read my article on La Sirena (Heidi’s personal label). To sum up Paradigm, it is a small Oakville-based operation that owns 55 acres of vines and makes very compelling wines by allowing the varietals to express their quality and terroir influences with minimal winemaker intervention, which is only possible when you have great land, vines, and someone who is confident in what they are doing.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/paradigm/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Inglenook Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/02/inglenook_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Inglenook Public Tasting" /><published>2019-02-02T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-02T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/02/inglenook_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/02/02/inglenook_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve had (the very affordable) Francis Coppola wines before and was skeptical of Inglenook even before reading the reviews by the major wine publications.  But I think you can officially change my status from skeptic to believer, because everything about this winery is impressive.  For example, when you make your way to the winery, Google Maps bring you to a small building that turns out to be the check-in desk where they confirm your reservation, give you a ticket to scan at the estate gate, and send you on your way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/1-1050by788-b4d3c5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/1-700by525-b4d3c5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/1-675by506-b4d3c5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/1-450by338-b4d3c5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/1-525by394-b4d3c5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/1-350by263-b4d3c5.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/1-350by263-b4d3c5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Where are you taking me?&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;For a while there, it seemed like the road would go on forever.  That’s definitely one way to heighten the expectations of visitors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The driveway is quite long and leads you to a large parking lot that is next to the largest campus I have seen in the Napa Valley so far.  What’s more, it contrasts wineries like Hall in that everything about the campus looks and feels historic.  The backstory of this land seems surreal when you hear about it, but once you explore and read the signs that are everywhere, you really start to understand that this land is special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/2-1050by788-8d83dd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/2-700by525-8d83dd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/2-675by506-8d83dd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/2-450by338-8d83dd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/2-525by394-8d83dd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/2-350by263-8d83dd.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/2-350by263-8d83dd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;So bright outside...&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;After parking in the large lot they have, you’ll walk past a large veranda on the way to the main winery building.  I know why that veranda exists now - it gets really bright outside and makes selfies tough.  And yes, those are grapevines over my shoulder.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/3-1050by788-0f73d2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/3-700by525-0f73d2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/3-675by506-0f73d2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/3-450by338-0f73d2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/3-525by394-0f73d2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/3-350by263-0f73d2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/3-350by263-0f73d2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Too much shade...&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I feel like Goldilocks; this angle has too much shade.  That shade is caused by the massive winery building, while behind me is the large open area that is perfect for mini-picnincs and enjoying bottles outside.  The resolution on my camera phone may be bad, but the view is really nice.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inglenook, or more accurately the winery that existed before it was purchased and named Inglenook, was founded by a Finnish animal fur trader in the 1850s, who had been responsibe for a vast amount of charting along the west coast.  He was a wine conneiseur, his wife a San Francisco socialite.  It’s no surprise that they compromised and moved from fur trading to operating a winery in Napa.  And it certainly wasn’t about the money - he wanted to show the world that he could make wines that could rival the world’s best in France.  This, a 100+ years before the Judgement of Paris.  Just hearing about the passion and history is enough to get you excited about the wines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Francis Coppola purchased the land, Robert Mondavi immediately called him to setup a dinner.  At this dinner, Mondavi proceeded to explain the history and potential to Francis, practically charging Coppola that he had the moral responsibility to restore Inglenook to its former glory.  After digging some 50+ year old wines out of the Inglenook cellar and tasting them with Mondavi, Coppola was convinced and so the dream was born.  And if that isn’t enough to get you excited, the current consulting winemaker (Philippe Bascaules) happens to be the President of Chateau Margaux, who now flies back to California every few months to make sure that Inglenook is producing amazing wines, as nature intended.  Coppola is also Italian – that’s why there is a Zindandel (known in Italy as Primitivo) here.  If you want French styled wine that just has great balance and takes avantage of Napa’s strengths, you need to try these wines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inglenook.com/Purchase/Details/BL16&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Blancaneaux&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($65)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A northern Rhone blend of Viognier, Marsanne, and Roussanne.  The fruit comes from Pritchet Hill (knob / giant hill), which is not to be confused with Pritchard Hill.  Pritchet Hill is the shadiest place in the Napa Valley (I know how that sounds), which is important for these varietals to shine.  There is almost no color at all to the wine and the nose is very light, reminiscent of French wine.  The palate has screaming high minerality, which makes the perception of the acidity maybe higher than it actually is.  There’s also decent fruit and a nice clean finish of yellow fruit (apple) and some stonefruit.  A really nice alternative to the Chardonnay/Sauvignon Blanc typically grown in the Napa Valley.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inglenook.com/Purchase/Details/RC15&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 RC Reserve Syrah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($62)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The RC stands for Roman Coppola, who is the eldest son and created this wine to be a cigar wine.  But obviously Syrah goes well with BBQ and other meats.  Deep red fruit and black pepper on the nose without any alcoholic heat.  The tannin makes the finish seem a little short initially, but on exhale, you still feel the wine.  Good medium+ body with some juicy flavor character.  The wood notes (e.g. cedar) are strong and integrated into the fruit as well.  This wine is very true to what Syrah is (without the wild game notes of the Northern Rhone) and doesn’t try to be overripe/candied to appease American palates.  50/50 aged in French and American oak.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inglenook.com/Purchase/Details/EP09&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2008 Magnum Edizione Pennino&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55 for a 750ml)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;100% Zinfandel and what a wine this is.  There is some much going on here - Fruitcake, forest floor and cedar are what I could pick out on the nose.  The palate is also wonderful with high intensity all the way through the palate and a good medium+ body every step of the way.  Very well balanced with really good integration of each component.  My advanced sommelier running the tasting said that their 2010 Zinfandel was the best Zinfandel ever made on the planet.  Judging by how good their 2008 is, I do not doubt it.  This may be one of the best Zins I have ever had (at least at the same level as Ridge/Turley).  The alcohol does not rear its head and the wine isn’t too candied.  A really amazing effort.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inglenook.com/Purchase/Details/CK15&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($78)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Rutherford (88% Cabernet), 100% French Oak.  The nose has a lot of rich medium bright red fruit with some dust, not unlike a lot of other Rutherford Cabs.  Ends cleanly with a shorter finish than others, but has that mouthwatering tingling acidity that begs you to drink more.  Definitely less fruit on the midpalate than others; it emphasizes a balance of the terroir character rather than dominating fruit, but it’s still really smooth and enjoyable.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inglenook.com/Purchase/Details/EP15&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Edizione Pennino&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($48)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Remove most of the teritary character from the 2008 Pennino described earlier and you get this wine.  Understandably, the fruit and acid are also sharper as the wine has not yet rounded into form, but you can already taste the potential.  I don’t really have much to say after the 2008 other than I’ll try checking in on this wine again in 10 years.  I still can’t believe I am talking about intentionally aging a Zinfandel…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inglenook.com/Purchase/Details/RB14&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Rubicon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($210)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wow, this really does remind me of a First Growth Bordeaux in so many ways.  The lower alcohol, the significant amount of tertiary notes on the mid-to-late palate and the nose that just hints at it.  This wine will probably peak in 20-30 years according to the Advanced Somm, though it can be aged well into its 40s.  It’s hard for me to see that though as it’s just so smooth right now and very approachable while showing off all the characteristics that you might expect from an aged wine.  Insider Tip for the wine collectors out there - the best vintages to look for (in order of greatness) 78, 79, 91, 95, 96, 01, 03, 04.  The Rubicon has a higher price point than many other wineries’ flagship wine, but I think it deserves it due to its complexity.  Though, the wine becomes more affordable with a Winery Membership (20% off!)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/4-1050by1400-dfa73f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/4-700by933-dfa73f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/4-675by900-dfa73f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/4-450by600-dfa73f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/4-525by700-dfa73f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/4-350by467-dfa73f.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/4-350by467-dfa73f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;There was none left for me...&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I feel like I needed to include a picture of this bottle in the post.  If you are wondering why, I’d recommend doing some research on the older Niebaum-Coppola wines that were released.  Then, you will understand…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After tasting the wines and regaining my bearings, I also started to notice details of the amazing building I was sitting in.  The building’s exterior sets your expectations high and the inside does not disappoint.  Before or after the tasting, you can navigate the cellars of the building and take a look at more history.  The tasting room itself feels 200+ years old and is staffed by professional Sommeliers who are dressed as if they were working in a three-star Michelin restaurant.  Their demeanor aside, you can tell that each one doesn’t just consider Inglenook a job - they sincerely believe that each wine is world-class and represents the best its varietal has to offer (e.g. Zinfandel, Cabernet, and the Northern Rhone white blend).  After all, one of the benefits of working at the winery is tasting the wines!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/5-1050by788-e29298.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/5-700by525-e29298.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/5-675by506-e29298.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/5-450by338-e29298.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/5-525by394-e29298.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/5-350by263-e29298.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/5-350by263-e29298.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;So many barrels&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view down the hallway inside their winery building.  As you can see from the walls in the picture, this building has been around for a very long time.  It’s impressive how aligned the doorways were as technology was very different back in the day.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/6-1050by788-fc549f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/6-700by525-fc549f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/6-675by506-fc549f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/6-450by338-fc549f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/6-525by394-fc549f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/6-350by263-fc549f.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/inglenook/6-350by263-fc549f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;For the bigshots&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;If you are a real big shot, maybe you get to hold your tasting in one of these private rooms off the main hallway.  What interests me even more is do you get to try the bottles that are aging in there?  I wasn’t able to go inside to see, but I can guess they are not recent vintages.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a fantastic location to bring friends and possibly enjoy a picnic outside on the lawn with a bottle or two of their wines.  Though, I think it was nearly as fulfilling to go alone and really take the time to enjoy each one of these unique wines.  Each had a different expression than most Napa wines I’ve had of the same varietal and the value is solid, especially if you become a member and save 20% on each of the wines that you purchase!  The wines also all had an old world vibe to them, without any flaws from being underripe.  If a friend visitng Napa were to ask me for European-styled wines that weren’t all Cabernets, this is where I would send them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will absolutely be visiting again and hopefully will find a way to pick up and lay down a bottle of Rubicon for a future First Growth blind tasting or for a celebration.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="rutherford" /><summary type="html">I’ve had (the very affordable) Francis Coppola wines before and was skeptical of Inglenook even before reading the reviews by the major wine publications. But I think you can officially change my status from skeptic to believer, because everything about this winery is impressive. For example, when you make your way to the winery, Google Maps bring you to a small building that turns out to be the check-in desk where they confirm your reservation, give you a ticket to scan at the estate gate, and send you on your way.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/inglenook/4.jpg" /></entry></feed>