<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-01-03T20:09:37+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Wines By Jeremy</title><subtitle>Wines by Jeremy offers an educative and enjoyable personalized wine experience. Located in the DC metro area, Wines by Jeremy provides a number of services including in-home exclusive tastings, highly curated event tastings, educational events, and wine cellar consulting.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Kapcsandy Private Tour and Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/07/kapcsandy_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kapcsandy Private Tour and Tasting" /><published>2019-12-07T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-07T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/07/kapcsandy_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/07/kapcsandy_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;You can read up on Kapcsandy’s history and prior vintage tastings in this article &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/07/21/kapcsandy_private_tasting.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HERE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  Although there is no membership club you can sign up for with Kapcsandy, they do have a benefit programs you can qualify for based on your purchases.  Since my tasting group loves and purchases as much Kapcsandy as I do, we try to make a trip once a year to taste the new vintage.  And I can’t say enough about Kapcsandy - it is my favorite winery experience in Napa, if you can afford it and meet the requirements for the tasting (see the previous article for details).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/1-1050by788-246534.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/1-700by525-246534.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/1-675by506-246534.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/1-450by338-246534.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/1-525by394-246534.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/1-350by263-246534.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/1-350by263-246534.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Louis in his happy place&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Last time, we got a tour from the wine ambassador of Kapcsandy.  This trip, Louis Jr. himself gave us the repeat full tour (we had a couple new people on the trip with us).  This tasting almost didn’t happen - we booked our trip to Napa during the same week Louis Jr. and his father were supposed to go on a family vacation.  Luckily for us they happened to cancel/move the trip and Louis was happy to host us again.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/2-1050by788-050817.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/2-700by525-050817.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/2-675by506-050817.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/2-450by338-050817.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/2-525by394-050817.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/2-350by263-050817.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/2-350by263-050817.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;If only I could have a barrel&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The beautiful barrel room with the 2017 vintage in barrel now.  The barrels still look clean/crisp because they use new French Oak each year when producing their wines.  If only I could have a barrel…  What a happy man I would be.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the Grand Vins, we tasted the 2013 and 2014 vintages last year, so tasting the amazing 2015 and 2016 vintages were in order.  And my word, did we all enjoy the wines…  But we knew that coming in.  When the only female Chief Editor of a major wine magazine calls a wine “sex in a glass”, you know you need to try that wine.  I think I walked away with 6 bottles of the 2016 Grand Vin - it may be the greatest young wine I have ever tasted in my life.  And I have tried many 100pt wines before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/3-1050by1400-092e24.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/3-700by933-092e24.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/3-675by900-092e24.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/3-450by600-092e24.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/3-525by700-092e24.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/3-350by467-092e24.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/3-350by467-092e24.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Bottles and Bottles&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Some of the bottles that we tasted this year.  It doesn’t include a picture of my favorite (the 2016 Grand Vin), but the ones in the picture were still really good bottles.  We happened to see Tony Arcudi on the property during the tasting too and were sure to say hello before diving in!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2016 also marked the first vintage for Tony Arcudi as the consulting winemaker for Kapcsandy.  Coincidence?  You can read up on my tasting of Tony Arcudi’s personal label and his background here &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/27/tony_arcudi_private_tasting.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HERE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  Suffice it to say that he is one of the newer winemakers in the Napa Valley that I am tracking closely and is someone that comes from the Heidi Barrett Winemaking tree (at Fantesca).  Also, I want to be him when I grow up.  So it wouldn’t be wrong to say that I had two reasons I needed to visit Kapcsandy this past year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/4-1050by1400-628431.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/4-700by933-628431.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/4-675by900-628431.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/4-450by600-628431.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/4-525by700-628431.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/4-350by467-628431.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kapcsandy/4-350by467-628431.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Telling Stories&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;There’s my favorite bottle, just waiting to be poured into my empty glass after Louis Jr. finishes telling his story.  2016 was probably the best vintage in Napa this millenium after 2013.  But I think I prefer the 2016 over the 2013 Grand Vin.  I almost felt like I could drink any more wine after the tasting this morning.  But after the bland lunch, I was ready to get back into it…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I noted in my earlier article, the wines of Kapcsandy are not in the normal affordable price segment - their Estate Cuvee starts at ~$125 while their Grand Cru runs to $325/350.  But, if you need a special occasion wine or have done well enough in life that you can afford several bottles, you will be glad you did and all of your wine friends will be jealous of you as soon as they taste a glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also noticed that my pictures were a bit lacking in my previous post, so I made sure to take and include some new ones.  But without further ado, the 2015/2016 vintages!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kapcsandywines.com/wines/2018-Furmint&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2018 Furmint&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($40)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Medium(+) intensity of lemon, lime, white peach, apricot, medium(+) soft acidity, with great concentration, depth, and medium body.  Very fresh, but soft and serious.  Fruit driven, but not overly fruity.  Very balanced wine that drinks very easy but is very serious.  Also a unique varietal like Furmint in Napa?  Very cool.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kapcsandywines.com/wines/2016-Estate-Cuv-e-Cabernet-Sauvignon&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Estate Cuvee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($130)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Deep crushed purple flowers, crushed rocks, all of the red, blue, and black fruit, but very fresh and balanced with the ripeness.  The nose is both serious and fun.  The tannins are so fine and balances with the acid and alcohol.  A little less ripe than the Grand Vin, but drinks very nice immediately out of the bottle.  Very complex.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kapcsandywines.com/wines/2016-Rapszodia&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Rapszodia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($285)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pronounced, perfumed, ripe cranberry, cherry, plum, peach and other stonefruit.  The palate is a bit more restrained with the red/black fruit, but there is a minerality that stands out and is supported by a deep tertiary layer that is just starting to peek out.  Long finish that feels good with the acidity and has a bit of fleshiness.  This is a serious wine that is a very good varietal representation that isn’t too cloying.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kapcsandywines.com/wines/2015-Roberta-s-Reserve&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Roberta’s Reserve&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($300)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pronounced nose of crushed, candied cherry, cranberry, rose petals, violets, other floral notes, and deep fresh red plum that sets a strong and concentrated undertone.  Good structure with medium(+) powdery tannin and acid that still needs time to integrated into the medium body.  Very fresh, young and needs time to smooth and round out.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kapcsandywines.com/wines/2015-Cabernet-Sauvignon-Grand-Vin&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Grand Vin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($325)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The intensity on the nose is ridiculous…  All the floral aromas with red, blue, and black fruit with sweet spices and just a touch of vanilla from the wood.  The palate is all of those things with very good integration, weight, concentration, and length.  The wine feels weighty and concentrated all the way through the palate with a long finish.  The tannin is high, powdery, but it isn’t out of sync like the Roberta’s Reserve currently is.  A little more red fruit than there normally is in the Grand Vins, but a sensational wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kapcsandywines.com/wines/2016-Cabernet-Sauvignon-Grand-Vin&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Grand Vin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($325)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The fruit orients toward the blue and black end of the spectrum on the nose (whereas the 2015 leaned towards red fruit).  Crushed, candied blackberries, blueberries, rocks, and other bright black fruit.  Elegant, concentrated, weighty, balanced black/blue fruit that is intense but not overly opulent on the palate.  The tannin is even finer and more integrated in this wine.  If I thought the 2015 was a perfect 100 point wine, this wine must be 105 points.  I can’t say enough about this wine, so I am not going to even try.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2004 Grand Vin&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose on this wine is unbelievable.  I am literally speechless after smelling this wine.  All I can do is stare blankly with my mouth open at people.  15 years old and there is so much pronounced primary/secondary/tertiary aromas and flavors on the palate.  Dark Jolly Ranchers, mocha, vanilla, and a haunting floral perfume on the nose.  Also, this wine was made from 3 YEAR OLD VINES by Helen Turley at the very beginning of Kapcsandy.  The tannins are still rough and grittier on the finish and still feel high/present on the palate because of the types of barrels used back in the day.  But if this is any indication on how the 2015/2016 will age, oh my goodness!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kapcsandywines.com/wines/2013-Vino-del-Sol&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Vino Del Sol+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Aged 42 months in Cognac barrels and made from the vines at the edge of the vineyard from the amazing 2013 vintage.  The concentration, flavors, length, balance, body, viscosity, etc. is even greater than the Vino Del Sol that we had last time.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing this article, I’m realizing I wrote it more for me (so I could relive the experience) than for readers.  Sorry, not sorry.  You need to try the wines of Kapcsandy too.  That way, when you read this article, you can reminisce with me!  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="yountville" /><summary type="html">You can read up on Kapcsandy’s history and prior vintage tastings in this article HERE. Although there is no membership club you can sign up for with Kapcsandy, they do have a benefit programs you can qualify for based on your purchases. Since my tasting group loves and purchases as much Kapcsandy as I do, we try to make a trip once a year to taste the new vintage. And I can’t say enough about Kapcsandy - it is my favorite winery experience in Napa, if you can afford it and meet the requirements for the tasting (see the previous article for details).</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/kapcsandy-2/4.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Kieu Hoang Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/30/kieu_hoang_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kieu Hoang Public Tasting" /><published>2019-11-30T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-30T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/30/kieu_hoang_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/30/kieu_hoang_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Kieu Hoang was a nice stop to unwind after a long day of tasting.  The views from the balcony are great, the wine and tasting fees are affordable, and the wines themselves are pleasant and easy to drink.  Though, if you asked me whether I would visit the winery again, the answer is likely “no”.  It wasn’t the most memorable experience, the wine ambassador wasn’t the most engaging, and the wines did not ship well (a large percentage of the bottles we shipped back to DC were faulty - not just one or two).  People have asked me why I wouldn’t give a winery a second chance.  My response is that there are ~425 wineries in Sonoma.  I will not likely be able to taste at all of them in my lifetime, so why bother trying the same one twice, especially if I didn’t like it the first time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/1-1050by1400-b8f6f2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/1-700by933-b8f6f2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/1-675by900-b8f6f2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/1-450by600-b8f6f2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/1-525by700-b8f6f2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/1-350by467-b8f6f2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/1-350by467-b8f6f2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Entrance&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The entrance to the winery looked innocuous.  The wine chandelier was a little awkward to walk around, but I liked the idea.  I would probably change the execution a little bit if I try something similar in the future.  Walk-in tastings are welcome and because they open until 5pm, it’s a nice way to finish a day of tasting as many places close at 4pm.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/2-1050by788-f3cc60.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/2-700by525-f3cc60.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/2-675by506-f3cc60.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/2-450by338-f3cc60.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/2-525by394-f3cc60.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/2-350by263-f3cc60.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/2-350by263-f3cc60.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Tasting Room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The tasting room looks very different than the entrance.  If you make a reservation to have your tasting in this room (instead of reserving a table), then you can get your tasting fee reimbursed with purchases (if you reserve a table, you won’t be able to get your tasting fee back).  Luckily, we came at a date/time where the winery wasn’t busy, so they sat us at an outdoor table, but still reimbursed our fees with purchases.  This looks like a pretty good room to have your tasting in though if you had to.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kieu Hoang is named after the owner; a Vietnamese-born American billionaire who owned a large percentage of Shanghai RAAS Blood Products for a time.  Kieu Hoang first became interested in wine because of him background and passion regarding people’s well-being.  He, like so many others, discovered that wine was healthy in moderation: both physically and for the soul.  The winery was purchased from Michael Mondavi in 2014 and re-oriented toward the Chinese market.  Most of the wine produced is exported to China and sold through affiliated pharmacies.  Because of the market orientation of the winery and wines, I’m not sure if it’s geared toward the preferences of the American wine drinker and maybe everything is as the owner intended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/3-1050by788-5ec3ba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/3-700by525-5ec3ba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/3-675by506-5ec3ba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/3-450by338-5ec3ba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/3-525by394-5ec3ba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/3-350by263-5ec3ba.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/3-350by263-5ec3ba.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The View from the Couches&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view from the tables on the deck of the tasting facility.  I really like how they use plants at the ends of vine rows to help pest control.  And the contrast of the green of the vineyard versus the unplanted hillsides is really something.  I’m usually an aggressive taster and will move on to the next winery as fast as possible, but it was hard not to enjoy relaxing here…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/4-1050by788-efd5c9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/4-700by525-efd5c9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/4-675by506-efd5c9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/4-450by338-efd5c9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/4-525by394-efd5c9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/4-350by263-efd5c9.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/4-350by263-efd5c9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Our Group&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Our tasting group enjoying the wine and views from the couches.  Again, if you reserve one for your tasting, you won’t get your tasting fee back.   But if you go during the evening of a weekday like we did, you’ll likely not need the reservation to enjoy it.  Again, the views were quite something.  Just make sure that you bring sunglasses with you to California.  It seems like it’s always bright outside…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the winery isn’t very impressive on the outside, the inside is very different (and attractive).  The tasting room is tastefully designed and the patio area is my happy place.  The wines themselves were all smooth and drinking well, but nothing stuck out to me as individualistic or something that separates this winery from others.  The Emperor label was great, but not at the $175 price point (compared to other wines in the same category).  Also, you can get the bottle for ~$50 cheaper if you purchase it at “The Wine Room” in Palo Alto, though don’t ask me how or why the price is that different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/5-1050by788-39f457.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/5-700by525-39f457.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/5-675by506-39f457.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/5-450by338-39f457.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/5-525by394-39f457.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/5-350by263-39f457.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/kieu-hoang/5-350by263-39f457.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Poor Attempt&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;My poor attempt at a picture of my branded wine glass and the view in the background.  I think we spent at least an extra 30 minutes unwinding and enjoying the view outside.  Sonoma and Napa are really something…  Being the only group outside was nice too.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are my notes on the wines I tasted.  NOTE: One fun thing Kieu Hoang does is that they let you construct your own tasting.  They will give you the list of all the wines they offer and you are able to select 4 bottles to taste.  Tasting the Emporer label will set you back an additional $20 and is served separately via Coravin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kieuhoangwinery.com/product/Kieu-Hoang--Pinot-Noir-2016&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Pinot Noir (Los Carneros)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($45)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Ripe red fruit (cherry, strawberry) that has aged a bit with some sweet spice, depth and medium intensity.  On the palate, this wine shows that it’s robust and hearty with tertiary earthiness and medium body.  The wine shows concentration with its flavors of raspberry, cranberry, lighter cherry and some earth undertones starting to develop.  Balancing acidity and pretty smooth.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kieuhoangwinery.com/product/KIEU-HOANG--GREEN-LABEL&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2010 Green Label&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($50)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sangiovese and Cabernet Sauvignon blend from Stag’s Leap/Rutherford.  Bright red fruit (pomegranate, strawberry) on the nose.  On the palate, similar tasting notes with vanilla and some baking spice.  Medium(+) grippy tannins and medium(+) acid.  Thanks to the acid, tannins, and mellow red fruit flavors, the wine feels rustic like Italian wines, but with a slightly different tasting profile.  Reminiscent of a Super Tuscan.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kieuhoangwinery.com/product/Kieu-Hoang--Red-Label1&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Red Label&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($60)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;100% Cabernet Sauvignon from Calistoga/Yountville.  There is concentration and elegance in this wine at the same time.  Deep, warm red cherry and red currant emerge from the glass with medium(+) intensity.  On the palate, the same flavors are blended with vanilla and baking spice.  The palate feels just a little hollow on the midpalate and the medium(-) body clashes with the alcohol a little, but overall this is a very enjoyable Napa Cabernet that isn’t too serious.  At the price point, it’s a nice wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kieuhoangwinery.com/product/KIEU-HOANG--GOLD-LABEL&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Gold Label&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;85% Cabernet Sauvignon with Merlot and Syrah sourced Howell Mountain and St. Helena.  The color and the nose are noticeably deeper and darker than the Red Label.  Black/red currant and black/red candied cherry dominate the nose.  The medium body clashes with the high acid and tannin - it probably needs some time to integrate but the structure will definitely support that.  The midpalate is again a bit lacking, but this is still a nice wine that will please those looking to explore mountain AVA styled wines.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kieuhoangwinery.com/product/Emperor-2011&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2011 Emperor Label&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($175)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Spring Mountain Estate of Cabernet Sauvignon.  I’ve had it at wine bars for $130, so considering they must have marked it up, you can probably find it for ~$100 somewhere else through a distributor.  The nose on this is deep with red and black fruit at a coy, medium(+) intensity.  On the body, there are a lot of things happening.  The fruit components are the same as the Gold Label, but they seem rearranged and integrated in a much more pleasing manner with cocoa and salinity.  The acidity is not biting and the midpalate is filled out by this medium(+) body wine.  There’s even some toast, caramel, and brown sugar on the finish.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you decide to visit, I hope that your shipping experience is better with ours.  Instead of waiting until the fall/winter for the heat to die down, they tried shipping 2-day in the latter part of the summer, likely contributing to the wine faults.  If you decide to just visit, enjoy a tasting and the views, then likely you won’t be disappointed.  Cheers and happy hunting for good wine!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="carneros" /><summary type="html">Kieu Hoang was a nice stop to unwind after a long day of tasting. The views from the balcony are great, the wine and tasting fees are affordable, and the wines themselves are pleasant and easy to drink. Though, if you asked me whether I would visit the winery again, the answer is likely “no”. It wasn’t the most memorable experience, the wine ambassador wasn’t the most engaging, and the wines did not ship well (a large percentage of the bottles we shipped back to DC were faulty - not just one or two). People have asked me why I wouldn’t give a winery a second chance. My response is that there are ~425 wineries in Sonoma. I will not likely be able to taste at all of them in my lifetime, so why bother trying the same one twice, especially if I didn’t like it the first time?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/kieu-hoang/4.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Donum Estate Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/23/donum_estate_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Donum Estate Private Tasting" /><published>2019-11-23T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-23T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/23/donum_estate_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/23/donum_estate_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;When you visit wineries for tastings, you may notice that a majority have a theme to them, likely due to past influences, and the owners will try to enhance that theme by incorporating art and/or architectural design (e.g. Round Pond and Tuscany, Cliff Lede and Rock-and-Roll, etc.).  I have never before visited a winery like Donum Estate where the Art experience matches or even exceeds the tasting experience.  And while the Chardonnays and Pinot Noirs (especially the Pinot) are well-regarded and rated, I think a good portion of the tasting fee ($95) goes towards your museum ticket to tour the sculptor garden.  And even though the tasting fee may seem pricey, Donum is always fully booked at least a month ahead of time.  So if you decide that you want to visit, be sure to book your reservation far in advance as there’s no guarantee they will have space for your group!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/1-1050by1400-9e0822.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/1-700by933-9e0822.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/1-675by900-9e0822.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/1-450by600-9e0822.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/1-525by700-9e0822.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/1-350by467-9e0822.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/1-350by467-9e0822.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Tasting Room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Once you get past the entrance corridor, this is the scene that you are greeted with.  I love the natural lighting and design of the space.  Although there is a tasting bar as you can see on the right, you’ll likely conduct your tasting in a private room if you come with a group of 4 or larger.  Just a beautiful space.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/2-1050by788-6b4114.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/2-700by525-6b4114.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/2-675by506-6b4114.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/2-450by338-6b4114.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/2-525by394-6b4114.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/2-350by263-6b4114.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/2-350by263-6b4114.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Wall of Pinot&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;On the left hand side of the room in the first picture, you’ll see the wall of Pinot above.  I’m not sure if it contains a bottle of every wine they’ve ever produced or what it is, but I sure hope all the bottles are empty (because they are not being stored in a dark space, haha).  I really liked a lot of the architectural things they’ve done with their space and this is just one more thing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When planning my first trip to Sonoma, I asked friends and colleagues in the wine world what were the must-see places.  Most came back with two names: Hudson and Donum.  While Hudson Ranch specializes in Chardonnay, Donum focuses on their small-but-quality Pinot Noir production.  And they are highly-regarded to the point where they are considered a Pinot powerhouse, similar to the status Kosta Browne and only a few others enjoy.  I personally prefer the Donum winemaker’s personal production (more on Auteur Wines in another article), but I understand where their reputation comes from, having tasted the wines.  I was very lucky to secure a reservation 2 months out from our trip to Sonoma as I found it’s difficult, even for members, to secure reservations as the estate is always busy thanks to its new construction and beautiful art collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/3-1050by788-0a1636.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/3-700by525-0a1636.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/3-675by506-0a1636.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/3-450by338-0a1636.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/3-525by394-0a1636.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/3-350by263-0a1636.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/3-350by263-0a1636.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Our Tasting Room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Our tasting was conducted in private room within the winery.  What was really cool was the wall on the right side was retractable.  Because the weather was so pleasant, we opened it up and enjoyed the tasting with a breeze and the smell of nature.  If you love to take pictures, it’s a great opportunity to pop outside with a glass of wine in hand.  As you can see, our group was enjoying the Chardonnays, conversation, and didn’t need any Instagram shots.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One sentence on Donum’s website really resonates with me for how I feel about the winery: “The interplay between our wine production and art collection expresses beauty through a singular sense of place.”  It is true that Donum feels like a singular place disconnected from the rest of the world when you are enjoying the wine and touring the gardens.  It’s been a journey for them though and this sanctuary wasn’t built overnight.  Setting out to craft Burgundian Grand-Cru level Pinot Noirs in 2001, each year they’ve increased production (modestly), price, and the scores only seem to be going up.  With the profits, they’ve been able to acquire addition land in the Russian River and Anderson Valleys, producing more site-specific, singular Pinots from around Sonoma.  There is no machine use in any of their vineyards (all work done by hand) and they currently produce around 5000 cases annually, which is mostly consumed by their 1800 wine club members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/4-1050by788-2e9969.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/4-700by525-2e9969.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/4-675by506-2e9969.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/4-450by338-2e9969.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/4-525by394-2e9969.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/4-350by263-2e9969.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/4-350by263-2e9969.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;United Nations?&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;In addition to the great quality Pinot, the other reason to visit Donum is for their art collection onsite, whose value has to be at least $100 million dollars, likely much more.  In fact, I would be interested to know the distribution of people that visit for the wine versus the art.  In this picture, you can see the same iconic statue that exists at the United Nations.  I think this is 1 of 2 or 3 in existence.  Just unbelievable.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/5-1050by788-e539c3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/5-700by525-e539c3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/5-675by506-e539c3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/5-450by338-e539c3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/5-525by394-e539c3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/5-350by263-e539c3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/5-350by263-e539c3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Zodiac&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Another famous art piece.  The different signs of the Zodiac, spread out in a circle according to the Chinese Calendar.  Just one of the pieces must have cost millions (I know it’s by a famous sculptor).  The entire set must have cost a fortune.  Unfortunately for me, they didn’t hand out a catalog to look at while taking the tour.  Though, I’m not sure if it would’ve been more impressive or a turn-off.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you drive up to the winery, please don’t crash your car while staring at the giant head sculpture near their gated entrance.  Once inside, you’ll be able to take in the architecture of the building before being greeted by your wine ambassador and led to your private tasting room.  Here, you will enjoy the wine, the conversation, the views, and even the weather as one of the walls is actually a giant sliding door that opens, allowing you to enjoy your tasting looking at the vineyards and feeling the cool Carneros breeze hit you while tasting the cool Chardonnays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/6-1050by788-be9ffe.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/6-700by525-be9ffe.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/6-675by506-be9ffe.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/6-450by338-be9ffe.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/6-525by394-be9ffe.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/6-350by263-be9ffe.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/6-350by263-be9ffe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Purple!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A picture of me with the lavender in the background.  One of the constant arguments I have with my friends is the color of my shirt: is it a shade of blue or a shade of purple.  I strongly argued the former, but looking at this picture (in literally “a new light”), I might have to agree with them now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/7-1050by788-280c08.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/7-700by525-280c08.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/7-675by506-280c08.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/7-450by338-280c08.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/7-525by394-280c08.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/7-350by263-280c08.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/7-350by263-280c08.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Giant Spider Money&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Yes, that is a giant spider in the center of the room.  When the owners purchased the sculpture, they didn’t move the spider inside the building.  They found the optimal spot for the spider, then built the building around the sculpture.  I know…  Apparently, this is by a famous sculptor and goes for millions (sorry, I don’t know much about art).  It’s very cool to see upclose, but now my friends and I joke about having “giant spider money”.  A new internal joke added to our arsenal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you finish your tastings, making your purchases, and signing up for the wine club (if you so choose), you’ll be taken on a guided tour of the sculpture garden behind the winery.  It’s hard to do the experience justice with words, so I’ll let the pictures give you a sneak peek at what to expect, but if you are familiar with artists Ai Weiwei, Keith Haring, and Louise Bourgeois, let’s just say you’ll be very entertained.  Because the tour component is longer than at most wineries, expect to spend a full 2 hours at Donum Estate and make your schedule accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/8-1050by1400-b68877.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/8-700by933-b68877.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/8-675by900-b68877.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/8-450by600-b68877.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/8-525by700-b68877.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/8-350by467-b68877.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/donum-estate/8-350by467-b68877.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Rubber Palm Tree&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I didn’t realize it when we were parking, but walking back to our rental car after the tasting, I noticed that the tree we parked under wasn’t actually a tree.  It was a piece of art that was created using shredded tires.  Pretty life-like though, right?  Again, because of the amount of art and their fame, I felt a little out of place at the winery - others were enjoying the experience much more than I.  Just something to note when you visit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, to the part of the experience that I cared for the most!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Russian River Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt; ($60)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Chardonnays are tank fermented and then aged in 50% new French Oak.  No MLF that contributes to the lean, elegant, and crisp style.  Medium intensity on the nose of lemon, lime and other citrus fruits with some crisp yellow apple.  They want the acid to shine first and foremost, so no lees aging either.  High acid, medium body, with pronounced intensity of lemon, lime, citrus, yellow fruit, and some lighter stonefruit.  Very fruit driven but there is a zesty spiciness, white pepper, and a slight chalkiness on the finish.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedonumestate.com/assets/upload/files/2019/donum_16ChardonnayCarneros_techsheet.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Russian River Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($60)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Medium(+) intensity of cream, stonefruit (peach, apricot), and some yellow fruit (pear/apple) at the tail end.  On the palate, the medium(+) body has more weight than the 2017.  The fruit is riper and the acid is better integrated into the body and alcohol as well.  There is a little less concentration than traditional RRV Chardonnays, but it has a purity, brightness, elegance, and Chablis-like finish.  I don’t know how long this can age, but it will be great for at least 3-5 years.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedonumestate.com/assets/upload/files/2019/donum_16Carneros_techsheet.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Carneros Estate Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Medium(+) intensity aromas of cherry, cola, vanilla, cream, plum, ripe strawberry, and a light white pepper.  There is a complexity and depth to this Pinot, even though tertiary character doesn’t play a large part in the aromas.  Medium body, medium(+) but integrated acidity, high alcohol (but you can’t feel it until the finish), same flavors on the palate with medium(+) intensity.  The wine isn’t super fruity or candied but it is solid with great concentration and integration already.  The Carneros gets more gamey/meaty over time, so it’ll be exciting to age and see!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedonumestate.com/assets/upload/files/2019/donum_16RRValley_techsheet.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Russian River Estate Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is a bit brighter, fleshier (more plum) and higher pitched (the alcohol/acidity/white-pepper integrate to pique the nose more).  The palate is slightly higher intensity with the alcohol showing itself more.  The flavors don’t quite show the vanilla and cream of the Carneros and the body is less rounded.  This likely has the greater aging potential of the two, but is a bit more raw right now.  This wine becomes more floral with dried fruit character over time.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedonumestate.com/assets/upload/files/2019/donum_16AndersonValley_techsheet.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Anderson Valley Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Elegant, medium(+) intensity on the nose with softer red fruit, and some savoury aspects (but not too much).  The balance on the palate is impeccable.  There is a ton of personality from floral notes, cherry, cream, white spice that combines with the acidity.  It’s already showing some savory character in its youth and will only continue to develop.  It’s harder to find this bottle on the market (of the three Pinots) so I walked away with a couple bottles of this.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want something more than just wine and views of nature with your tasting, this is the place to visit.  Just be ready to devote the time and money that comes with the wine and the experience!  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="carneros" /><category term="sonoma" /><category term="sonoma-coast" /><summary type="html">When you visit wineries for tastings, you may notice that a majority have a theme to them, likely due to past influences, and the owners will try to enhance that theme by incorporating art and/or architectural design (e.g. Round Pond and Tuscany, Cliff Lede and Rock-and-Roll, etc.). I have never before visited a winery like Donum Estate where the Art experience matches or even exceeds the tasting experience. And while the Chardonnays and Pinot Noirs (especially the Pinot) are well-regarded and rated, I think a good portion of the tasting fee ($95) goes towards your museum ticket to tour the sculptor garden. And even though the tasting fee may seem pricey, Donum is always fully booked at least a month ahead of time. So if you decide that you want to visit, be sure to book your reservation far in advance as there’s no guarantee they will have space for your group!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/donum-estate/7.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hudson Ranch Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/16/hudson_ranch_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hudson Ranch Private Tasting" /><published>2019-11-16T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-16T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/16/hudson_ranch_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/16/hudson_ranch_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Hudson Ranch is truly a ranch in every sense of the word: the amount of land it encompasses (~2000 acres), the livestock and gardens they maintain on the property, the living quarters built for workers and their families, etc.  It’s truly a wonder.  Though with all the resources and new equipment they have, it’s baffling to me that they are aiming to produce no more than 8000 bottles of wine a year.  They do sell a good amount of fruit, but only to the best producers (e.g. Aubert, Kongsgaard, and Kistler).  And with the amount of wine they do produce, their quality and scores are off the charts; the 2016 Little Bit scored 99pts from The Wine Advocate, while the 2015 Old Master and the 2016 Ladybug both scored 97pts.  Regardless of the scores they received from others, tasting the wines myself, I’d put them in the Top 3 in the Napa area.  And at their price point, it’s the best QPR Chardonnay around.  A must visit if you are heading to Sonoma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/1-1050by1400-3101c6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/1-700by933-3101c6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/1-675by900-3101c6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/1-450by600-3101c6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/1-525by700-3101c6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/1-350by467-3101c6.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/1-350by467-3101c6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Apertifs for the win&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Arriving at Hudson Ranch.  I’ve been to wineries where we were the only groups there before.  I’ve never been to a winery this large where that was the case.  We got a tour of the winery and gardens before the tasting.  But they wouldn’t make us do that without wine!  So we got small pours of the White Study to walk with.  Unfortunately, that meant I couldn’t take good notes of that wine while doing so.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/2-1050by1400-4f7511.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/2-700by933-4f7511.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/2-675by900-4f7511.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/2-450by600-4f7511.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/2-525by700-4f7511.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/2-350by467-4f7511.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/2-350by467-4f7511.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Map of the Vineyards&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Talking through all of Hudson Ranch’s holdings.  They own A LOT of land in the area, but only a small percentage is planted.  And an even smaller percentage is used to produce wines under their label.  Most of the fruit is sold as they have a great reputation, on the level of Hyde Vineyards.  In fact, I might dare to say that they are to Chardonnay what Beckstoffer is to Cabernet.  Before you bite my head off, try their Little Bit!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found out about Hudson Ranch in a roundabout way.  Kongsgaard wines are one of the cult brands in Napa, up on Atlas Peak.  I’ve been on the waiting list forever for a chance to purchase their Chardonnay and try it out.  When I learned that Kongsgaard produced one of their Chardonnays from Hudson’s vineyards, that John Kongsgaard was also Hudson Ranch’s consulting winemaker, and that Hudson Ranch took tasting appointments, I had to sign up and make it the first stop of my day on the way to Sonoma.  Now that I am finally off the wait list at Kongsgaard, I still purchase more bottles of Hudson Ranch each vintage, even though they are a relatively unknown brand to collectors compared to collectors.  That’s how impressed I was with the Hudson Chardonnays.  I can’t speak highly enough of them and encourage those that are ABC drinkers (Anything but Chardonnay) to give these wines a shot.  They are delicious, but in a much different way than Hyde (HdV) or Burgundian Chardonnays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/3-1050by788-ba5feb.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/3-700by525-ba5feb.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/3-675by506-ba5feb.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/3-450by338-ba5feb.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/3-525by394-ba5feb.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/3-350by263-ba5feb.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/3-350by263-ba5feb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Vegetation&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The walk around their gardens was impressive.  Although it seems like their isn’t enough water to grow anything and the soil is of poor quality, all of the plants look like they’ve been supersized.  We inquired as to what fertilizers they were using.  They laughed and said they didn’t use anything unusual.  It just goes to show what is underneath the surface.  The scent intensity of the herbs in their gardens were ridiculous too…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Driving up from San Francisco, it’s relatively quick to get to Hudson Vineyards compared to the wineries in Napa as it is located straight west from the town of Napa, which itself is south of most wineries.  Hudson is also on the way to the town of Sonoma, so make it the first stop of your day (unless you want to instead go see the morning fogline from Hanzell at 10am which is also great).  The drive to the winery is like any other as you meander your way on a private road through the vineyard up to their facilities.  But once you make it to the facilities, be prepared for a different experience than most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/4-1050by1400-daffe4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/4-700by933-daffe4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/4-675by900-daffe4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/4-450by600-daffe4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/4-525by700-daffe4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/4-350by467-daffe4.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/4-350by467-daffe4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Aloe Vera&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Yes, that is a single planting of Aloe Vera.  And my friend T$ is 5’10”.  That is the level of ridiculousness we saw while walking around the gardens.  That would make for a lot of skin salve to protect yourself from the sun beating down on you.  I forget if they were opening a restaurant or considering hiring a chef to make food pairings with the gardens, but they do already utilize the vegetables to make salads and use the olives to make olive oil (which they bottle and sell).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are, you will be greeted by your wine ambassador with a glass of the White Study, which is composed of varietals traditionally found in Italy, near the Alps in the Veneto region.  After looking at a map of the grounds and discussing the absurd amount of land that Lee Hudson owns in the area, you’ll get a tour of their garden and the facilities (see the pictures for some examples of the sights you’ll see).  The garden looks like it’s filled each day with fertilizer (but the soil itself looks poor) and the equipment and facilities look brand new.  You could definitely see them becoming a large producer of wines in the region, but that’s not their goal.  Lee Hudson is from Texas and has that ranch mentality at heart where he is happy tending to his land and vines, moreso than producing large volumes of wine and focusing on profit.  John Kongsgaard helped talk Lee into making some wine, but low volume and only the highest quality.  And everything about the newly-built facilities screams quality and a high price tag.  Luckily, the latter isn’t true of their wines…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/5-1050by788-f2b87f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/5-700by525-f2b87f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/5-675by506-f2b87f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/5-450by338-f2b87f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/5-525by394-f2b87f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/5-350by263-f2b87f.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hudson-ranch/5-350by263-f2b87f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Tasting Menu&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A shot of the four bottles that were planned for our tasting.  These are not the traditional bottles used for the tasting, but I emailed and specially requested to taste both the Little Bit and Ladybug Chardonnays, even though they were officially sold out.  I was also able to purchase several bottles, so it was really my lucky day…  That Little Bit still haunts me and I occasionally get urges to open one of my remaining bottles.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tasting the wines, it felt like we had stumbled upon a great secret of Sonoma.  Here is a ranch that grows tremendously high-quality grapes, selling the majority to producers that make $125-$150 bottles from those grapes, and yet they produce wines from some of their best for $85 a bottle.  And according to some critics, they can outscore those other bottles and be called out as the best white wines in Napa.  The only negative is that their low production means that you need to be aggressive in signing up for their mailing list and purchasing the bottles you want on release, because they do tend to sell out quickly on their website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read about each of the wines on this webpage: &lt;a href=&quot;https://hudsonranch.com/our-wines&quot;&gt;https://hudsonranch.com/our-wines&lt;/a&gt;.  And by clicking the picture of each wine (do not right-click and open in a new tab), you’ll be able to see the technical sheet for each wine.  Without further ado, these were the wines that we were able to taste.  Again, please note that these may note be the same bottles offered for your tasting.  We specially requested the Little Bit and Ladybug chardonnays be included even though they were sold out at the time.  So be sure to call and ask/negotiate what you’ll be able to sample before you arrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2018 White Study&lt;/strong&gt; ($36)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A Fruili (Northern Italy) blend of Ribolla Gialla, Friulano, and Chardonnay that displays yellow fruit and high, crisp acid.  Since we were walking and sipping this wine outdoors, I didn’t have a chance to take thorough tasting notes, but it’s an interesting blend uncommon in Napa/Sonoma that can serve well as an apertif before moving onto the heavier Chardonnay varietal wines.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Little Bit Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt; ($85)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Hugely pronounced stonefruit (peach/apricot), ripe yellow fruit (apples/pears), and tropical fruit (mango/melon) with butter, cream and vanilla.  Thanks to the cooler climate, this slow ripening Chardonnay has impressive acidity to balance the medium(+) body and opulent fruit/MLF flavors.  There is such aging potential here and it takes a little while to open up in its youth.  But this wine is an absolute powerhouse.  Even though our group normally prefers Burgundian-styled Chardonnays, this was our favorite over the Ladybug.  Elegant, but powerful and present.  I bought nearly a case of this wine it was so good…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Ladybug Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt; ($85)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is a quite a bit lighter in intensity with lighter yellow fruit, citrus, and crisp stonefruit.  The palate has medium(+) intensity with yellow fruit (apple/pear), cream, and butter.  The acidity presents itself more here (the vines were quite vigorous and they had to drop 30% of the fruit in green harvest) and there is some more lemon/lime type flavors rather than the riper development of the Little Bit.  That makes this wine lighter for easier drinking.  This wine likely will appeal to a broader category of wine drinkers than its sister.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Phoenix&lt;/strong&gt; ($65)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pronounced, perfumed aromas of deep-but-bright fruit-driven (but not candied) red fruit that includes cherry, plum, strawberry, kirsch, and black cherry in the medley.  Medium bodied, medium(+) ripe but grippy tannins.  Slighly less ripe red fruit on the palate with black pepper providing a strong undertone and toast, cedar, and other wood notes rounding out the palate.  This wine needs 5-10 years to smooth the tannins and fill out the body a bit.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Old Master&lt;/strong&gt; ($125)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Deeper nose with more black fruit than the Phoenix and some freshness reminiscent of fennel.  A Right-Bank Bordeaux blend mostly composed of Cabernet Franc and the rest Merlot.  Pronounced intensity on the palate with a perfume of fruit that hits you hard and fast.  On the mid-palate and finish, ripe but fresh red fruit with some hints of black fruit in the background.  The tannin is medium(+), ripe and grippy which pairs well with the fresh medium(+) acidity.  Again, this wine needs 5 years to round out the tannin and body, but has greater potential than the Phoenix because of the extra depth, concentration, and riper flavors to pair with future tertiary notes.  There is also some toast and baking spices that come out on the finish.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Syrah&lt;/strong&gt; ($90)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;After 6 years, the fruit is already tapered back in intensity on the nose with tertiary notes blended with the deep red fruit in medium(+) bright intensity.  The palate has red fruit, tertiary character, and is drinking very smoothly.  The wine was served perhaps a little warmer than it should have been, but I purchased some bottles of the 2016 to watch the evolution over time myself.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2018 Grenache Rose&lt;/strong&gt; ($32)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Whole cluster and fermented in a concrete egg.  I was surprised by the higher acidity and minerality to go with the fresh strawberry, stonefruit and salinity.  This wine is lighter in intensity and tasting it at the end (it was a spur-of-the-moment bottle) was probably a disservice to how it would be perceived as the first wine in the tasting.  Still, very different than other Roses in the area and our group bought some to enjoy later.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The $65 tasting fee, which won’t be reimbursed based on your purchases, can seem a bit steep compared to the other tasting fees in Sonoma and even Napa.  Though, if you can ensure your tasting lineup looks similar to the above, you won’t be disappointed.  In addition, being able to try possibly the best Chardonnays you will ever have is an opportunity that is hard to pass up.  It was for me when I was finalizing my reservation.  So the next time someone talks about Sonoma not being able to compare with Napa on quality, be sure to send them here and follow up for their reaction.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="carneros" /><summary type="html">Hudson Ranch is truly a ranch in every sense of the word: the amount of land it encompasses (~2000 acres), the livestock and gardens they maintain on the property, the living quarters built for workers and their families, etc. It’s truly a wonder. Though with all the resources and new equipment they have, it’s baffling to me that they are aiming to produce no more than 8000 bottles of wine a year. They do sell a good amount of fruit, but only to the best producers (e.g. Aubert, Kongsgaard, and Kistler). And with the amount of wine they do produce, their quality and scores are off the charts; the 2016 Little Bit scored 99pts from The Wine Advocate, while the 2015 Old Master and the 2016 Ladybug both scored 97pts. Regardless of the scores they received from others, tasting the wines myself, I’d put them in the Top 3 in the Napa area. And at their price point, it’s the best QPR Chardonnay around. A must visit if you are heading to Sonoma.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/hudson-ranch/5.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Venge Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/09/venge_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Venge Private Tasting" /><published>2019-11-09T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-09T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/09/venge_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/09/venge_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Nils Venge is a household name in the Napa Valley.  He’s consulted for wineries such as Groth, Saddleback, Carter Cellars, and was even the first American winemaker to receive a 100pt score for a wine (earning it for his 1985 Groth Reserve Cabernet Sauvignon from Robert Parker).  It turns out that the winemaking talent runs in the family, no doubt also the hard work and perseverance required to be a successful winemaker.  Venge Vineyards is run by Nil’s son, Kirk.  And while Kirk doesn’t quite have the same resume and reputation that his father does, I have no doubt that he will garner it in the future.  The quality of the wines in the tasting communicate that quite clearly.  So consider yourself lucky that you can enjoy his wines at affordable prices until that happens!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/1-1050by788-40b43b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/1-700by525-40b43b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/1-675by506-40b43b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/1-450by338-40b43b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/1-525by394-40b43b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/1-350by263-40b43b.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/1-350by263-40b43b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Smooth and Sleek&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Smooth and sleek tasting room.  The fact that it was empty says less about the popularity of the winery and more about it’s tasting policy (they can only have 20 people per day per their alcohol license) and the view outside - the group before and after us also took their tasting outside.  If it ever got cold enough to have the tasting indoors, I don’t think people would be disappointed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/2-1050by788-6e6fe4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/2-700by525-6e6fe4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/2-675by506-6e6fe4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/2-450by338-6e6fe4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/2-525by394-6e6fe4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/2-350by263-6e6fe4.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/2-350by263-6e6fe4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;View of the Vineyard&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view from their patio.  Their tasting room is pretty far off the main road, so you won’t encounter many people coming and going from the winery.  This is important as I’m pretty sure the road you take is a one-lane road.  This makes for a very peaceful tasting where the only stimuli are the views, wine, and conversation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Venge Vineyards doesn’t have the advertising or fame of many other vineyards in Napa.  With their current alcohol license (they can only host a maxium of 20 people per day), I think that is fine.  In fact, I’m sure it helps them build deeper relationships with consumers since they do not have the production level or resources to sustain a large, rotating membership pool.  To get an tasting appointment with them, I had to submit a request and then take a phone call with one of their front-office folks to explain how I heard about them and where my interest came from.  Although the logistics were a little tougher than normal, it was well worth the effort.  I am used to paying much more for the quality of the wines and exclusivity of the experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/3-1050by788-ca8af7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/3-700by525-ca8af7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/3-675by506-ca8af7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/3-450by338-ca8af7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/3-525by394-ca8af7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/3-350by263-ca8af7.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/3-350by263-ca8af7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Our Tasting Group&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Wine is always better with friends.  I’m lucky to have a good group to call on when I’m on the west coast!  Most of us agreed on the quality/price of the tasting and purchased the two bottles necessary to get the free tasting fee.  The Silencieux was my favorite and I walked away with two bottles.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When navigating to the winery, rely on Google Maps to make the correct turn (even if the signage is absent/unclear) and just trust the one-lane road all the way back to the winery.  You’ll get to drive past the entire vineyard in front of the winery along the way.  When you arrive, you may see one other group wrapping up their tasting, but other than yourself and the wine ambassador on duty that day, you’ll have the place to yourself.  Once you get settled outside, prepare to try 5 really good wines.  And for purchasing as little as $70-$80 worth of wine (2 bottles), you’ll get your $45 tasting fee waived.  It’s a “can’t lose” situation here.  So just enjoy yourselves to the max.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/4-1050by788-612b4c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/4-700by525-612b4c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/4-675by506-612b4c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/4-450by338-612b4c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/4-525by394-612b4c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/4-350by263-612b4c.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/4-350by263-612b4c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Close look&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A close look at the first set of bottles that we tasted.  While none of the wines were showstopping to me, all of them were great quality and very much worth their modest (by Napa standards) prices.  If you like your wines smooth with moderate complexity and like to try a mix of blends and varietals, you’ll enjoy visiting Venge.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When people ask me what type of wine they should expect from Venge, I think it boils down to a few points for me.  It’s affordable (which is always important); the quality is not off-the-charts, but very solid; the blends are different and interesting; the grapes are sourced from different areas, giving you different styles of wine in each bottle; and the red wines have a prettiness and are made to be consumed immediately, though you can age them if you want to.  This is similar to the style that Mark Beringer that ushered in at Beringer as well.  I don’t know if this is the beginning of a trend among winemakers, but I personally approve and think that it will engage younger drinkers that don’t/can’t sustain a cellar to grab a perfectly aged bottle from each evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/5-1050by1400-2310d3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/5-700by933-2310d3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/5-675by900-2310d3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/5-450by600-2310d3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/5-525by700-2310d3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/5-350by467-2310d3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/venge/5-350by467-2310d3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Posers&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I learned some things about posing, Instagram, filters and other topics on this trip.  While I don’t quite have my pose down, others were more than happy to show me how it’s done.  Just imagine yourself in their shoes, drinking some darn good wine…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can I elaborate on the actual wines you can expect to taste at the winery?  Of course I can!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vengevineyards.com/Acquire/Vineyard-Designates/Juliana&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2018 Jewell Vineyard Sauvignon Blanc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($35)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fermented predominantly in stainless steel, but also some in concrete egg to round out the acidity a bit and add a bit of minerality.  It is still searing high, even when served warm and interacts with the citrus flavors well.  This is not your traditional Napa Valley ripe Sauvignon Blanc with melon/stonefruit flavors.  This wine indexes closer to the varietal qualities of the grape like New Zealand with its lemon, lime, and mineral character.  Very good.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vengevineyards.com/Acquire/Blended-Designates/Scouts-Honor&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Scout’s Honor (Red Blend)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($39)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A blend of Zinfandel, Charbono, Syrah, and Petite Sirah which is a highly unusual blend - I can’t think of another like it in the Napa Valley.  Deep red baked fruit with black pepper and baking spices on the nose.  Although it’s deep, it’s also bright which is very interesting.  Very light body, medium sweet tannins, with ripe, light, juicy red fruit on the palate with cinnamon, other baking spices, and hints of earth.  This is white-meat red wine and for those that like sweet Pinots.  This is their highest production wine and also the most likely to appear in stores and restaurant menus, so keep an eye out.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vengevineyards.com/Acquire/Vineyard-Designates/Signal-Fire&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Signal Fire Vineyard Zinfandel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($45)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The white and black pepper are on full display on the nose with bright red fruit.  Medium body, medium(+) acid, medium ripe tannin, with flavors of red plum, cooked cherry, vanilla, and sweet baking spices.  The wine has a long finish and leaves you with a little white spice.  A very nice rendition of Zinfandel that is both enjoyable and interesting.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vengevineyards.com/Acquire/Blended-Designates/Silencieux&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Silencieux Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($60)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pronounced nose of raspberry, strawberry, and blueberry jam with integrated alcohol that provides a minty note.  Very soft body with high, smooth tannin that needs a few more years for integration.  The body emulates the nose but the alcohol bites a bit with the baking spices on the finish.  The alcohol actually reaches the point where it burns the mouth a bit.  So decant this wine and serve it during cooler weather to maximize enjoyment.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Missouri Hopper Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt; ($125)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cabernet from one of the famed Beckstoffer sites.  There is a brightness with crushed candied cherry that eclipses the Silencieux.  The aromas and flavors are a bit deeper as well.  Again, the flavors are intense but balanced and feel lighter on the palate.  There is some tertiary complexity that is just starting to emerge and blend into the profile, but it’s too young to judge how it’ll integrate and play into the big picture.  You can taste the quality of the grapes though which is what you want in the best wines.  I don’t think this wine scored any major accolades, but wow it was really good to drink…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to support smaller wineries like Venge Vineyards that thrive on foot-traffic and inquisitive visitors to the Napa Valley since I hope to have one myself one day and because they introduce different styles, flavors, and techniques that continue to add diversity to the wine world.  If the wines seem like they match your palate, I highly recommend that you fill out the form on the winery’s website and plan a trip there.  It’s a low risk, high reward chance to take.  So do it!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="calistoga" /><summary type="html">Nils Venge is a household name in the Napa Valley. He’s consulted for wineries such as Groth, Saddleback, Carter Cellars, and was even the first American winemaker to receive a 100pt score for a wine (earning it for his 1985 Groth Reserve Cabernet Sauvignon from Robert Parker). It turns out that the winemaking talent runs in the family, no doubt also the hard work and perseverance required to be a successful winemaker. Venge Vineyards is run by Nil’s son, Kirk. And while Kirk doesn’t quite have the same resume and reputation that his father does, I have no doubt that he will garner it in the future. The quality of the wines in the tasting communicate that quite clearly. So consider yourself lucky that you can enjoy his wines at affordable prices until that happens!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/venge/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Beringer Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/02/beringer_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beringer Private Tasting" /><published>2019-11-02T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-02T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/02/beringer_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/02/beringer_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;You can read up on Beringer’s history and prior vintage tastings in this article &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/09/08/beringer_private_tasting.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HERE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  As a Private Reserve member of Beringer, I try to get out to the winery once a year to taste the new vintage.  And the wines made enough of an impact on me that I wanted to write a separate article to cover the 2015 vintage.  This is not just because 2015 was a great vintage.  2015 was the first vintage fully produced by their new winemaker: Mark Beringer.  After spending years honing his craft at Duckhorn, Mark came back home to take the reigns.  And what a difference this has made on the wines Beringer producers…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are used to the big, structured, almost harsh renditions of Private Reserve that required 10-20 years of cellar aging before they were ready, you are in for one heck of a surprise.  The new style being ushered in by Mark Beringer is all about approachability early in the life of the wines.  And this is without taking anything good away from the wines (as demonstrated by James Suckling’s back-to-back 99 point ratings of the 2015 and 2016 Private Reserves).  What this means is that all of their upper tier wines (e.g. the Private Reserves, Single Vineyard bottles, etc.) can now be enjoyed immediately upon release and they are really, really good.  I think that this change is a win for consumers as people don’t have the patience or basement-space to age wines for 5-10 years before enjoying them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beringer-2/1-1050by700-2aac0d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beringer-2/1-700by467-2aac0d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beringer-2/1-675by450-2aac0d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beringer-2/1-450by300-2aac0d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beringer-2/1-525by350-2aac0d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beringer-2/1-350by233-2aac0d.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beringer-2/1-350by233-2aac0d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;It was very bright outside&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A picture standing near the Rhine House garden and fountain at Beringer.  If you visit Beringer, you should absolutely pay the extra fee to taste the high-end wines located in the Rhine House, as opposed to tasting wines you can find in your local grocery stores in other sections of the winery.  More tasting means the sun was perfectly placed to hit me right in the eyes.  I need to remember to bring my sunglasses with me…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can really tell the difference comparing the 2013 Private Reserve against Mark’s 2015 Private Reserve.  The 2013, rated 97 points by the Wine Advocate, has a huge amount of tannins that are not yet polished in year 6 and could probably age for 30-40 years.  Robert Parker scores tend to emphasize ageability and intensity and that is what you see in this wine.  The 2015 still has high tannins, but less overall and are much more polished than the 2013, even at age 4.  The nose is also much more perfumed and seductive, begging you to taste what is in your glass.  If you asked me which bottle I’d rather have in 20 years, I’m pretty sure it’d be the 2013.  But if I had to choose a wine to drink tomorrow, it’s the 2015 by a long shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So pay attention and try some of the newer Beringer wines if you can.  And if you are in the area, stop by the winery to try the amazing 2015 and 2016 vintages as both are arguably two of their greatest vintages in this millenium.  Until then, enjoy the notes below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beringer.com/wines/private-reserve/chardonnay-napa-valley/2017&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Private Reserve Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($48)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The fruit, butter, and nut are all very well balanced.  The alcohol is high, but integrated and leaves you with a warm finish.  The fruit is fresh and not baked/cooked which is nice and bright.  A lighter/brighter style than past vintages that still has good presence and intensity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beringer.com/wines/distinction-series/bancroft-ranch-merlot/2015&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Bancroft Ranch (Howell Mountain) Merlot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($90)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Very bright, pretty nose of crushed candied violet, rich blue fruit, and chocolate.  The body could use some time to integrate a bit more (it’s lighter and rougher than it should be).  I like how the extraction is tempered a bit, but still has a ton of personality.  Give this 2-3 years and you’ll have a great Merlot for any occasion.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beringer.com/wines/single-vineyard/home-vineyard-cab/2015&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 St. Helena Home Vineyard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($150)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Deeper red, blue, and black fruit on the nose.  Also some crushed white rocks and candied cherry.  Very sensual on the palate, though is a bit light on the mid-palate and could use some Merlot to fill that out.  But once the wine ages and the tannins round out even more, this is going to be a real stunner.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beringer.com/wines/private-reserve/cabernet-napa-valley/2015&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Private Reserve Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($170)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The tannins are harsher than I remember last year and the aromas are a little closed, likely meaning they decanted this bottle for less time than they did last time.  Again, just means that even if a wine is ready sooner than past vintages, it doesn’t mean that you won’t need to decant a bit to get the bottle over the finish line!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beringer.com/wines/private-reserve/cabernet-napa-valley/2014&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Private Reserve Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($190)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Even deeper red and black fruit on the nose than the 2015.  The fruit and wood flavors are beautiful with the crushed rocks in there as well.  Though the wine is still fruit driven and has tons of tannins that still need to age and round out.  This needs more time than the 2015 to reach it’s destination, but it’s going to be a good one.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beringer.com/wines/single-vineyard/steinhauer-ranch-cabfranc/2015&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Steinhauer Ranch Cabernet Franc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($125)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Defined cheese rind, tertiary notes, and crush violets on the nose.  On the palate, the fruit is present, but not as dominant as in the Cabernet Sauvignons.  The balance between the earthiness and fruit this early in its life is crazy, though I bet the bottle was open overnight.  The tannins are medium(+), but soft and well integrated.  Probably the best drinking wine today at the tasting.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="st-helena" /><summary type="html">You can read up on Beringer’s history and prior vintage tastings in this article HERE. As a Private Reserve member of Beringer, I try to get out to the winery once a year to taste the new vintage. And the wines made enough of an impact on me that I wanted to write a separate article to cover the 2015 vintage. This is not just because 2015 was a great vintage. 2015 was the first vintage fully produced by their new winemaker: Mark Beringer. After spending years honing his craft at Duckhorn, Mark came back home to take the reigns. And what a difference this has made on the wines Beringer producers…</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/beringer-2/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bethel Heights Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/10/26/bethel_heights_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bethel Heights Public Tasting" /><published>2019-10-26T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-26T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/10/26/bethel_heights_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/10/26/bethel_heights_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Willamette Valley is a fantastic place to find and drink great wine, but most wineries there don’t have the picturesque views that are common in other wine regions.  Bethel Heights is the exception to that statement.  Not only that, they have some of the highest-rated wines in the region and the tasting fee is unbelieveably good compared to the quality/quantity of wines you get to taste.  And if that’s not enough to convince you, their wines have a ripeness that reminds you of the Russian River Valley in Sonoma.  It was a fun change of pace to enjoy these wines after a long day of tasting.  So even if you think the price point of the bottles are out of your desired range, I highly recommend visiting, especially if you have a camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/1-1050by788-05ec44.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/1-700by525-05ec44.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/1-675by506-05ec44.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/1-450by338-05ec44.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/1-525by394-05ec44.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/1-350by263-05ec44.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/1-350by263-05ec44.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;The Tasting Bar&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;You can decide to conduct your tasting at the bar, but I highly recommend enjoying your tasting outside.  To get your next wine in a timely manner, you need to be prepared to carry your wine glass inside for each subsequent pour.  But, the view is totally worth it.  Though, if you are looking to give the wines the attention they deserve, it might be hard to do outside.  I know I was struggling to do so…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bethel Heights is a family-run winery between the Casteels and Dudleys.  Although it’s only in its second generation (established in 1977), that still makes Bethel Heights one of the oldest vineyards in the Eola-Amity Hills AVA.  The vineyards are planted on south-facing slopes and benches that are predominantly volcanic, which give the wines their ripeness and minerality.  The Van Duzer Corridor brings cooling winds from the ocean through the area, preserving the acidity in the grapes during the evenings.  And with nearly 50 acres planted, they have a lot of fruit to choose from when making their wines.  All of these factors contribute to the winemaker’s ability to make really enticing wines that are well worth their price tag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/2-1050by788-155383.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/2-700by525-155383.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/2-675by506-155383.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/2-450by338-155383.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/2-525by394-155383.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/2-350by263-155383.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/2-350by263-155383.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;On a stool on the patio&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view from my stool on the patio.  There are only a handful of the best seats, so I started here while waiting for one of those seats to open up.  As you can see, the view was still gorgeous.  Though, the forboding sky scared me a little bit.  The view and wines really did remind me of what I like about visiting Napa.  Now I have a go-to in Willamette.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/3-1050by788-17552a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/3-700by525-17552a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/3-675by506-17552a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/3-450by338-17552a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/3-525by394-17552a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/3-350by263-17552a.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/3-350by263-17552a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;The first-class seats&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The four first-class seats at the winery.  Snapped this picture before sitting down in one of the two on the right.  The sky did end up clearing a bit, but I really want to return on a bright, clear day.  Still, just a stunning, open view…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most exciting piece of their vineyards for me is the drastically different Justice Vineyard.  Here, the volcanic soil is at its thinnest.  Underneath are layers of marine sediment, not unlike the hallowed soils of Burgundy.  You can taste the difference in these wines compared to the other blocks.  Paired with the ripeness Bethel Heights is able to achieve and you get delicious elixirs that are unlike any wine you have probably had before.  Even if you aren’t a wine geek, I’m confident that as you taste the wines on their tasting list, you’ll be able to pick out subtle differences that will have you liking some and loving others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/4-1050by788-f00b5e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/4-700by525-f00b5e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/4-675by506-f00b5e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/4-450by338-f00b5e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/4-525by394-f00b5e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/4-350by263-f00b5e.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/4-350by263-f00b5e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;The cousin and her husband&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It’s always better to roll with an entourage, haha.  Seriously though, I don’t know why they were wearing sunglasses…  The sun wasn’t even out!?!  I guess this weather must have been “bright” for Portlandians.  I did want some myself when the sun began to creep out toward the end of the tasting.  And they do make for a cool picture…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tasting room itself is simple but well done.  The patio and view are where it’s really at though.  It’s hard to predict the weather in Willamette, but I highly recommend that you do your utmost to visit on a sunny day.  Once you take a seat in one of the lawn chairs, you’ll understand why.  I normally enjoy my tastings and leave as soon as I’ve finished typing my notes, but I caught myself staring at the view for a good 15-20 minutes after my tasting was over.  If you also love a good view, I would plan to spend some additional time here.  Probably the best view from a balcony I’ve seen in the Willamette AVA.  NOTE: The number of lawn chairs and benches outside are pretty limited though, so you may need to be patient (or get their near opening) to secure your spot.  See my numerous pictures for further evidence of said view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/5-1050by788-109116.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/5-700by525-109116.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/5-675by506-109116.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/5-450by338-109116.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/5-525by394-109116.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/5-350by263-109116.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/5-350by263-109116.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Yes, yours truly&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Can’t say “no” to family and my cousin wanted a picture of me.  But she also wanted me to post it on the blog, so here it is!  You happy, Jen?  The sun just started to creep out and was hitting me right in my eyes.  Still, quite a view, isn’t it?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While tasting the wines, you can read the scores from wine critics on their tasting menu.  A subtle hint to visitors that they are recognized nationally for their quality.  And their wines are as good as their scores suggest.  If you like white and black pepper in your Pinot, you are going to like these wines.  I personally don’t, but understand the quality of these wines.  The chardonnays were very nice, but the best QPR buy may be their off-dry, $20 Riesling.  While Riesling is known in Washington and some vineyards are trying to grow it in Oregon, theirs is really good in spite of the fact that the vines are a little young.  And please note that we were here on Memorial day (a Monday), so the place wasn’t packed, but I would expect this place to be full on normal days.  On those days, your ability to enjoy the winery may be a little compromised, so please plan appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/6-1050by788-56fff4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/6-700by525-56fff4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/6-675by506-56fff4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/6-450by338-56fff4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/6-525by394-56fff4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/6-350by263-56fff4.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bethel-heights/6-350by263-56fff4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;The sun came out&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The sun finally came out at the end of our tasting.  I had to get a picture in so you can see the difference and understand when I say to make sure you visit on a sunny day.  It warmed up a bit too, making it perfect to sit outside without a jacket.  Just stunning…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, the wines!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bethelheights.orderport.net/product-details/0296/2016-Pinot-Noir-Justice-Vineyard&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Pinot Noir – Justice Vineyard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($56)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Scored 93pts by Wine Advocate.  Deep nose of baked raspberry pie, black raspberry, red cranberry, and red currant.  Medium body, medium(+) acidity, and medium tannin.  While the palate does lead with the red fruit, the combination of white spice, baking spices and alcohol take over and increase the heat in your mouth.  The palate is also less ripe than the nose with plenty of green/stemmy character, which accentuates the brightness and spice character.  I would pair this wine with some lighter meat if the spice character feels a bit strong, which I’m guessing it will for a good number of people.  I was surprised to find no whole cluster fermentation with this wine – I thought that’s where the green/stemmy character came from, but I guess not.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bethelheights.orderport.net/product-details/0405/2016-Pinot-Noir-West-Block&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Pinot Noir – West Block&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($60)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Scored 93pts by Wine Spectator.  42 year old vines from the oldest part of the vineyard.  Similar nose to the Justice, this wine has even more acidity on the palate while also being a tad riper in its flavor profile on the palate.  The black pepper is still present but less intense and better integrated with the red fruit.  Intense, complex, but also very enjoyable.  I much prefer this to the Justice Vineyard and think this will also improve over time.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bethelheights.orderport.net/product-details/0359/2016-Pinot-Noir-Casteel&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Pinot Noir – Casteel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Scored 94pts by Vinous.  This pinot is riper and more brooding than the West Block, giving off notes of black raspberry and black cherry in addition to the red fruit.  The white pepper adds some complexity and zest on the nose.  On the palate, the flavors are just as integrated as the West Block, but slightly more intense.  The tannins are a little rougher, but I think that means this wine will age longer than the other two.  The white and black pepper builds on the palate after every sip, begging for some charcuterie to pair with.  And the cranberry peaks out at the end so the wine finishes brightly.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bethelheights.orderport.net/product-details/0294/2016-Chardonnay-Justice-Vineyard&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Chardonnay – Justice Vineyard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($56)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Scored 94pts by Wine Enthusiast.  Cool climate chardonnay coming off the front of the property.  40% new French oak.  On the nose, you get pronounced notes of yellow apple, yogurt, cream, butter and vanilla.  Medium acid, medium body and medium(+) alcohol.  The secondary flavors are less pronounced on the palate, giving way to the fresh yellow fruit flavors (lemon, apple) and other citrus/zesty flavors.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bethelheights.orderport.net/product-details/0293/2016-Chardonnay-Casteel&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Chardonnay – Casteel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Scored 94pts by Wine Advocate.  Their barrel-select chardonnay, similar in style, selection method, % of new French Oak, and aging time as their Casteel Pinot Noir.  The richness on the nose and palate are elevated compared to the Justice.  There is less yogurt, but more butter and focused yellow fruit on the nose.  On the palate, everything is better integrated and clearly delineated.  While the Justice had complexity, this wine feels like it’s already been integrated and has a theme.  I’d be interested to see this one age because it feels like medium acid, but I wouldn’t be surprised if it was higher and I just couldn’t detect it due to the integration with the body.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bethelheights.orderport.net/product-details/0252/2016-Riesling&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Estate Riesling&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($20)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Grown at one of the owners’ vineyards on a high elevation plot.  Young vines, the wine is fermented to 0.5% residual sugar (RS), so it’s not sweet, but definitely off-dry.  Ripe stonefruit and tropical fruit (melon, pineapple) pop with medium(+) intensity.  On the palate, the high acidity of the Riesling reverberates and cuts through the ripe stonefruit flavors.  There are hints of tropical fruit, but not as pronounced as the nose.  The alcohol and acid do combine to burn a bit on the finish, but this wine is just really nice.  It is far better than its price would suggest.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, I highly recommend visiting Bethel Heights if you have the chance while in the Eola-Amity Hills area.  There are so many reasons to say “Yes” and nothing to preclude you other than their availability and how crowded the winery is.  I would love to hear what you agree that this seems to be a hybrid of RRV and Willamette.  Especially over a bottle of the Casteel, haha.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="oregon" /><category term="willamette-valley" /><category term="eola-amity-hills" /><summary type="html">Willamette Valley is a fantastic place to find and drink great wine, but most wineries there don’t have the picturesque views that are common in other wine regions. Bethel Heights is the exception to that statement. Not only that, they have some of the highest-rated wines in the region and the tasting fee is unbelieveably good compared to the quality/quantity of wines you get to taste. And if that’s not enough to convince you, their wines have a ripeness that reminds you of the Russian River Valley in Sonoma. It was a fun change of pace to enjoy these wines after a long day of tasting. So even if you think the price point of the bottles are out of your desired range, I highly recommend visiting, especially if you have a camera.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/bethel-heights/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Cristom’s “The Cristom Experience” Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/10/19/cristom_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cristom's &quot;The Cristom Experience&quot; Private Tasting" /><published>2019-10-19T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-19T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/10/19/cristom_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/10/19/cristom_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;This is actually my second time visiting Cristom.  The first made such an impression on me, I signed up for a membership and will try to visit once a year.  Looking back at my first post on the winery, I noticed that my pictures and wine reviews were lacking.  So if you want to read up on the background of Cristom, read my previous post at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/17/cristom_private_tasting.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HERE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  In this post, you’ll find new pictures of the estate (they’ve expanded it a bit thanks to their continuing success) and my reviews of the latest vintage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My suggestion, get to Cristom sooner rather than later.  If you look between the two posts, you’ll notice that that 2016 vintage is more expensive than the 2015 vintage.  And if you look on their website at their newly posted 2017 vintages, you’ll notice the prices have gone up again.  Everyone is catching on to the fact that their wines are of great quality and are starting to buy more and more.  Don’t miss your chance to pick up bottles before the bottles hit $100+ in 5-10 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/1-1050by788-cb6eed.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/1-700by525-cb6eed.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/1-675by506-cb6eed.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/1-450by338-cb6eed.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/1-525by394-cb6eed.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/1-350by263-cb6eed.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/1-350by263-cb6eed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;The winery&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The winery hasn’t changed much in the last year on the surface.  The weather was certainly a bit more brooding than the last time I was here.  Still, I was very happy to be here to taste the new vintage.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/2-1050by1400-3ddaed.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/2-700by933-3ddaed.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/2-675by900-3ddaed.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/2-450by600-3ddaed.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/2-525by700-3ddaed.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/2-350by467-3ddaed.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/2-350by467-3ddaed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;The Welcome Sign&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Like the sign says, you could do the 5 wine walk-in tasting for $15, or you could do the Cristom Experience for $50 and taste 8-10 wines, including the 4 ladies.  Of course, I had to do the latter since those 4 were the mostly likely bottles I was going home with.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/3-1050by788-9ffebd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/3-700by525-9ffebd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/3-675by506-9ffebd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/3-450by338-9ffebd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/3-525by394-9ffebd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/3-350by263-9ffebd.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/3-350by263-9ffebd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;The Tasting Room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I thought we would have the tasting room to ourselves on a Friday morning, but I guess not.  Plenty of room to do a walk-in tasting at the standing bar.  Or, you could sit outside on the new patio.  I definitely recommend that and you’ll see a picture of the view later below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/4-1050by788-c9f2ee.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/4-700by525-c9f2ee.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/4-675by506-c9f2ee.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/4-450by338-c9f2ee.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/4-525by394-c9f2ee.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/4-350by263-c9f2ee.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/4-350by263-c9f2ee.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;The vineyard&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view into the vineyard.  Not nearly as busy as the last time we were here when they were using chainsaws on their vines to re-graft new clones/varietals on the rootstocks.  Beautiful and well maincured.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/5-1050by788-b69e84.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/5-700by525-b69e84.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/5-675by506-b69e84.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/5-450by338-b69e84.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/5-525by394-b69e84.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/5-350by263-b69e84.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/5-350by263-b69e84.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Selfie Time!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I get a little nausea looking at this picture.  Nothing beats walking through a vineyard except walking through a vineyard with a glass of wine in your hand.  I wish it wasn’t as cloudy, but that is what Willamette Valley is like.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/6-1050by788-2585b7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/6-700by525-2585b7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/6-675by506-2585b7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/6-450by338-2585b7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/6-525by394-2585b7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/6-350by263-2585b7.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/6-350by263-2585b7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;From the new patio&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view from their newly completed patio.  It’s not as good as staring into the vineyards, but the view will do.  Very easy imagining just spending a day with a couple of bottles on those two seats with someone special.  It’s the wine version of the shot from seats on a beach looking at the ocean.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/7-1050by788-6755b5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/7-700by525-6755b5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/7-675by506-6755b5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/7-450by338-6755b5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/7-525by394-6755b5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/7-350by263-6755b5.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/7-350by263-6755b5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;In the tasting room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Once we got to tasting, the mood got serious.  Lots of wine glasses, lots of tasting, lots of revisiting, lots of second-guessing ourselves as to our favorites and which ones we were going to buy.  I think I did pretty well in my selections, but everyone thinks they are a genius…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/8-1050by788-3ff1d8.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/8-700by525-3ff1d8.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/8-675by506-3ff1d8.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/8-450by338-3ff1d8.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/8-525by394-3ff1d8.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/8-350by263-3ff1d8.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom-2/8-350by263-3ff1d8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;The vineyards&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A view of their vineyards.  My favorite are the Pinot Noirs from Jessie, but the Syrahs are a potential QPR darling, even at $40-$50.  After that, it’s between the Eileen and Marjorie for me, but they are starting to replant in Marjorie so Eileen are the safe bet for now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2017-Estate-Pinot-Gris&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Estate Pinot Gris&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($20)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;MLF and lees aging add some roundness and also flavor complexity.  The acid was still medium(+) and the flavors dwell in the yellow and green fruit range.  The integration has just started, so I would wait a couple years before partaking, but it’s already an interesting wine that is unlike others in the region.  Complex and yet refreshing.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2016-Mt--Jefferson-Cuv-e-Pinot-Noir-Copy&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Mt. Jefferson Cuvee Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($35)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Their most distributed Pinot Noir that has won awards for the best Pinot Noir in restaurants.  On both the nose and the palate, there’s cranberry, tart strawberry/cherry, and some green from the whole cluster fermentation.  Blended with grapes from 21 vineyards, 60% of which is estate grown.  Fresh, complex, and an unripe style of Pinot that is meant to emphasize the acidity and it’s ability to pair easily with many types of food.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Estate Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt; ($50)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Blend of the four ladies (the Paul vineyard did not make it in yet).  Riper than the Mt. Jefferson on the nose.  Medium brightness of candied cranberry, strawberry, and some ripe tomato.  Medium(+) acid, medium body, and very smooth on the palate.  The fruit is a bit subdued compared to the nose and there is some green and depth thanks to the whole cluster fermentation with some white spice.  This is the wine that I would serve to my friends for a smooth, easy drinking experience that would leave them wanting more.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Symbion&lt;/strong&gt; ($55)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Using grapes from the winemaker’s personal estate (Steve Dorner).  The name is a play off of “symbiosis” - what Steve tries to embody in his winemaking.  The nose is a bit riper and more brooding than the Estate Pinot.  There is more grippy tannin and weight to this wine than the estate, meaning I would probably lay this wine down for a couple years more or pair with meat when drinking.  Similar style and flavors as the Estate Pinot, but with a touch more ripeness.  Also a very nice, easy drinking wine to share with friends.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Dundee Hills AVA&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is richer and a tad brighter than the other two above, but the flavor tends more towards candied cranberry, light cherry, and some baking spices.  The body is a tad lighter and the integrated medium(+) acidity leaves your mouth watering.  The tannin is powdery, almost medium(+) that makes me think this could age quite a bit.  The winery owner’s favorite AVA bottle produced by Cristom (they do a few each year by buying grapes from elsewhere).  Done in low quantity, so you won’t find it on their website anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2016-Eileen-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir-Copy111&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Eileen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($65)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Gets the most influence of the wind at the top of the hill, which creates really nice aromatics and complexity that customers seem to love.  Bright, ripe cranberry, strawberry, and potent aromatics.  On the palate, very integrated medium(+) acid and medium tannin that structure the wine as well as integrated red fruit and alcohol that goes down very smooth.  There is certainly a lot of complexity, but the wine is so seductive in its grace and balance that you prefer not to think about it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2016-Jessie-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir-Copy11&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Jessie&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($65)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The steep hill the grapes grow on reminds me of Burgundy and is the most expensive for them to farm because of the incline.  This wine is for the serious drinker.  Riper red fruit (approaching cherries), flavors from the whole-cluster fermentation, medium(+) tannin that approach high, medium(+) acid, and this mouthwatering minerality that is integrated with the acid.  Medium(+) finish and nice length on the palate.  I could just drink this wine all day long by myself and not tire of it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2016-Louise-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir-Copy11&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Louise&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($65)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fruit-forward taste because of its flatter angle, lower elevation and its warmer location in the sun.  There is an added ripeness and depth on the nose as well.  The alcohol is a bit more noticeable, but the winemaker has integrated it well.  This is definitely the most fruit-driven of the ladies and would be what I served someone that is used to Russian River Valley Pinot.  For me, it feels a little too “juicy” in taste for my preference.  One of the reasons I prefer the Jessie is that it will have ripeness, but balance that and the alcohol with acid.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2016-Marjorie-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir-Copy11&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Majorie&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($70)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The 2016 has not been released to the public yet (still aging in bottle).  3 rows of original vines are left - there is a lot of replanting going on right now.  The depth and aromatics here are due to the older vines, rather than the terroir, like the Louise.  The tannin is a bit unintegrated and the body is lighter, almost medium(-), than the rest.  There is probably some younger fruit used in these wines that produces this effect.  The tart red fruit flavors are very seductive though and make this a wine you could drink alongside the Jessie in a competition.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, make sure to try Cristom in your local restaurants or at their vineyards when you can.  The whole cluster fermentation produces flavors that remind me of Burgundy with a bit more ripeness and a cheaper price.  That last part won’t be true for long though…  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="oregon" /><category term="willamette-valley" /><category term="eola-amity-hills" /><summary type="html">This is actually my second time visiting Cristom. The first made such an impression on me, I signed up for a membership and will try to visit once a year. Looking back at my first post on the winery, I noticed that my pictures and wine reviews were lacking. So if you want to read up on the background of Cristom, read my previous post at HERE. In this post, you’ll find new pictures of the estate (they’ve expanded it a bit thanks to their continuing success) and my reviews of the latest vintage.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/cristom-2/5.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bjornson Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/10/12/bjornson_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bjornson Private Tasting" /><published>2019-10-12T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-12T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/10/12/bjornson_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/10/12/bjornson_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Bjornson may not be a winery you think of when you hear Eola Amity Hills, but it needs to be.  The wines and wine ambassadors are capable of entertaining both wine novices and afficionados.  This may be the winery my cousin and I enjoyed the most equally.  For me, I was intrigued by the odd varietals (e.g. Gamay, Auxerrois) and the differing styles of Pinot why my cousin and her husband enjoyed the stories behind the wines and found appreciation for each by connecting them to the stories.  Whichever side of the spectrum you fall on, I guarantee that you’ll find a good, educational time at Bjornson.  And if you get Coach Barb as your wine ambassador, consider yourself lucky.  She’s awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/1-1050by788-84fb5e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/1-700by525-84fb5e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/1-675by506-84fb5e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/1-450by338-84fb5e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/1-525by394-84fb5e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/1-350by263-84fb5e.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/1-350by263-84fb5e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Winery&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Bjornson Winery.  As you can see, it is Certified Sustainable and it’s building looks amazing from the outside.  I used to have a rock wall that my father and I made to separate our yard from our neighbor’s.  I’ve seen better looking rock walls, but to turn that concept into a building and a winery no less?  I am 100% on board with that.  Tell me that’s not a gorgeous building!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I head out wine tasting, I love co-locating my tastings to minimize the amount of driving.  Smart, right?  Visiting Bjornson Vineyards was a side-effect of that methodology; it was a Eola Amity Hills tasting day.  The nice thing about that style of tasting is that you get to stumble upon wineries you normally wouldn’t go out of your way to visit.  Bjornson was that winery on this day trip and I am glad it was.  It’s just north and a little east from other well-known wineries in the region (e.g. Cristom), but when you get there, it feels like a world away.  You literally can’t hear anything getting out of your car on the property.  And that is a great feeling…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/2-1050by788-baba7d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/2-700by525-baba7d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/2-675by506-baba7d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/2-450by338-baba7d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/2-525by394-baba7d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/2-350by263-baba7d.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/2-350by263-baba7d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Inside&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The inside of the winery.  I think it looked fine - it’s hard to make the interior live up to an exterior like that.  The wine ambassaors were fun an very knowledgable.  Ours, who is talking to my cousin and her husband, is a former college women’s basketball coach who has retired and move on to her second love in life: wine.  Her anecdotes and stories were hilarious and really interesting.  We all had a great time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bjornson Vineyards is a relatively new winery - it’s first official vintage release was in 2009.  The vines were planted a few years before that and were producing fruit before the winery building was built and opened.  But from the portfolio of wines on their order form, you’d think they’ve been around for 30+ years.  The tastings are good QPR value; I think their cheapest tasting option is 6 wines for $20.  I was able to taste a couple other wines as I went for the more expensive option, but I think you’ll be happy with the wines no matter your choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/3-1050by788-d591e1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/3-700by525-d591e1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/3-675by506-d591e1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/3-450by338-d591e1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/3-525by394-d591e1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/3-350by263-d591e1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/3-350by263-d591e1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Their Vineyards&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Their vineyards outside of the winery, just across the street from the parking lot.  You can see that it starts to slope down on the edge to the left.  But it was just gorgeous out here, off the main road a little bit.  You couldn’t hear anything out here.  That was the thing that struck me the most.  It was just dead quiet getting out of the car and walking through the vineyard…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always say that most important factor to a good tasting experience (besides the wine) is the quality of your wine ambassador.  And if I had a ranking system for them, Coach Barb would be near the top.  After a career coaching in Collegiate Women’s Basketball, Coach Barb moved to Portland and began working with her second love: wine.  I’m jealous of her career and the fact that she followed her heart afterwards.  But her stories, her energy, her love and care for the topic all made us that much more interested in the wines, their character, and yes we all bought a couple bottles to go home with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one thing I picked up from Coach Barb (and I believe it) is that when people come visit the winery and do a tasting with her, they 99% of the time fall into one or more of four categories of wine drinkers: (1) The socializers that are at the winery as a social activity rather than for the wine itself; (2) The learners that are engaged and inquisitive and ask tons of questions all over the map; (3) The technical wine drinkers who want all of the winemaking decisions and fact sheets, whether or not they are talented enough tasters to track those decision in the profile of the wines; and (4) The palate hunters that don’t want to talk or do anything except taste and decide if it’s good or bad.  I definitely fall into many/all of these categories, but it’s interesting to listen to how she handles and tailors the tasting to each type of person.  Another lesson on my road to (hopefully) a future wine ambassador.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winery’s descriptions of the wines can be found on Bjornson’s website &lt;a href=&quot;https://bjornsonwine.com/wines/&quot;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;.  My tasting notes are below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2018 Auxerrois&lt;/strong&gt; ($22)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fermented in Acacia barrels and described as “Chardonnay’s sassy, flirty sister”.  Lemon, lime, some heat with other lighter yellow fruit (apple) on the nose.  On the palate, mouthwatering medium(+) acidity that is forward on the tongue and some alcohol burn on the cheeks.  Flavors of zesty, ripe lemon, cooked yellow apple, and unripe green pear.  The wine finishes crisp/clean, but the rebound comes back and flirts with you.  A very interesting wine that could use some time for integration.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Family Cuvee Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt; ($29)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Vintage that was hot late in the season.  Light garnet in color.  Bright but rich red fruit flavors of ripe cranberry, ripe strawberry, and cranberry.  The generous, candied red cranberry opens up over time.  Medium(+) intensity with aromatic lift.  The palate has that red fruit in lower intensity, with earth, minerality, toast, and baking spices that is integrated with the alcohol providing most of the finish.  A lighter-bodied Pinot that will keep you warm on a cool spring day.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Bjornson Estate Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt; ($29)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Hottest vintage on record but with late rains that lightened the concentration of the fruit.  The intensity of the red fruit (especially the ripe/partially baked cranberry) and the light white spice is slightly more intense than the 2014 above, but not quite pronounced.  The red fruit and white spice is the dominant force on the palate, with the minerality and toast just beginning to show.  Medium(+) acidity with a medium(+) finish.  This wine may lack complexity now compared to the 2014, but I would bet that this will be the better wine in 3 years.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Bjornson Estate Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt; ($29)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Released April 2019.  Hot growing season with late rain right before harvest.  Brambly/Barnyard character that wasn’t there on the previous two.  This may be the least intense of the three, but may have must been the most cloying as well.  Red fruit, fleshy plum, white spice, and some ripe tomato on the nose, but all balanced and fairly well integrated already.  Bright medium(+) acidity, medium(-) finish but length that extends across the tongue.  This has a lot of potential, but I have no idea what it will look like in a few years.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Pinot Noir BW#21003&lt;/strong&gt; ($45)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The only wine they still co-ferment and cold soak.  The very first label they made in 2009 from their first block of vines with many different clones since they were still figuring it out (Pommard, Dijon, etc.).  They couldn’t agree on a name for the wine, so they used their bonded winery number since it shows the breadth of what they are going for.  They made this wine as early as they did to beat a law bill that would have restricted them from building a tasting room if they weren’t producing wine by a certain point.  There is a complexity and depth on the nose in this vintage that easily surpasses their Estate Pinot.  There are additional notes of black fruit like cherry and raspberry, but not fully ripe with baking spices, cedar, and toast also on the palate.  Medium(-) body, but with medium(+) acid and medium tannin providing structure.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Pinot Noir Magnus&lt;/strong&gt; ($60)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Made from the Top 5 barrels of the vintage.  If the winemaker doesn’t think the quality is up to par for the vintage, they won’t make the Magnus.  This is the only vintage during which they’ve made it (that I know of).  Similar depth on the nose as the BW#21003, but a bit brighter with its red and black fruit (mostly red).  The flavors cover the entire palate and focus on the red fruit, baking spices, and cedar notes, but should evolve over the next 5-10 years thanks to the medium(+) acid and tannin.  The palate doesn’t have the same depth as the nose, but I’m hoping the development of tertiary flavors will add to that.  The finish lasts for a decent 20-25 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Reserve Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt; ($35)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Reserve Chardonnay spends 9 months in neutral oak, 5 months in once-used lightly toasted oak, then in twice-used lightly toasted oak.  It is almost as if they are gently massaging the oak into the wine.  On the nose, bright yellow fruit that feels fresh and just hints of MLF (butter and cream).  The palate emphasizes the fruit, cream, but not much vanilla or other barrel notes.  I was surprised to learn that this was all wood aged since it’s fairly reductive and has bright yellow fruit flavors.  Not quite as concentrated or viscous as others, but very enjoyable.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Gamay Noir&lt;/strong&gt; ($29)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Strong cherry notes, raisins, baking spices, other bright red fruit on the nose.  No bubble gum makes me think that this is Cru Beaujolais in style and not carbonic maceration.  There is some underlying yeast and citrus notes along with the strong red fruit.  The yeast/brioche detracts from the theme of the wine though, clashing with the cranberry and light cherry on the palate.  Without the yeast and with slightly more vanilla to go with the toast this has, this could be very nice.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With affordable wines like these, I see no reason not to stop by when you are in the area.  I highly recommend you find a way to try the Magnus as it’s quite a wine that would rate comparably to the best of them in Willamette.  I certainly will be stopping by here again in the future (next time, not by chance) and I hope you do too!  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="oregon" /><category term="willamette-valley" /><category term="eola-amity-hills" /><summary type="html">Bjornson may not be a winery you think of when you hear Eola Amity Hills, but it needs to be. The wines and wine ambassadors are capable of entertaining both wine novices and afficionados. This may be the winery my cousin and I enjoyed the most equally. For me, I was intrigued by the odd varietals (e.g. Gamay, Auxerrois) and the differing styles of Pinot why my cousin and her husband enjoyed the stories behind the wines and found appreciation for each by connecting them to the stories. Whichever side of the spectrum you fall on, I guarantee that you’ll find a good, educational time at Bjornson. And if you get Coach Barb as your wine ambassador, consider yourself lucky. She’s awesome.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/bjornson/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Siltstone Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/10/05/siltstone_winery_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Siltstone Public Tasting" /><published>2019-10-05T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-05T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/10/05/siltstone_winery_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/10/05/siltstone_winery_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;When choosing wineries to enroll as a member, there are many factors to look at: the wine quality, prices, bottle minimums, membership benefits, etc.  The most important factor for me is simple: do they treat you like family?  If the answer is “yes”, everything else will work itself out.  In the case of Siltstone Wines, this is almost literally true for me as the owners and I share the same family name.  Even if we didn’t though, I would love this winery all the same.  A family starting the winery from nothing, growing the grapes themselves, making the wines themselves, and sharing the wines themselves.  It’s everything I want to do in the future.  On top of everything, there is an energy and happiness that pervades the place - it makes you want to spend your afternoon there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/1-1050by788-a1621a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/1-700by525-a1621a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/1-675by506-a1621a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/1-450by338-a1621a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/1-525by394-a1621a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/1-350by263-a1621a.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/1-350by263-a1621a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Tasting Room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Siltstone winery almost looks like a roadside diner when you drive by it on the highway.  It can be easy to miss and if you do, don’t brake hard to try to make the turn into the entrance.  Relax and take your time.  That phrase embodies this winery in that it feels home.  And for me, it very well may be (need to take that 23-and-me test).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/2-1050by788-3a7bc7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/2-700by525-3a7bc7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/2-675by506-3a7bc7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/2-450by338-3a7bc7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/2-525by394-3a7bc7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/2-350by263-3a7bc7.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/2-350by263-3a7bc7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;It's small inside&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The inside of their tiny tasting room.  If you look in the mirror, you can see it only takes 6 people to make the tasting room feel packed.  That and how long my reach is in order to take pictures, haha.  Don’t worry, there is an outdoor patio in the back to enjoy the wines more easily.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Siltstone tasting room is located just right off the highway – you can literally see and/or hear the cars drive by while at the winery and it’s very easy to accidentally miss the entrance while driving to the winery.  Once you get over those two things, it’s smooth sailing from there as the winery itself is super laid back, but also filled with people who care about what they do since it truly is their livelihood.  And with the care that they show every customer, you truly do get the feel of family…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/3-1050by788-4692e1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/3-700by525-4692e1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/3-675by506-4692e1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/3-450by338-4692e1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/3-525by394-4692e1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/3-350by263-4692e1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/3-350by263-4692e1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;My cousin&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;My cousin Jennifer at our table on the back patio.  The facility may not be up to your normal standards, but the hospitality is second to none.  There is a meat-and-cheese table in the back that you can help yourself to, the wine ambassadors will come outside to your table to pour the next wine on the tasting list, and the atmosphere/conversation is very jovial.  The roof extension helps protect your from the summer sun and fall rains.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My brother happened to find Siltstone during his research for his honeymoon (he surprised his wife with a weekend in Willamette before heading to the Bahamas as they are both Pinot-philes).  After he gave me his impression of the place and a couple bottles of the J. Myers and Sons upon his return, I knew I had to stop by the next time I visited Portland.  I called ahead to schedule an appointment and let them know my availability like I normally do.  Once I explained the story of why I was visiting (my sister-in-law barely had time to take off her makeup from the wedding in Cleveland), the offered to open up the winery just for me.  Luckily, that wasn’t necessary after some schedule tweaking on my end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/4-1050by788-0eac8c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/4-700by525-0eac8c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/4-675by506-0eac8c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/4-450by338-0eac8c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/4-525by394-0eac8c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/4-350by263-0eac8c.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/4-350by263-0eac8c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Parking Lot&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;As you can see, the parking lot extends right up to the edge of the vines.  This is family winery that wasn’t founded with millions of dollars.  It was built from scratch to what it is today, so I can appreciate these small details.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I arrived, the first two things I noticed was that it was a really small place and it was crazy busy.  Though, everyone there seemed to be a local, rather than an out-of-towner.  The tasting room manager, Heather, had given birth only 10 days ago was already back pouring wines while her mother-in-law cared for her baby on the tasting patio (there was a mini-crowd around the baby).  The tasting room inside is small as you can see from my picture, but they had additional seats outside in the back.  You can choose to going inside every time you need another pour or they will walk around with bottles, check on everyone’s progress.  It just allows you to be very relaxed (lazy, even) and enjoy the wines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/5-1050by788-6a6661.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/5-700by525-6a6661.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/5-675by506-6a6661.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/5-450by338-6a6661.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/5-525by394-6a6661.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/5-350by263-6a6661.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/5-350by263-6a6661.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;First Person View&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A first-person view of the patio.  You can see the sign over the door that was made from the top of a barrel, the coal-fires outside to keep the patrons warm in the fall, and the fact that most of the tables were full (people seemed to know about this place).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Putting aside the ambiance of the place and looking at the vineyards, all of the Myers family vines are farmed Certified Sustainable. Joel Myers (why their Grand Vin is called J. Myers and Sons) first planted grapes in the 1960s by himself.  Today, the winery produces about 1,500 cases of wine (miniscule amount) under the Siltstone label from the Guadalupe Vineyard, Blacktail Vineyard, and Owl Ranch Vineyard.  A limited quantity of their premium Pinot noir label, J. Myers &amp;amp; Sons, is blended from select barrels after exceptional vintages (I only saw a 2012 and 2014 at the winery).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/6-1050by1400-4e25a1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/6-700by933-4e25a1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/6-675by900-4e25a1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/6-450by600-4e25a1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/6-525by700-4e25a1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/6-350by467-4e25a1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/6-350by467-4e25a1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;With the Founder&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;With the man that started it all at Siltstone.  The Myers family owns and operates the winery, while the grand vin is named after him and the family: “J. Myers &amp;amp; Sons”.  It is a coincidence that my father’s name, my brother’s name, and my name is J. Myers, but it is a pretty amazing one.  Since the label seemed tailor-made for us, I bought a case to share with my family…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But wines need to be good to want to visit a winery right?  So let’s look at the wines!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Owl Ranch Sauvignon Blanc&lt;/strong&gt; ($15)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Smoke, flint, baked yellow apple, and cream on the nose.  Same notes on the palate with a bit more cream and sheep cheese funk.  It definitely feels like the wine underwent some MLF or at least had a good amount of time on the lees.  A unique style of Sauvignon Blanc that doesn’t align with any of the established styles - very interesting.  Probably not your crisp, cool wine on a hot day, but I could see this served a bit colder with dairy products.  Not my favorite, but could be a great fit for others that like their exotic cheeses.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Blacktail Pinot Gris&lt;/strong&gt; ($15)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Ripe green and yellow apple/pear on the nose with other citrus notes such as orange peel, orange blossom and ripe grapefruit.  Similar flavors appear on the palate, but the length doesn’t go past the mid-palate and has a medium finish with its green fruit.  This is a much easier-drinking wine than the Owl Ranch Sauvignon Blanc and has enough intensity initially to pair with some white-meat driven meals.  Serve chilled to maximize the acidity and leave your palate with a clean finish.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Willamette Valley Rose&lt;/strong&gt; ($11)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;100% Pinot Noir, picked early with a higher pH from the vineyard right behind the tasting room.  Direct press to steel tank and then into the bottle after fermentation.  Light aromas of cranberry and strawberry, but more pronounced were the notes of oranges, grapefruit, and some stonefruit character.  Medium(+) acidity with similar flavors as the nose, but they are all fairly integrated together and the medium(-) intensity makes it hard to pull them apart.  The pink grapefruit was the strongest among them.  Medium finish with integrated alcohol that added to the body.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Willamette Valley Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt; ($17)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Their easy-drinking table Pinot Noir.  Cranberry, cedar, mulch, white spice, and some bell pepper on the nose.  The palate also presents medium(+) intensity flavors of cranberry, cedar and white spice, though it’s starting to hint at black pepper.  Medium intensity with a medium finish, but a medium(-) body makes me imagine serving this a little chilled outside with hot dogs.  Not much green pepper on the palate, but I would recommend this to friends that want more spice in their Pinot than the traditional cherry-flavored, ripe Pinots.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Guadalupe Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt; ($30)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Riper cranberry than the Willamette Valley Pinot Noir, with notes of strawberry and cherry in there too.  On the palate, the fruit feels a bit more baked thanks to the medium acid, the medium(+) alcohol, and the baking spices on the palate.  There are tertiary notes of leather, cedar, and toast as well.  Even at 6 years, the wine already feels very integrated with both its flavors and tannin/alcohol.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2011 Guadalupe Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt; ($30)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is a bit more subdued than the 2013, likely due to the extra 2 years in age.  On the palate, although the intensity is medium, the length has increased on the palate and leaves you with a finish of cranberry, baking spices and a touch of cedar.  The medium(+) acid is well integrated with the brooding fruit, providing lift for its age and adding some brightness while not seeming over-the-top.  This wine is drinking very nicely right now, which leads me to believe the 2013 will continue to improve.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 J. Myers &amp;amp; Sons Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt; ($45)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;2x barrel select of the Guadalupe in only the best vintage years (50 cases a year when they make it).  2012 and 2014 are the only ones currently available.  Take the notes of the Guadalupe above and imagine an added richness, a bit more ripeness (some cherry and plum now too), an undertone of wet earth / mulch, and you get this wine.  Drinking wonderfully right now, this wine also shows good length, spice that is integrated with the core of the fruit, and a medium(+) finish.  If you like a tertiary character in your Pinot, this will be $40 well spent.  Though, I do own 1% of the 2012 and 2014 vintages now, haha.  So it may be hard to find!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want a place in Willamette that is popular to the locals and relatively unknown to the outsiders, I recommend stopping by Siltstone.  The wine quality will not be on the same level of Cristom or Beaux Freres, but the experience will be as good or better and the wines will be much more affordable.  Just be sure that you have enough self-control to not each everything at the charcuterie and cheese table, haha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you do stop by, say “hello” for me!  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="oregon" /><category term="willamette-valley" /><category term="dundee-hills" /><summary type="html">When choosing wineries to enroll as a member, there are many factors to look at: the wine quality, prices, bottle minimums, membership benefits, etc. The most important factor for me is simple: do they treat you like family? If the answer is “yes”, everything else will work itself out. In the case of Siltstone Wines, this is almost literally true for me as the owners and I share the same family name. Even if we didn’t though, I would love this winery all the same. A family starting the winery from nothing, growing the grapes themselves, making the wines themselves, and sharing the wines themselves. It’s everything I want to do in the future. On top of everything, there is an energy and happiness that pervades the place - it makes you want to spend your afternoon there.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/siltstone/1.jpg" /></entry></feed>