<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-03-18T02:50:25+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Wines By Jeremy</title><subtitle>Wines by Jeremy offers an educative and enjoyable personalized wine experience. Located in the DC metro area, Wines by Jeremy provides a number of services including in-home exclusive tastings, highly curated event tastings, educational events, and wine cellar consulting.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Kenzo Estate Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2020/01/11/kenzo_estate_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kenzo Estate Private Tasting" /><published>2020-01-11T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-11T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2020/01/11/kenzo_estate_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2020/01/11/kenzo_estate_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Imagine you own 3,800 acres of pristine land in wine country and had the resources to hire world-class experts in every aspect of the winemaking process.  Now open your eyes.  You aren’t standing in front of Screaming Eagle, Harlan, or any other big name in the cult world today.  You are standing in front of Kenzo Estates.  Established by Kenzo Tsujimoto in the mid-1990s, this estate is the equivalent of the Royal Palace of Oz in from a fantasy wine novel…  You know I love it since I am posting nine pictures of our tour and tasting there!  It is quite a drive outside the town of Napa (both to its gates and then from its gates to the winery itself), but well worth it.  If the pictures aren’t enough to entice you, how about these names: Heidi Barrett, David Abreu, and Thomas Keller (assuming you get the food pair option).  The style of wine is very different from its Napa brethren (much more elegant with herbal notes) but carries similar price tags to the best.  But as 80% of the wine is exported and consumed in Japan, don’t expect much availability in the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Winery Entrance&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/1-800-eb97f0.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/1-350-eb97f0.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kenzo/1-450-eb97f0.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kenzo/1-700-eb97f0.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The first thing I noticed driving into the parking lot is that it isn’t paved.  Instead, they utilize cobblestones for their entrance.  A winery that puts that much thought into the design (without regard for cost) is putting its best foot forward and immediately impresses those that have been to many wineries before&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Rock Wall&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/2-800-fa264d.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/2-350-fa264d.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kenzo/2-450-fa264d.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kenzo/2-700-fa264d.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;They even use a beautifully constructed rock wall to form the terrace separating the vines from the parking lot.  Just great design decisions all around the vineyard about the little things.  It may not seem like a big deal, but the impacts of all the little things add up to a big impact…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are reading this and lived through the 1990s-2000s, you’ll know the Japanese game publisher and developer CAPCOM.  Kenzo just so happens to be the founder (most new winery owners made their money outside the wine world).  In 1990, CAPCOM purchased the property that would become Kenzo Estate with the intentions of developing a resort.  Imagine if that had happened…  During his time at CAPCOM, Kenzo developed a burgeoning interest in the Napa Valley after the Judgement of Paris in 1976.  This no doubt led to the purchase of this land and hope to share Napa with visitors of the resort.  Unfortunately, the resort didn’t pan out, so Kenzo personally acquired the property in the mid-1990s and moved on with another plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Their Lineup&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/3-800-8d8895.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/3-350-8d8895.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kenzo/3-450-8d8895.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kenzo/3-700-8d8895.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I’ve seen a similar bar layout for other wineries (note: there is a correlation) and I have to say I am a fan.  I like how the portfolio is laid out so you can recognize later what you didn’t taste (and can ask about it if you are interested).  While we got our pour of Sauvignon Blanc here, we didn’t stay for long.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Our Tasting Table&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/4-800-2879ce.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/4-350-2879ce.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kenzo/4-450-2879ce.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kenzo/4-700-2879ce.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Yeah, I know what you are thinking…  Why doesn’t my patio look like this?  Although all of the tasting tables are outdoors, they make sure no one is baking in the sun while drinking their wines.  The smell in the are, the wind cooling you down and the view of the vineyards - it was great to have the tasting outside.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was only after some people approached him about wanting to plant vines there that he saw the potential for planting a vineyard and producing his own wine.  And it is easy to see why they did.  The land itself has natural flowing slopes, it’s nestled in the hills above 1,500 feet, and still gets the effects of morning fog that burns off during the day.  So what did Kenzo do?  He brought in the best viticulturalist in Napa (David Abreu, who also owns a winery and produces $600 wine), my favorite winemaker (Heidi Barrett of Screaming Eagle fame), and even the best restaurateur in Napa (Thomas Keller of French Laundry fame who also owns his restaurant group).  I don’t know how you beat that all-star lineup…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Vineyards&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/5-800-e1bd76.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/5-350-e1bd76.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kenzo/5-450-e1bd76.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kenzo/5-700-e1bd76.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The road through the vineyards.  You may notice that the rootstocks and vines look young.  That is because they are.  They will need some time to hit peak maturity, but another wine to think about it is that the wines will keep getting better each vintage in the meantime.  I’m excited.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Me with the Vines&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/6-800-ad8425.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/6-350-ad8425.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kenzo/6-450-ad8425.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kenzo/6-700-ad8425.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I definitely could have used some sunglasses out there.  But I was fine - the vineyards are my happy place.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Mapping it out&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/7-800-47d2a6.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/7-350-47d2a6.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kenzo/7-450-47d2a6.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kenzo/7-700-47d2a6.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Friends discussing the architecture of the property with our wine ambassador.  I love the forest backdrop to the vineyards.  It creates this nature screen for wildlife and also just makes for an incredible view.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kenzo started his enterprise in 2008 by selling his wines in Japan, which accounts for 80% of his current sales.  He exports most of the 5,000 cases Kenzo Estate produces to high-end Tokyo restaurants, wine-club members, and fancy hotel bars.  His master plan calls for an annual production of 16,000 cases and sales split 50-50 between the United States and Japan.  That aspirations are high, but so is his devotion, level of resources, and farmable land.  With the quality that Kenzo Estate is putting out, even with the younger age of their vines, I have no doubt that this goal is achieveable, so keep an eye out at you local high-end restaurants!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Up the Rows&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/8-800-4f2096.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/8-350-4f2096.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kenzo/8-450-4f2096.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kenzo/8-700-4f2096.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Looking up the rows of the vineyards.  Beautiful blue sky, forest in the backgroud, a hump to illustrate the terrain.  I really liked walking among the vines in this place.  I hope to visit again someday.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;To the wines!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/9-800-e708fd.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kenzo/9-350-e708fd.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kenzo/9-450-e708fd.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kenzo/9-700-e708fd.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The vines were literally next to our tasting table.  I hope this photograph illustrates how close the vines were to where we were sitting for our tasting.  It took a little time to kick off the dust from our shoes.  But once we did, we were ready to taste!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will let my pictures above do the talking about the tour and what visiting the estate was like.  For notes about the wines, see below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kenzoestate.com/wine-items/asatsuyu&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2018 Asatsuyu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A beautiful Sauvignon Blanc that spends 3 months in steel tank and 3 months in neutral oak.  Green and yellow fruit, but also some grass notes.  I like how this wine integrates the varietal character with the ripeness of the Napa Valley, rather than letting one dominate the other.  A terrific example of “sense of place” that pushed me to purchase a couple bottles to share with friends.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kenzoestate.com/wine-items/yui&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2018 Yui&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;32% Malbec with the rest Cabernet Franc and Cabernet Sauvignon.  Beautiful pink salmon color and wonderful texture and mouthfeel that has body, but doesn’t possess overly extracted flavors or aromas.  More grapefruit, peach, and strawberry flavors than other Roses I’ve had in the area.  This is both a smooth enjoyable wine and a serious Rose that is unlike any others in the region.  Really impressed by the flavor complexity, mouthfeel and great acidity.  One of my favorite roses that I’ve tasted, period.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kenzoestate.com/wine-items/rindo&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Rindo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($130)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Left bank Bordeaux Blend (46% Cabernet, 30%+ Merlot, with the rest Cabernet Franc) that is their flagship wine (highest volume produced).  Deep, rich, cooked red fruit with low pitched baking spices.  On the palate, this wine is softly textured and restrained in intensity.  This isn’t your big, heavy traditional left-bank wine as the palate is brighter than the nose (cranberry and strawberry dominate).  In its youth, this wine is soft enough to have alone, but presents enough intensity to pair with food.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kenzoestate.com/wine-items/murasaki&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Murasaki&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($290)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;83% Merlot-dominant blend.  Murasaki means purple in Japanese, in line with the color of the wine.  The nose has brighter red fruit than the Rindo with some black fruit as well, but the baking spice is more accentuated on the nose.  The palate has some electricity thanks to the acid and bright red fruit.  It’s still very soft in body, texture, tannin and it has a medium(+) finish with a little green fennel at the end adding to the complexity.  The finish grows on you as you have more of the wine, but this is both an engaging and relaxing wine at the same time.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kenzoestate.com/wine-items/ai&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Ai&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($280)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;90% Cabernet Sauvignon with 2% each of other Bordeaux varietals filling out the rest of the wine.  The nose on this wine is absolutely wild.  Earthier and spicier than the other reds, the nose on this wine is like minestrone soup - meat, tomato, green pepper, corn, etc.  On the palate, you still get those same notes, except a bit less in intensity with stewed red fruit integrated into the profile as well.  This has to be one of the more unique wines I have ever tasted.  I really hope to try this wine again to confirm that I and the bottle weren’t crazy that day…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kenzoestate.com/wine-items/muku&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2018 Muku&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($50 for 375ml)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This is a really great dessert wine.  95% Sauvignon Blanc and 5% Semillon, this wine has a fragrant nose of rich yellow fruit and stonefruit, and pronounced intensity (they even serve it in a flute draw the nose back).  On the palate, the acidity gradually builds, but doesn’t detract from the medium(+) body and the pronounced flavors that finish long.  The ripeness isn’t overdone like some dessert wines either – this is like drinking nectar from nature.  Very beautiful and pure…  I made sure to buy a few bottles to enjoy myself when Royal Tokaji would be too intense and Sauternes would be too muddled.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the prices of the bottles are intimidating, the price for the tasting is not.  If you can spare the time to do a 1000am tasting before driving back to Napa for lunch, I highly recommend you take the opportunity.  As the brand’s reputation grows, it will become more difficult to secure reservations as the facility isn’t structured to handle large numbers of guests.  And it’s not every day you get the opportunity to visit the Royal Palace of Oz in the real world, haha.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="wild-horse-valley" /><summary type="html">Imagine you own 3,800 acres of pristine land in wine country and had the resources to hire world-class experts in every aspect of the winemaking process. Now open your eyes. You aren’t standing in front of Screaming Eagle, Harlan, or any other big name in the cult world today. You are standing in front of Kenzo Estates. Established by Kenzo Tsujimoto in the mid-1990s, this estate is the equivalent of the Royal Palace of Oz in from a fantasy wine novel… You know I love it since I am posting nine pictures of our tour and tasting there! It is quite a drive outside the town of Napa (both to its gates and then from its gates to the winery itself), but well worth it. If the pictures aren’t enough to entice you, how about these names: Heidi Barrett, David Abreu, and Thomas Keller (assuming you get the food pair option). The style of wine is very different from its Napa brethren (much more elegant with herbal notes) but carries similar price tags to the best. But as 80% of the wine is exported and consumed in Japan, don’t expect much availability in the market.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/kenzo/3.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/kenzo/3.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bevan Cellars Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2020/01/04/bevan_cellars_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bevan Cellars Private Tasting" /><published>2020-01-04T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-04T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2020/01/04/bevan_cellars_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2020/01/04/bevan_cellars_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;You can read up on the background of Bevan Cellars and prior vintage tastings in in this article &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/09/07/bevan_cellars_private_tasting.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HERE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you may notice about this article is that I dropped the rating (compared to my last tasting here).  The change from 99 to 94 is primarily due to the number and quality of the wines used for this tasting were not up to the standard that was set during my previous visit.  We were also given the remnants of open bottles to taste, rather than being able to taste fresh bottles.  In a couple cases, the pour was smaller than other bottles because the remainder in the bottle wasn’t enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Tasting Room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/bevan-cellars-2/1-800-225a08.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/bevan-cellars-2/1-350-225a08.jpg 350w, /assets/images/bevan-cellars-2/1-450-225a08.jpg 450w, /assets/images/bevan-cellars-2/1-700-225a08.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The tasting room used at Brasswood Winery.  I really need to taste their wines too at some point, since I’ve been to the winery twice now…  I like the tasting bar setup and how you can see outside, but the people on the outside cannot see inside, haha.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the wines had their flavors in well-rounded form thanks to being opened the day before, I think they also lost some of their intensity and precision because of that.  I think my tasting group noticed that as well, since they ranked Bevan Cellars their least impressive wines of the day.  In all fairness, we did have a rockstar lineup that day, but I can empathize with their viewpoint on the wines.  It’s really too bad, because we hit it off with the co-owner of the winery (Victoria De Crescenzo) and she invited us to her new winery in Healdsburg, which we accepted and will be visiting on another trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Posing with the Fountain&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/bevan-cellars-2/2-800-4a70aa.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/bevan-cellars-2/2-350-4a70aa.jpg 350w, /assets/images/bevan-cellars-2/2-450-4a70aa.jpg 450w, /assets/images/bevan-cellars-2/2-700-4a70aa.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Two awesome people (Nick and Jess) posing next to the water fountain outside in the center area of the Brasswood patio.  Our tasting was at 1000, which explains the lack of other people at the winery.  When we left our tasting shortly after 1100, the patio was bustling with people.  Luckily, we had already taken the photos we wanted and were on to the next winery!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got word that the previous wine ambassador I had befriended and tasted with (Dan Walsh) had left his position at Bevan Cellars and is now the Hospitality Director at Knights Bridge Winery.  This was the reason Victoria was conducting our tasting.  If you plan to visit Bevan Cellars in the near future, you may want to confirm your tasting lineup before visiting to ensure they break out at least 3 of their Cabernets.  But if you do get a good lineup, you are in for a great tasting…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Entrance to the Winery&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/bevan-cellars-2/3-800-484685.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/bevan-cellars-2/3-350-484685.jpg 350w, /assets/images/bevan-cellars-2/3-450-484685.jpg 450w, /assets/images/bevan-cellars-2/3-700-484685.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A shot of my glass of Chardonnay, with the bottle I was about to try next (the Petaluma Gap Pinot Noir).  I’ve spoken with plenty of people that like the opulence and mouthfeel of Cabernet Sauvignon, but could do without the high tannin.  Both of the Bevan Pinots are definitely for Cabernet-lovers like them.  If you like opulence and richness in your wine, Bevan is difficult to beat in this category.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, Bevan Cellars are for drinkers that really like rich, round texture and mouthfeel to their wines. Bevan does not rack their wines and blends all of the barrels together in a tank, then redistributes to each barrel, ensuring integration of flavors and texture early on.  They ferment the free run and the press juice separately, then top off the free run juice barrels with the press juice during the fermentation to replace the angel’s share.  Some years, they may choose not to use the press juice at all.  They press the juice off the tank while it is still fermenting (anywhere from 8-10 brix of sugar left) and then barrel it while it is finishing the fermentation - most people wait until the fermentation finishes the sugar.  They use a pulsar in tank too to pump gas from the bottom and break up the cap instead of pump over or punch downs (same as Quiceda Creek which is another fantastic winery).  This really softens the tannins and allows them to create high tannin wines that have great mouthfeels in their youth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the wines!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bevancellars.com/store/detail?item=2017-chardonnay-ritchie-vineyard-russian-river-valley&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Ritchie Vineyard Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($70)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;From a vineyard that is shaped like an inverted cone (the volcano collapsed on itself).  The grape sizes are different in each cluster (like hens and chicks) as they produce this Chardonnay by combining a younger block and an older block.  100% new French oak and it is fairly obvious on the nose as there are notes of ripe yellow fruit, butter, cream, and vanilla.  They produce the wine in a reductive style without much SO2, which is only possible in a very clean facility.  The bottle should peak at 3 years of age.  Rich, beautiful, but not as big as the Hudson Ranch.  I think this is super enjoyable right now and doesn’t need the age if you don’t want to wait!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bevancellars.com/store/detail?item=2017-pinot-noir-petaluma-gap&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Petaluma Gap Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The blue and red fruit on the nose is so rich, integrated, and deep.  On the palate, the depth is just remarkable with pretty red (cranberry, cherry) and black fruit, baking spice that integrates with the alcohol and medium(+) body.  The tannins are medium(+), maybe high due to the amount of extraction, but are very fine grained.  The concentration is striking, but the ripeness on the palate is toned back and is also covered a bit by the tannin.  A very approachable, very rich Pinot that is for Cabernet-lovers, not for those that like Burgundian Pinots.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bevancellars.com/store/detail?item=2016-red-wine-ontogeny-napa-valley&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Ontogeny&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($95)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Deep red/blue fruit and crushed candied blackberry with tight integration on the nose.  On the palate, the acid is a little green and strong, the tannin is high but again fine-grained, and flavors are long and concentrated on the palate.  This wine is the “bane of Russell’s existence” as there is so much information to digest to formulate this wine.  This really shows his ability to blend and I hear the 2017 is even better with its large dose of Cabernet Franc (from the Sugarloaf blend that won’t be made that year since the 2017 Merlot was thrown out due to smoke taint).  This wine is the first thing he blends, then he makes the Sugarloaf, Tench, EE, etc.  That alone shows you how much this wine means to him.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bevancellars.com/store/detail?item=2016-bevan-cellars-tench-vineyard-cabernet-sauvignon-oakville&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Tench Vineyard Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($195)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The vineyard for this wine is RIGHT next to Screaming Eagle.  48 acres planted (55 acres total).  The owners and Bevan Cellars formed a 25 year partnership where they manage the vineyard and Russell makes wine from it.  They also sell some of the fruit to Thomas Rivers Brown and Phillipe Melka (two famous consulting winemakers), so you know it’s good fruit.  The pronounced nose is generous, rich, and lively with its red/blue/black fruit.  On the palate, it’s just as rich and generous but mainly red/black fruit with the acidity enhanced by the minerality of Petit Verdot splash in this wine.  The body is a little leaner than Kapcsandy, but make no mistake this wine is top quality.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bevancellars.com/store/detail?item=2015-cabernet-sauvignon-wildfoote-vixen-stags-leap-district&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Wildfoote Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($195)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pronounced red fruit with some candied red fruit in there as well.  It reminds me of a sleeping giant, like many amazing wines that are closed in their youth, but smash their way onto the scene after a few years in hibernation.  Though, as the most feminine of their Cabernets, it has an elegance, weight, and finish that is fierce that doesn’t rely on sheer intensity alone.  I have a couple bottles of the 2016 vintage of this Stags Leap and hope it unveils itself in a few years to be a worthy rival to my Shafer Hillside Selects and Cliff Lede Poetry.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you buy a bottle of their Cabernet Sauvignon, the tasting is free, which is why I highly recommend visiting if the bottle is not out of your price range.  Think of it like paying for a tasting and buying an extremely good bottle of Cabernet for $100.  Just be sure to confirm the wine lineup before visiting to confirm it has the varietals and values you want and you’ll come back a very happy person.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="st-helena" /><summary type="html">You can read up on the background of Bevan Cellars and prior vintage tastings in in this article HERE.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/bevan-cellars-2/1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/bevan-cellars-2/1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Italics Winegrowers Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/28/italics_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Italics Winegrowers Private Tasting" /><published>2019-12-28T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-28T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/28/italics_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/28/italics_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;I’m surprised there aren’t more movies/videos on wine in the world today.  Maybe people are too afraid to rock the market like the movie Sideways did to Merlot and Pinot Noir.  One of the more recent ones to hit Netflix is the special “Decanted”, which follows and interviews a few winemakers from Napa.  It starts with an interview of Heidi Barrett in her helicopter (awesome), but a majority of the movie revolves around the creation of a new winery that I hadn’t heard of before.  Since I had been to almost (if not) all the other places featured or discussed in the special, I decided I needed to make a reservation and visit this new winery.  I’m glad we did as we found some great wines and had a fun tasting experience in their wine cave!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Entrance to the Winery&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/italics/1-800-7e0e10.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/italics/1-350-7e0e10.jpg 350w, /assets/images/italics/1-450-7e0e10.jpg 450w, /assets/images/italics/1-700-7e0e10.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I forget whether or not the entrance is finished in the “Decanted” Netflix special or not - I remember it showing footage of the dug out cave.  But as you can see, Italics does not have a traditional wine tasting facility to handle guests like many others.  The facilities are underground and inside the same cave that they use for their wine tasting.  There are several wineries that do this (e.g. Pine Ridge), but it’s not the norm.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Italics wasn’t just a good tasting.  I think it may have been the most pleasant surprise of our last trip.  And we visited 14 wineries too!  Italics is nestled back in the north-western part of Coombsville, which is a newer AVA in the region that doesn’t have much press or attention yet (except maybe Paul Hobb’s Coombsville Cabernet and Favia which is owned by the Erickson power couple).  Because Coombsville sees cooler temperatures than the valley floor, the wines from the region are fresher, more red fruit than black, and also enables winemakers to make varietal wines that may not turn out as well elsewhere in the valley, such as Viognier and Petit Verdot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Taking in the View&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/italics/2-800-4512ef.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/italics/2-350-4512ef.jpg 350w, /assets/images/italics/2-450-4512ef.jpg 450w, /assets/images/italics/2-700-4512ef.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you made a 180 degree turn from the view in the first picture and walked toward the edge of the parking lot, this is the view you would see.  Italics overlooks not just some of its vines, but the vineyards of other wineries as well.  I’m not sure if it’s the best view in Coombsville, but it has to be at least Top 3.  Just captivating…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Italics is a little tricky to navigate to, but when you make your reservation, you should receive directions along with your email confirmation of the tasting.  Still, you will need to pay attention to the road signs as you get to the last parts of the directions.  Be sure to watch the Decanted Netflix special too since you’ll be able to see what the winery looks like in the video and then make sure the place you arrive at looks the same way.  It definitely helped me out.  After you arrive, you’ll be greeted by your wine ambassador with glasses of Chardonnay for your group.  They’ll explain the history and background of the winery as you enjoy your wine overlooking their vineyards and the road leading to the winery (it is a really nice view).  Afterwords, you’ll be led inside the wine cave for a tasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Our Wine Ambassador&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/italics/3-800-7fe659.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/italics/3-350-7fe659.jpg 350w, /assets/images/italics/3-450-7fe659.jpg 450w, /assets/images/italics/3-700-7fe659.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our Wine Ambassador giving us an explanation of the current state of the winery as well as a look into its history and how it came to be (ie. Filling in the details that the Netflix special didn’t have time to cover).  Still surprised about the Chinese Investment and Wine Cave Tasting Room stories.  Read the rest of the entry to get the details!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the interesting things I learned was a very interesting loophole in the tax law for California vineyards and wineries that Italics and some others (like Pine Ridge) take advantage of.  Now, I may not get this exactly right, so if you are a millionaire looking to start a winery in Napa, please consult someone in the area with more expertise before writing off your taxes.  But if your winemaking/wine sales facility occupies the same land as your grapes (ie. your vineyards grow over the top of your wine cave that you use for tastings and sales), the government can only tax you once for the land - it cannot tax you twice.  So it can tax you once for growing the grapes on the land, but can’t tax you again for the wine sales using the same exact piece of land.  Again, I’m not entirely sure that is an accurate explanation, but I learned enough to know that when I start my own winery one day, I should consult finance professionals that specialize in the wine business.  Because that is a lot of money we are talking about…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Our Tasting Room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/italics/4-800-0ffd00.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/italics/4-350-0ffd00.jpg 350w, /assets/images/italics/4-450-0ffd00.jpg 450w, /assets/images/italics/4-700-0ffd00.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;We signed up for the elevated tasting, so we had a private room in the wine cave for our tasting.  While you can still see the entrance, there’s little reason to look.  The spread that was lined up for us as well as the personalized tasting lists were more than enough to get our attention until the main stars (ie. the wines) showed up.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;No Cheating!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/italics/5-800-f31941.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/italics/5-350-f31941.jpg 350w, /assets/images/italics/5-450-f31941.jpg 450w, /assets/images/italics/5-700-f31941.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A closer look at the entrance to the private room and the spread once it was lined up.  The charcuterie was very good, but the cheeses stole the show.  They were so good that we inquired as to what types they were and where we might be able to buy some.  Finding the right food to pair with wine is important as it can really elevate the experience.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another interesting thing we learned about the winery is that it exists in its form today because of the escalated tensions between the USA and China these last few years.  Apparently, Italics was originally owned and built by a Chinese businessman.  However, he was unable to complete the winery before the tariffs between China and America were instantiated.  Because he was no longer able to infuse more money into the winery (Chinese governement limited investment in US) and everything was unfinished, he had to sell the unfinished winery to the current owners, who appeared on the Netflix special.  This part of the history isn’t really discussed, but it is really interesting how things work out someitimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Tasting Menu&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/italics/6-800-e477b7.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/italics/6-350-e477b7.jpg 350w, /assets/images/italics/6-450-e477b7.jpg 450w, /assets/images/italics/6-700-e477b7.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;We tried a few extra wines that were not on the tasting list because our group is awesome, haha.  Seriously, if you show passion for a wine/varietal or two and the wine ambassador can tell you are serious about purchasing them, they likely will find a way to get you a pour.  This doesn’t always work, but just remember that they want you to be happy and increase their sales.  NOTE: I didn’t write about the Chardonnay and Viognier below, even though we tried them, because I did not have my laptop with me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tasting in the cave was well executed.  The lighting was well done, the cheese and characuterie pairing was fantastic (we hunted down the cheeses afterwards), the tasting cards were personalized for the group, and we got to dip into a few bottles that were not on the tasting menu.  I’m sure the wine ambassador was happy they did that since one of those bottles (the Viognier) was our most purchased bottle!  Our other favorite bottle was the Petit Verdot - both are uncommon to see as varietal bottlings in the Napa area.  The 16 Appelations blend was also unusual - a blend of grapes from every AVA in the Napa region.  This was far from your traditional “Chardonnay, Cabernet, Cabernet Reserve, plus one other varietal” tasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Explaining the Wines&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/italics/7-800-d56ec5.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/italics/7-350-d56ec5.jpg 350w, /assets/images/italics/7-450-d56ec5.jpg 450w, /assets/images/italics/7-700-d56ec5.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Getting our explanation of the wines.  I must say that I was really impressed with the tasting.  The wines I liked the most were varietals I am not used to having from Napa - Petit Verdot and Viognier.  Be sure to stop in and give these wines try yourself.  The 16 Appelations wine is also a fun bottle - a blend using grapes from every AVA in the Napa Valley.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some introductions and side-conversation (our wine ambassador used to live in the DC area before leaving it all behind and coming to Napa), we jumped headfirst into the wines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.italicswinegrowers.com/product/2014-Sixteen-Appellations&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Sixteen Appellations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;More raisined character than the 2015 with deeper red rhubarb and spice notes. On the palate, the super smooth tannin and acid are drinking perfectly, yet would allow for aging. This is a people pleaser that will satisfy everyone.  It also has a deep, underlying layer that has great concentration and length. Vines started growing here in 1990 but with 3309C Bordeaux clones that came around 1970.  Meaning the vines will continue to improve with age and the quality of the wine will increase.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.italicswinegrowers.com/product/2015-Sixteen-Appellations&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Sixteen Appellations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It’s brighter and leaps from the glass because there is no Petit Verdot, letting the Cabernet Franc shine freely. Fresh/slightly perfumed red fruit and white spice on the nose.  More tannin and grip than the ‘14, but the complexity on the palate is intriguing. This wine also has the better aging potential.  Some stem tannin or a green fennel to it as well?  I can’t wait to see this wine in 5 years. Still cerebral now, but you may need to wait if you are looking for a people pleaser.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.italicswinegrowers.com/product/2015-Italics-Cabernet-Sauvignon&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Estate Coombsville&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($95)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I really enjoyed this wine and believe it’s a fantastic representation of the AVA.  The nose has depth and concentration with ripe and dark red fruit. The acid is remarkable for a Cabernet - so bright yet elegant.  The palate is very smooth with high ripe tannin, high acid, red fruit, some oak influence, and tertiary elements starting to develop.  I can imagine this wine being complex and still bright in 10 years.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 St. Helena One of 16&lt;/strong&gt; ($125)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is darker red and black fruit and deeper than the Coombsville Estate Cabernet, but also a bit more restrained (medium+ intensity) with cocoa and vanilla.  The palate is intense, richly concentrated, soft integrated tannin, and high acid.  This wine is drinking really well right now - seductively delicious that is impossible to say no to.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Petit Verdot Coombsville&lt;/strong&gt; ($115)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Restrained and powdery on the nose.  The palate has such soft, very high, but fine grained tannins, great concentration and a variety of flavors that leaves you in a bit of disbelief.  This wine is for those that like having wines that are different / off the beaten path.  This is going to age really well and become very interesting…  Still can’t believe a varietal Petit Verdot could turn out like this in Napa.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.italicswinegrowers.com/product/2016-Italics-Estate-Cabernet-Franc&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Estate Cabernet Franc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($125)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Beautiful pronounced perfume of crushed candied cherry and vanilla.  On the palate, the wine is lighter bodied (medium), but the flavors are still intensely pronounced and a little less ripe than the red fruit displayed on the nose.  Not a complex as I traditionally like my Cabernet Francs, but I could still drink an entire bottle myself.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend a visit to Italics, both for the wine and the story.  For my friends that came on the trip with me, they had a blast getting their families to watch Decanted over winter break and then talk about all the different places that were featured (including Italics) and how they were able to visit all of them.  It’s at least one step up from just showing pictures of the places, haha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even without that claim to fame, the wine is great, different, and the tasting experience is above par.  So what are you waiting for?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="coombsville" /><summary type="html">I’m surprised there aren’t more movies/videos on wine in the world today. Maybe people are too afraid to rock the market like the movie Sideways did to Merlot and Pinot Noir. One of the more recent ones to hit Netflix is the special “Decanted”, which follows and interviews a few winemakers from Napa. It starts with an interview of Heidi Barrett in her helicopter (awesome), but a majority of the movie revolves around the creation of a new winery that I hadn’t heard of before. Since I had been to almost (if not) all the other places featured or discussed in the special, I decided I needed to make a reservation and visit this new winery. I’m glad we did as we found some great wines and had a fun tasting experience in their wine cave!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/italics/4.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/italics/4.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Keplinger Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/21/keplinger_wines_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Keplinger Private Tasting" /><published>2019-12-21T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-21T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/21/keplinger_wines_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/21/keplinger_wines_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;While only 14% of the winemakers in Napa today are female, there are several that I follow who I consider to be in the upper-tier of best winemakers in the country, if not the world.  If you’ve read most of my articles, you’ll know that I have a love affair with the wines of Heidi Barrett.  The wines of Helen Turley (at Marcassin) and Celia Welch (at Scarecrow) are a little out of my price range currently (I want to try them so badly…), but the wines of Cathy Corison and Helen Keplinger are right up my alley.  While I’ve done articles on Heidi and Cathy, I haven’t been able to visit Helen yet.  I’ve had some of her personal label before and really like her wines at Carte Blanche.  She’s even worked with Heidi at Kenzo Estate in the past!  So I decided to take our group for a visit.  Luckily, she has a tasting room in downtown Napa and her husband, who is also the Wine Director for Carte Blanche, helped get us setup for a tasting with their wine ambassador.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;My Friends are Hilarious&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/keplinger/1-800-2e9406.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/keplinger/1-350-2e9406.jpg 350w, /assets/images/keplinger/1-450-2e9406.jpg 450w, /assets/images/keplinger/1-700-2e9406.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keplinger does tastings one group at a time.  That’s because their tasting room in downtime Napa only has one table in it for tastings.  It also turns out that the tasting room is just behind a pane of glass, so people on the streets of Napa can walk up to the building and stare at you while you are tasting.  I used that as an opportunity to get a picture before heading into the room, because the quarters are a little tight when inside.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt bad for the wine ambassador because I have poor planning skills.  We overstayed at Kapcsandy and our lunch took at while to be served, so we packed most of our sushi to go and still were running a few minutes late when we arrived.  The wine ambassador was very gracious - she allowed us to finish our lunch in their small tasting room while going into the history of Keplinger wines before we were ready to try the wines.  And I must say, I was surprised how well the Rhone varietal wines we tried followed the lunch sushi.  I’m not saying you need to do this too, but it was a really good experience.  We also purchased a good amount of wine, so I don’t feel as bad looking back on the situation now, haha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Our Tasting Group Crushed It&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/keplinger/2-800-05d50b.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/keplinger/2-350-05d50b.jpg 350w, /assets/images/keplinger/2-450-05d50b.jpg 450w, /assets/images/keplinger/2-700-05d50b.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A look at the tasting table after our group had finished with it.  As you can see, we take no prisoners and crushed all of the wines in our glasses.  It’s rare to taste so many varietals commonly associated with the Rhone Valley of France while in Napa.  We savored every sip from the glass and walked out with a bunch of bottles&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Helen graduated with her Masters from UC Davis in the 90s and has consulted for several wineries in the past, including the illustrious Bryant Family Winery, she is now concentrating solely on Keplinger Wines.  I’m really happy for her that her production, distribution, and sales are at the point where she can just concentrate on her personal project.  That may not be every winemaker’s dream (ask Paul Hobbs), but that certainly would be my dream.  And while you may find Syrah at some other wineries in Napa (e.g. Darioush), it is not common and the style which Helen uses is much more reminiscent of the Southern Rhone than any other vineyard.  It certainly brought back memories for me when I visited Chateauneuf-du-Pape on my way to Avignon.  Because that, I like to think of Helen’s wines as a blend of new world and old world style winemaking.  Helen also doesn’t filter her wines and predominantly uses neutral oak to not lose the fruit character of her wines (sounds familiar… haha).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Yes, that's our lunch&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/keplinger/3-800-96cbf3.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/keplinger/3-350-96cbf3.jpg 350w, /assets/images/keplinger/3-450-96cbf3.jpg 450w, /assets/images/keplinger/3-700-96cbf3.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This one picture really sums up our whirlwind 4-day trip to Napa.  Even though I planned for 2 hours at Kapcsandy, our tasting bled over making us late for lunch, which made us late for this tasting.  So this is us, eating our sushi out of to-go boxes while the food is still hot before our tasting.  Keplinger was very flexible and we made up time to enjoy a great tasting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you take a look on the Keplinger Wines website, they produce around 10 different bottlings.  Also, tasting reservations are by appointment only and they don’t have a set tasting menu that everyone does.  So when you reach out for a reservation via email, be sure to include any preferences you may have so that they can tailor the tasting to what you prefer.  Our group wanted to taste the Cabernet Sauvignon (since Helen made some famous ones in the past and we knew she was skilled) and we wanted to taste an older vintage in comparison to a younger vintage, so we could see how the wines would age.  If you would just like a greater breadth of the portfolio for your tasting, just let them know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Hands Shaking with Excitement&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/keplinger/4-800-a8425a.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/keplinger/4-350-a8425a.jpg 350w, /assets/images/keplinger/4-450-a8425a.jpg 450w, /assets/images/keplinger/4-700-a8425a.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you ask me, I’ll say that my hands were shaking with excitement, and that’s why this picture is blurry.  In actuality, I was probably just avoiding my glass in front of me and hadn’t lifted weights in a while.  We all enjoyed each of the wines, though the Basilisk Syrah (both the 2013 and 2016) were the ones we purchased the most of.  I got several bottles of the Oakville Ranch Cab too.  Because that just has to be good…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you understand what we asked for, here are the wines that we actually tasted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.carteblanchewine.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/2016-Carte-Blanche-Chardonnay-UV.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Carte Blanche Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($65)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wow.  Rich, ripe yellow fruit, cream, brioche, and yellow cake on the nose.  Medium(+) acid, medium(+) body that is as smooth and rich as the nose, not overly alcoholic, concentrated, and mellow but solid.  This wine is priced just under the heavyweights and I think that’s where the quality level is too.  A really nice Chardonnay that’s brighter than most, but all the power that you may want from Napa.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://keplingerwines.com/store/detail?item=2013-keplinger-caldera&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Caldera&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($90)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;60% Mourvèdre with the rest Grenache and Counois, just like the Southern Rhone.  From the Gold Butt vineyard on Apple Hill and dry farmed at 2900 feet.  The Grenache provides red fruit and blood orange on the nose, but the Mourvèdre and Counois combine to display iron, blood, animal fur, and savory notes.  On the palate, the fruit is much more restrained, leaving the tertiary character (iron/savory) to really come out.  This is the style of wine my brother and his wife love - I just wish I purchased a bottle…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://keplingerwines.com/store/detail?item=2013-keplinger-basilisk&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Basilisk&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($90)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;100% Grenache from the Greywacke vineyard in the Russian River Valley area.  The vineyard is in a warm, super steep pocket of land (it looks like a serpents tail).  This is a vibrant Grenache with pretty red fruit on the nose.  It’s surprising how structured this wine is, given how pretty the notes are - it could absolutely age for a longer period because of the medium(+) acid and tannin.  A beautiful single varietal expression that reminds you of the best bottling of a vineyard from Chateauneuf.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt; ($185)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Only 96 cases of this wine was produced from Oakville Ranch.  The nose is so beguiling and seductive with its crushed rose petals and the juicy, deep red fruit at medium(+) intensity.  On the palate, that same beauty just seems to continue on.  The tannin is very soft and the acidity provides freshness while the flavors open on the palate. This is drinking amazing but they only have 11 bottle left, so we couldn’t buy any…  However, I got a friend to go in with me on a 6-pack of the 2016.  So I am extremely excited to try those wines!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://keplingerwines.com/store/detail?item=2016-keplinger-basilisk&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Basilisk&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;We asked to try the Basilisk at a younger age because we were so enthralled by the 2013 and wanted to know how it would taste earlier on in its life.  100% Grenache like the 2013, this wine is an absolute giant.  It’s actually high tannin and acid (very uncommon for Grenache), but is balanced with the intensity of flavors the wine.  This needs a little time to age and integrate but wow, this wine is special.  I also bought a 6-pack of this.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should warn readers that when purchasing bottles, they will only sell the wines to you in 6-packs.  So when visiting Keplinger for a tasting, keep that in mind and try to bring along a group of people that will share a 6-pack purchase with you.  Luckily, I have a fantastic group of wine friends I could do that with, but I know this might be an issue for others, especially if your friends don’t spend similar amounts of money for their wines as you do.  But if this isn’t an issue for you and you love the wines of the Rhone Valley, then you must absolutely visit Keplinger wines and support one of the best female talents of Napa.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><summary type="html">While only 14% of the winemakers in Napa today are female, there are several that I follow who I consider to be in the upper-tier of best winemakers in the country, if not the world. If you’ve read most of my articles, you’ll know that I have a love affair with the wines of Heidi Barrett. The wines of Helen Turley (at Marcassin) and Celia Welch (at Scarecrow) are a little out of my price range currently (I want to try them so badly…), but the wines of Cathy Corison and Helen Keplinger are right up my alley. While I’ve done articles on Heidi and Cathy, I haven’t been able to visit Helen yet. I’ve had some of her personal label before and really like her wines at Carte Blanche. She’s even worked with Heidi at Kenzo Estate in the past! So I decided to take our group for a visit. Luckily, she has a tasting room in downtown Napa and her husband, who is also the Wine Director for Carte Blanche, helped get us setup for a tasting with their wine ambassador.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/keplinger/3.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/keplinger/3.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Mayacamas Wine Bar Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/14/mayacamas_wine_bar_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mayacamas Wine Bar Tasting" /><published>2019-12-14T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-14T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/14/mayacamas_wine_bar_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/14/mayacamas_wine_bar_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;When you think about the historical wineries of Napa, you may think of Beringer, Inglenook, and others.  Cult collectors will surely name Mayacamas near the top of their list.  LeBron James, the wine connoisseur of the NBA, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.espn.com/espn/feature/story/_/id/22358028/the-nba-obsession-wine&quot;&gt;took the Cleveland Cavaliers to Mayacamas&lt;/a&gt; during a bonding weekend to enjoy the wines and educational experience.  But you don’t need to make a reservation for $100pp and drive 30min from the town of Napa to enjoy the wines of Mayacamas.  Thanks to a recent trend of wineries in hard-to-commute locations, you can visit the newly-opened Mayacamas wine bar in downtown Napa for a tasting of their current releases ($35pp).  And if you’d like, you can include some back vintage Chardonnays and Cabernets as well ($60pp).  All while being able to walk to dinner afterwards.  Sounds too good to be true, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First established in 1889, Mayacamas has been producing great, ageworthy wines for over a century.  It’s amazing that they’ve continued to exist until today: reviving after Prohibition, surviving the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sfchronicle.com/wine/article/Mayacamas-winery-still-standing-tasting-room-12273311.php&quot;&gt;Nun’s Fire in October 2017&lt;/a&gt;, and enduring plenty of other obstacles, I’m sure…  Despite their history, cult status, and continued streak of red-hot wine critic scores and the collectability of their wines, their prices have stayed relatively modest compared to the high-end of the Napa market.  When I heard that they had opened their Napa wine bar location, I had to bring my tasting group.  And I must admit, telling the LeBron James story was amusing as the reactions I got were all of the map, haha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things I love about Mayacamas is that they have stayed true to their style through the different phases of the American palate.  There was a time when sweet, white Zinfandel was the most popular drink in the USA.  This “sweet” trend/preference started after Prohibition (I should make a podcast episode on the reason why…) and continued until a decade or two ago, when people’s preferences swung back to dry wines.  Even today, the American palate puts a premium on intense, dark, extracted, highly tannic wines.  I’m guilty of the same thing - just peek at my wine collection.  Luckily, there are wineries and winemakers that do not agree with the current Napa style and intentionally produce wines under 14% ABV with lighter extraction.  Dunn Vineyards on Howell Mountain may be one of the most famous examples, but Mayacamas has been keeping ABV and extraction down (and fresh acid up) for an even longer period of time.  These wines will likely taste nothing like the other wines you will have on your trip to Napa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to take a group of people (6 or more), I recommend making a reservation to guarantee the private table alcove in the back of the bar.  However, if it’s four or less people, feel free to do a walk-in tasting.  Just be prepared for it to be busy during the weekend.  If you do make a reservation though, it helps them to prepare any extra bottles they may want to pour for you and helps them ensure they have library vintages available (if you’d like to add them to your tasting, which I HIGHLY recommend).  When I am able to make it to their vineyard and winery on Mt. Veeder, I’ll write more about the history of the winery and the buildings in that article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the visit was after a long day of tasting and I forgot to take pictures…  Sorry.  But I did manage to take notes on the wines!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mayacamas.com/resources/pdfs/Mayacamas_2017_Chardonnay.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($50)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Grown at 1800 feet on Mt. Veeder where there is a lot of light for sugar development, but not a lot of heat for phenolic development.  The nose is medium(+) intensity with salinity and yellow fruit.  On the palate, the acid is high because they block MLF, but allow 7 months of lees aging.  Lots of vanilla as well that integrates with the yellow fruit, pastry, banana, and lychee character.  On the palate, you get green apple, yellow apple, peach, and apricot – just a lovely medley of fruit.  Mayacamas has a “golf of wine” approach: aim to use the least amount of strokes (winemaker interventions) as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2002 Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt; ($135)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The intensity on the nose is incredible with the nuttiness, marzipan, light butter, cream, brioche, and dried yellow fruit.  It was a bit surreal for everyone to taste this wine since the acidity was so bright and kept the wine very fresh.  This inspired our entire group to purchase young bottles and try to age them in order to try something like this again.  It’s crazy what mountain fruit can become…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2010 Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;They stopped making Pinot in 2013, so this was a real treat.  Red fruit and some funkiness on the nose that makes me think of northern burgundy.  Bright acid and solid fruit - this is like a Gevrey Chambertin Premier Cru, but with a little less black olive in the profile.  I’m interested to see how this wine will continue to age and the acid will allow that to happen gracefully.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mayacamas.com/resources/pdfs/Mayacamas_2014_Merlot.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Merlot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($60)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Lost my notes for this bottle, but I remember it being medium intensity, very bright, unripe red fruit (cranberry, strawberry), with acidity that rings inside your cheeks.  Not the “mellow” Merlot you may be used to.  Again, very different in style to traditional Merlots.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mayacamas.com/resources/pdfs/Mayacamas_2014_Cabernet_Sauvignon.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($125)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bright, ripe red fruit (pomegranate, cherry) on the nose.  The same flavors carry through on the palate and do not show secondary character (no new oak for the Cabernets).  The lighter body and alcohol feel great on the palate and the high acidity makes the wine come alive.  A very different style of Cabernet than what you normally find in Napa.  I would really like to enjoy this during the late spring and early summertime.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mayacamas.com/resources/pdfs/Mayacamas_2003_Cabernet_Sauvignon.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2003 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($250)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is very deep with medicinal red candy, earth and iron.  But there is a ray of brightness that also shines through.  On the palate, you get ripe pomegranate and sour cherry with soft, ripe medium(+) tannin and medium(+) acid.  This wine still has a massive amount of life in it and shows what a vibrant wine can be after 16 years of aging.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mayacamas.com/resources/pdfs/Mayacamas_2004_Cabernet_Sauvignon.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2004 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($250)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Whereas the 2003 showed its age openly, the 2004 shows lots of life and very little age on the nose.  On the palate, the acid is still high and present, the tannin is medium and soft, and the flavors are of medium intensity.  It’s funny - it feels like a baby Amarone because it’s a little raisined in character, but has acid, tannin, and lots of life to age gracefully.  I don’t know when it’ll find its peak, but 15 years isn’t it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tasting the aged Cabernets and especially the aged Chardonnay were rare treats that are hard to find at most wineries in Napa.  If you are in the town of Napa waiting for your dinner reservation, I highly recommend that you walk over to the Mayacamas tasting room and try some of these wines.  NOTE: They will not refund your tasting fee with purchases, so don’t feel compelled to buy a bottle if it doesn’t match your palate.  But you never know if you don’t try this style of wine.  So be adventurous and cheers to your future experience!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="mount-veeder" /><summary type="html">When you think about the historical wineries of Napa, you may think of Beringer, Inglenook, and others. Cult collectors will surely name Mayacamas near the top of their list. LeBron James, the wine connoisseur of the NBA, took the Cleveland Cavaliers to Mayacamas during a bonding weekend to enjoy the wines and educational experience. But you don’t need to make a reservation for $100pp and drive 30min from the town of Napa to enjoy the wines of Mayacamas. Thanks to a recent trend of wineries in hard-to-commute locations, you can visit the newly-opened Mayacamas wine bar in downtown Napa for a tasting of their current releases ($35pp). And if you’d like, you can include some back vintage Chardonnays and Cabernets as well ($60pp). All while being able to walk to dinner afterwards. Sounds too good to be true, right?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kapcsandy Private Tour and Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/07/kapcsandy_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kapcsandy Private Tour and Tasting" /><published>2019-12-07T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-07T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/07/kapcsandy_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/12/07/kapcsandy_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;You can read up on Kapcsandy’s history and prior vintage tastings in this article &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/07/21/kapcsandy_private_tasting.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HERE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  Although there is no membership club you can sign up for with Kapcsandy, they do have a benefit programs you can qualify for based on your purchases.  Since my tasting group loves and purchases as much Kapcsandy as I do, we try to make a trip once a year to taste the new vintage.  And I can’t say enough about Kapcsandy - it is my favorite winery experience in Napa, if you can afford it and meet the requirements for the tasting (see the previous article for details).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Louis in his happy place&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kapcsandy-2/1-800-c894f7.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kapcsandy-2/1-350-c894f7.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kapcsandy-2/1-450-c894f7.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kapcsandy-2/1-700-c894f7.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last time, we got a tour from the wine ambassador of Kapcsandy.  This trip, Louis Jr. himself gave us the repeat full tour (we had a couple new people on the trip with us).  This tasting almost didn’t happen - we booked our trip to Napa during the same week Louis Jr. and his father were supposed to go on a family vacation.  Luckily for us they happened to cancel/move the trip and Louis was happy to host us again.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;If only I could have a barrel&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kapcsandy-2/2-800-3270d6.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kapcsandy-2/2-350-3270d6.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kapcsandy-2/2-450-3270d6.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kapcsandy-2/2-700-3270d6.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The beautiful barrel room with the 2017 vintage in barrel now.  The barrels still look clean/crisp because they use new French Oak each year when producing their wines.  If only I could have a barrel…  What a happy man I would be.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the Grand Vins, we tasted the 2013 and 2014 vintages last year, so tasting the amazing 2015 and 2016 vintages were in order.  And my word, did we all enjoy the wines…  But we knew that coming in.  When the only female Chief Editor of a major wine magazine calls a wine “sex in a glass”, you know you need to try that wine.  I think I walked away with 6 bottles of the 2016 Grand Vin - it may be the greatest young wine I have ever tasted in my life.  And I have tried many 100pt wines before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Bottles and Bottles&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kapcsandy-2/3-800-d894e6.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kapcsandy-2/3-350-d894e6.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kapcsandy-2/3-450-d894e6.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kapcsandy-2/3-700-d894e6.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some of the bottles that we tasted this year.  It doesn’t include a picture of my favorite (the 2016 Grand Vin), but the ones in the picture were still really good bottles.  We happened to see Tony Arcudi on the property during the tasting too and were sure to say hello before diving in!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2016 also marked the first vintage for Tony Arcudi as the consulting winemaker for Kapcsandy.  Coincidence?  You can read up on my tasting of Tony Arcudi’s personal label and his background here &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/27/tony_arcudi_private_tasting.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HERE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  Suffice it to say that he is one of the newer winemakers in the Napa Valley that I am tracking closely and is someone that comes from the Heidi Barrett Winemaking tree (at Fantesca).  Also, I want to be him when I grow up.  So it wouldn’t be wrong to say that I had two reasons I needed to visit Kapcsandy this past year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Telling Stories&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kapcsandy-2/4-800-dd8ab7.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kapcsandy-2/4-350-dd8ab7.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kapcsandy-2/4-450-dd8ab7.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kapcsandy-2/4-700-dd8ab7.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;There’s my favorite bottle, just waiting to be poured into my empty glass after Louis Jr. finishes telling his story.  2016 was probably the best vintage in Napa this millenium after 2013.  But I think I prefer the 2016 over the 2013 Grand Vin.  I almost felt like I could drink any more wine after the tasting this morning.  But after the bland lunch, I was ready to get back into it…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I noted in my earlier article, the wines of Kapcsandy are not in the normal affordable price segment - their Estate Cuvee starts at ~$125 while their Grand Cru runs to $325/350.  But, if you need a special occasion wine or have done well enough in life that you can afford several bottles, you will be glad you did and all of your wine friends will be jealous of you as soon as they taste a glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also noticed that my pictures were a bit lacking in my previous post, so I made sure to take and include some new ones.  But without further ado, the 2015/2016 vintages!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kapcsandywines.com/wines/2018-Furmint&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2018 Furmint&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($40)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Medium(+) intensity of lemon, lime, white peach, apricot, medium(+) soft acidity, with great concentration, depth, and medium body.  Very fresh, but soft and serious.  Fruit driven, but not overly fruity.  Very balanced wine that drinks very easy but is very serious.  Also a unique varietal like Furmint in Napa?  Very cool.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kapcsandywines.com/wines/2016-Estate-Cuv-e-Cabernet-Sauvignon&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Estate Cuvee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($130)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Deep crushed purple flowers, crushed rocks, all of the red, blue, and black fruit, but very fresh and balanced with the ripeness.  The nose is both serious and fun.  The tannins are so fine and balances with the acid and alcohol.  A little less ripe than the Grand Vin, but drinks very nice immediately out of the bottle.  Very complex.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kapcsandywines.com/wines/2016-Rapszodia&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Rapszodia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($285)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pronounced, perfumed, ripe cranberry, cherry, plum, peach and other stonefruit.  The palate is a bit more restrained with the red/black fruit, but there is a minerality that stands out and is supported by a deep tertiary layer that is just starting to peek out.  Long finish that feels good with the acidity and has a bit of fleshiness.  This is a serious wine that is a very good varietal representation that isn’t too cloying.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kapcsandywines.com/wines/2015-Roberta-s-Reserve&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Roberta’s Reserve&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($300)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pronounced nose of crushed, candied cherry, cranberry, rose petals, violets, other floral notes, and deep fresh red plum that sets a strong and concentrated undertone.  Good structure with medium(+) powdery tannin and acid that still needs time to integrated into the medium body.  Very fresh, young and needs time to smooth and round out.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kapcsandywines.com/wines/2015-Cabernet-Sauvignon-Grand-Vin&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Grand Vin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($325)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The intensity on the nose is ridiculous…  All the floral aromas with red, blue, and black fruit with sweet spices and just a touch of vanilla from the wood.  The palate is all of those things with very good integration, weight, concentration, and length.  The wine feels weighty and concentrated all the way through the palate with a long finish.  The tannin is high, powdery, but it isn’t out of sync like the Roberta’s Reserve currently is.  A little more red fruit than there normally is in the Grand Vins, but a sensational wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kapcsandywines.com/wines/2016-Cabernet-Sauvignon-Grand-Vin&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Grand Vin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($325)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The fruit orients toward the blue and black end of the spectrum on the nose (whereas the 2015 leaned towards red fruit).  Crushed, candied blackberries, blueberries, rocks, and other bright black fruit.  Elegant, concentrated, weighty, balanced black/blue fruit that is intense but not overly opulent on the palate.  The tannin is even finer and more integrated in this wine.  If I thought the 2015 was a perfect 100 point wine, this wine must be 105 points.  I can’t say enough about this wine, so I am not going to even try.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2004 Grand Vin&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose on this wine is unbelievable.  I am literally speechless after smelling this wine.  All I can do is stare blankly with my mouth open at people.  15 years old and there is so much pronounced primary/secondary/tertiary aromas and flavors on the palate.  Dark Jolly Ranchers, mocha, vanilla, and a haunting floral perfume on the nose.  Also, this wine was made from 3 YEAR OLD VINES by Helen Turley at the very beginning of Kapcsandy.  The tannins are still rough and grittier on the finish and still feel high/present on the palate because of the types of barrels used back in the day.  But if this is any indication on how the 2015/2016 will age, oh my goodness!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kapcsandywines.com/wines/2013-Vino-del-Sol&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Vino Del Sol+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Aged 42 months in Cognac barrels and made from the vines at the edge of the vineyard from the amazing 2013 vintage.  The concentration, flavors, length, balance, body, viscosity, etc. is even greater than the Vino Del Sol that we had last time.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing this article, I’m realizing I wrote it more for me (so I could relive the experience) than for readers.  Sorry, not sorry.  You need to try the wines of Kapcsandy too.  That way, when you read this article, you can reminisce with me!  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="yountville" /><summary type="html">You can read up on Kapcsandy’s history and prior vintage tastings in this article HERE. Although there is no membership club you can sign up for with Kapcsandy, they do have a benefit programs you can qualify for based on your purchases. Since my tasting group loves and purchases as much Kapcsandy as I do, we try to make a trip once a year to taste the new vintage. And I can’t say enough about Kapcsandy - it is my favorite winery experience in Napa, if you can afford it and meet the requirements for the tasting (see the previous article for details).</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/kapcsandy-2/4.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/kapcsandy-2/4.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Kieu Hoang Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/30/kieu_hoang_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kieu Hoang Public Tasting" /><published>2019-11-30T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-30T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/30/kieu_hoang_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/30/kieu_hoang_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Kieu Hoang was a nice stop to unwind after a long day of tasting.  The views from the balcony are great, the wine and tasting fees are affordable, and the wines themselves are pleasant and easy to drink.  Though, if you asked me whether I would visit the winery again, the answer is likely “no”.  It wasn’t the most memorable experience, the wine ambassador wasn’t the most engaging, and the wines did not ship well (a large percentage of the bottles we shipped back to DC were faulty - not just one or two).  People have asked me why I wouldn’t give a winery a second chance.  My response is that there are ~425 wineries in Sonoma.  I will not likely be able to taste at all of them in my lifetime, so why bother trying the same one twice, especially if I didn’t like it the first time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Entrance&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kieu-hoang/1-800-b8f6f2.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kieu-hoang/1-350-b8f6f2.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kieu-hoang/1-450-b8f6f2.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kieu-hoang/1-700-b8f6f2.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The entrance to the winery looked innocuous.  The wine chandelier was a little awkward to walk around, but I liked the idea.  I would probably change the execution a little bit if I try something similar in the future.  Walk-in tastings are welcome and because they open until 5pm, it’s a nice way to finish a day of tasting as many places close at 4pm.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Tasting Room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kieu-hoang/2-800-f3cc60.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kieu-hoang/2-350-f3cc60.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kieu-hoang/2-450-f3cc60.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kieu-hoang/2-700-f3cc60.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The tasting room looks very different than the entrance.  If you make a reservation to have your tasting in this room (instead of reserving a table), then you can get your tasting fee reimbursed with purchases (if you reserve a table, you won’t be able to get your tasting fee back).  Luckily, we came at a date/time where the winery wasn’t busy, so they sat us at an outdoor table, but still reimbursed our fees with purchases.  This looks like a pretty good room to have your tasting in though if you had to.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kieu Hoang is named after the owner; a Vietnamese-born American billionaire who owned a large percentage of Shanghai RAAS Blood Products for a time.  Kieu Hoang first became interested in wine because of him background and passion regarding people’s well-being.  He, like so many others, discovered that wine was healthy in moderation: both physically and for the soul.  The winery was purchased from Michael Mondavi in 2014 and re-oriented toward the Chinese market.  Most of the wine produced is exported to China and sold through affiliated pharmacies.  Because of the market orientation of the winery and wines, I’m not sure if it’s geared toward the preferences of the American wine drinker and maybe everything is as the owner intended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The View from the Couches&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kieu-hoang/3-800-5ec3ba.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kieu-hoang/3-350-5ec3ba.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kieu-hoang/3-450-5ec3ba.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kieu-hoang/3-700-5ec3ba.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The view from the tables on the deck of the tasting facility.  I really like how they use plants at the ends of vine rows to help pest control.  And the contrast of the green of the vineyard versus the unplanted hillsides is really something.  I’m usually an aggressive taster and will move on to the next winery as fast as possible, but it was hard not to enjoy relaxing here…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Our Group&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kieu-hoang/4-800-efd5c9.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kieu-hoang/4-350-efd5c9.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kieu-hoang/4-450-efd5c9.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kieu-hoang/4-700-efd5c9.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our tasting group enjoying the wine and views from the couches.  Again, if you reserve one for your tasting, you won’t get your tasting fee back.   But if you go during the evening of a weekday like we did, you’ll likely not need the reservation to enjoy it.  Again, the views were quite something.  Just make sure that you bring sunglasses with you to California.  It seems like it’s always bright outside…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the winery isn’t very impressive on the outside, the inside is very different (and attractive).  The tasting room is tastefully designed and the patio area is my happy place.  The wines themselves were all smooth and drinking well, but nothing stuck out to me as individualistic or something that separates this winery from others.  The Emperor label was great, but not at the $175 price point (compared to other wines in the same category).  Also, you can get the bottle for ~$50 cheaper if you purchase it at “The Wine Room” in Palo Alto, though don’t ask me how or why the price is that different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Poor Attempt&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kieu-hoang/5-800-39f457.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/kieu-hoang/5-350-39f457.jpg 350w, /assets/images/kieu-hoang/5-450-39f457.jpg 450w, /assets/images/kieu-hoang/5-700-39f457.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;My poor attempt at a picture of my branded wine glass and the view in the background.  I think we spent at least an extra 30 minutes unwinding and enjoying the view outside.  Sonoma and Napa are really something…  Being the only group outside was nice too.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are my notes on the wines I tasted.  NOTE: One fun thing Kieu Hoang does is that they let you construct your own tasting.  They will give you the list of all the wines they offer and you are able to select 4 bottles to taste.  Tasting the Emporer label will set you back an additional $20 and is served separately via Coravin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kieuhoangwinery.com/product/Kieu-Hoang--Pinot-Noir-2016&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Pinot Noir (Los Carneros)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($45)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Ripe red fruit (cherry, strawberry) that has aged a bit with some sweet spice, depth and medium intensity.  On the palate, this wine shows that it’s robust and hearty with tertiary earthiness and medium body.  The wine shows concentration with its flavors of raspberry, cranberry, lighter cherry and some earth undertones starting to develop.  Balancing acidity and pretty smooth.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kieuhoangwinery.com/product/KIEU-HOANG--GREEN-LABEL&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2010 Green Label&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($50)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sangiovese and Cabernet Sauvignon blend from Stag’s Leap/Rutherford.  Bright red fruit (pomegranate, strawberry) on the nose.  On the palate, similar tasting notes with vanilla and some baking spice.  Medium(+) grippy tannins and medium(+) acid.  Thanks to the acid, tannins, and mellow red fruit flavors, the wine feels rustic like Italian wines, but with a slightly different tasting profile.  Reminiscent of a Super Tuscan.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kieuhoangwinery.com/product/Kieu-Hoang--Red-Label1&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Red Label&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($60)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;100% Cabernet Sauvignon from Calistoga/Yountville.  There is concentration and elegance in this wine at the same time.  Deep, warm red cherry and red currant emerge from the glass with medium(+) intensity.  On the palate, the same flavors are blended with vanilla and baking spice.  The palate feels just a little hollow on the midpalate and the medium(-) body clashes with the alcohol a little, but overall this is a very enjoyable Napa Cabernet that isn’t too serious.  At the price point, it’s a nice wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kieuhoangwinery.com/product/KIEU-HOANG--GOLD-LABEL&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Gold Label&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;85% Cabernet Sauvignon with Merlot and Syrah sourced Howell Mountain and St. Helena.  The color and the nose are noticeably deeper and darker than the Red Label.  Black/red currant and black/red candied cherry dominate the nose.  The medium body clashes with the high acid and tannin - it probably needs some time to integrate but the structure will definitely support that.  The midpalate is again a bit lacking, but this is still a nice wine that will please those looking to explore mountain AVA styled wines.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kieuhoangwinery.com/product/Emperor-2011&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2011 Emperor Label&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($175)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Spring Mountain Estate of Cabernet Sauvignon.  I’ve had it at wine bars for $130, so considering they must have marked it up, you can probably find it for ~$100 somewhere else through a distributor.  The nose on this is deep with red and black fruit at a coy, medium(+) intensity.  On the body, there are a lot of things happening.  The fruit components are the same as the Gold Label, but they seem rearranged and integrated in a much more pleasing manner with cocoa and salinity.  The acidity is not biting and the midpalate is filled out by this medium(+) body wine.  There’s even some toast, caramel, and brown sugar on the finish.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you decide to visit, I hope that your shipping experience is better with ours.  Instead of waiting until the fall/winter for the heat to die down, they tried shipping 2-day in the latter part of the summer, likely contributing to the wine faults.  If you decide to just visit, enjoy a tasting and the views, then likely you won’t be disappointed.  Cheers and happy hunting for good wine!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="carneros" /><summary type="html">Kieu Hoang was a nice stop to unwind after a long day of tasting. The views from the balcony are great, the wine and tasting fees are affordable, and the wines themselves are pleasant and easy to drink. Though, if you asked me whether I would visit the winery again, the answer is likely “no”. It wasn’t the most memorable experience, the wine ambassador wasn’t the most engaging, and the wines did not ship well (a large percentage of the bottles we shipped back to DC were faulty - not just one or two). People have asked me why I wouldn’t give a winery a second chance. My response is that there are ~425 wineries in Sonoma. I will not likely be able to taste at all of them in my lifetime, so why bother trying the same one twice, especially if I didn’t like it the first time?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/kieu-hoang/4.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/kieu-hoang/4.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Donum Estate Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/23/donum_estate_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Donum Estate Private Tasting" /><published>2019-11-23T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-23T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/23/donum_estate_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/23/donum_estate_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;When you visit wineries for tastings, you may notice that a majority have a theme to them, likely due to past influences, and the owners will try to enhance that theme by incorporating art and/or architectural design (e.g. Round Pond and Tuscany, Cliff Lede and Rock-and-Roll, etc.).  I have never before visited a winery like Donum Estate where the Art experience matches or even exceeds the tasting experience.  And while the Chardonnays and Pinot Noirs (especially the Pinot) are well-regarded and rated, I think a good portion of the tasting fee ($95) goes towards your museum ticket to tour the sculptor garden.  And even though the tasting fee may seem pricey, Donum is always fully booked at least a month ahead of time.  So if you decide that you want to visit, be sure to book your reservation far in advance as there’s no guarantee they will have space for your group!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Tasting Room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/donum-estate/1-800-9e0822.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/donum-estate/1-350-9e0822.jpg 350w, /assets/images/donum-estate/1-450-9e0822.jpg 450w, /assets/images/donum-estate/1-700-9e0822.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Once you get past the entrance corridor, this is the scene that you are greeted with.  I love the natural lighting and design of the space.  Although there is a tasting bar as you can see on the right, you’ll likely conduct your tasting in a private room if you come with a group of 4 or larger.  Just a beautiful space.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Wall of Pinot&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/donum-estate/2-800-6b4114.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/donum-estate/2-350-6b4114.jpg 350w, /assets/images/donum-estate/2-450-6b4114.jpg 450w, /assets/images/donum-estate/2-700-6b4114.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;On the left hand side of the room in the first picture, you’ll see the wall of Pinot above.  I’m not sure if it contains a bottle of every wine they’ve ever produced or what it is, but I sure hope all the bottles are empty (because they are not being stored in a dark space, haha).  I really liked a lot of the architectural things they’ve done with their space and this is just one more thing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When planning my first trip to Sonoma, I asked friends and colleagues in the wine world what were the must-see places.  Most came back with two names: Hudson and Donum.  While Hudson Ranch specializes in Chardonnay, Donum focuses on their small-but-quality Pinot Noir production.  And they are highly-regarded to the point where they are considered a Pinot powerhouse, similar to the status Kosta Browne and only a few others enjoy.  I personally prefer the Donum winemaker’s personal production (more on Auteur Wines in another article), but I understand where their reputation comes from, having tasted the wines.  I was very lucky to secure a reservation 2 months out from our trip to Sonoma as I found it’s difficult, even for members, to secure reservations as the estate is always busy thanks to its new construction and beautiful art collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Our Tasting Room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/donum-estate/3-800-0a1636.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/donum-estate/3-350-0a1636.jpg 350w, /assets/images/donum-estate/3-450-0a1636.jpg 450w, /assets/images/donum-estate/3-700-0a1636.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our tasting was conducted in private room within the winery.  What was really cool was the wall on the right side was retractable.  Because the weather was so pleasant, we opened it up and enjoyed the tasting with a breeze and the smell of nature.  If you love to take pictures, it’s a great opportunity to pop outside with a glass of wine in hand.  As you can see, our group was enjoying the Chardonnays, conversation, and didn’t need any Instagram shots.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One sentence on Donum’s website really resonates with me for how I feel about the winery: “The interplay between our wine production and art collection expresses beauty through a singular sense of place.”  It is true that Donum feels like a singular place disconnected from the rest of the world when you are enjoying the wine and touring the gardens.  It’s been a journey for them though and this sanctuary wasn’t built overnight.  Setting out to craft Burgundian Grand-Cru level Pinot Noirs in 2001, each year they’ve increased production (modestly), price, and the scores only seem to be going up.  With the profits, they’ve been able to acquire addition land in the Russian River and Anderson Valleys, producing more site-specific, singular Pinots from around Sonoma.  There is no machine use in any of their vineyards (all work done by hand) and they currently produce around 5000 cases annually, which is mostly consumed by their 1800 wine club members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;United Nations?&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/donum-estate/4-800-2e9969.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/donum-estate/4-350-2e9969.jpg 350w, /assets/images/donum-estate/4-450-2e9969.jpg 450w, /assets/images/donum-estate/4-700-2e9969.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;In addition to the great quality Pinot, the other reason to visit Donum is for their art collection onsite, whose value has to be at least $100 million dollars, likely much more.  In fact, I would be interested to know the distribution of people that visit for the wine versus the art.  In this picture, you can see the same iconic statue that exists at the United Nations.  I think this is 1 of 2 or 3 in existence.  Just unbelievable.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Zodiac&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/donum-estate/5-800-e539c3.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/donum-estate/5-350-e539c3.jpg 350w, /assets/images/donum-estate/5-450-e539c3.jpg 450w, /assets/images/donum-estate/5-700-e539c3.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Another famous art piece.  The different signs of the Zodiac, spread out in a circle according to the Chinese Calendar.  Just one of the pieces must have cost millions (I know it’s by a famous sculptor).  The entire set must have cost a fortune.  Unfortunately for me, they didn’t hand out a catalog to look at while taking the tour.  Though, I’m not sure if it would’ve been more impressive or a turn-off.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you drive up to the winery, please don’t crash your car while staring at the giant head sculpture near their gated entrance.  Once inside, you’ll be able to take in the architecture of the building before being greeted by your wine ambassador and led to your private tasting room.  Here, you will enjoy the wine, the conversation, the views, and even the weather as one of the walls is actually a giant sliding door that opens, allowing you to enjoy your tasting looking at the vineyards and feeling the cool Carneros breeze hit you while tasting the cool Chardonnays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Purple!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/donum-estate/6-800-be9ffe.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/donum-estate/6-350-be9ffe.jpg 350w, /assets/images/donum-estate/6-450-be9ffe.jpg 450w, /assets/images/donum-estate/6-700-be9ffe.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A picture of me with the lavender in the background.  One of the constant arguments I have with my friends is the color of my shirt: is it a shade of blue or a shade of purple.  I strongly argued the former, but looking at this picture (in literally “a new light”), I might have to agree with them now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Giant Spider Money&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/donum-estate/7-800-280c08.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/donum-estate/7-350-280c08.jpg 350w, /assets/images/donum-estate/7-450-280c08.jpg 450w, /assets/images/donum-estate/7-700-280c08.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes, that is a giant spider in the center of the room.  When the owners purchased the sculpture, they didn’t move the spider inside the building.  They found the optimal spot for the spider, then built the building around the sculpture.  I know…  Apparently, this is by a famous sculptor and goes for millions (sorry, I don’t know much about art).  It’s very cool to see upclose, but now my friends and I joke about having “giant spider money”.  A new internal joke added to our arsenal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you finish your tastings, making your purchases, and signing up for the wine club (if you so choose), you’ll be taken on a guided tour of the sculpture garden behind the winery.  It’s hard to do the experience justice with words, so I’ll let the pictures give you a sneak peek at what to expect, but if you are familiar with artists Ai Weiwei, Keith Haring, and Louise Bourgeois, let’s just say you’ll be very entertained.  Because the tour component is longer than at most wineries, expect to spend a full 2 hours at Donum Estate and make your schedule accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Rubber Palm Tree&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/donum-estate/8-800-b68877.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/donum-estate/8-350-b68877.jpg 350w, /assets/images/donum-estate/8-450-b68877.jpg 450w, /assets/images/donum-estate/8-700-b68877.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I didn’t realize it when we were parking, but walking back to our rental car after the tasting, I noticed that the tree we parked under wasn’t actually a tree.  It was a piece of art that was created using shredded tires.  Pretty life-like though, right?  Again, because of the amount of art and their fame, I felt a little out of place at the winery - others were enjoying the experience much more than I.  Just something to note when you visit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, to the part of the experience that I cared for the most!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Russian River Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt; ($60)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Chardonnays are tank fermented and then aged in 50% new French Oak.  No MLF that contributes to the lean, elegant, and crisp style.  Medium intensity on the nose of lemon, lime and other citrus fruits with some crisp yellow apple.  They want the acid to shine first and foremost, so no lees aging either.  High acid, medium body, with pronounced intensity of lemon, lime, citrus, yellow fruit, and some lighter stonefruit.  Very fruit driven but there is a zesty spiciness, white pepper, and a slight chalkiness on the finish.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedonumestate.com/assets/upload/files/2019/donum_16ChardonnayCarneros_techsheet.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Russian River Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($60)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Medium(+) intensity of cream, stonefruit (peach, apricot), and some yellow fruit (pear/apple) at the tail end.  On the palate, the medium(+) body has more weight than the 2017.  The fruit is riper and the acid is better integrated into the body and alcohol as well.  There is a little less concentration than traditional RRV Chardonnays, but it has a purity, brightness, elegance, and Chablis-like finish.  I don’t know how long this can age, but it will be great for at least 3-5 years.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedonumestate.com/assets/upload/files/2019/donum_16Carneros_techsheet.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Carneros Estate Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Medium(+) intensity aromas of cherry, cola, vanilla, cream, plum, ripe strawberry, and a light white pepper.  There is a complexity and depth to this Pinot, even though tertiary character doesn’t play a large part in the aromas.  Medium body, medium(+) but integrated acidity, high alcohol (but you can’t feel it until the finish), same flavors on the palate with medium(+) intensity.  The wine isn’t super fruity or candied but it is solid with great concentration and integration already.  The Carneros gets more gamey/meaty over time, so it’ll be exciting to age and see!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedonumestate.com/assets/upload/files/2019/donum_16RRValley_techsheet.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Russian River Estate Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is a bit brighter, fleshier (more plum) and higher pitched (the alcohol/acidity/white-pepper integrate to pique the nose more).  The palate is slightly higher intensity with the alcohol showing itself more.  The flavors don’t quite show the vanilla and cream of the Carneros and the body is less rounded.  This likely has the greater aging potential of the two, but is a bit more raw right now.  This wine becomes more floral with dried fruit character over time.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedonumestate.com/assets/upload/files/2019/donum_16AndersonValley_techsheet.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Anderson Valley Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Elegant, medium(+) intensity on the nose with softer red fruit, and some savoury aspects (but not too much).  The balance on the palate is impeccable.  There is a ton of personality from floral notes, cherry, cream, white spice that combines with the acidity.  It’s already showing some savory character in its youth and will only continue to develop.  It’s harder to find this bottle on the market (of the three Pinots) so I walked away with a couple bottles of this.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want something more than just wine and views of nature with your tasting, this is the place to visit.  Just be ready to devote the time and money that comes with the wine and the experience!  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="carneros" /><category term="sonoma" /><category term="sonoma-coast" /><summary type="html">When you visit wineries for tastings, you may notice that a majority have a theme to them, likely due to past influences, and the owners will try to enhance that theme by incorporating art and/or architectural design (e.g. Round Pond and Tuscany, Cliff Lede and Rock-and-Roll, etc.). I have never before visited a winery like Donum Estate where the Art experience matches or even exceeds the tasting experience. And while the Chardonnays and Pinot Noirs (especially the Pinot) are well-regarded and rated, I think a good portion of the tasting fee ($95) goes towards your museum ticket to tour the sculptor garden. And even though the tasting fee may seem pricey, Donum is always fully booked at least a month ahead of time. So if you decide that you want to visit, be sure to book your reservation far in advance as there’s no guarantee they will have space for your group!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/donum-estate/7.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/donum-estate/7.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hudson Ranch Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/16/hudson_ranch_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hudson Ranch Private Tasting" /><published>2019-11-16T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-16T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/16/hudson_ranch_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/16/hudson_ranch_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Hudson Ranch is truly a ranch in every sense of the word: the amount of land it encompasses (~2000 acres), the livestock and gardens they maintain on the property, the living quarters built for workers and their families, etc.  It’s truly a wonder.  Though with all the resources and new equipment they have, it’s baffling to me that they are aiming to produce no more than 8000 bottles of wine a year.  They do sell a good amount of fruit, but only to the best producers (e.g. Aubert, Kongsgaard, and Kistler).  And with the amount of wine they do produce, their quality and scores are off the charts; the 2016 Little Bit scored 99pts from The Wine Advocate, while the 2015 Old Master and the 2016 Ladybug both scored 97pts.  Regardless of the scores they received from others, tasting the wines myself, I’d put them in the Top 3 in the Napa area.  And at their price point, it’s the best QPR Chardonnay around.  A must visit if you are heading to Sonoma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Apertifs for the win&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/hudson-ranch/1-800-3101c6.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/hudson-ranch/1-350-3101c6.jpg 350w, /assets/images/hudson-ranch/1-450-3101c6.jpg 450w, /assets/images/hudson-ranch/1-700-3101c6.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Arriving at Hudson Ranch.  I’ve been to wineries where we were the only groups there before.  I’ve never been to a winery this large where that was the case.  We got a tour of the winery and gardens before the tasting.  But they wouldn’t make us do that without wine!  So we got small pours of the White Study to walk with.  Unfortunately, that meant I couldn’t take good notes of that wine while doing so.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Map of the Vineyards&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/hudson-ranch/2-800-4f7511.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/hudson-ranch/2-350-4f7511.jpg 350w, /assets/images/hudson-ranch/2-450-4f7511.jpg 450w, /assets/images/hudson-ranch/2-700-4f7511.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Talking through all of Hudson Ranch’s holdings.  They own A LOT of land in the area, but only a small percentage is planted.  And an even smaller percentage is used to produce wines under their label.  Most of the fruit is sold as they have a great reputation, on the level of Hyde Vineyards.  In fact, I might dare to say that they are to Chardonnay what Beckstoffer is to Cabernet.  Before you bite my head off, try their Little Bit!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found out about Hudson Ranch in a roundabout way.  Kongsgaard wines are one of the cult brands in Napa, up on Atlas Peak.  I’ve been on the waiting list forever for a chance to purchase their Chardonnay and try it out.  When I learned that Kongsgaard produced one of their Chardonnays from Hudson’s vineyards, that John Kongsgaard was also Hudson Ranch’s consulting winemaker, and that Hudson Ranch took tasting appointments, I had to sign up and make it the first stop of my day on the way to Sonoma.  Now that I am finally off the wait list at Kongsgaard, I still purchase more bottles of Hudson Ranch each vintage, even though they are a relatively unknown brand to collectors compared to collectors.  That’s how impressed I was with the Hudson Chardonnays.  I can’t speak highly enough of them and encourage those that are ABC drinkers (Anything but Chardonnay) to give these wines a shot.  They are delicious, but in a much different way than Hyde (HdV) or Burgundian Chardonnays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Vegetation&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/hudson-ranch/3-800-ba5feb.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/hudson-ranch/3-350-ba5feb.jpg 350w, /assets/images/hudson-ranch/3-450-ba5feb.jpg 450w, /assets/images/hudson-ranch/3-700-ba5feb.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The walk around their gardens was impressive.  Although it seems like their isn’t enough water to grow anything and the soil is of poor quality, all of the plants look like they’ve been supersized.  We inquired as to what fertilizers they were using.  They laughed and said they didn’t use anything unusual.  It just goes to show what is underneath the surface.  The scent intensity of the herbs in their gardens were ridiculous too…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Driving up from San Francisco, it’s relatively quick to get to Hudson Vineyards compared to the wineries in Napa as it is located straight west from the town of Napa, which itself is south of most wineries.  Hudson is also on the way to the town of Sonoma, so make it the first stop of your day (unless you want to instead go see the morning fogline from Hanzell at 10am which is also great).  The drive to the winery is like any other as you meander your way on a private road through the vineyard up to their facilities.  But once you make it to the facilities, be prepared for a different experience than most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Aloe Vera&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/hudson-ranch/4-800-daffe4.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/hudson-ranch/4-350-daffe4.jpg 350w, /assets/images/hudson-ranch/4-450-daffe4.jpg 450w, /assets/images/hudson-ranch/4-700-daffe4.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes, that is a single planting of Aloe Vera.  And my friend T$ is 5’10”.  That is the level of ridiculousness we saw while walking around the gardens.  That would make for a lot of skin salve to protect yourself from the sun beating down on you.  I forget if they were opening a restaurant or considering hiring a chef to make food pairings with the gardens, but they do already utilize the vegetables to make salads and use the olives to make olive oil (which they bottle and sell).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are, you will be greeted by your wine ambassador with a glass of the White Study, which is composed of varietals traditionally found in Italy, near the Alps in the Veneto region.  After looking at a map of the grounds and discussing the absurd amount of land that Lee Hudson owns in the area, you’ll get a tour of their garden and the facilities (see the pictures for some examples of the sights you’ll see).  The garden looks like it’s filled each day with fertilizer (but the soil itself looks poor) and the equipment and facilities look brand new.  You could definitely see them becoming a large producer of wines in the region, but that’s not their goal.  Lee Hudson is from Texas and has that ranch mentality at heart where he is happy tending to his land and vines, moreso than producing large volumes of wine and focusing on profit.  John Kongsgaard helped talk Lee into making some wine, but low volume and only the highest quality.  And everything about the newly-built facilities screams quality and a high price tag.  Luckily, the latter isn’t true of their wines…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Tasting Menu&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/hudson-ranch/5-800-f2b87f.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/hudson-ranch/5-350-f2b87f.jpg 350w, /assets/images/hudson-ranch/5-450-f2b87f.jpg 450w, /assets/images/hudson-ranch/5-700-f2b87f.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A shot of the four bottles that were planned for our tasting.  These are not the traditional bottles used for the tasting, but I emailed and specially requested to taste both the Little Bit and Ladybug Chardonnays, even though they were officially sold out.  I was also able to purchase several bottles, so it was really my lucky day…  That Little Bit still haunts me and I occasionally get urges to open one of my remaining bottles.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tasting the wines, it felt like we had stumbled upon a great secret of Sonoma.  Here is a ranch that grows tremendously high-quality grapes, selling the majority to producers that make $125-$150 bottles from those grapes, and yet they produce wines from some of their best for $85 a bottle.  And according to some critics, they can outscore those other bottles and be called out as the best white wines in Napa.  The only negative is that their low production means that you need to be aggressive in signing up for their mailing list and purchasing the bottles you want on release, because they do tend to sell out quickly on their website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read about each of the wines on this webpage: &lt;a href=&quot;https://hudsonranch.com/our-wines&quot;&gt;https://hudsonranch.com/our-wines&lt;/a&gt;.  And by clicking the picture of each wine (do not right-click and open in a new tab), you’ll be able to see the technical sheet for each wine.  Without further ado, these were the wines that we were able to taste.  Again, please note that these may note be the same bottles offered for your tasting.  We specially requested the Little Bit and Ladybug chardonnays be included even though they were sold out at the time.  So be sure to call and ask/negotiate what you’ll be able to sample before you arrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2018 White Study&lt;/strong&gt; ($36)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A Fruili (Northern Italy) blend of Ribolla Gialla, Friulano, and Chardonnay that displays yellow fruit and high, crisp acid.  Since we were walking and sipping this wine outdoors, I didn’t have a chance to take thorough tasting notes, but it’s an interesting blend uncommon in Napa/Sonoma that can serve well as an apertif before moving onto the heavier Chardonnay varietal wines.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Little Bit Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt; ($85)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Hugely pronounced stonefruit (peach/apricot), ripe yellow fruit (apples/pears), and tropical fruit (mango/melon) with butter, cream and vanilla.  Thanks to the cooler climate, this slow ripening Chardonnay has impressive acidity to balance the medium(+) body and opulent fruit/MLF flavors.  There is such aging potential here and it takes a little while to open up in its youth.  But this wine is an absolute powerhouse.  Even though our group normally prefers Burgundian-styled Chardonnays, this was our favorite over the Ladybug.  Elegant, but powerful and present.  I bought nearly a case of this wine it was so good…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Ladybug Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt; ($85)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is a quite a bit lighter in intensity with lighter yellow fruit, citrus, and crisp stonefruit.  The palate has medium(+) intensity with yellow fruit (apple/pear), cream, and butter.  The acidity presents itself more here (the vines were quite vigorous and they had to drop 30% of the fruit in green harvest) and there is some more lemon/lime type flavors rather than the riper development of the Little Bit.  That makes this wine lighter for easier drinking.  This wine likely will appeal to a broader category of wine drinkers than its sister.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Phoenix&lt;/strong&gt; ($65)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pronounced, perfumed aromas of deep-but-bright fruit-driven (but not candied) red fruit that includes cherry, plum, strawberry, kirsch, and black cherry in the medley.  Medium bodied, medium(+) ripe but grippy tannins.  Slighly less ripe red fruit on the palate with black pepper providing a strong undertone and toast, cedar, and other wood notes rounding out the palate.  This wine needs 5-10 years to smooth the tannins and fill out the body a bit.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Old Master&lt;/strong&gt; ($125)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Deeper nose with more black fruit than the Phoenix and some freshness reminiscent of fennel.  A Right-Bank Bordeaux blend mostly composed of Cabernet Franc and the rest Merlot.  Pronounced intensity on the palate with a perfume of fruit that hits you hard and fast.  On the mid-palate and finish, ripe but fresh red fruit with some hints of black fruit in the background.  The tannin is medium(+), ripe and grippy which pairs well with the fresh medium(+) acidity.  Again, this wine needs 5 years to round out the tannin and body, but has greater potential than the Phoenix because of the extra depth, concentration, and riper flavors to pair with future tertiary notes.  There is also some toast and baking spices that come out on the finish.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Syrah&lt;/strong&gt; ($90)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;After 6 years, the fruit is already tapered back in intensity on the nose with tertiary notes blended with the deep red fruit in medium(+) bright intensity.  The palate has red fruit, tertiary character, and is drinking very smoothly.  The wine was served perhaps a little warmer than it should have been, but I purchased some bottles of the 2016 to watch the evolution over time myself.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2018 Grenache Rose&lt;/strong&gt; ($32)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Whole cluster and fermented in a concrete egg.  I was surprised by the higher acidity and minerality to go with the fresh strawberry, stonefruit and salinity.  This wine is lighter in intensity and tasting it at the end (it was a spur-of-the-moment bottle) was probably a disservice to how it would be perceived as the first wine in the tasting.  Still, very different than other Roses in the area and our group bought some to enjoy later.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The $65 tasting fee, which won’t be reimbursed based on your purchases, can seem a bit steep compared to the other tasting fees in Sonoma and even Napa.  Though, if you can ensure your tasting lineup looks similar to the above, you won’t be disappointed.  In addition, being able to try possibly the best Chardonnays you will ever have is an opportunity that is hard to pass up.  It was for me when I was finalizing my reservation.  So the next time someone talks about Sonoma not being able to compare with Napa on quality, be sure to send them here and follow up for their reaction.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="carneros" /><summary type="html">Hudson Ranch is truly a ranch in every sense of the word: the amount of land it encompasses (~2000 acres), the livestock and gardens they maintain on the property, the living quarters built for workers and their families, etc. It’s truly a wonder. Though with all the resources and new equipment they have, it’s baffling to me that they are aiming to produce no more than 8000 bottles of wine a year. They do sell a good amount of fruit, but only to the best producers (e.g. Aubert, Kongsgaard, and Kistler). And with the amount of wine they do produce, their quality and scores are off the charts; the 2016 Little Bit scored 99pts from The Wine Advocate, while the 2015 Old Master and the 2016 Ladybug both scored 97pts. Regardless of the scores they received from others, tasting the wines myself, I’d put them in the Top 3 in the Napa area. And at their price point, it’s the best QPR Chardonnay around. A must visit if you are heading to Sonoma.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/hudson-ranch/5.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/hudson-ranch/5.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Venge Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/09/venge_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Venge Private Tasting" /><published>2019-11-09T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-09T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/09/venge_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/11/09/venge_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Nils Venge is a household name in the Napa Valley.  He’s consulted for wineries such as Groth, Saddleback, Carter Cellars, and was even the first American winemaker to receive a 100pt score for a wine (earning it for his 1985 Groth Reserve Cabernet Sauvignon from Robert Parker).  It turns out that the winemaking talent runs in the family, no doubt also the hard work and perseverance required to be a successful winemaker.  Venge Vineyards is run by Nil’s son, Kirk.  And while Kirk doesn’t quite have the same resume and reputation that his father does, I have no doubt that he will garner it in the future.  The quality of the wines in the tasting communicate that quite clearly.  So consider yourself lucky that you can enjoy his wines at affordable prices until that happens!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Smooth and Sleek&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/venge/1-800-40b43b.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/venge/1-350-40b43b.jpg 350w, /assets/images/venge/1-450-40b43b.jpg 450w, /assets/images/venge/1-700-40b43b.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Smooth and sleek tasting room.  The fact that it was empty says less about the popularity of the winery and more about it’s tasting policy (they can only have 20 people per day per their alcohol license) and the view outside - the group before and after us also took their tasting outside.  If it ever got cold enough to have the tasting indoors, I don’t think people would be disappointed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;View of the Vineyard&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/venge/2-800-6e6fe4.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/venge/2-350-6e6fe4.jpg 350w, /assets/images/venge/2-450-6e6fe4.jpg 450w, /assets/images/venge/2-700-6e6fe4.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The view from their patio.  Their tasting room is pretty far off the main road, so you won’t encounter many people coming and going from the winery.  This is important as I’m pretty sure the road you take is a one-lane road.  This makes for a very peaceful tasting where the only stimuli are the views, wine, and conversation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Venge Vineyards doesn’t have the advertising or fame of many other vineyards in Napa.  With their current alcohol license (they can only host a maxium of 20 people per day), I think that is fine.  In fact, I’m sure it helps them build deeper relationships with consumers since they do not have the production level or resources to sustain a large, rotating membership pool.  To get an tasting appointment with them, I had to submit a request and then take a phone call with one of their front-office folks to explain how I heard about them and where my interest came from.  Although the logistics were a little tougher than normal, it was well worth the effort.  I am used to paying much more for the quality of the wines and exclusivity of the experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Our Tasting Group&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/venge/3-800-ca8af7.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/venge/3-350-ca8af7.jpg 350w, /assets/images/venge/3-450-ca8af7.jpg 450w, /assets/images/venge/3-700-ca8af7.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wine is always better with friends.  I’m lucky to have a good group to call on when I’m on the west coast!  Most of us agreed on the quality/price of the tasting and purchased the two bottles necessary to get the free tasting fee.  The Silencieux was my favorite and I walked away with two bottles.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When navigating to the winery, rely on Google Maps to make the correct turn (even if the signage is absent/unclear) and just trust the one-lane road all the way back to the winery.  You’ll get to drive past the entire vineyard in front of the winery along the way.  When you arrive, you may see one other group wrapping up their tasting, but other than yourself and the wine ambassador on duty that day, you’ll have the place to yourself.  Once you get settled outside, prepare to try 5 really good wines.  And for purchasing as little as $70-$80 worth of wine (2 bottles), you’ll get your $45 tasting fee waived.  It’s a “can’t lose” situation here.  So just enjoy yourselves to the max.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Close look&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/venge/4-800-612b4c.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/venge/4-350-612b4c.jpg 350w, /assets/images/venge/4-450-612b4c.jpg 450w, /assets/images/venge/4-700-612b4c.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A close look at the first set of bottles that we tasted.  While none of the wines were showstopping to me, all of them were great quality and very much worth their modest (by Napa standards) prices.  If you like your wines smooth with moderate complexity and like to try a mix of blends and varietals, you’ll enjoy visiting Venge.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When people ask me what type of wine they should expect from Venge, I think it boils down to a few points for me.  It’s affordable (which is always important); the quality is not off-the-charts, but very solid; the blends are different and interesting; the grapes are sourced from different areas, giving you different styles of wine in each bottle; and the red wines have a prettiness and are made to be consumed immediately, though you can age them if you want to.  This is similar to the style that Mark Beringer that ushered in at Beringer as well.  I don’t know if this is the beginning of a trend among winemakers, but I personally approve and think that it will engage younger drinkers that don’t/can’t sustain a cellar to grab a perfectly aged bottle from each evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Posers&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/venge/5-800-2310d3.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images/venge/5-350-2310d3.jpg 350w, /assets/images/venge/5-450-2310d3.jpg 450w, /assets/images/venge/5-700-2310d3.jpg 700w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I learned some things about posing, Instagram, filters and other topics on this trip.  While I don’t quite have my pose down, others were more than happy to show me how it’s done.  Just imagine yourself in their shoes, drinking some darn good wine…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can I elaborate on the actual wines you can expect to taste at the winery?  Of course I can!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vengevineyards.com/Acquire/Vineyard-Designates/Juliana&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2018 Jewell Vineyard Sauvignon Blanc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($35)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fermented predominantly in stainless steel, but also some in concrete egg to round out the acidity a bit and add a bit of minerality.  It is still searing high, even when served warm and interacts with the citrus flavors well.  This is not your traditional Napa Valley ripe Sauvignon Blanc with melon/stonefruit flavors.  This wine indexes closer to the varietal qualities of the grape like New Zealand with its lemon, lime, and mineral character.  Very good.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vengevineyards.com/Acquire/Blended-Designates/Scouts-Honor&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Scout’s Honor (Red Blend)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($39)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A blend of Zinfandel, Charbono, Syrah, and Petite Sirah which is a highly unusual blend - I can’t think of another like it in the Napa Valley.  Deep red baked fruit with black pepper and baking spices on the nose.  Although it’s deep, it’s also bright which is very interesting.  Very light body, medium sweet tannins, with ripe, light, juicy red fruit on the palate with cinnamon, other baking spices, and hints of earth.  This is white-meat red wine and for those that like sweet Pinots.  This is their highest production wine and also the most likely to appear in stores and restaurant menus, so keep an eye out.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vengevineyards.com/Acquire/Vineyard-Designates/Signal-Fire&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Signal Fire Vineyard Zinfandel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($45)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The white and black pepper are on full display on the nose with bright red fruit.  Medium body, medium(+) acid, medium ripe tannin, with flavors of red plum, cooked cherry, vanilla, and sweet baking spices.  The wine has a long finish and leaves you with a little white spice.  A very nice rendition of Zinfandel that is both enjoyable and interesting.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vengevineyards.com/Acquire/Blended-Designates/Silencieux&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Silencieux Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($60)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pronounced nose of raspberry, strawberry, and blueberry jam with integrated alcohol that provides a minty note.  Very soft body with high, smooth tannin that needs a few more years for integration.  The body emulates the nose but the alcohol bites a bit with the baking spices on the finish.  The alcohol actually reaches the point where it burns the mouth a bit.  So decant this wine and serve it during cooler weather to maximize enjoyment.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Missouri Hopper Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt; ($125)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cabernet from one of the famed Beckstoffer sites.  There is a brightness with crushed candied cherry that eclipses the Silencieux.  The aromas and flavors are a bit deeper as well.  Again, the flavors are intense but balanced and feel lighter on the palate.  There is some tertiary complexity that is just starting to emerge and blend into the profile, but it’s too young to judge how it’ll integrate and play into the big picture.  You can taste the quality of the grapes though which is what you want in the best wines.  I don’t think this wine scored any major accolades, but wow it was really good to drink…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to support smaller wineries like Venge Vineyards that thrive on foot-traffic and inquisitive visitors to the Napa Valley since I hope to have one myself one day and because they introduce different styles, flavors, and techniques that continue to add diversity to the wine world.  If the wines seem like they match your palate, I highly recommend that you fill out the form on the winery’s website and plan a trip there.  It’s a low risk, high reward chance to take.  So do it!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="calistoga" /><summary type="html">Nils Venge is a household name in the Napa Valley. He’s consulted for wineries such as Groth, Saddleback, Carter Cellars, and was even the first American winemaker to receive a 100pt score for a wine (earning it for his 1985 Groth Reserve Cabernet Sauvignon from Robert Parker). It turns out that the winemaking talent runs in the family, no doubt also the hard work and perseverance required to be a successful winemaker. Venge Vineyards is run by Nil’s son, Kirk. And while Kirk doesn’t quite have the same resume and reputation that his father does, I have no doubt that he will garner it in the future. The quality of the wines in the tasting communicate that quite clearly. So consider yourself lucky that you can enjoy his wines at affordable prices until that happens!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/venge/1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/venge/1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>