<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-11-11T19:12:53+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Wines By Jeremy</title><subtitle>Wines by Jeremy offers an educative and enjoyable personalized wine experience. Located in the DC metro area, Wines by Jeremy provides a number of services including in-home exclusive tastings, highly curated event tastings, educational events, and wine cellar consulting.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Domaine Drouhin Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/10/domaine_drouhin_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Domaine Drouhin Public Tasting" /><published>2018-11-10T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/10/domaine_drouhin_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/10/domaine_drouhin_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Starting a new winery is hard.  There are so many things to do on the operations side such as clearing out the field, adjusting the soil, planting and caring for the vines, etc.  But just as important as making the product is building a brand and fostering a consumer base that will purchase your product.  This is even harder when you are entering an established market like Willamette Valley.  Thankfully for Domaine Drouhin, they had the branding piece covered already when they established the winery in 1987 and have continued to add to their reputation and legacy from Burgundy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/domaine-drouhin/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Doorway to France&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The doorway to Oregon soil and French Soul&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I visited their tasting room in Beaune, France (capital of the Burgundy area) last year and had a great time.  Their Clos de la Roche Grand Cru from a magnum was crazy good, but more on that in its own review, haha.  Needless to say, I left impressed with their wines.  So when I heard that they had a sister winery in Willamette, you know I had to visit.  I didn’t quite know what to expect as I was driving to the vineyard.  But when I saw the winery, I just shook my head and told myself “of course it would be like this”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/domaine-drouhin/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;A look to the vines&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Wine is only as good as the vines/soil they come from.  A view off the patio into some of their nearby vines&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Owner of 225 acres in the heart of the Dundee Hills area, the winery itself is surrounded by seemingly endless rows of vines with no other structures in sight besides the road you took.  Inside, the place was packed with people.  Many picking up their bottle allocations, many there to sample the wines, and more people than I expected just enjoying a day at the vineyard with their family.  The wines themselves were an interesting mix of new world power with old world flavor profiles and acidity.  This tasting was right after lunch, so my palate was a little off-center, but I would firmly place the tasting in the good category.  The tasting consisted of the following wines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.domainedrouhin.com/2016_Arthur_Chardonnay&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 DDO Chardonnay Arthur&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($35)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The white flowers, balanced body and solid acidity reminded me of Burgundian whites, but the fruit profile was definitely riper (e.g. stonefruit) than what you would find at their French estate.  Not too over-the-top, this is a nice Chardonnay to casually drink.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.domainedrouhin.com/2015_Roserock_Pinot_Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Roserock Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($35)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Roserock covered a higher range of flavors than I normally encounter at this price point in America, meaning you can drink this young or let it evolve a bit with a few years of aging.  Though I wouldn’t wait more than 3 or so.  Balanced with structure and levity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.domainedrouhin.com/2015_Pinot_Noir_Dundee_HIlls&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 DDO Pinot Noir Dundee Hills&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($45)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;There is a noticeable difference of structure and intensity between the Roserock and DDO Dundee Hills.  More red fruit here that is still young in the bottle, balanced, and a noticeably longer finish.  Some wood spice character is also starting to come out - you can age this for 5 years if you wanted.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.domainedrouhin.com/2015_Roserock_Zephirine&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Roserock Zephirine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($60)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;While the previous wines focused on the balance and fruit, the Zephirine takes you on a bit of a turn towards more complexity, particularly terroir driven notes (more vivid floral notes, lighter red fruit, but some wood spice and just a hint of cacao.  This can age even longer than the Dundee Hills (up to 8-10).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.domainedrouhin.com/2015_Laurene&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 DDO Pinot Noir Laurene&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($70)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This is where the complexity hits its peak in the tasting.  To the floral, light red fruit, and light spice character, now add riper fruit (e.g. Cherry) and more dusty character from the terroir.  This felt like the best expression of French and Oregon flavors and concepts of the bunch.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of their French roots, if I my schedule had allowed, I would’ve really liked to have done the “French Soul, Oregon Soil” tasting ($40) instead.  Conducted only at 10AM, they taste wines from their French and Oregon Estates to compare and contrast the Chardonnay and Pinot Noir flavors and characteristics.  Looking back at the tastings, I personally still prefer their French wine - there’s just a level of nuance they achieve with those wines that make them that much more cerebral and enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the $15 fee is very reasonable - The membership pricing and benefits (20% off or free shipping on 6 or more bottles for new memeber) are also pretty solid.  I did not bring back any bottles with me since there are so many good wineries in the area and my luggage was only so big.  However, I encourage you to put this place in your Top 5 of wineries to visit when in the region.  They definitely provide a unique perspective of the terroir in the area and the views are too good to ignore.  Just be prepared to wade through a mass of humanity on the weekend, haha.  Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="oregon" /><category term="willamette-valley" /><category term="dundee-hills" /><summary type="html">Starting a new winery is hard. There are so many things to do on the operations side such as clearing out the field, adjusting the soil, planting and caring for the vines, etc. But just as important as making the product is building a brand and fostering a consumer base that will purchase your product. This is even harder when you are entering an established market like Willamette Valley. Thankfully for Domaine Drouhin, they had the branding piece covered already when they established the winery in 1987 and have continued to add to their reputation and legacy from Burgundy.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/domaine-drouhin/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Argyle “Masters of Sparking” Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/03/argyle_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Argyle &quot;Masters of Sparking&quot; Private Tasting" /><published>2018-11-03T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-03T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/03/argyle_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/03/argyle_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;When people think of Oregon wine, they normal think of red still wine that ranges from the finesse of Burgundy Pinot Noir to the power of Russian River Valley Pinot Noir.  They don’t necessarily think of Sparkling wine, which is a key product of Pinot Noir all around the world, not just Champagne.  And when it comes to Oregon Sparkling Wine, there is no place more established than Argyle; heck, it’s even called out specifically in my Wine and Spirits Education Trust (WSET) Sparkling Wine Class!  The reputation alone is enough to entice even seasoned wine professionals, but when I discovered there was a special Sparkling tasting that also lets you to disgorge a bottle by hand, I made Argyle my first call during my itinerary construction.  I brought along my cousin and her husband for a full weekend of tastings in Willamette as their wedding gift, but this visit was definitely a gift to myself, haha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/argyle/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;beautiful tasting room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view of Argyle’s tasting room as your enter the winery.  Clean, rustic and just feels like a place I would want to drink good wine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winery itself is spacious and gorgeous, polished yet rustic, and has parts from its old barrel storage facility incorporated into different aspects of the new building.  Argyle’s tasting area could hold 100 people without issue and there’s even enough room for kids to run around outside.  Upon entering the facility, we were greeted with a sparkling Riesling that resembled Deutcher Sekt (German Sparkling Wine), but was a little drier and lower in acidity.  After we finished exploring the tasting area, the manager of the winery picked us up and took us to the back for a private tour and tasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/argyle/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;just nod&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Learning about the unique terroir of the Willamette Valley and why Pinot Noir is so delicious here.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We first walked through the back space of the storage area, where it was the coolest and darkest.  There we saw unspeakable things, like wines that had been aging on their lees for nearly 10 years, long enough to make even great Champagne Negociant houses blush; the prestige cuvees (best wines) of a Champagne Negociant (e.g. Moet Chandon) is normally aged on the lees for 5-7 years.  Although the bottles didn’t have the iconic black mold growing on the bottles (this was a warehouse, not an underground cave after all), you could tell that these were cared for greatly before they made it to the gyropalates for riddling and eventual disgorgement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One curious thing - there was a pupitre in a corner that someone had been manually riddling.  Turns out, this is for perspective customers of this tasting!  Our host grabbed a bottle and a cap-popping tool and we all headed outside.  The weekend was my cousin’s wedding present, so I let her husband do the disgorging – it was actually well-done…  Once we cleaned up and geeked out a bit more on the production process, it was time to head inside for the tasting.  Our lineup consisted of the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sparkling Wine - Zero Dosage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sparkling Wine - Dosage A&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sparkling Wine - Dosage B&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sparkling Wine - Dosage C&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sparkling Wine - Final Blend&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.argylewinery.com/2014SpiritHillBlancdeBlancs&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Spirit Hill Blanc de Blancs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($50)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This 100% Chardonnay sparkling wine from Eola-Amity Hills has great acidity, minerality, and enough creaminess to balance the lemon flavors.  This is a high energy sparkling that doesn’t seem tamed at all by the time it has spent in neutral oak barrels.  Worth getting at the membership price point.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.argylewinery.com/2014KnudsenVineyardBrut&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Knudsen Vineyard Brut&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($50)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Old vine plot, so you know it’s going to be complex.  Higher elevation helps to preserve the high acidity and lighter citrus flavors.  But this wine is about the barrel aging, which brought out some smoke character to pair with the red fruit (from the Pinot Noir) and citrus.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.argylewinery.com/product/2014-Argyle-Brut-Ros-&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Brut Rose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($50)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Another sparkling wine from the Eola-Amity Hills, so you know its going to have some degree of minerality.  But it’s the lighter, unripened red fruit that play the most prominent role here.  You can feel a little tannin, but this is a delicate wine for drinking chilled on a hot summer day.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.argylewinery.com/2007ExtendedTirageBrut&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2007 Extended Tirage Brut&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;My favorite from the tasting as discussed further below.  The bright acidity, creamy texture, ripe fruit (stonefruit, citrus), and aged character (toast, nuts) are all well integrated into this sparkling wine.  The complexity and character are off the charts and the novelty of its production is also fun to show off.  Buy and try this wine - you will not regret it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2007 Extended Tirage Brut Rose&lt;/strong&gt; ($120)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If this wine was priced similarly to the Extended Tirage Brut, I would have also picked up a bottle.  There is similar character to the Brut Rose and the Extended Tirage Brut with some additional fleshiness on the palate as well.  However it’s priced a little too high for my taste.  Definitely still worth tasting at the winery if you get the chance!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/argyle/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;delicious&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Argyle’s linup of Sparkling Wines&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, there are 10 wines in this tasting that are broken up into two sets, so come prepared.  The first set is purely for educational purposes - both for you and the winery.  You receive the same sparkling wine with four different dosage levels (including Zero Dosage) and are asked which is your preference.  After all, it’s important the winery produces wines that consumers like!  Next you can try to guess the dosage levels of each sparkling wine and then which of the four the Final Blend is.  Hint: It’s not the Zero Dosage wine.  But getting it right is actually much harder than you might think as they all feel pretty similar on the palate.  After discussing Argyle’s approach to sparkling wine, you’ll then taste the next set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/argyle/5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;captivated&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Discussing Argyle’s methodology when it comes to producing its Sparkling wines and how the dosage affects more than just taste.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of all these wines, I was absolutely captivated by the 10 Year Old Sparkling Wine, which I found out later was the highest rated of the group.  Unlike Champagne where fertilization of the soil every few years is necessary, Oregon has more fertile soil by comparison, which in turn leads to wines with greater flavors.  Normally, this is greatly desired, but in Sparkling wine, you want a more neutral base wine so that the flavors which result from the lees aging are more prominent (e.g. brioche, cream).  To deal with this stronger fruit flavor in the base wine, Argyle makes a wine that ages on the lees for ~10 years to increase the strength of those flavors.  What results is a strong, but subtle wine of great flavor that seemingly could explode at any moment, favoring one flavor (fruit) or the other (lees aging).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/argyle/6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;every day I'm hustling&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;You know why I am smiling right?  Guess who ranked all of the dosage levels correctly and then guessed the final blend?  This guy…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tasting itself though was a very educational experience.  Tasting four wines of the exact same blend, from the same vintage, and from the same vineyards, differing only in the dosage was a real treat.  So many things I learned about in class that are hard to taste/test practically became much more clear.  The room used for the tasting itself was a small room enclosed by glass, surrounded by racks holding some of their rarest/oldest wines.  I couldn’t quite convince the manager to open one of the bottles, but I was able to get a 6-pack of the 10 Year Old Sparkling Wine at a members discount with free shipping, which isn’t bad.  My cousin and her husband ended up becoming members on the winery, so I probably got the discount transitively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in Sparkling wines, but don’t want to pay for that ticket to Europe, Argyle is a great alternative that stands among the best in America.  And do take advantage of the food truck outside or eat lunch before your tasting appointment.  You will thank yourself, haha.  Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="oregon" /><category term="willamette-valley" /><category term="dundee-hills" /><summary type="html">When people think of Oregon wine, they normal think of red still wine that ranges from the finesse of Burgundy Pinot Noir to the power of Russian River Valley Pinot Noir. They don’t necessarily think of Sparkling wine, which is a key product of Pinot Noir all around the world, not just Champagne. And when it comes to Oregon Sparkling Wine, there is no place more established than Argyle; heck, it’s even called out specifically in my Wine and Spirits Education Trust (WSET) Sparkling Wine Class! The reputation alone is enough to entice even seasoned wine professionals, but when I discovered there was a special Sparkling tasting that also lets you to disgorge a bottle by hand, I made Argyle my first call during my itinerary construction. I brought along my cousin and her husband for a full weekend of tastings in Willamette as their wedding gift, but this visit was definitely a gift to myself, haha.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/argyle/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Archery Summit Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/27/archery_summit_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Archery Summit Public Tasting" /><published>2018-10-27T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-27T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/27/archery_summit_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/27/archery_summit_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;One of the toughest questions I’ve been asked about my Oregon travels is “where do I find good Pinot?”  The reason this is tough is because it’s everywhere, especially with Willamette Valley being a short 1-hour drive from Portland.  But when people ask me where the best Oregon Pinot Noir can be found, I normally respond with Archery Summit in my Top 3.  As its name implies, the winery can be found on the top of a hill not far from Domaine Drouhin, Sokol Blosser, and others.  I love their planting pattern too - you almost need to weave through the vines while driving up to the tasting room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tasting room itself is small, holding only ~20 people at a time, and their entrance to the storage level from the tasting room area is a small hidden entrance down some stairs.  All of this gives it a homely, friendly feel until you start the tasting.  Don’t let the modest exterior and tasting room fool you - Archery Summit is a powerhouse in Willamette that produces exceptional wines.  Although they are only ~25 years old, they own 6 vineyards encompassing 120 acres, have some of the oldest Pinot vines in the valley (40+ years), maintain the only cave system in Oregon, and consistently deliver high-scoring wines, especially for Pinot Noirs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Wine Advocate usually scores them in the 90-92 range while the Wine Enthusiast and Wine Spectator usually score them in the 93-95 range, meaning that the wines are less about power (Wine Advocate gives higher scores for that) and more about finesse and balance (what WE and WS hone in on more).  If you asked me to rate the wines, I would lean toward the 93-95 range.  Not because I prefer finesse over power, but because the purity of the wines cover any shortcomings with regards to power.  Another reason I scored the Archery Summit visit well is their tasting fee ($30) is very reasonable for the number of wines (and their quality) included in the tasting.  Certainly better than many places in Napa.  Without further ado, below are the wines on their tasting menu:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.archerysummit.com/product/2016-Pinot-Noir-Ros-&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Rose of Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($32)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Much more color in this rose than its counterparts from other vineyards, likely due to a longer maceration with the skins or there is more press juice that is used for the wine.  This additional richness is clear on the palate as well, but can be balanced by serving at a colder temperature if that’s your preference.  I found it hard to discern the flavors since the wine was very different than other Roses I’ve had and can’t put it better than the winery themselves: “aromas of fresh guava, starfruit, blood orange juice and rosewater. The palate is layered with notes of raspberry, grapefruit peel and juicy cranberry with lingering hints of delicate orange blossom.”&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.archerysummit.com/product/2016-Archer-s-Edge-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Archer’s Edge Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($90)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Probably the wine I am most conflicted about.  It has such great potential, but didn’t show as well today as I would’ve liked.  Candied red fruits and grapey in its flavor profile and lighter in body thanks to its younger vines.  I hope that some secondary flavors develop in the future, but right now, this is mainly a nice, easy-drinking wine.  I don’t quite get the cocoa powder as described in the winery’s tasting notes, but the basalt soil does begin to come into play.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.archerysummit.com/product/2015-Renegade-Ridge-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Renegade Ridge Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($90)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Renegade Ridge definitely had more intensity to it.  Lighter red/blue fruit notes and even some hints of citrus.  There is a slight dusty cocoa as well that adds a bit of complexity.  The tannins, acid, and body were all very balanced and in line with the intensity of the wine.  Definitely better to enjoy this wine while it’s younger rather than trying to age it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.archerysummit.com/product/2015-Arcus-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Arcus Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($125)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wonderful nose – a lot more floral than the other wines.  Violets and roses, with bright red juicy fruit on both the nose and palate, with just a touch of spice adding complexity.  Great mouthfeel with enough tannins to age it a bit as well.  The spice from the wood is bigger in this wine than the others, but it blends well with the dusty cocoa and red fruit.  The red fruit was a complex mix and very cerebral - I ended up buying a bottle of this wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.archerysummit.com/product/2015-Red-Hills-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Red Hills Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($100)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Blue fruit is more prominent than red fruit (but there is rose petal on the nose).  The most interesting flavors though were the black tea and the sweet spices in the wine.  Though, they certainly did not feel out of place or overly intense - everything was still smoothly integrated in the wine.  There are several Pinots in the area that fit into this flavor profile (black tea, sweet spice) - I find them fascinating, but it may not be to everyone else’s tastes.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.archerysummit.com/product/2015-Premier-Cuv-e-Pinot-Noir1111&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Premium Cuvee Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($54)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Probably the best quality-to-price ratio (QPR) wine from Archery Summit.  The ripeness and richness is more like the Arcus (though more black fruit here) than any of the other wines we tasted, making it very competitive with a lot of other similarly priced wines from the area.  I liked the coffee hints that were there with the dusty cocoa.  It’s very hard not to take two bottles of this over a bottle of one of the other bottles in the tasting lineup…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The membership benefits for Archery Summit are very appealing as well - in addition to significant discounts on the wines, you are invited to winery events and can bring guests with you multiple times for free tastings.  At their non-discounted prices, the cost is a little steep / reminds you of Russian River Valley (RRV), but are still worth it if you can afford it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theme of the wines from Archery Summit reminds me of Kapcsandy.  Not nearly the complexity or price, but that purity of fruit without much candied notes in the wine that is often seen elsewhere.  And although the tasting room is on the smaller side, they can still handle larger groups - a bachelorette party I sent there a couple of months ago had no problems and thoroughly enjoyed their visit.  I highly recommend visiting for a tasting before purchasing their single-vineyard wines, but if you find the 2015 Premium Cuvee at a wine store that you trust, buy a bottle and share with friends a taste of what Willamette has to offer.  Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="oregon" /><category term="willamette-valley" /><category term="dundee-hills" /><summary type="html">One of the toughest questions I’ve been asked about my Oregon travels is “where do I find good Pinot?” The reason this is tough is because it’s everywhere, especially with Willamette Valley being a short 1-hour drive from Portland. But when people ask me where the best Oregon Pinot Noir can be found, I normally respond with Archery Summit in my Top 3. As its name implies, the winery can be found on the top of a hill not far from Domaine Drouhin, Sokol Blosser, and others. I love their planting pattern too - you almost need to weave through the vines while driving up to the tasting room. The tasting room itself is small, holding only ~20 people at a time, and their entrance to the storage level from the tasting room area is a small hidden entrance down some stairs. All of this gives it a homely, friendly feel until you start the tasting. Don’t let the modest exterior and tasting room fool you - Archery Summit is a powerhouse in Willamette that produces exceptional wines. Although they are only ~25 years old, they own 6 vineyards encompassing 120 acres, have some of the oldest Pinot vines in the valley (40+ years), maintain the only cave system in Oregon, and consistently deliver high-scoring wines, especially for Pinot Noirs.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Au Sommet Private Tasting with Amuse Bouche and Coup de Foudre</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/20/au_sommet_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Au Sommet Private Tasting with Amuse Bouche and Coup de Foudre" /><published>2018-10-20T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-20T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/20/au_sommet_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/20/au_sommet_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; We also had wines from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amusebouchewine.com/index.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amuse Bouche&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coupdefoudrewine.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coup de Foudre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; while at Au Sommet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last winery for one of our weekend trips to Napa and it was indeed a good one.  Once you contact the winery to setup an appointment, you’ll have a couple of options for the tasting: the Amuse Bouche building in downtown Napa or the Au Sommet vineyard on Atlas Peak.  We obviously chose Atlas Peak, but if you are pressed for time (it is a 20min drive from Napa) or are a nervous driver (it’s unpaved roads only 1.5 lanes wide going up a mountain), I recommend you stay in Napa.  Once you do make it to the winery though, like so many others, the view is worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/au_sommet/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;It really was a great view&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Enjoying the view from of the vineyards from the tower on the property&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you drive up the mountain, you can still see the devastating effects of the forest fires from last year: some houses completely burnt down, others nearby amazingly unscathed, and blackened plots of land that are starting to show signs of life again.  I hope it wasn’t disrespectful, but multiple times, we slowed down to take pictures because of the impressions the sights left on us.  When we finally made it to the winery, we took a moment to reflect on the power and unpredictability of nature, then proceeded to listen to the story the wines had to tell us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/au_sommet/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;I told you it was a great view&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view of the vineyards from the watchtower as I am explaining something that is probably important&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/au_sommet/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;I may talk with my hands a bit&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view from the ground as I continue to explain something that is probably important&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tasting room itself is almost a side house/renovated shed next to the main property (I think the family lives in the main building).  There was a watchtower-like structure that we could climb to get a view of the valley below and also catch a glimpse of the helipad that Heidi Barrett uses to land her helicopter when she comes here.  Oh, did I mention that Heidi is a collaborator with some of the wines?  After some more pictures and breathing in the mountain air with no sounds but the birds chirping, we were ready to taste the wines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amusebouchewine.com/pret-a-boire/index.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Pret a Boire&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A rose composed of 66% Grenache and 33% Syrah.  This wine was a balancing act of ripeness, freshness, acidity and body.  There are few roses that command this type of price point, but I think it’s warranted.  It will assuredly test your palate’s limits when it comes to subtlety.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amusebouchewine.com/richard-g-peterson/richard-g-peterson-pinot-noir.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Richard Peterson Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;One of the most purchased wines by our group at this tasting.  The only varietal that Heidi Barrett does not work with is the one that her father (Richard Peterson) specializes in: Pinot Noir.  And this Pinot Noir is very good.  Stylistically, it reminds me of Burgundy Pinots that cost much more than this bottle.  This is a great price point too when you consider the other Pinot Noirs grown in the Russian River Valley nearby.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coupdefoudrewine.com/lesbouquinistes.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Les Bouquinistes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($58)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A complicated blend of Syrah, Merlot, Petit Verdot, Zinfandel.  This is definitely not a typical blend of varietals that you’ll see elsewhere.  And because of that, you know that I bought a few bottles…  The price point also makes it very attractive.  The wine is also quite enjoyable in addition to being cerebral - wine experts and newbies alike should be able to enjoy this one.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ausommetwine.com/au-sommet/index.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Au Sommet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($250)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The estate Cabernet Sauvignon produced from the vines on this Atlas Peak property.  Very drinkable now, as is Heidi’s style, but you can taste that there is potential for aging.  The wine is also reflective of the Atlas Peak terroir and how it differs from the other mountain AVAs around Napa Valley.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amusebouchewine.com/amuse-bouche/index.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Amuse Bouche&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($225)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This is the wine for which a reporter once asked where the grapes came from and Heidi responded she would have to kill him if she told him.  This Merlot from an undisclosed site was just something special; I couldn’t quite put my finger on what though in this right-bank Bordeaux style wine.  Both the Au Sommet and this were wonderful, but I walked away with bottles of this because of that extra something.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amusebouchewine.com/vin-perdu/index.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Vin Perdu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I also walked away with bottles of this.  The second label Merlot to the Amuse Bouche, this wine has great perfume, ripeness and balance on the palate.  If the Amuse Bouche is quality play, this is the value play as it will stand up nicely against other estates’ premium Merlot offering.  This is capable of some aging too, so don’t drink it all right away!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coupdefoudrewine.com/cabernetsauvignon.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Coup de Foudre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($95)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I love the concept of this bottle; you can peel off the label and then document where/when you had it and how it made you feel.  But that is window dressing as the wine is plenty good without the trick to the label.  It’s also priced at the right level - it should not be compared to the Au Sommet nor Amuse Bouche, but to other estates’ $100 Cabernet.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/au_sommet/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;So much good wine in the storage room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The wine tasting bar and inventory storage.  We did our tasting outside to enjoy the weather&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theme of the wines is similar to that of other Heidi Barrett style wines - great quality, fruit, midpalate, balance and the wines are approachable early in their development.  The breadth of varietals and AVAs used for these wines makes it a great visit too if you want something more than just the typical Chardonnay/Sauvignon Blanc + Cabernet Sauvignon offering.  The view, clean cool air and the drive up to Atlas Peak are nothing to scoff at either, even though it was hard to stomach at times.  If you have the time, consider making a reservation for a tasting!  Though, be warned, the wines are available for purchase only via 6-packs (or 3-packs in the case of the Au Sommet), so make sure you go as a group to the tasting!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="atlas-peak" /><summary type="html">NOTE: We also had wines from Amuse Bouche and Coup de Foudre while at Au Sommet.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/au_sommet/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Shafer Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/13/shafer_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shafer Private Tasting" /><published>2018-10-13T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-13T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/13/shafer_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/13/shafer_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s hard for me to recall another winery with as large a production, well-known reputation, but as reclusive from the public eye as Shafer.  But I totally understand and appreciate it - especially since we had the whole place to ourselves during our visit.  Although the estate appears large and the tasting room is gorgeous, there are actually not many people onsite.  Besides ourselves, the Shafer wine educator and the father/son proprietors, I don’t recall seeing anyone else on the property at the time.  There were three workers in the field grafting vines, but that’s it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people don’t make it past Stags Leap Cellars (which is also great) when they visit the Stags Leap AVA.  Besides driving past the 1976 Judgement of Paris winner for red wines, there are other obstacles to visiting Shafer, such as it’s only open on weekdays and by tasting appointment only.  But once you make it there, your realize the journey was well worth it…  Quite a number of fantastic wines to taste, fantastic views of the hillside from the winery with grapevines completely surrounding the building, and a great educational experience with a takeaway notebook detailing their wines, origins and process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/shafer/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;some good looking folks there&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Group picture along the gravel road in front of the winery&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harden yourselves before you partake in this tasting, because the pours are generous and these wines will both chip away and melt you at the same time.  The tasting menu looks like the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shafervineyards.com/wine/red-shoulder-ranch-chardonnay.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Red Shoulder Chardonnay (Carneros)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($52)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;14 mths in 75% new French Oak.  Ripe fruit that produces aromas from floral to tropical.  Similar to the Fantesca Chardonnay, this wine is produced without MLF, but undergoes lees aging for 14mths which gives it a great creamy mouthfeel, additional complexity, but without sacrificing the great acidity.  The natural yeast (from the grape skins) used for the fermentation also adds to the complexity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shafervineyards.com/wine/td9.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TD-9 (Cabernet Sauvignon, Merlot, Malbec)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($60)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;20 mths in 100% new French Oak.  Made with fruit from the southern Vaca Mountains.  This wine reminds me a bit of Bordeaux blends, though the use of Merlot and Malbec in greater proportions together is unusual.  Again, good fruit and phenolic development while maintaining good acidity and freshness thanks to the cooler southern climate.  A good intro to Shafer wines.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shafervineyards.com/wine/one-point-five.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One Point Five (Cabernet Sauvignon)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($95)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;20mths in 100% new French Oak.  After graduating from the TD-9, this should be your next wine.  Some Hillside Select fruit makes it into this bottle and you can tell it’s the beginning of something special.  It hints at some of the secondary/tertiary notes that the Hillside Select is famous for, without overwhelming the senses.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shafervineyards.com/wine/relentless.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relentless (Syrah and Petit Sirah)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($92)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;30 mths in new French Oak.  If you want a Syrah to blow you away, this is that wine.  Unctuous color and overwhelming body that is still smooth on the palate, with black fruit, smoke, tiny bit of meat juice, some cacao and a long finish.  Instead of Relentless, I might have named this wine Shameless, because that’s what it feels like.  Everyone in the group purchased at least one bottle of this wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shafervineyards.com/wine/hillside-select.php&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hillside Select (Cabernet Sauvignon)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($285)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;32 mths in new French Oak.  What a wine…  And with the pour you get, you could spend 20 minutes just with this wine alone.  Volcanic, poor nutrient soil leads half the normal amount of grapes per acre, leading to a wine that is as intense as the Relentless, but more complex flavors than the One Point Five, with great aging potential.  Bottle purchases are limited to two per person, so grab as many as you can and prepare for the long haul.  You’ll be glad you did!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The converation with our wine guide was also very enjoyable and unhurried - I think we spent 2.5 hours on the property.  And although their website limits the number of guests to 8, there is room enough at the table for more - it just gets roudier and harder to hear the wine guide, which is why they like to impose that limit.  Not surprisingly though, our group quieted down when we dug into the wines, as if the seriousness of the wines made us serious when tasting them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/shafer/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;rolling hills make some smooth wine&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Some of their softer rolling hills that make some softer, more rounded wines that can be drunk early&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On that note, I think Shafer’s theme is its commitment to producing serious wines that are cerebral, different (see: Relentless), powerful, and moving.  We lost track of time and were late to our next appointment because of how touching the wine and scenery were.  Wear some nice clothes, because you are going to want to take some pictures on this property.  If you are in the area on a weekday, I highly recommend trying to setup an appointment.  But be warned, Shafer usually books up 2-4 weeks out, especially Thurs, Fri, and Mon (for good reason).  And if you are thinking about becoming a collector or just laying down some bottles for a future special occasion, the Hillside Select is not a bad choice, especially since you’ll likely only be able to buy it when you visit the winery and it’s limited to 2 per person.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="stags-leap" /><summary type="html">It’s hard for me to recall another winery with as large a production, well-known reputation, but as reclusive from the public eye as Shafer. But I totally understand and appreciate it - especially since we had the whole place to ourselves during our visit. Although the estate appears large and the tasting room is gorgeous, there are actually not many people onsite. Besides ourselves, the Shafer wine educator and the father/son proprietors, I don’t recall seeing anyone else on the property at the time. There were three workers in the field grafting vines, but that’s it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/shafer/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Favia Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/06/favia_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Favia Private Tasting" /><published>2018-10-06T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-06T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/06/favia_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/10/06/favia_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Besides Bo and Heidi Barrett, there may not be another couple in the valley that has the background, experience and reputation of Annie and Andy Erickson.  Both have worked for their share of cult wineries that produced highly acclaimed wines wines and the price tags that go along with them.  But now, they work for themselves at their family winery in Coombsville.  The new up-and-coming AVA of the Napa Valley, Coombsville is still not on many people’s radar and wasn’t on mine until this visit.  Though, knowing Annie and Andy, I knew this was going to be an incredible experience.  I later found out that Coombsville winemakers like the make the anology of Coombsville is to Napa as Brooklyn is to NYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Located near Napa proper, it almost feels like you are driving to someone’s house when you arrive - no hills, no isolation, just another house with vineyards surrounding it.  The grapevines that you see are actually the property of another winery nearby.  The vines Favia owns are on sloped hills behind the house and across the way.  The tasting is very intimate, by appointment only and only available on weekdays.  And though there is no tasting fee, there is a minimum bottle purchase requirement that they ask you to meet while scheduling your appointment.  My group didn’t have a problem with this but I encourage you to find a bottle of their wines in a shop, try it out, then decide if the style and price range are to your liking before making your own appointment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andy and Annie were kind enough to take time from their busy workday to come speak with our group and opened themselves up to questions.  I acted like a schoolboy talking to his high school crush and locked up a bit, but did manage to ask for a picture with Andy.  Though I am kicking myself that I missed the opportunity to get one with Annie…  As for the wines, they were very different in style than the ones we had so far that weekend:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.faviawine.com/product/2015-Favia-Suize-Viognier-Amador-County?pageID=298543A9-B2DD-8454-41A3-067A79EC92F5&amp;amp;sortBy=DisplayOrder&amp;amp;maxRows=20&amp;amp;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Suize Viognier Amador County&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Viognier was one of the most complex I have ever had without being overly intense and gives the great estates of Condrieu a run for their money.  Needless to say, it surpasses Napa and Virginia Viogniers with ease.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.faviawine.com/product/2014-Favia-La-Magdalena-Red-Wine-Napa-Valley?pageID=298543A9-B2DD-8454-41A3-067A79EC92F5&amp;amp;sortBy=DisplayOrder&amp;amp;maxRows=20&amp;amp;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 La Magdelena&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($175)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A blend of Cabernet Sauvignon and Cabernet Franc.  The Magdelena is still very young and needs time to integrate and develop its identity.  Very fresh with high acidity, but already is showing some terroir character.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.faviawine.com/product/2014-Favia-Coombsville-Cabernet-Sauvignon-Napa-Valley?pageID=298543A9-B2DD-8454-41A3-067A79EC92F5&amp;amp;sortBy=DisplayOrder&amp;amp;maxRows=20&amp;amp;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Coombsville Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($175)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Again, very young and needs time before it can truly be enjoyed.  This wine does not try to pretend to be a valley wine - probably one of the most compelling examples of the Coombsville terroir that I have had (besides the Cerro Sur).  The wine felt a little closed, so I’d like to reserve full judgment until it’s near its optimal point.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.faviawine.com/product/2014-Favia-Cerro-Sur-Red-Wine-Napa-Valley?pageID=298543A9-B2DD-8454-41A3-067A79EC92F5&amp;amp;sortBy=DisplayOrder&amp;amp;maxRows=20&amp;amp;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Cerro Sur (Cabernet Franc)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($175)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The bottle I am most excited for - it also happens to be Andy and Annie’s favorite varietal (Cabernet Franc) and according to them, it’s also the bottle that best represents the vineyard’s sense of place.  100% Varietal Cabernet Franc is gaining traction in Napa and I think this bottle will help with that.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the wine tasting list was short, each bottle was a hit, which works for me!  If I had to qualify Favia with a theme, it would be doing what the terroir and grapes want with precise execution and not messing anything up from the human intervention perspective.  It’s a little ironic too, given the level of talent both Annie and Andy have to shape the wine to what will score well and what Napa consumers want.  But I really respect this approach and will continue to give this methodology careful consideration.  The red wines are all very young though and won’t hit their sweet spot for a while.  And it’s not because of the tannin like other Napa wine - it is more because the wines are in hiberation and are closed in their flavors.  Once they do come out of their shells though, they are going to be quite something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you are looking for a little zen behind your wine, consider making a reservation at Favia!  I highly recommend a morning reservation when your palate is fresh and isn’t weighed down by a heavy lunch, especially since the intensity of the wines aren’t as high as others in the valley.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="coombsville" /><summary type="html">Besides Bo and Heidi Barrett, there may not be another couple in the valley that has the background, experience and reputation of Annie and Andy Erickson. Both have worked for their share of cult wineries that produced highly acclaimed wines wines and the price tags that go along with them. But now, they work for themselves at their family winery in Coombsville. The new up-and-coming AVA of the Napa Valley, Coombsville is still not on many people’s radar and wasn’t on mine until this visit. Though, knowing Annie and Andy, I knew this was going to be an incredible experience. I later found out that Coombsville winemakers like the make the anology of Coombsville is to Napa as Brooklyn is to NYC.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hall Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/09/29/hall_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hall Public Tasting" /><published>2018-09-29T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-29T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/09/29/hall_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/09/29/hall_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in earlier articles, Napa can be both the ultimate educational experience and ultimate relaxation getaway - it all depends on what you are looking for.  Hall Winery is predominantly for those that are looking for the later, though you can definitely purchase 100 point quality wine there too if you wish.  For being both a purveyor of fine wine and tastings with a beautiful landscape, it’s surprisingly easy to find.  Right off the main highway (Route 29), the giant metal rabbit out in front of the winery is hard to miss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you park and approach this St. Helena winery, you’ll see both the beautiful, neo-architectural winery and the 1800s historic barn next to it.  Prepare yourself, because the inside is just another level compared to the exterior.  You may feel like you are entering a blend of a futuristic winery and art gallery.  If you are brave enough to take the Ultimate Cabernet Experience instead of the traditional tasting, you will be led to the barn where all of the technology and art fade away and all that is left is you and amazing wine.  If you are feeling especially fancy, you can arrange for a special personalized tasting at their Rutherford Estate as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hall/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Vineyards of Hall&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Vineyards at Hall after a spring rain in the morning&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally think that the public tasting is a great deal that exposes you to some really high quality wine without a $75+ tasting fee; two of the wines are over $130 each and scored 98 Points or better with The Wine Advocate.  So if powerful and ageable wines are your preference, you are going to be very happy here.  In addition, while you are tasting the wine in the main area, you’ll get a glimpse of the gorgeous view behind the winery.  But best of all, there is no reservation required for the regular tasting!  So if you happen to find yourself in Napa with no plan, feel free to drop by here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hall/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Makeup is hard&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Getting ready for my close up.  Or maybe caught getting caught off-guard during it?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the wines, the tasting list generally looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ultimate-cabernet-sauvignon-experience-150&quot;&gt;Ultimate Cabernet (Sauvignon) Experience ($150)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hallwines.com/shop-90-point-wines-14/2014-hall-kathryn-hall-cabernet-sauvignon.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Kathryn Hall&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($175)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hallwines.com/shop-90-point-wines-14/2014-hall-bergfeld-st-helena-cabernet-sauvignon.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Bergfeld&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($175)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Almost as important as the flavors of this wine (floral, fruitcake, sweet spice, tea, with bright red fruit) is the texture and weight on the palate.  How wine feels in your mouth is obviously important, but until you have a wine that blows you away, you won’t truly appreciate how important it is.  This wine was one of those that opened my eyes to what amazing texture and weight feel like.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Their choice of any two of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hallwines.com/shop-90-point-wines-14/2014-hall-mount-veeder-cabernet-sauvignon.html&quot;&gt;Mt. Veeder&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hallwines.com/winery-exclusive-wines/2014-hall-howell-mountain-cabernet-sauvignon.html&quot;&gt;Howell Mountain&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hallwines.com/winery-exclusive-wines/2014-hall-stags-leap-cabernet-sauvignon.html&quot;&gt;Stag’s Leap&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hallwines.com/winery-exclusive-wines/2015-hall-diamond-mountain-cabernet-sauvignon.html&quot;&gt;Diamond Mountain&lt;/a&gt; ($175 each)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Unfortunately, I misplaced my notes for the wines I tasted, but do remember that the tasting notes were pretty much what I got from the wines.  In addition to Beringer, Hall is another great location to taste single AVA Cabernets and observe the nuances.  The wines here are a bit riper and warmer in style, but are also more accessible earlier in their life.  They also score very well with Robert Parker on a consistent basis.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One of the 2014 Platinum Collection: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hallwines.com/2014-the-bishop&quot;&gt;Bishop&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hallwines.com/2014-rainin&quot;&gt;Rainin&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hallwines.com/2014-sacrashe&quot;&gt;Sacrashe&lt;/a&gt; ($325 each)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I’m partial to Howell Mountain wines (The Bishop) and Rainin gets near 100pt scores, so of course we got the Sacrashe at our tasting.  Although I was initially disappointed, that feeling disappeared as quickly as the wine from my glass.  Really great integration of black fruit, creme de cassis, cedar and terroir notes.  The difference between Hall’s Platinum Series and their Signature wines is an additional degree of purity and complexity.  That might sound like a contradiction on the surface, but once you taste these wines, it will make sense.  The price point and rarity make it hard to obtain bottles, so tasting at the winery is recommended.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;normal-tasting-40&quot;&gt;Normal Tasting ($40)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.waltwines.com/pinot-noir-14/2016-walt-clos-pepe-sta-rita-hills-pinot-noir.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 WALT Clos Pepe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Santa Rita Hills Pinot Noir.  As with all their wines, there’s an extra degree of ripeness and spice notes from the wood aging.  For this Pinot, red cherry and blackberries are the dominant fruits.  In the summertime, the wood spice and alcohol warmth might seem a bit much for a Pinot - this wine is at its best during the fall and winter when you don’t want to drink something as heavy as a Cabernet.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hallwines.com/shop-90-point-wines-14/2014-hall-terra-secca-cabernet-sauvignon.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Terra Secca&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($65)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;For Napa Cabernet, it’s hard to beat the quality-to-price ratio (QPR) of the Hall Terra Secca.  Really great concentration/intensity of black fruit with the hallmark spices that you expect from Hall.  A bit richer in body than the Hall Cabernet Sauvignon with an extra layer of flavor that’s earthy in character.  But make no mistake - this is a nicely balanced wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hallwines.com/winery-exclusive-wines/2014-hall-ellies-cabernet-sauvignon.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Ellie’s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Terra Secca utilizes earthiness to provide complexity, while Ellie’s leverages herbal flavors to provide complexity in the wine.  Again, because of the flavors of sage and clove, this wine is best enjoyed in the Fall time instead of reaching for some heavy mulled wine.  In addition, while the Terra Secca lies on the powerful side of balanced, Ellie’s lies on the elegant side of balanced.  Having both back-to-back provided a good contrast, though I would’ve served the Ellie’s first.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hallwines.com/shop-90-point-wines-14/2014-hall-jack-s-masterpiece-cabernet-sauvignon.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Jack’s Masterpiece&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($135)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Although the Kathryn Hall and Platinum series receive most of the marketing attention, Jack’s Masterpiece quietly outscores some of those wines year after year with a better price point.  The 2014 reminded me of Howell Mountain with its crushed rocks / graphite notes, but of course it had great rich fruit character as well, like black currant and cassis.  The body was lighter than I was expecting though - great finesse for those than prefer that style.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hallwines.com/shop-90-point-wines-14/2014-hall-kathryn-hall-cabernet-sauvignon.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Kathryn Hall&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($175)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If the Jack’s reminded me of Howell Mountain, then the Kathryn Hall reminded me of Rutherford.  This wine is richer and bigger in body, but the detail that grabbed me was a dustiness that you see a lot in Rutherford.  Still, this wine is so smooth and approachable, even in its youth, but it could definitely age 10-20 years effortlessly.  This is another one of those wines that you can enjoy without thinking, but then drink again while paying attention and point out 4-6 distinct flavors.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hall/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Picnic Time&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The outdoor picnic area available to winery members.  Who wouldn’t want to enjoy a bottle out here?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like the membership benefits of Hall.  There is a separate area where wine club members can conduct their tasting (much quieter) and you can purchase bottles, go outside, and enjoy the view of the mountains from a lawn chair.  They even have fire pits for the fall time!  The lawn in the back is well manicured as well, leaving you with the impression that you are a member of a high class country club.  Definitely one of the best views from the valley floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hall/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Napa scenery is always beautiful&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Another angle of the picnic area from nature’s point of view.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theme of the wines is similar to that of other Napa Valley wineries in that it promotes fruit, wood spice, and power.  However, I’ve found that most of Hall’s wines have much more rounded tannins than other places and are already approachable in their youth.  No need to wait any requisite amount of time to enjoy the wines.  Also, candied fruit and white flower are common notes that seem to come up for me throughout the tasting, though I didn’t explicitly call them out above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you follow critics like Robert Parker or Jeb Dunnuck, you’ll notice that some of the Hall wines score very highly on a consistent basis - the Kathryn Hall and Jack’s Masterpiece received potential 100 point scores for the 2015 vintage.  I’m not one to chase scores, but I can see why people do as these wines are great and ready now.  Visit Hall, buy a bottle or two and sit outside with a group of friends when you get the chance.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="st-helena" /><summary type="html">As I mentioned in earlier articles, Napa can be both the ultimate educational experience and ultimate relaxation getaway - it all depends on what you are looking for. Hall Winery is predominantly for those that are looking for the later, though you can definitely purchase 100 point quality wine there too if you wish. For being both a purveyor of fine wine and tastings with a beautiful landscape, it’s surprisingly easy to find. Right off the main highway (Route 29), the giant metal rabbit out in front of the winery is hard to miss.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/hall/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Gandona Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/09/22/gandona_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gandona Private Tasting" /><published>2018-09-22T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-22T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/09/22/gandona_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/09/22/gandona_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Many of the wineries I’ve talked about have very nice views from their property, but the one from Gandona is just surreal.  Located up on Pritchard Hill in the Vaca Mountains, Gandona sits at 1800 feet and overlooks Lake Hennessey.  It is also next to popular cult wineries such as Bryant Family, Colgin, and others that charge $500+ per bottle of wine.  With those kinds of neighbors, you’d get the feeling that this place would be unapproachable.  Not true at all - Gandona is another winery that invites you in with open arms, both with its open-air tasting room that takes full advantage of the view and their great host / wine ambassador.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gandona is reservation-only as there is only one visiting group allowed on the property at a time.  Besides our host, I don’t think we saw another human on the property, though the owners’ cat became quite close with one of us.  The level of attention you receive, the views and the wine all contribute to a first class experience at a first class winery.  The only thing I wish I could change is their production level.  Because they emphasize quality, the number of cases produced each year is quite low, meaning they consistently sell out of the wine they do produce.  Despite their limited production and availability, the prices are reasonable with respect to the quality.  The wine tasting menu is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Chardonnay was on point - the acidity wasn’t too sharp, the fruit was ripe but not overly so, and no overpowering notes from lees aging - just a solid, balanced Chardonnay.  We had it while walking outside to the vineyards, so I didn’t get a chance to write notes down at the time.  Biggest takeaway is that its on par with other Chardonnays in its price range and is geared towards balance rather than intensity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gandona.com/wine/#encosta&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2011 Encosta&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($90)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Their second-label Cabernet Sauvignon.  This is a good value buy if you are looking to try Cabernet from the Pritchard Hill region.  Solid, yet balanced and the volcanic character of Pritchard Hill is clear in the wine.  The 2011 in particular is drinking really well right now as its tannins are softer than other vintages.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Encosta&lt;/strong&gt; ($90)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Most of my group purchased the 2011 Encosta as it had a levity and elegance that were really enticing.  I purchased bottles of the 2014 because of its aging potential and what it can become.  Again, I think it has more personality than other Pritchard Hill Cabernets at the same price.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gandona.com/wine/#gandona&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Estate Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($225)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The more table-ready of the two Estate Cabernets we tasted.  This wine served as a good comparison point against the intensity of the 2011 and 2014 Encostas.  Somewhere in the middle, this is still not ready, or at least requires more decanting than we had, but only needs 3-5 more years.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Estate Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt; ($225)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This wine is huge - I can only imagine what the 2013 will be like when it rounds into form (I also grabbed some bottles of that).  A little tougher to feel the nuance right now, but it’ll be older than the ‘11/’12 when it hits its peak, meaning there should be a good chance to check out the wine when its tertiary notes are more apparent.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gandona.com/wine/#fraga&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Estate Port&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($85)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;100% Touriga Nacional.  The Estate Port is a way of paying homage to the ancestry of the owner (who is Portugese).  And while it is delicious, the price point is a little high for me as it is a 375ml bottle.  Though, I know what they are aiming for - a top flight Port that is grown in a great terroir and will compare to the best of the Douro.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a bit of a trek to the winery, so it would be smart to pair this tasting with other wineries in the region (e.g. Chappellet, David Arthur, etc.).  We were late to this tasting because we didn’t buffer enough time to get up the mountain.  Also, when you make the appointment, they will send you directions.  BE SURE YOU PRINT THEM OUT.  Google Maps may not take you to the correct location and when you reach the point where the instructions become important, there won’t be any cell phone service to look up those directions.  So be sure to plan ahead!  Also, be prepared to buy a bottle or two if you like the wines - the tasting was free, but don’t be that person who tries to take advantage of that fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if they wouldn’t let me do another tasting there, I would love to go back one day and spend an hour just looking out at Lake Hennessey from their perch - it was probably the best view we had all weekend.  This is also a great stop for those that want to learn more about the Pritchard Hill AVA, but don’t want to pay for Colgin/Bryant and want something a little more cultish/smaller than Chappellet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure to visit on a good weather day and enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="pritchard-hill" /><summary type="html">Many of the wineries I’ve talked about have very nice views from their property, but the one from Gandona is just surreal. Located up on Pritchard Hill in the Vaca Mountains, Gandona sits at 1800 feet and overlooks Lake Hennessey. It is also next to popular cult wineries such as Bryant Family, Colgin, and others that charge $500+ per bottle of wine. With those kinds of neighbors, you’d get the feeling that this place would be unapproachable. Not true at all - Gandona is another winery that invites you in with open arms, both with its open-air tasting room that takes full advantage of the view and their great host / wine ambassador.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Clark-Claudon Private Tour and Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/09/15/clark_claudon_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Clark-Claudon Private Tour and Tasting" /><published>2018-09-15T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-15T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/09/15/clark_claudon_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/09/15/clark_claudon_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Not all of the best places in Napa are the highly rated (e.g. Lokoya), produced by someone famous (e.g. Michel Rolland) or have a well-established pedigree (e.g. Opus One).  Some are family businesses that truly enjoy making good wine and sharing it with others.  Add unassuming, hard-to-find, and approachable to that mix, and you have Clark-Claudon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first had a bottle of Clark-Claudon Cabernet Sauvignon after seeing it ranked fairly high on Vivino.  As soon as I poured myself a glass, I was hooked.  Deep inky color, a very fresh nose of blue/black fruit, and crushed rocks in the palate profile - it was one of my first Cabernets where the fruit and secondary/tertiary flavor characteristics truly harmonized for me.  So I looked them up on the internet, sent an email requesting a tasting and set off on my journey to pay homage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/clark_claudon/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Not the best lighting...&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Taking a quick photo outside their Howell Mountain vineyard before we dig into the tasting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/clark_claudon/2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;He looks surprised&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Getting an explanation of the wine’s flavors.  The meat and cheese plate they served was a perfect match for the wine…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, I want to say that Laurie Claudon may be one of the nicest, most generous people in the Wine Industry.  During the course of our tasting, we spilled water and broke a glass, yet she was gracious through it all.  And the passion she showed for their wine was just truly inspiring.  There are two places that you can schedule the tasting: 1) at Alpha Omega as Clark Claudon borrows AO’s facilities for their wine production process; or 2) at their vineyard just behind Howell Mountain in the Pope Valley.  While the Alpha Omega campus is beautiful, Laurie recommends conducting the wine tasting at their vineyard and I wholeheartedly agree with that recommendation.  I will warn you - it’s a trek to get up there (25min from the Route 29), so try to schedule some other wine tastings up there as well or make it your first or last tasting of the day for travel time purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/clark_claudon/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;No sweat, we had wine with us&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Walking up into the vineyards after the tasting.  No one told us there would be exercise involved…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/clark_claudon/4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Such a good time&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Talking about the terroir’s effect on the wine.  That and the owner’s beekeeping and birdhouse hobby&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their tasting room on Howell Mountain is actually an small house that has been converted into a mini-office.  Your host (Laurie or her husband) will greet you with their Sauvignon Blanc and a as cheese/meat plate to enjoy with their red wines during the tasting.  If you ask nicely, you can even walk up into the vineyards with some wine and get a beautiful look at the rolling hills that produce these incredible wines.  Speaking of which, the tasting lineup looks like the following.  &lt;strong&gt;NOTE: When buying wines from Clark-Claudon, I highly recommend becoming a First-Flight member as you save 40% off the wine without necessarily needing an allocation.  The prices below reflect the “First-Flight” membership price.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.clarkclaudon.com/wines/All-Wines/2017-Wild-Iris-Sauvignon-Blanc&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Wild Iris (Sauvignon Blanc)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($34.58)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Another wonderful Sauvignon Blanc – I really like how this one turned out due to the Howell Mountain AVA terroir.  Fragrant, light bodied but good mouthfeel, a nice touch of minerality, and good fruit development that makes it to melon in terms of ripeness.  At the First-Flight price, this wine is a steal.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.clarkclaudon.com/wines/All-Wines/2013-Clark-Claudon-20-Year-Anniversary-Estate-Cabernet?svin=cur&amp;amp;sname=clark-claudon%2020%20year%20anniversary%20estate%20cabernet&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Estate Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($89.78)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;14.2% ABV, 2 years in 65% new French Oak.  It’s a coincidence that the 20th Anniversary Estate Cabernet is one of the best Napa vintages in recent memory.  But it’s not a coincidence that this bottle turned out well – the winemakers did a great job of harnessing and expressing the cacao and cigar box of the terroir, while balancing it with red/black fruit and maintaining the acidity structure.  One of the few 2013s you can drink now if you wanted, but I can feel the forest floor flavor will make an appearance in the future, adding to the complexity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.clarkclaudon.com/wines/All-Wines/2012-Clark-Claudon-Estate-Cabernet&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Estate Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($89.78)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;14.9% ABV, 2 years in 65% new French Oak.  It’s funny - what’s true of the valley floor is not nessarily true of the mountain AVAs.  That’s why they are their own AVAs!  Although 2013 was known as a tremendous vintage in Napa with great ripe fruit and 2012 less so, for Clark-Claudon, their 2012 Cab is actually higher in alcohol (so the fruit was more ripe) than the 2013!  And you can feel that in this wine.  Instead of cigar box, this has more tobacco leaf and other lighter tertiary flavors to go along with its core of black fruit.  Again, complex yet balanced.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.clarkclaudon.com/wines/All-Wines/2013-Eternity&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Eternity (Reserve Cabernet Sauvignon)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($133)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;15% ABV, 2 years in 70% new French Oak.  Take everything about the 2013 Estate Cab, add a bit more fruit development (cassis and fruitcake), more tertiary complexity (think cedar as well), a bigger/smoother body, and you get this wine.  Simply wonderful, but not quite ready to drink just yet because of the tannin structure.  Instead, wait a few years on this wine and pop open the 2011 instead as its in the perfect drinking window.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.clarkclaudon.com/wines/All-Wines/2011-Eternity&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2011 Eternity (Reserve Cabernet Sauvignon)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($133)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;There is a levity to this wine and a total integration / smoothing of the tannins that make it utterly irresistible right now.  2011 was a down year for the majority of Napa to be sure, but all of the great wineries were still able to produce great wines that year and this is a great example.  Again, what’s true of the valley floor may not be true of the Mountain AVAs!  Ready to drink now, it’s hard to keep your hands off it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, the Estate Cabernets are exactly as I remember them with the 2013 having a bit more strength and tannin.  The Eternities add layers of richness and depth to the attractive parts of the Estate Cabernet.  Many of the people who visited with me also chose the 2011 Eternity over the 2013 despite knowing the 2013 had a higher score and possible potential.  But when you drink something great, you want more of that greatness tomorrow, not 5-10 years from now.  That immediate gratification mentality may be indicative of my generation’s wine drinker, but I don’t think its wrong (see: Heidi Barrett’s style, Barolo production changes, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/clark_claudon/5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Why so serious&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It was going to be a great picture, but then someone had to crack a joke.  I couldn’t help myself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theme of Clark Claudon’s wines seems to be bringing out what the mountain fruit wants, rather than fitting it into the Napa Valley Wine Drinker’s box.  If you like big rich Cabernets that still feel fresh and reflect their terroir, then go buy this wine since there isn’t very much produced.  And make a visit to the winery if you can - this is a wonderful family running a small, but quality operation who enjoy having people over to share that joy with!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="howell-mountain" /><summary type="html">Not all of the best places in Napa are the highly rated (e.g. Lokoya), produced by someone famous (e.g. Michel Rolland) or have a well-established pedigree (e.g. Opus One). Some are family businesses that truly enjoy making good wine and sharing it with others. Add unassuming, hard-to-find, and approachable to that mix, and you have Clark-Claudon.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/clark_claudon/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Napa Wine Tour April 2018 Testimonial - Day One</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/09/12/napa_wine_tour_april_2018_testimonial_-_day_one.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Napa Wine Tour April 2018 Testimonial - Day One" /><published>2018-09-12T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-12T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/09/12/napa_wine_tour_april_2018_testimonial_-_day_one</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/09/12/napa_wine_tour_april_2018_testimonial_-_day_one.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note from Jeremy&lt;/strong&gt;: Perspective is everything, especially on a topic as vast as wine.  As I continue to refine the wine trip experiences, it’s important for me to reflect on what went well and what needs improvement.  Orri participated on the last trip I organized and graciously volunteered to share his perspective on the experience both for my and your benefit.  I have divided his submission into multiple posts (by day), but otherwise, they are unedited.  Without further ado, the first day as recounted by Orri!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wine is an incredibly personal experience.  For all that people like to follow trends and seek out expert ratings, at the end of the day, each palate is different - and each wine-drinking experience is different, as well.  Then, what to look for to have the best wine experience you can have?  You want a personable guide.  You want an expert who is capable and interested in exploring your palate with you, of opening the door for you to the dizzying universe of possibility.  Someone who is invested in your enjoyment.  Someone like Jeremy Myers, WSET Diploma candidate and CSW.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was Jeremy who first introduced me to my palate, over the course of several small-group wine tasting sessions.  Every week a different theme, a new country in this new world that was wine.  He spoke the local dialect of every hidden street market in every forgotten corner - every breathtaking vista opening up before me came with the knowledge that the next wine would take me to yet a different forest floor, yet another ancient cavern.  He didn’t just thrust a wine glass into my hand, he helped me understand what I liked - and more than that, he helped me understand why I liked what I liked.  And he did it all while putting me at ease.  He did it all while making me laugh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was my introduction to Jeremy - and if that’s your only exposure to his unique brand of wine tastings, then you should still count yourself fortunate.  Recently, however, I had the singular good fortune to accompany Jeremy and a group of close friends on a whirlwind tour of hand-picked exclusive wine tastings at some of the best winemakers in Napa.  While it was my first introduction to Napa Valley (and I may be ruined for future trips without Jeremy), the itinerary he constructed would accommodate the most veteran of vine-fellows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Barrel tasting after candlelit cave tasting; personal greetings from winemakers’ winemakers (the ones whose wine the vintners at V Sattui drink on special occasions - if they can get a hold of it; if they’ve even heard of them).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I’m getting ahead of myself.  Our four-day fourteen-winery winestravaganza began with the imposing facade of the Italian winemaker Del Dotto’s St. Helena Cellar setting.  We descended the steps outside, skirting a huge fountain (complete with a gargoyle built into the wall), and entered a sophisticated marble-lined hall with soaring ceilings, where we were immediately greeted with the sharpest Sauvignon Blanc I’ve ever had.  Ten minutes into the trip, and I was already having the time of my life.  We proceeded into a mosaic-walled cave dimly lit by chandeliers, full of wine barrels that stretched out into the distance, occasional tasting alcoves built into the wall at discreet distances.  We enjoyed a brief digression on the part of our host at Del Dotto to explain how barrel tastings work and introducing the concept of a wine thief.  While the cave barrel tasting began with a delicious 2017 Pinot Noir (Cinghiale Vineyard), a 2016 Sangiovese, and a 2016 Cabernet Franc; it was the second half of the cave tasting that really blew me away.  We had a wine made from the same varietal, of the same vintage, from three different vineyards, and aged 4 different ways.  Del Dotto is somewhat unique among Napa wineries in the level of depth they get into with aging their wine.  The default that many wineries wind up going with is Medium+ Toast, with the focus being rather on the country of origin for the wood.  Not so at Del Dotto.  They served us their 2016 Cabernet Sauvignon aged in French Oak and in American Oak (I preferred the American, personally, but there were plenty of takers for the French in our party), explaining about the difference between Missouri and Minnesota Oak, and showing us barrel after barrel, each with a different toast level.  Other highlights were the Vineyard 887 2016 Cab Sauv and the Rutherford Estate 2016 Cab Sauv.  We finally came up for air and enjoyed an off-tasting-menu 2016 Chardonnay from the bottle complete with a complementary charcuterie plate as we compiled our group order.  And then it was off to lunch to try to reset our palates before perhaps the most exclusive tasting of the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the wineries are where you go in Napa to experience wine, the restaurants at Napa might be best described as where you go to experience each other.  A brief recess from the master classes that make up the bulk of your time in the liquid playground that is Napa.  Time to soak up some of the wine and digest, both metaphorically and literally.  Discussing the highlights of the experience together, taking a moment to collect yourself before diving back in.  It’s not uncommon for newcomers to Napa to underestimate the difficulty in finding a place to eat, especially as party size creeps above 5 people to 6, to 8, or even to 10.  Luckily for us, this was not Jeremy’s first rodeo, and he secured us lunch reservations for all four days before we even began.  That first shared meal of the first day was at Brix, maybe 10 minutes up Saint Helena Highway from Del Dotto.  While the food was more than adequate, it was the company and the surroundings that really elevated the experience.  There’s something about driving on the valley floor past rows after rows of single- and double-cordon trained vines, with the occasional head-trained block of Zinfandel jumping out, that transports you away from your every day and allows you to inhabit the moment.  With good wine, good views, and good friends.  Or, as Michel Rolland (famed French winemaker) was quoted to us as saying - what keeps you coming back to Napa is “ze beatiful wine, ze beautiful land, and ze beautiful women”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To continue the theme of foreign and foreign-influenced producers for the first day, we entered the little-known but much-revered Kapcsandy winery.  This is not your every day Napa winery.  We’re talking about a father-and-son pair of vintners making 98+ point wines.  Helen Turley and Denis Malbec personally consulted with them to plant their vines and make their wines when they were getting started.  While appointments for tastings are always recommended in Napa, in the case of Kapcsandy, it’s 100% required.  They are only open a couple of days a week, and only have one official appointment time per day - at 10:30.  In our case, they made an exception and allowed us to join them at 1:30.  The reason for the exclusivity is that aside from the father and son (who will personally host your private tasting), the sum total number of employees is 7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to describe Kapcsandy?  Their ethos is very blue collar - the facility is a squat, unassuming building that houses a pristine, industrial factory floor, and they boast the longest grape sorting table in Napa, or possibly the world - but their prices are anything but.  The $150 tasting fee covers charcuterie, a warm welcome and spirited tour by one of the 7 employees, and a personally hosted private tasting with the son (with a brief hello from the father).  It was a little surreal being personally hosted by one of the geniuses responsible for such amazing wine - turns out he’s pretty amiable, as well - and it wouldn’t be the last time we enjoyed such an experience on the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tasting itself spanned from Furmint ($35), a Hungarian wine just about impossible to find in the US, to their silky, chocolatey, complex fruit bomb Vino Del Sol ($45) all the way up to their bread and butter of Roberta’s Reserve and Rapszodia at $285 and their $375 Grand Vin.  Between the 9 of us on that trip, we wound up buying 80-90% of their available stock on that Vino Del Sol.  This wasn’t the first time I’ve ever seen Jeremy speechless from wine, but Kapcsandy’s wines did so consistently and at length.  When Jeremy is speechless, what hope have newcomers like I of conveying the intricacies of a beautiful wine?  All I can say is that if you have the opportunity to experience Kapcsandy first-hand, you should shoot first and ask questions later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having experienced one extreme of focus on wine to the exclusion of ambience, it was time to go to a winery that struck a different balance.  We were headed to Darioush.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re not familiar with Darioush, picture a sprawling column-lined entryway up to a giant building of imported Iranian stone.  Picture elegant, bordering on opulent, decor.  Picture polish.  Picture a winery calculated to convey a very particular vision - that of Khaledi Darioush, an Iranian immigrant to the US whose life story has been packaged up for tourist consumption in winery form.  This is ambience as art form, with wine as the frame in which an experience is painted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the quality of the wine can’t stand up to the likes of Kapcsandy, they were more than serviceable.  And truthfully, we needed a bit of a transition from the heights of Kapcsandy back to Earth.  I personally walked away with a bottle of their 2016 Signature Chardonnay, which manages a perfect balance between the two extremes of butter and tart that California Chardonnays often choose, as well as one of their 2015 Duel - a delicious blend in which the spiciness of the Shiraz is well-balanced by a bigger Cabernet Sauvignon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well-lubricated, and fighting serious palate exhaustion, we made our way to our first dinner at Fume Bistro &amp;amp; Bar, a locals’ neighborhood restaurant not far from our hotel.  With relief, we relaxed around a table of good food, going over the thrills and spills of the day, before finally retiring to our hotel for an early night of rest to recover before a yet-bigger day on the morrow, silently giving thanks to the anonymous wise legislators who decided that Napa tastings shouldn’t start after 4:30 nor begin before 10.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Orri Ganel</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="testimonial" /><category term="tour" /><summary type="html">Note from Jeremy: Perspective is everything, especially on a topic as vast as wine. As I continue to refine the wine trip experiences, it’s important for me to reflect on what went well and what needs improvement. Orri participated on the last trip I organized and graciously volunteered to share his perspective on the experience both for my and your benefit. I have divided his submission into multiple posts (by day), but otherwise, they are unedited. Without further ado, the first day as recounted by Orri!</summary></entry></feed>