<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-01-07T19:24:36+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Wines By Jeremy</title><subtitle>Wines by Jeremy offers an educative and enjoyable personalized wine experience. Located in the DC metro area, Wines by Jeremy provides a number of services including in-home exclusive tastings, highly curated event tastings, educational events, and wine cellar consulting.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Plumpjack Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/01/05/plumpjack_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Plumpjack Public Tasting" /><published>2019-01-05T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-05T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/01/05/plumpjack_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/01/05/plumpjack_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Plumpjack is a great example of a newer winery on historic land that is producing fantastic wines.  Many people in my social wine circle have heard the name, but not much else other than it supposedly makes great wines.  As you may know by now, that is alone is enough to pique my curiosity and schedule a visit.  It turns out that the legend of Plumpjack started in 1992, when the Lt. Governor of California and a music composer got together and opened a wine store in San Francisco.  Those who are Shakespeare lovers may also get the reference to Sir John “Plumpjack” Falstaff from Henry V.  When someone told me the reference, I knew I was really going to like this place because the personality of Sir “Plumpjack” is pretty close to my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/1-1050by788-4fc29d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/1-700by525-4fc29d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/1-675by506-4fc29d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/1-450by338-4fc29d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/1-525by394-4fc29d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/1-350by263-4fc29d.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/1-350by263-4fc29d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;PJW!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The entrance to the Plumpjack Winery!  We arrived close to 10:15 and somehow were the first visitors to the winery that day.  I will admit, sometimes it’s nice to be the only people at a winery and hog all of the attention of the staff…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Plumpjack is relatively young, the history of the estate goes back to the 1880s when it was known as Mount Eden Winery (the brand got moved to what is now Conn Creek Winery to the north).  Some of the buildings onsite are from around that time, although the tasting room has definitely undergone interior renovations.  Plumpjack could have built its brand in that historic/established direction, but instead chose to build a laid-back, inviting image.  It even became one of the first luxury-priced wineries to bottle its wine with screwcaps to combat the growing problem of cork taint at the time.  Combined with the wide appeal of its wine and the higher production volume today, Plumpjack has grown into a powerhouse that appears in many homes and high-end restaurants.  Its 2013 and 2016 Cabernet Sauvignon Reserve also scored 100 points in the Wine Advocate, so you know the quality is top notch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plumpjack made for a great start to the day.  The drive, entrance and the tasting room all had a relaxing effect, as if to say it was ok to show up in a T-shirt and jeans.  Since we arrived close to opening at 1000, we were also the only people at the winery and received lots of attention from everyone there.  We missed Aaron Miller (their winemaker since 2012 and a UC Davis graduate), but were able to share some stories with the wine ambassadors about studying for the WSET exams and wishing we were all just a little smarter…  The Plumpjack group now owns two other wineries: CADE Winery on Howell Mountain and Odette Winery in Stags Leap.  What’s nice is that at each of the wineries, they will serve a wine from one of the other wineries as part of your tasting so you get an idea of the different styles and taste profiles of each place.  It also gives you a nice incentive to visit and try the rest of their portfolio, because as you can imagine those wines are also delicious!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/2-1050by788-c4d299.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/2-700by525-c4d299.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/2-675by506-c4d299.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/2-450by338-c4d299.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/2-525by394-c4d299.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/2-350by263-c4d299.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/plumpjack/2-350by263-c4d299.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;First-Class Wine Ambassadors&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Another benefit of going to the winery early in the day - everyone is available for a photograph!!  Everyone was very nice and they opened a couple extra wines for our tasting, for which we were very grateful.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tasting room itself is a relatively small space with a small patio in the back, hence the recommendation to make tasting reservations.  The bar is a small semi-circular slab of rock (as seen above) and there is also a small gift shop on the right in case you want to purchase any branded wine accessories.  I’m sure there are other interesting details about the building that I missed, but they poured the wine right away and had a couple off-menu wines to share since we were the first visitors of the day.  Also, I immediately felt like I needed to retract that thought of being able to wear a T-shirt and jeans here - the wine made me snap to attention really quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.plumpjackwinery.com/SHOP.AMS?LEVEL=BOT&amp;amp;PART=PJ17CHSC7&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Reserve Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($52)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;1:2 ratio of new to neutral oak and a 1:2 ratio of St. Helena grapes to Carneros.  Light aromas of lemon zest and lime with ripe green apples and acid that tingles the cheeks.  The lemon and lime are also on the palate, but definitely not as pronounced as on the nose.  A nice, crisp finish without a seering amount of acidity.  I didn’t get the almonds and vanilla on the palate from the wood as suggested by the tasting notes, but it could be that I wasn’t looking for it as well as this being the first wine of the day.  Not nearly the minerality of a Chablis, but still some similar characteristics in this wine.  Definitely not your traditional Napa Chardonnay.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.plumpjackwinery.com/SHOP.AMS?LEVEL=BOT&amp;amp;PART=PJ16MEC7&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Merlot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($64)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;96% Merlot from Oak Knoll with the rest Malbec.  Red and black fruit, chocolate, vanilla, and smoke make for a deep nose with a tingling brightness.  You can still feel the acidity, dust and medium smooth tannin on the palate.  Though, the finish does feel a little hot.  This is definitely a Merlot that Cabernet-Lovers will want to take a long look at.  The flavor profile is a little lighter on the palate, but the texture is very Cab-like.  I picked up a bottle of this for the winter-time!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Cade Napa Valley Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt; ($82)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Less or riper tannins that Cade’s Howell Mountain Cabernet make this a very accessible Cabernet in its youth.  Deep and rich red fruit with some brighter blue fruit on the nose as well.  It’s palate also feels very pretty and approachable with slightly candied notes and raspberry jam blended in.  You don’t need to pair this wine with anything; you can just drink it straight out of the bottle.  But make no mistake - it still has enough complexity to keep your interest.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.plumpjackwinery.com/SHOP.AMS?LEVEL=BOT&amp;amp;PART=PJ15CSCM&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Estate Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($130)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Huge grape jam on the nose with black and blue fruit.  The palate is really smooth (similar to the Cade) with ripe tannins that aren’t grippy but are definitely present.  From a texture standpoint, there is more weight on this wine than the previous Cade.  While the aromas are pronounced, the palate isn’t overly ripe with fruit notes and there is added complexity from cocoa powder, vanilla, and dusty notes.  For drinking right now, I prefer this over the Cade Napa Valley Cabernet and the other critics scores reflect that opinion.  Reminds me of really good black cherry pie…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2007 Oakville Estate Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt; ($371)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cherry, spice, cranberry, some herbaceous notes, but it all leaps out of the glass and the finish goes on forever.  I can’t believe this wine is 11 years old.  There is so much complexity on the nose but it all feels bright, fresh, and utterly irresistible.  The palate is a little lighter than the younger wines – I think it’s caused by a difference in style by the previous winemaker.  But the palate is just as intense as the nose and has flavors across all three segments (primary/secondary/tertiary).  If a wine could drop the mic, walk away, and leave the audience in awe, this is one of those wines.  I might pick this in a blind tasting next to Bordeaux First Growths…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.plumpjackwinery.com/SHOP.AMS?LEVEL=BOT&amp;amp;PART=PJ16SYC7&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Napa Valley Syrah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($62)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It’s hard to taste another wine immediately after a showstopper, but this Syrah held up surprisingly well.  A lot of bright, ripe red ripe fruit that explodes out of the glass.  There’s an underlying meat/blood component, but it’s buried underneath the red fruit and would need aging to bring it more to the forefront.  The body is med+/full with good lingering acid and tannin that is present but pretty soft.  The flavors are dominated by the bright, pretty ripe red fruit but should evolve similarly to the nose.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The style of the red wines reminds me of Nickel and Nickel in how pretty they are on the nose, but the flavor intensity and complexity were an added dimension I really liked, especially at the price points of the Merlot and Syrah.  The tannins were not quite as high as Beringer or similar-styled wines, so I would drink any of these earlier rather than later.  Another aspect that I really appreciated was that they included shipping with a case of wine, which if you buy as much wine as I do, you know that free shipping (especially free 2-day shipping here) is about the same as a 15% to 20% discount on the wines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still can remember the 2007 Oakville Estate Cabernet, but know that it will be hard to obtain or try again with that availability and pricepoint.  Instead, it may be worth trying to find a bottle of the 2016 Cabernet Sauvignon Reserve try aging that for 10 years.  Though, I have a feeling the Cabernet Sauvignon Reserve will also be out of my pricepoint after that 100pt score…  Such is life.  Still, this is a great, quality tasting for $40 and who knows, you may be able to try the reserve at the winery too!  So get out there and give it a try.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="oakville" /><summary type="html">Plumpjack is a great example of a newer winery on historic land that is producing fantastic wines. Many people in my social wine circle have heard the name, but not much else other than it supposedly makes great wines. As you may know by now, that is alone is enough to pique my curiosity and schedule a visit. It turns out that the legend of Plumpjack started in 1992, when the Lt. Governor of California and a music composer got together and opened a wine store in San Francisco. Those who are Shakespeare lovers may also get the reference to Sir John “Plumpjack” Falstaff from Henry V. When someone told me the reference, I knew I was really going to like this place because the personality of Sir “Plumpjack” is pretty close to my own.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/plumpjack/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Lokoya Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/29/lokoya_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lokoya Private Tasting" /><published>2018-12-29T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-29T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/29/lokoya_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/29/lokoya_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t get much better than Lokoya…  Not views of the valley below, not the tasting room, not the isolation/attention, and definitely not the wines.  I guess the only things to complain about is that they only make four wines (all Cabernet Sauvignons) and that I don’t make enough money to drink these wines regularly.  Though, I find myself saying that often for all the best wines.  Even with an allocation, I couldn’t get access to the 2015 Mt. Veeder and Howell Mountain, which happen to be my two favorite mountain terroirs of the four they produce from.  The other two are their Spring Mountain and Diamond Mountain wines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tasting room for Lokoya is up on Spring Mountain, past Fantesca but before Pride Mountain Winery.  It’s fairly difficult to find the gate as it’s unbranded and the location isn’t really advertised.  Don’t worry though - it’s neigh impossible to get a reservation for a tasting there, so if finding the place is your issue, consider it a small one.  Once you reach the property though, you’ll see that the views of the valley below are breathtaking, tempting you to sit outside on the patio all day.  Unfortunately though, that’s not on the menu…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/1-1050by788-b98616.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/1-700by525-b98616.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/1-675by506-b98616.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/1-450by338-b98616.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/1-525by394-b98616.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/1-350by263-b98616.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/1-350by263-b98616.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;token group photo&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Group photo with a glimpse of the valley from the Lokoya patio.  It really is quite something…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lokoya was purchased by Jackson Family Wines (one of the large wine conglomerates in the world today) to be the crown jewel of their Spire Collection.  And the entire experience does not disappoint.  From the moment you walk in the door, you are greeted by the wine ambassador and given a glass of excellent sparkling wine; I forget what Grand Cru Champagne we had.  Regardless, it was very good and quite pricey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/2-1050by788-82b819.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/2-700by525-82b819.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/2-675by506-82b819.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/2-450by338-82b819.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/2-525by394-82b819.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/2-350by263-82b819.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/2-350by263-82b819.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;just amazing&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Can you imagine hosting friends for a wine pairing meal here?  Also, lined around the room on both sides were cabinets that contained bottles of past vintages that are not for sale.  Imagine being able to break out some past vintages here.  I don’t think I could put a price on an experience like that…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you are led inside and listen to the history of the winery and winemaker (I am a huge fan of Chris Carpenter’s wines), it’s impossible not to just stare in awe of how pristine everything looks.  Coupled with the fact that only one group is allowed at the property at a time, we all felt like a million bucks.  In fact, everything was so overwhelming that it felt like I didn’t belong.  Definitely my first time ever feeling uncomfortable in a winery, albeit in a good way.  Finally, we were led to our table where the wines for the tasting had already been decanted and poured in our glasses.  I thought I was entering my comfort zone again.  These wines make you feel many things, but comfortable isn’t one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lokoya.com/collection#spring-mountain&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Spring Mountain Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($375)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This was the first wine of the tasting, so that might bias me, but I am pretty sure out of all the wines, this had the most perfumed floral notes on the nose.  Black and red fruit with minerality comes through on the palate.  Purity and integration define this wine with great balance between power and elegance.  Definitely the best Spring Mountain Cabernet I’ve had.  With proper aging, only the Fantesca Cabernet might begin to compare.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lokoya.com/collection#mount-veeder&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Mount Veeder Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($375)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Oh my goodness.  I lost myself in this wine.  If the Spring Mountain was about purity and integration, this wine was powerful, complex and dominated by the terroir’s minerality.  Blue fruit (more than black or red) with some spice in there as well.  There’s a saying that “If God created Cabernet, the Devil created Pinot”.  Of the many Cabernets I’ve had, this might be Cabernet that best fits that piece of hte equation; it just commands your attention and your respect.  Very masculine - please age this for 20-30 years before drinking.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lokoya.com/collection#howell-mountain&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2006 Howell Mountain Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($450)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;They were running low on the 2013 Howell Mountain, so they opened a library vintage instead.  Even though it was 11 years old, it was still brooding with the dark chocolate and black fruit I love so much from this AVA.  The one interesting note was that there wasn’t much tobacco / cigar box, but an herbal tinge (e.g. fennel) that was likely due to the aging.  This wine seemed to change the most over the course of the tasting and was really nice.  A clear example that these wines are going to age very nicely.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lokoya.com/collection#mount-veeder&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2006 Mount Veeder Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($450)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Compared to the 2013, the 2006 had minerality that was just as distinct, but more chocolate/espresso flavors and black fruit rather than blue fruit.  I’m surprised the floral bouquet was still so aromatic and the tannins were still so present (but sweet/rounded).  Still, the piece that captures the attention is the texture and the complexity - the flavors are layered and integrated at the same time.  I can’t tell which one I preferred more: the ‘06 Howell or the ‘06 Mount Veeder.  There is a reason why these two are my favorite mountain AVAs.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll admit, it must have been dumb luck that I was able to schedule a tasting here.  Out of the 10 wineries I visited in three days, this was by far the highlight of that weekend and continues to be one of my most fond memories of Napa Valley.  It’s really too bad that all they have to taste is four wines; this is where I give the edge to places like Kapcsandy who have wines that are also of extreme quality, but you get to walk through the full portfolio and various library vintages.  Still the winery and views are almost enough to make you forget that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/3-1050by1174-8a4f8d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/3-700by783-8a4f8d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/3-675by755-8a4f8d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/3-450by503-8a4f8d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/3-525by587-8a4f8d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/3-350by391-8a4f8d.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/lokoya/3-350by391-8a4f8d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;missing half the group&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The wine tasting with the meat and cheese board pairing.  If you thinking they are smiling big in this picture, you should’ve seen how much they were smiling after.  I forgot to take an “after” picture because I was so obsessed with the wines.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all walked away with a bottle of the 2013 Mt. Veeder.  In hindsight, I really wish I bought a couple cases given the rating of the vintage by every wine publication and the 2013 Mt. Veeder itself (100pts Wine Advocate).  I’m sure you got this from the tasting notes, but the theme of the wines here is power, character, and terroir.  There are many powerful Cabernets in the Napa Valley, but these wines are just rock solid and don’t rely on the fruit to do the heavy lifting.  And even though these wines will keep for 30-40 years, there is an approachability like all of Chris Carpenter’s wines that allows you to drink this early (if you really want to).  But I like to think of these wines as an investment in oneself, so save it for a special occasion for when you really deserve it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to be able to try these wines, but can’t get a reservation at Lokoya on Spring Mountain, make a reservation at Cardinale.  It’s much easier to get a reservation there and it’s also part of the Spire Collection.  When emailing them to confirm your reservation, you can ask for them to add Lokoya to your tasting menu.  It may add a few dollars to your tasting fee, but it is well worth it.  The Cardinale wine is also of high quality and worth the trip on its own merits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alas, I hope the day comes where I can purchase and consume Lokoya wines as freely as I’d like, but I doubt that will ever be the case.  So my advice to the readers - if you see a bottle in someone’s house, befriend them for life and pray you are lucky enough to be around when that bottle gets opened, haha.  For those that have cases of this wine in their cellars: will you be my friend?  Haha, cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="spring-mountain" /><summary type="html">It doesn’t get much better than Lokoya… Not views of the valley below, not the tasting room, not the isolation/attention, and definitely not the wines. I guess the only things to complain about is that they only make four wines (all Cabernet Sauvignons) and that I don’t make enough money to drink these wines regularly. Though, I find myself saying that often for all the best wines. Even with an allocation, I couldn’t get access to the 2015 Mt. Veeder and Howell Mountain, which happen to be my two favorite mountain terroirs of the four they produce from. The other two are their Spring Mountain and Diamond Mountain wines.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/lokoya/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Romeo Vineyards Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/22/romeo_vineyards_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Romeo Vineyards Public Tasting" /><published>2018-12-22T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-22T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/22/romeo_vineyards_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/22/romeo_vineyards_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;I hope everyone is having fun gearing up for Christmas!!  This may be a little late on my part, but I wanted to share some Christmas cheer by publishing articles on some fantastic wineries over the next few weeks.  That way, people will have all the belated Christmas gift ideas that they need!  The first one we are going to start with is Romeo Vineyards.  I’m fairly sure that most people reading this have never heard of Romeo Vineyards before.  Before I stumbled upon this gem in the town of Calistoga, I hadn’t heard of them either, save one or two deals on Vivino.  As one of the few places in the Napa Valley that is open until 5:00pm or later (it’s actually open until 6:30pm!), I thought I would end a day of tasting by visiting this small family-owned winery and trying a few wines.  Needless to say, that is not how it went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, huge props to Nate who ran the tasting for me.  Without his knowledge, friendliness, and genuine passion for the wines he was pouring, the score for the experience would be much different.  He was one of the most knowledgeable ambassadors I have ever tasted with (I could swear he is an Advanced Somm) and was super excited to share how amazing their wines are and how mispriced they are compared to their quality.  But don’t let all that praise fool you - the wines spoke for themselves and what a story they told.  As you can see in the tasting notes below, I tasted pretty much every wine and every vintage that they have stored down in their massive wine cellar.  My notes are also not as fully detailed as they normally are; part of it is I was tired after a long day of tastings and part of it is that tasting 15+ great wines from different vintages without spitting much of it will lead you to enjoying the overall experience rather than nitpicking the details of each wine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/1-1050by1400-ef32f3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/1-700by933-ef32f3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/1-675by900-ef32f3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/1-450by600-ef32f3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/1-525by700-ef32f3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/1-350by467-ef32f3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/1-350by467-ef32f3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Gateway to a hidden treasure&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Romeo is difficult to find in Calistoga.  It took me walking around the block a couple times to find the place.  But trust me, the search is worth it.  Through this passage lies a great tasting experience that will surprise you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The style of the wines was also much different that what I was used to; this novelty also had a positive effect on me while tasting the wines.  I am seriously enamored with their juicy, approachable style of wine that seemingly ages forever, even though the wines don’t seem like they need to.  Some of the wines are a little closed down (e.g. their 2004 Old Vine Cabernet Sauvignon) and require a decanter to coax out the flavors a bit.  But for the most part, every wine seems like it’s at its perfect drinking window.  Just note that the best temperature for storing and serving wine in this style is lower than what you are used to (e.g. 50-51 degrees) so be sure to take note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entrance to the winery is hard to find as there aren’t really any signs and the building it’s in is unassuming; I am pretty sure that they share it with some other business.  But once you find the terrace entrance as seen above, come prepared to have some preconceptions about good wine and expensive wine flipped on their head.  Great wine does not need to be expensive.  Thanks to the economics of supply-and-demand, it normally is.  But when you find a hidden gem that has a good supply but not much demand (it is relatively unknown), it can result in great deals for the consumer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvested from ~50-year-old vines, the grapes are used in small lot wines to ensure quality and distinctive character.  These vines are near a reservoir, which leads to high diurnal temperature swings (hot days, cool nights) that preserve the high acidity of the grapes and allows the vineyard manager to leave the grapes on the vines for an extremely long hangtime to achieve great flavor intensity.  The winemaker then uses a high skin/pulp to juice ratio during a colder maceration/fermentation to gain its intense but balanced flavors, while maintaining high acidity and a lighter body in the wine.  After reading all of that, you would think that you were drinking wines in the $150+ price range.  I am happy to burst your bubble!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/2-1050by1400-ab991a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/2-700by933-ab991a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/2-675by900-ab991a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/2-450by600-ab991a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/2-525by700-ab991a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/2-350by467-ab991a.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/romeo/2-350by467-ab991a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Tank-powered Coravin!!!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A shot inside Romeo’s tasting room.  There are so many great things about this picture.  The tasting room is small (fits at most 10 people), the wine ambassador (Nate) is amazing, the fact that he’s using a coravin connected to an Argon tank is awesome, and he was pouring me a 2004 Old Vine Cabernet Sauvignon.  I was so happy when I took this photo, haha.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wines we tasted (and what little I wrote down) is below.  &lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; The best wines, which also happen to be the ones I tasted, are not listed on their website and can only be purchased through the winery directly, so make sure you visit in person!  I know they are running low on inventory for a few of these, so there isn’t that much time left for finding the older vintages!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2007 Miscela Bordeaux Blend&lt;/strong&gt; ($65)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Really nice nose – juicy but not overripe and with some earth.  The alcohol does not come out at all and everything feels well woven together.  Juicy raisins on the palate with a nice medium(-) body that goes down easy.  The tannin and acidity are in good balance.  It is a just a really good wine that is easy to enjoy but has a deeper cerebral aspect if you want to enjoy that aspect too.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2006 Petit Verdot&lt;/strong&gt; ($46)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;100% varietal Petit Verdot.  I don’t know what was more shocking - the fact they attempted it or how good the wine was.  Big and intense but super enjoyable with lighter tannins and body (still juicy) than I was expecting.  A nice representation of the varietal’s characteristics with enough age to let the tertiary character of the PV shine too.  And this was Nate’s least favorite of the Petit Verdots on the menu….&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2004 Petit Verdot&lt;/strong&gt; ($55)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sweet brown sugar mixed with earth and the juiciness of the 2006.  There is also a high pitched acidity (citrus-like in character) on the back of the nose that makes the wine feel alive at 14 years old.  I thought the 2006 was good, but now I see why he said it didn’t compare to the others.  The vibrancy adds a good amount of complexity and makes the mid-palate feel much more interesting.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Petit Verdot&lt;/strong&gt; ($55)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Their youngest Petit Verdot.  Popcorn kernels (weird, right?) jump out at you and the rest of the red fruit just rushes in after it.  There are also notes of blackberry and blueberry in the wine.  Silky smooth for its varietal and age - I could see how people prefer the younger PV.  But give me that 2004 all day.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2003 Napa Valley Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt; ($70)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Seriously, the first note to come out was gerber baby carrot.  With some time, plum, raisin, bright acidity, and an earthiness also come out of the glass.  Like the others before it, this wine is super smooth with a good amount of juiciness and a lighter body than other Cabernets you’ll have in the valley.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2005 Petit Verdot&lt;/strong&gt; ($42)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;After the 2003 Cabernet, we went back to the 2005 PV.  The nose is still a little closed, but in a cloying type of way where it wants you to wait for it to open up.  Much more earthiness and tannin than the other PVs – the tannin is sharp/compact and the body is not as juicy as the others.  This thing could age another 5 to 10 years if it wanted.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2002 Eugenia Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt; ($85)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Strawberry, raspberry, plum, spice, and earth.  All of this combines into a really nice wine that is so smooth, complex and balanced.  This wine may seem feminine, but the tasting notes that progressively open and its intricacies leave you feeling as if you have experienced powerful in a different sense.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1997 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This wine really struck me as something quite spectacular.  Seemingly made in an old world style, but still has plenty amount of fruit left in its life.  This wine balances being enjoyable and cerebral very well.  I didn’t take any notes on the exact flavors because I was just struck by the sensibility and integration of the wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1998 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt; ($70)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Definitively less fruit than the 1997 Cabernet.  Nate mentioned this and I agree - this is a French farmers wine; there is no fruit left on the palate but this would still make for a great cigar wine.  Still, the textural components are all well balanced and while the flavor may not have much fruit, the wine doesn’t feel too old or tired at all.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2004 Old Vine Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt; ($90)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;By local “definition”, this wine is an old vine Cabernet (over 35 years old).  The wine was very closed in the glass, but I was told would have great potential if I had the time to let it open.  I bought a bottle a tried it again later and he was right.  It was probably the favorite bottle of the night.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Old Vine Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt; ($48)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A very different wine than the 2004.  This is a very pretty wine with lots of red/black fruit and with a crushed flower quality to the taste.  Even though this is a young with, it’s still super approachable with a great mouthfeel.  Do not hesitate to open this bottle and drink right away.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2009 Petit Verdot&lt;/strong&gt; ($55)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A balance between juicy and reserved on the nose.  Like the other PVs, this is really smooth for being a 100% varietal wine with a good amount of tannins that can still support aging for another decade if you wanted to.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Petit Verdot&lt;/strong&gt; ($55)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A bit bigger in the acid and tannin category than the other Petit Verdots.  It’s interesting – the juiciness ends a little quickly on the finish thanks to the acid/tannin, but that does not affect the palate at all.  Not much grip, just a really nice texture.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2008 Malbec&lt;/strong&gt; ($42)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Grapes from Calistoga, but the nose reminded me of Knights Valley.  I don’t even think I felt the tannins and the acid is med/med+ but you don’t even notice it until it hits your cheeks.  I haven’t had a 10 year old Malbec before, so this was a treat.  Also juicy and smooth – the color is not dark like other Malbecs and the body is not heavy either.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Soiree Petit Verdot Port&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;18.5% ABV after fortification, I need more of this.  That is all.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How’s everyone feeling after all that wine?  Not only was the wine great, but you will notice that not a single bottle came out to more than $90.  They were also kind enough to give me free shipping on a case (of course I bought a case after a tasting like that…).  So just make sure that you stop by for a tasting.  You will be glad that you did.  Cheers!!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="calistoga" /><summary type="html">I hope everyone is having fun gearing up for Christmas!! This may be a little late on my part, but I wanted to share some Christmas cheer by publishing articles on some fantastic wineries over the next few weeks. That way, people will have all the belated Christmas gift ideas that they need! The first one we are going to start with is Romeo Vineyards. I’m fairly sure that most people reading this have never heard of Romeo Vineyards before. Before I stumbled upon this gem in the town of Calistoga, I hadn’t heard of them either, save one or two deals on Vivino. As one of the few places in the Napa Valley that is open until 5:00pm or later (it’s actually open until 6:30pm!), I thought I would end a day of tasting by visiting this small family-owned winery and trying a few wines. Needless to say, that is not how it went.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/romeo/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Nickel and Nickel Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/15/nickel_and_nickel_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nickel and Nickel Private Tasting" /><published>2018-12-15T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-15T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/15/nickel_and_nickel_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/15/nickel_and_nickel_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Nickel and Nickel is another winery right next to the Highway 29 in Napa.  In fact it’s right across the street from Robert Mondavi and next to Opus One, both of which have storied histories, so you know they set up shop in the right place.  The styling used for Nickel and Nickel’s logo is also very similar to Far Niente, which isn’t to far away.  That’s not a coincidence - the two are sister wineries.  While Far Niente is known for its rounded portfolio, Nickel and Nickel has built its reputation through its vast number of single vineyard Cabernet Sauvignons.  Even the single vineyard tasting gives you a preview of less than half (6 out of 15) of the single vineyard Cabernet Sauvignons on their menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/1-1050by788-40cb0b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/1-700by525-40cb0b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/1-675by506-40cb0b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/1-450by338-40cb0b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/1-525by394-40cb0b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/1-350by263-40cb0b.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/1-350by263-40cb0b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Follow the red brick walkway&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The wine tasting building is actually a house that functions as the wine tasting location.  The wine tastings are conducted inside as well as on the back patio.  Because the house isn’t that big, reservations are required to throttle visitor throughput.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a previous article discussing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/09/08/beringer_private_tasting.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beringer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I mentioned that Beringer was a great location to explore single vineyard Cabernet Sauvignons.  If I were to contrast these two and their interpretations of premium Cabernet Sauvignon, it would be that Beringer makes its Cabernets heavier and with more tannin for aging, while the Cabernets from Nickel and Nickel are softer and ready to drink earlier.  As far as educative experiences go, this Cabernet tasting was very helpful in isolating the characteristics of the different terroir along the valley floor (e.g. Oakville, Yountville, Rutherford, and St. Helena).  Even if you don’t have the most discerning wine palate yet, this is a fun experience to see if you can taste anything different between the wines.  Once you are able to take that first step, the rest follows.  Also, you will impress your sommelier at dinner if you know what AVA you want your Napa Cabernet from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/2-1050by788-a9e080.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/2-700by525-a9e080.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/2-675by506-a9e080.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/2-450by338-a9e080.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/2-525by394-a9e080.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/2-350by263-a9e080.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/2-350by263-a9e080.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Where's the wedding?&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A look into the house.  This is the waiting area your wine ambassador will escort you to as they setup your tasting.  A nice, classy room to enjoy a glass of Chardonnay and share some laughs with fellow wine drinkers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Approaching the building, it feels like you are visiting a friend’s house.  This house must have been around for some time; once inside, you can tell that the house and furniture all have some age on them.  As you look around and wait for your wine ambassador to come fetch you for your tasting, you are given a glass of their Stiling Chardonnay to enjoy in the meantime.  Once they are ready for you, you’ll be led on a tour of the grounds, through the back patio, and into the white triangular-shaped building in the picture above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/3-1050by788-fd4e21.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/3-700by525-fd4e21.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/3-675by506-fd4e21.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/3-450by338-fd4e21.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/3-525by394-fd4e21.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/3-350by263-fd4e21.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/3-350by263-fd4e21.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Where's the wedding?&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view of the grounds from the back patio of the house.  With this much space, you’d think that there would be a wedding hosted here every weekend, but alas there is not.  Seems like the space could be used for something fun.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting the tour of the winemaking facility and asking any questions you might have of their philosophy and production process, it’ll be time to taste some wines!  As with every winery, the wine ambassador can make or break the tasting experience.  Luckily, I had a great one who also allowed me to taste the Syrah that is not normally on the menu and entertained me with great detail about the wines here.  If you do the single vineyard Cabernet tasting, your list will also look like the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.farniente.com/product/2015-Nickel---Nickel-Stiling-Vineyard-Chardonnay--Russian-River-Valley--Sonoma&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Stiling Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Chardonnay from the Russian River Valley.  Good balance between the acidity, fruit, and secondary/tertiary flavors.  I also liked the intensity and finish.  I was surprised that I would have such a good white wine with my all-red tasting.  I am definitely interested in finding a bottle of this and buying one in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.farniente.com/product/2015-Nickel---Nickel-Branding-Iron-Vineyard-Cabernet-Sauvignon--Oakville&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Branding Iron&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($120)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cabernet from Oakville.  Deep blue fruit but also some red fruit present with a levity to the nose.  The initial impact on the palate is a bit more subtle than the nose suggests.  Not enough intensity or complexity for me to choose this wine over the others, but if you want a subtle wine that is driven by primary flavors (e.g. fruit notes), then this is the wine you want.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.farniente.com/product/2015-Nickel---Nickel-C-C--Ranch-Cabernet-Sauvignon--Rutherford&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 CC Ranch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($120)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cabernet from Rutherford.  Better to drink this earlier in its life as I don’t know how it will age.  The acid is very nice and even though it’s 15%+ alcohol, I can’t really smell the heat at all.  It has good viscosity and length on the palate but with a lower intensity of fruit, hence why I don’t know how the mid-palate will develop and recommend trying an older bottle of this before deciding to age it yourself.  The CC Ranch is still an easy drinking wine now without a tertiary component.  If you like the Branding Iron, you may also like this.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.farniente.com/product/2015-Nickel---Nickel-Hayne-Vineyard-Cabernet-Sauvignon--St--Helena&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Hayne Vineyard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($120)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cabernet from St. Helena.  A really pretty nose with ripe red fruit that feels a little ethereal with some flowers and roses.  It has a lighter body and is brighter than the previous wines with more acidity that also cleans the palate on the finish.  The intensity again is a bit light for my taste (this contrasts the Corison Cabernet which as a light body, but intense flavor), but may be up other people’s alley!  If you want a wine similar to the Branding Iron / CC Ranch but with more acid, look no further.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.farniente.com/product/2015-Nickel---Nickel-State-Ranch-Cabernet-Sauvignon--Yountville&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 State Ranch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($120)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cabernet from Yountville.  Take the notes from the Hayne Vineyard Cabernet, but make them a bit deeper, thicker, more pronounced and you get this wine.  The high acid is prominent too on the palate.  Comparing the two, I would take the State Ranch, but again it’s all about your preferences!  There’s also definitely room for several years of aging too.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.farniente.com/product/2015-Nickel---Nickel-Element-28-Cabernet-Sauvignon--Napa-Valley&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Element 28&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($150)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Subtle with the fruit, emphasizing instead violet/floral notes and vanilla on the nose.  The Element 28 seems like a polished version of the State Ranch and takes the wine to the next level.  There’s also more earthiness on the palate that balances with the fruit and adds to the complexity.  This wine is probably my favorite of all the Nickel and Nickel Cabernets I tasted because of that balance and its intensity, though it won’t overpower you palate either.  The tannins are high and present, affecting the perceived length of the finish and making sure the wine can age 10+ years if it wants to.  Of course it’s also the most expensive wine on the tasting menu…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.farniente.com/product/2015-Nickel---Nickel-Rock-Cairn-Vineyard-Cabernet-Sauvignon--Oakville&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Rock Cairn Vineyard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($120)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cabernet from Oakville.  The nose is so powerful with bright black fruit.  The palate pulls the intensity back a bit but has a solid body, enough acid/tannin to hold up the wine but not get in the way, and medium+ length on the mid-palate and finish.  This wine is probably my second favorite after the Element 28 but doesn’t have the same level of tertiary notes and focuses on the black fruit instead.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.farniente.com/product/2014-Nickel---Nickel-Darien-Vineyard-Syrah--Russian-River-Valley--Sonoma&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Syrah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($65)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Syrah from the Russian River Valley.  They planted two acres of Syrah in the Pinot Noir block they purchased some time ago.  Having rosemary-rubbed lamb with this wine would be sooo good.  Made from cooler fruit that has quite a bit of character - the wild flavors of Syrah and black pepper is well integrated into the wine, making this cerebral and yet easy drinking at the same time.  A really good value buy here for an interesting Syrah that reminds you of the Rhone Valley in France.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would be remiss if I didn’t give a shout-out to Ian Stout who was my wine ambassador for the visit.  Ian hails from Texas and is following in the footsteps of his father, who is a Master Sommelier and owns a Syrah vineyard back in Texas.  Ian’s tasting setup was great - it was both a progression of intensity and fruit flavor types (start with light blue/red to deep red to finishing with black).  He was very knowledgable about the wines and the terroirs; I think the tasting ran over by 30 minutes because of the discussion we would have after each wine.  The cheeses used for the paired tasting were very good as well (I can’t believe I didn’t mention that earlier!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/4-1050by788-329f2f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/4-700by525-329f2f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/4-675by506-329f2f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/4-450by338-329f2f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/4-525by394-329f2f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/4-350by263-329f2f.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/nickel-nickel/4-350by263-329f2f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;I love getting dirty&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Inside the white triangular-shaped building, you will walk past the different fermentation tanks and also this little area: soil samples from the different single vineyard sites of their Cabernet Sauvignon.  It’s good to have an image of the soil as you taste the wine so you can remember the influence of the terroir&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned before, I enjoyed this tasting very much.  If I had to name a theme for their wines, I would use one of the anologies they used to describe themselves.  The winemakers at Nickel and Nickel think of winemaking like sculpting with marble in that you should start with a single piece and shave it down to its form.  In their case, they only make 100% varietal wine and use winemaking techniques to adjust and achieve what the wine wants to be, rather than blend several varietals together to get what the winemakers want.  It’s an interesting way to look at winemaking, especially since blending is considered a traditional technique and is used by most wineries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally enjoyed the last three bottles and thought the first few (besides the Chardonnay) were just a bit too light/pretty without enough character.  I still think that if you are looking to refine your palate and enjoy a different take (or many different takes) on Cabernet Sauvignon, you should give Nickel and Nickel a look.  And while you are at it, pay its sister vineyard a visit as well - hopefully, I will in the future.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="oakville" /><summary type="html">Nickel and Nickel is another winery right next to the Highway 29 in Napa. In fact it’s right across the street from Robert Mondavi and next to Opus One, both of which have storied histories, so you know they set up shop in the right place. The styling used for Nickel and Nickel’s logo is also very similar to Far Niente, which isn’t to far away. That’s not a coincidence - the two are sister wineries. While Far Niente is known for its rounded portfolio, Nickel and Nickel has built its reputation through its vast number of single vineyard Cabernet Sauvignons. Even the single vineyard tasting gives you a preview of less than half (6 out of 15) of the single vineyard Cabernet Sauvignons on their menu.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/nickel-nickel/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Brian Arden Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/08/brian_arden_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Brian Arden Public Tasting" /><published>2018-12-08T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-08T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/08/brian_arden_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/08/brian_arden_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;As more investment pours into Napa Valley and the large conglomerates (e.g. Constellation Brands) continue to purchase more property and consolidate the industry, it’s getting harder to find quality smaller wineries with that family feel (e.g. Clark-Claudon).  Luckily, there is one right off the Silverado Trail that has been growing, slowly but surely these past 5-10 years.  This recent visit to Brian Arden was a coming of age for both of us - the last time I visited several years ago, they had just opened their facility on the Silverado Trail and I was just discovering how amazing wine could be.  The only thing I can say is “look at us now!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/1-1050by788-27a8a2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/1-700by525-27a8a2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/1-675by506-27a8a2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/1-450by338-27a8a2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/1-525by394-27a8a2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/1-350by263-27a8a2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/1-350by263-27a8a2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;beautiful winery&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I really do like the architecture of the winery.  If I had to design one for myself, I hope it comes out looking as good as this one.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even after some years, Brian Arden still looks like an architectural novelty as you enter the driveway.  Though, it isn’t like Hall where the novelty seems artistically driven - the novelty here is they aimed for a clean design that seems classy and homely at the same time.  The abundance of windows makes the tasting room a little warm during the afternoon, but also allows you to enjoy the incredible views from inside the tasting room.  Inside the tasting room there was constant traffic, but it never got to the point of crowded nor too loud.  The proprietor Brian Harlan, who is also the winemaker, made it a point to come inside and thank every group for their patronage and get their feedback on the wines.  This wasn’t an easy thing for him to do as he was simultaneously receiving delivery of the bottles that will be used for this upcoming vintage - a lot of delicate work to balance, for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/2-1050by788-c2ef70.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/2-700by525-c2ef70.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/2-675by506-c2ef70.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/2-450by338-c2ef70.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/2-525by394-c2ef70.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/2-350by263-c2ef70.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/brian-arden/2-350by263-c2ef70.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;peaceful tasting&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;There’s nothing like sitting at a table enjoying good wine and people watching…  Well, the view outside those windows might have been even more captivating…  Have to love the Napa Valley!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many other small producers, Brian first got his start with a larger winery (Terra Valentine) and has met / worked with others who are in the premium wine category.  Incorporating all of that knowledge into his winemaking style, but keeping things very approachable (like his winery), Brian produces enjoyable wines that can be drunk immediately, are still complex, while also being value deals at their price points.  In addition, all of his single varietal wines are actually 100% (and not just 75% as required by California Law to label your bottle with a varietal).  To keep things interesting though, the only continuous grape contracts they have are for their Chardonnay and the Zinfandel (they own their Zin vines).  The source of all their other fruit can and does change year-to-year, depending on what’s available for purchase from others.   This means that each vintage will likely taste very different from their previous ones.  They also have more fun wines coming down the pipe (e.g. Sparkling Rose, Rose, Riesling, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His dogs also roam the winery (did I mention they were dog friendly?), distracting all serious tasters with their demand for attention.  But I have a duty to my readers…  So without further ado, the wines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.brianardenwines.com/product/2015-Sauvignon-Blanc&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Sauvignon Blanc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($34)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Made from Calistoga grapes.  Brian’s wife, Amanda, likes New Zealand Sauvignon Blanc with its higher acidity and green flavors like gooseberry. Brian does not.  And like every good husband, he made the wine the way she likes it - dubbing the wine “In Amanda Style”, which is also how all of the pourers refer to it.  Medium+ acid, lemon, lime, and a zesty flint on the nose and palate.  Medium body and a roundness to the structure, acidity, and intensity makes this very approachable.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Sangiovese&lt;/strong&gt; ($45)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Warm red cherry/rhubarb pie and sweet spice permeate the nose.  Swirling the glass kicks up the intensity and brings out the alcohol.  The alcohol is still warm on the palate, but there is a sweet/candied fruit richness that’s there as well.  Reminds me of a Pinot Noir in texture but the flavor profile of a toned down version of the Del Dotto Sangiovese.  The grapes are sourced from Vincent Arroyo for this vintage, while the previous two have come from elsewhere.  Pale rose and plum color.  According to Brian, “it was just too good” to use in a blend and needed to be a varietal wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.brianardenwines.com/product/2012ZinNV&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Zinfandel, Burton Ranch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($45)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Made from vines that have been around since the late 1800s (think 130+ years old).  The logo on the Brian Arden bottles was made in tribute to their 55 acres of Zinfandel that is up in Lake County (near Kelseyville, which luckily avoided the Summer 2016 fires in Lake County).  Even more pungent than the Sangiovese, there is cooked/stewed raisin, a little rhubarb, sweet spice, and a solid warming core on the body with a lingering raisin finish.  Almost a bit port-ish in quality, though much warmer.  It has a surprising amount of acidity as well.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.brianardenwines.com/product/2012BARED&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 B.A. Red&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($45)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The only blend that they make.  2012 was 45% Sangiovese, 35% Syrah, 15% Cabernet Sauvignon, and 5% Zinfandel.  Every year, the blend changes – not just the percentages, but even the varietals used in the blend change.  I don’t know how to describe the nose as there are lots of different things happening which are hard to attribute/summarize.  Sweet spice and cooked pie character are still there though with some black pepper from the Syrah.  Not as fruit driven as the other wines, but the nose seems brighter and the palate has more acid.  Definitely a good wine for the winter time…  Pairing with different foods will bring out different characteristics of the wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.brianardenwines.com/product/2012-Cabernet-Sauvignon&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The 2011 Cabernet Sauvignon came from Howell Mountain but this year’s came from the valley floor in Coombsville, which is east of the town of Napa.  This is a good easy drinking Napa Cabernet.  The nose is deep with black fruit, red fruit (plum), and spices.  The tannins are very smooth; you hardly notice them, but the acidity is definitely present.  Medium body, high alcohol, medium+/high intensity.  It’s probably best to serve this a little chilled to bring out the acidity a bit more..&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Malbec&lt;/strong&gt; ($50)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The first and only Malbec that they’ve done so far.  In fact, it’s actually the first wine “made” at the winery when they opened the doors in 2014.  Great fragrant nose with alcohol that integrates with the spice, but the blue and black fruit are really strong and hold up the wine.  Good acidity, body and smooth chewy tannin with spice still stimulating the palate.  The fruit flavors are a bit more restrained on the palate, but not in a bad way.  I might take this wine over the Cabernet Sauvignon because they are similar in style.  Made with fruit from Trefethen.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because Brian does not grow the grapes for many of these wines, more effort needs to go into the wine production process to ensure he gets the results he is looking for, as there is no blending besides the B.A Red.  There were cooked/stewed fruit and spice notes that was present in several of the wines, so if you prefer lighter wines with higher acidity and cranberry flavors, you may want to look elsewhere.  The heat (alcohol), spice, and bigger body qualities were similar to Frank Family, but the fruit is riper/deeper while the Frank Family wines had more cranberry and tertiary pieces.  If you are like me and need wines that will keep you going during the winter months at a reasonable price, it’s hard to do better than this in Napa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, the prospect of a nice, leisurely atmosphere with a great view outside and the chance to talk wine with the owner of the winery and his wine ambassadors is hard to turn down.  And who knows - many of the wines described above may taste totally different next year.  Does that mean I might need to go again next year to check them out - it may!  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="calistoga" /><summary type="html">As more investment pours into Napa Valley and the large conglomerates (e.g. Constellation Brands) continue to purchase more property and consolidate the industry, it’s getting harder to find quality smaller wineries with that family feel (e.g. Clark-Claudon). Luckily, there is one right off the Silverado Trail that has been growing, slowly but surely these past 5-10 years. This recent visit to Brian Arden was a coming of age for both of us - the last time I visited several years ago, they had just opened their facility on the Silverado Trail and I was just discovering how amazing wine could be. The only thing I can say is “look at us now!”</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/brian-arden/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Frank Family Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/01/frank_family_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Frank Family Public Tasting" /><published>2018-12-01T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-01T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/01/frank_family_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/12/01/frank_family_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Frank Family is one of those vineyards that aren’t hyped by the major wine reviewers, but you continue to hear its name talked about on the wine apps (e.g. Vivino and Delectable) and see its bottles in stores, as their wines are nationally distributed.  I finally had enough and decided to find out for myself what the fuss was all about.  Like many other wineries, it was founded with capital earned in another industry.  In the case of Frank Family, it was Hollywood.  But not as actors - the owner was President of Disney and the son is currently the President of Dreamworks Studios.  And what person in the movie business wouldn’t appreciate good vino?  Better yet, what person in any industry wouldn’t appreciate good vino?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/1-1050by788-006b98.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/1-700by525-006b98.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/1-675by506-006b98.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/1-450by338-006b98.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/1-525by394-006b98.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/1-350by263-006b98.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/1-350by263-006b98.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Where's Waldo&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It’s a little hard to miss Frank Family while driving by…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Found off Highway 29 in Calistoga, the Frank Family winery is very traditional in the design of its buildings and landscape.  After all, the winery portion was purchased from Larkmead some years back.  The interior is very polished with a darker, old fashioned wood theme.  After taking a picture on their red carpet (of course they had one), I was led inside and joined by two other groups for the tasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/2-1050by1400-7a45f3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/2-700by933-7a45f3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/2-675by900-7a45f3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/2-450by600-7a45f3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/2-525by700-7a45f3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/2-350by467-7a45f3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/2-350by467-7a45f3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Red Carpet Rollin&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Enjoying my time on the red carpet.  I must admit, I look very asian in this photograph, but definitely not up to the crazy rich asian standard.  That movie changed the game.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The five others that were seated with me at the tasting were relatively new to wine, so the hostess adjusted the tasting to their experience level.  And though she didn’t have any formal training or a wine background, she was very engaging and very good at recalling her facts!  It’s nice to enjoy tastings like this because it serves as a reminder that not everyone will develop a passion or an intellectual curiosity for all things wine.  But that doesn’t mean that they can’t enjoy it for what it is as much as I do.  And instead of serious talk about wine chemistry, we enjoyed sharing stories about the biggest bloopers we’ve all made with wine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/3-1050by788-18aca9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/3-700by525-18aca9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/3-675by506-18aca9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/3-450by338-18aca9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/3-525by394-18aca9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/3-350by263-18aca9.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/frank-family/3-350by263-18aca9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Storytelling and Laughs&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Sharing some stories and some laughs over sparkling wine in the tasting room.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While lots of fun, the pace and conversation at the table did distract me a bit from analyzing the wines and I couldn’t really ask questions regarding some of the more intricate details of their wine production process.  It may very well be that my rating of the wines/wineries would’ve been higher on a different day with different circumstances.  Though, if you are looking for a winery to bring a party of 6-8 people, Frank Family could be a very nice choice for the price point, since your party would likely be seated alone.  Without further ado, the wines on the tasting menu!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frankfamilyvineyards.com/wine/bubbles/blanc-de-blancs13&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blanc de Blanc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Made in the traditional method (like Cremant, Champagne, and Cava) with 36 months on the lees and hand-riddled (remuage with a pupitre).  The nose is clean with traces of lemon, lime, brioche, and definitely a high malic acid note (e.g. green apples) that is powerful.  The high malic acid did overpower the palate a bit, leading to an imbalance in my mind that might have been avoided if the grapes had a brix level that was a little higher (ie. the grapes were more ripe).  Still, it makes for a very refreshing sparkling wine if served cold on a hot day.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frankfamilyvineyards.com/wine/reserve/lewis-vineyard-reserve-chardonnay&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Carneros Lewis Vineyard Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($65)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wow – the melon and malolactic fermentation (MLF) flavors jump right out of the glass with high intensity.  There is a little bit of a terroir influence to it as well.  Medium(+) body, the butter is pretty pronounced on the palate but well blended with the melon and other stonefruit character.  The medium acid means the grapes must have been pretty well developed - the acid was enough though to match the finish that goes on for quite a bit.  The wine is dry, but there is an underlying ripeness that carries the wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frankfamilyvineyards.com/wine/reserve/lewis-vineyard-reserve-pinot-noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Carneros Lewis Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($65)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is initially tight, but when you coax the wine a bit, the fruit and spice come out in force with ripe cranberry and fruitcake leading on the nose.  The mouthfeel was much lighter than I was expecting from a Carneros Pinot this ripe.  The palate has cooked cranberry, toast, spices, a medium body, and a smooth palate.  What makes this wine interesting is the little piece of forest floor / tertiary / savory character in there at such a young age.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frankfamilyvineyards.com/wine/reserve/zinfandel-chiles-valley&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Reserve Zinfandel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Blended with Petit Sirah, this Zinfandel has a very fragrant/strong nose, a good amount of body and tannin, but with lighter fruit flavors (cranberry/strawberry), some sweet spice notes, and higher acid that tingles the cheeks.  This is not your normal Zin – it has some elements that remind me of Turley Zinfandel, which is always a flattering comparison.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.frankfamilyvineyards.com/wine/reserve/2014-rutherford-reserve-cabernet-sauvignon&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Rutherford Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($95)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;100% Rutherford Cab.  The blue and red fruit on the nose and palate is almost candied.  And although the wine and acid isn’t that bright (like Corison), the acid is still mouthwatering and the perfume is pretty and light coming off the wine.  Give it a swirl to really open up the fruit, spices, tertiary notes (coffee/cedar), and high acid that wafts the flavors up.  Super smooth on the palate, a med(+) body, and a light but persistent finish.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The price points of the first four wines are at the upper-end for solid Napa wines (the Rutherford Cabernet is even with peers).  The profiles of the wines are appealing to a large portion of the population (e.g. their candied notes), especially those that want something a little lighter bodied than traditional Napa Valley, with good fragrance and some tertiary development too.  And while the wines are not “ripe” by some people’s Napa valley standards (cranberry notes in a few of them), they are definitely not underripe.  The wines taste like they undergo a slighly colder fermentation to preserve that floral prettiness and acid.  I can definitely see why this vineyard is popular with many people, but some of the wines seem like they focus on complexity and intensity at a cost to integration and balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frank Family definitely has one of the more relaxed atmospheres in the valley (even more so than Hall), which is very inviting for people that don’t yet know much about wine and want to fit in with the crowd at the winery.  I personally like my wines with a bit more natural personality at the risk of being something that some patrons will love and others not so much.  Still, deft hands make these wines and I definitely recommend Frank Family as a nice stop if it’s your first visit to Napa and you want something more relaxing.  Even if you don’t stop by, try buying one of their wines the next time you see it at your local wine store!  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="calistoga" /><summary type="html">Frank Family is one of those vineyards that aren’t hyped by the major wine reviewers, but you continue to hear its name talked about on the wine apps (e.g. Vivino and Delectable) and see its bottles in stores, as their wines are nationally distributed. I finally had enough and decided to find out for myself what the fuss was all about. Like many other wineries, it was founded with capital earned in another industry. In the case of Frank Family, it was Hollywood. But not as actors - the owner was President of Disney and the son is currently the President of Dreamworks Studios. And what person in the movie business wouldn’t appreciate good vino? Better yet, what person in any industry wouldn’t appreciate good vino?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/frank-family/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Larkmead Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/24/larkmead_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Larkmead Public Tasting" /><published>2018-11-24T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-24T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/24/larkmead_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/24/larkmead_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Another winery with a storied history longer than most (dating back to the late 1800s) that continues to produce top notch wines is Larkmead.  Though unlike many others with the same length of history, Larkmead continues to be a small production winery, choosing to concentrate on quality over quantity as its 2013 The Lark (100pt by Wine Advocate) demonstrates.  Its smaller size and simple-but-bright tasting room provides quite the contrast to Frank Family, which is right across the street.  Both are located in Calistoga off the main highway, so there’s no reason not to visit either or both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/1-1050by788-c0baba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/1-700by525-c0baba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/1-675by506-c0baba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/1-450by338-c0baba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/1-525by394-c0baba.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/1-350by263-c0baba.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/1-350by263-c0baba.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Peaceful, but not for long&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The winery getting ready to start the day.  The winemaking facilty is on the right and the wine tasting building is on the left.  You can take the wine tour and visit both buildings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a reason why both wineries are so close together.  Larkmead sold its original winery building to Frank Family back in the day, but kept their vineyards and continued to produce wine, later constructing its new tasting room that I had the pleasure of visiting.  It is very refreshing with a white/light theme that is very fashionable but relaxing.  There are many reasons why this small family winery produces excellent wines, but I think the level of interaction with their vines is the most important one.  They hand prune and hand harvest everything in addition to walking the vineyards every day observing their development and making adjustments as needed.  As it was close to harvest time, I got to wander the vineyards with them and tasted some of the grapes - I’ve never tasted a Sauvignon Blanc grape that good before - ripe but with high acid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/2-1050by788-cfb649.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/2-700by525-cfb649.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/2-675by506-cfb649.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/2-450by338-cfb649.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/2-525by394-cfb649.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/2-350by263-cfb649.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/larkmead/2-350by263-cfb649.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Wine loves Art&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The private tasting room for larger reservations.  The family loves and creates art, which makes for great decorations around a tasting table.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shout-out to Deanna Basham for taking me on a tour of the vineyards, for letting the wine sell itself while demonstrating a vast depth of knowledge, and for off-roading a little bit on the tasting menu - I had a couple more than the published menu.  Though, if you also show respect for the great wines they produce, I’m sure they will treat you like family and expand the tasting menu.  It’s just too bad that “The Lark” is nearly impossible to get ahold of; they only produce 4-6 barrels of this rockstar each vintage.  Below are the wines I was able to sample:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.larkmead.com/wine/lillie&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Lillie&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;285 cases made of these 500ml bottles of 100% Sauvignon Blanc.  Sur Lie aging, nicely rounded, really nice high acidity, a 3-to-1 ratio of foudre to partially new French oak barrels used for aging, with notes of subdued melon/honeysuckle and jasmine that give it a pretty nose.  On the palate, you see similar notes with a creamy feel on the finish thanks to the sur lie aging.  So smooth for a Sauv Blanc and not heavy by any means.  14% ABV.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.larkmead.com/wine/firebelle&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Firebelle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($125)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;71% Old Vine Merlot, 21% Cab Sauv, 8% Petit Verdot, grown in gravel.  14.5% ABV.  18 months in 65% new French Oak barrels.  Ripe cherry and rose on the nose.  It’s so bright – just smelling the wine is enough to make my mouth water from the acidity.  The wine finishes crisp as well with a bunch of tannin (though not mouthfilling).  The palate is dusty and very dry (high acid/tannin), with cherry and cocoa powder flavors.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.larkmead.com/wine/cabernet-sauvignon&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($100)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;14.7% ABV.  18 months in 65% new French Oak.  Blend of grapes from gravel, sand, and clay terroirs, making ~2700 cases.  97% Cab Sauv and 3% Cab Franc.  Dusty, deeper black fruit with a sweet tinge on the nose.  On the palate, the tannins are not overpowering but they are definitely grippy.  The body is medium but may get heavier when everything integrates and settles down.  It finishes drier because of the tannin and the high acid.  Need to lay this down for a few years to melloe the tannins and allow the earthy/savoury character to come out more.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.larkmead.com/wine/dr-olmo&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Dr. Olmo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($150)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Not nearly as bright on the nose as the Firebelle or even the Cabernet Sauvignon from above.  This bottle of 100% Cabernet Sauvignon is much deeper, brooding even.  The black fruit on the nose opens up more over time and does feel a little cooked.  Grown in all gravel, the savoury quality is also clearer.  This serves as a good contrast to the Cabernet from earlier - this degree of complexity is my style.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.larkmead.com/wine/lmv-salon&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 LMV Salon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($150)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;60/40 Cabernet Sauvignon and Franc.  A little less bright than the 2015 Cabernet, but still has a good intensity of red fruit on the nose.  The mouthfeel and body feel a bit more ready for consumption than the 2015 Cabernet as well, but it still finishes with very fine and present tannin.  This is a lighter wine in general and is much more primary (fruit) in its aromas and flavors than the others.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Proprietary Red Blend&lt;/strong&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A nice, enjoyable wine that is 50/50 Cabernet Sauvignon and Malbec.  The nose is lighter, like a perfume fragrance that you are trying to suss out.  Serve this one a little more chilled than the others, but it’s also very smooth.  A light white rock dust on the nose adds to the complexity and the interest.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.larkmead.com/wine/cabernet-sauvignon&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2002 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I don’t know what the price is, but it’s definitely worth at least $100 more than the others.  That is what happens when the right wine ages well.  The nose is still very nice, fresh, fragrant, and light with a raisin quality that is starting to come out.  But the body/mouthfeel/acid/tannin are in perfect balance.  I wish I had a mirror to see my reaction when drinking this wine…  And it still has a great clean finish with its brick red color.  If I were to buy any wine I tasted today, it would be this one - I don’t know if I could wait 10+ years hoping for the other wines to reach this level.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is definitely balance between the old world style and new world style with these wines as the terroir really comes through along with medium(+) acidity that keeps the wines vibrant while achieving a ripeness found in the best Bordeaux vintages.  The price point of these wines might be a little higher than you may be used to, but they also demonstrate the little nuances that distinguish a $150 bottle from a $75 bottle.  I also think there is clear personality to the wines which make them seem unique as well.  My only concern is that most of these wines require a good amount of decanting if they are to be enjoyed right away.  Except that last bottle of course!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I did not walk away with any bottles or a membership, I do have a clear picture of where they rank next to other vineyards like Frank Family, Round Pond, and others whose Cabernets have hints of that dusty, Rutherford feel.  Even if you do not have the resources to purchase a case of the wine in the event you like it, I still recommend that you visit for a tasting to understand what is waiting for you when you can afford the nicer wines out there.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="calistoga" /><summary type="html">Another winery with a storied history longer than most (dating back to the late 1800s) that continues to produce top notch wines is Larkmead. Though unlike many others with the same length of history, Larkmead continues to be a small production winery, choosing to concentrate on quality over quantity as its 2013 The Lark (100pt by Wine Advocate) demonstrates. Its smaller size and simple-but-bright tasting room provides quite the contrast to Frank Family, which is right across the street. Both are located in Calistoga off the main highway, so there’s no reason not to visit either or both.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/larkmead/2.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Wine Membership Discussion</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/22/wine_membership_tips.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wine Membership Discussion" /><published>2018-11-22T14:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-22T14:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/22/wine_membership_tips</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/22/wine_membership_tips.html">&lt;p&gt;Happy Thanksgiving everyone!!!  I hope everyone is with family and/or friends celebrating over a nice, hot meal and a good bottle of wine.  Since this is a time for giving thanks, thank you, the readers, for following along on this deep dive into Napa wineries with a dose of Willamette Valley as well.  Soon, we will have a look at some in France, in case anyone is thinking of vacationing there at some point.  Some topics have continuously come up in feedback from you, so I’d like to take some time to write about one of them today: Wine Memberships.  Wine memberships is a broad topic and could be discussed in the context of several different segments of the wine industry - e.g. Wine Bars, Distributors/Wine Stores, Wineries.  Today we will focus the conversation on memberships as they pertain to wineries, but much of the same logic applies for other membership types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full discloser: I have been or recently became a member at several of the wineries I’ve written about so far.  This is not a coincidence - what better way to start writing than to write about things you really like?  My situation is a bit unusual though - I consume wine at a faster rate than most and use some of my membership wines for tastings with customers as well.  The normal consumer can likely handle around 3 memberships for various reasons discussed below, though if you handle 7 or more, I’d love to hear from you!!  We’ll discuss the pros/cons below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/wine-memberships/1-1050by788-e0df7c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/wine-memberships/1-700by525-e0df7c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/wine-memberships/1-675by506-e0df7c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/wine-memberships/1-450by338-e0df7c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/wine-memberships/1-525by394-e0df7c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/wine-memberships/1-350by263-e0df7c.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/wine-memberships/1-350by263-e0df7c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;I would live here&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It wouldn’t be a post about wine without a picture of a winery or vineyard in it. I decided to include one of my favorite shots of the Douro Valley in Portugal that wasn’t used in another post!  Don’t worry - we will discuss the wineries of the Douro at some point.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what are wine memberships and why do they exist?  Wine membership is a contract of sorts - it is a commitment from you (the consumer) to purchase a certain number of bottles at each allocation point during the year in return for benefits and other privileges that non-members do not have access to.  It’s obvious to understand why consumers participate, but why do wineries have these programs?  It’s all about the economics.  Each year, wineries invest a significant portion (for smaller ones, it can be all) of their available capital to produce the current vintage - the breakdown of these costs deserves its own article…  This is a huge risk - if all their capital is tied up in wine and they can’t sell that wine, or even if they can’t sell it at the rate that they need to in order to pay their bills, they will go under.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the basis of the “En Primeur” system in France, where large/famous estates (e.g. Lafite-Rothschild, Cheval Blanc) will sell futures in wine (you pay now for a bottle in 2-4 years) that is a lower price than what the wines will cost on release (when the wines are actually ready).  To some, this may seem like an ancient version of the “derivative” financial instrument and they would be right.  This is practiced much more efficiently today in the Agriculture industry (e.g. Corn Futures), but derivatives may never work for the wine industry as a whole.  That’s because no two wines taste the same or cost the same to produce.  If each product is slighly different, how can you manage to track the cost/value of each one to price the derivative?  Wine would need its own stock market!!  (That might be an idea…  Haha).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, that’s enough background from me - I always seem to excitedly dig into the history of wine.  Now that we know why membership programs benefit both the consumer and producer (and therefore know why they exist), let’s actually dig into more of the details for consumers.  Generally, the membership benefits at a given winery are a combination of the following.  Wineries may have incremental membership programs too where the more bottles you commit to buying, the greater the number of benefits and the degree of those benefits (e.g. price discount) are in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;list-of-potential-benefits-from-a-winery-membership&quot;&gt;List of Potential Benefits from a Winery Membership&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price Discount on Purchases&lt;/strong&gt; - Who doesn’t want to pay less for wine?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Free or Discounted Tours and Tastings at the Winery&lt;/strong&gt; - Again, who doesn’t want to pay less for wine?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Access to Limited Production Wines, Library Wines, and Larger Formats)&lt;/strong&gt; - This benefit is tailored to the wine collector types.  Those who crave the rare, highly rated, hard-to-access wines.  This definitely includes me to a degree, especially since I don’t want to wait 10 years when I buy a wine to drink it at its optimal point.  So I purchase library wines that have already undergone that aging in an optimal environment and are ready for consumption when I buy it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guaranteed Availability of Wines for Purchase&lt;/strong&gt; - Some wineries become so popular that their entire inventory is spoken for, even before they release the wine.  Sometimes in order to even get access to purchase they wine they produce, you need to join their wine club.  The most popular small producers, sometimes referred to as cult producers, may have waiting lists that last years before they have room for your allocation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discounted Shipping&lt;/strong&gt; - If you live far enough away from the winery, you’ll know that shipping isn’t cheap.  In addition, many things can go wrong during ground shipping and the storage they use that maybe you want to use 2-day or overnight shipping to make sure your expensive wine arrives in pristine condition.  This can cost its own small fortune.  Discounted/Free Shipping can sometimes be a bigger savings than the discounts they give you on their wines…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Access to Private Areas at the Winery&lt;/strong&gt; - In Napa, most larger wineries have special access areas that are available only to wine club members.  Some even may have different areas for different member levels.  If you are lucky enough to have a tasting in the owner’s tent out in the vineyards, you’ll know what I am talking about when I say this benefit means something (see my Chappellet Review for an example).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ability to Reserve the Winery for Private Events&lt;/strong&gt; - You and your friends probably need to live close to the winery to take advantage of this benefit.  Still, I can imagine having a great birthday party or wedding at one of my favorite wineries!  After all, it seems like the views from every winery is great and relaxing.  Though, imagining the cost of holding such events may be more nightmarish.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Invitation to Winery Events&lt;/strong&gt; - No event is more exciting at a winery than the annual release party.  It’s a chance to thank the wine gods for a good harvest, thank all of the winery’s employees for their hard work, and thank the consumers for purchasing the wine and making this annual cycle possible.  Access to this and other events (e.g. Some may host a summer bbq, a birthday party for the winery, etc.) is one of the lesser celebrated perks of being a winery member.  What I would give to not just get a picture with my winemaking idols, but to get one at a party with unbridled joy on both of our faces.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Less Thinking, More Drinking&lt;/strong&gt; - Do you have a problem choosing new wines every time you go to the store?  Do you just want to drink your favorite wine whenever you feel like it?  Do you forget to purchase that wine or find it’s not in your local stores?  A winery membership takes care of those problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;list-of-potential-drawbacks-from-a-winery-membership&quot;&gt;List of Potential Drawbacks from a Winery Membership&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commitment to Purchasing Bottles&lt;/strong&gt; - Remember, the reward for the winery is that you purchase a minimum amount of their wine.  While many winery memberships can be cancelled at any given time, if you want to continue to enjoy the perks, you will need to continue buying.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Winery Co-Location&lt;/strong&gt; - If you don’t live close to the winery, taking advantage of a majority of the membership benefits can be tough.  Living in DC, I can only take advantage of my membership benefits a couple times a year (e.g. free/discounted tastings), and some not at all (e.g. winery events).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decreased Desire/Ability to Explore&lt;/strong&gt; - Some people might not consider this a drawback but I do.  Part of what I love about the wine world is you never know what amazing wine you might drink tomorrow.  But if you are always going to the same wineries to take advantage of your membership benefits, you may not ever discover the amazing wine that is just down the street.  If you keep getting their shipments too, you may not have the money nor space in your wine rack to explore other places either…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexibility of Allocation Shipments&lt;/strong&gt; - It may be that you joined a winery to get access to their Cabernet Sauvignon, but come springtime, you will also receive the Sauvignon Blanc that you may not be fond of.  Many wineries are flexible in what gets shipped as part of your allocation, but some are not.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficult Discontinuing the Membership&lt;/strong&gt; - This may also be a drawback that only I feel, but I have cancelled a few winery memberships over the years and it was not easy.  It wasn’t that the winery made the process hard, but it felt very personal to do it.  When you discontinue a winery membership, depending on its size, it can feel like you are divorcing a friend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As long as the winery isn’t outside your price range (it’ll likely be more expensive than your local grocery store’s selection, but may be the right price point for nice dinners or celebrations), the drawbacks don’t really seem to impact you until you hit that third winery.  By then, you might be considering another winery membership, but may feel the need to discontinue a previous membership to make room in your budget and your cabinet.  In addition, you may find yourself needing to plan a schedule of which wineries to visit which weekends to take advantage of the membership perks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, there is no right answer.  Or put more accurately, there may be different answers for different people.  Just remember that when you drink that bottle of wine, many people contributed to getting that great juice into the bottle (and making the bottle too!).  As long as you are paying hommage to that fact and treat those people and their products with respect, you are entitled to desiring that they put every effort forward to getting you the best bottle of wine they can manage at that price point.  So get out there, visit some wineries, drinks some wines, give thanks to all of the people that contributed to those wines, and let the good times roll.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="tips" /><summary type="html">Happy Thanksgiving everyone!!! I hope everyone is with family and/or friends celebrating over a nice, hot meal and a good bottle of wine. Since this is a time for giving thanks, thank you, the readers, for following along on this deep dive into Napa wineries with a dose of Willamette Valley as well. Soon, we will have a look at some in France, in case anyone is thinking of vacationing there at some point. Some topics have continuously come up in feedback from you, so I’d like to take some time to write about one of them today: Wine Memberships. Wine memberships is a broad topic and could be discussed in the context of several different segments of the wine industry - e.g. Wine Bars, Distributors/Wine Stores, Wineries. Today we will focus the conversation on memberships as they pertain to wineries, but much of the same logic applies for other membership types.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/wine-memberships/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Cristom’s “The Cristom Experience” Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/17/cristom_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cristom's &quot;The Cristom Experience&quot; Private Tasting" /><published>2018-11-17T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-17T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/17/cristom_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/17/cristom_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;There are many exciting wineries to visit in the Portland / Willamette Valley area.  Although not as famous as Domaine Drouhin nor Argyle, Cristom is undoubtedly one of my favorites in the region, if not my absolute favorite.  Everything about Cristom screams family – from the shape/structure of the tasting room, to their candor and joy while conducting their tastings, to the accessible prices of their wines and your ability to taste anything (with the right appointment), to even the way they named the winery (named after the co-owners - Christine and Thomas).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/1-1050by788-201740.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/1-700by525-201740.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/1-675by506-201740.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/1-450by338-201740.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/1-525by394-201740.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/1-350by263-201740.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/1-350by263-201740.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Chainsaw Massacre&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Taking a chainsaw to the previously grafted section.  This way, they can re-plant a different varietal or a new clone of the same varietal on the rootstock.  It will be a couple years before they can harvest grapes from the new vines.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/2-1050by1400-37527d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/2-700by933-37527d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/2-675by900-37527d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/2-450by600-37527d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/2-525by700-37527d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/2-350by467-37527d.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/2-350by467-37527d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;TV Antennae&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A picture of the newly grafted vines.  The sealant used at the grafting point and the top of the new vines is to protect them from disease, since the point of the wounds can get easily infected.  Very cool to watch as everything was happening.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I happened to visit Cristom at a busy time too as they were in the middle of re-grafting a large section of their vineyard.  They were generous enough to bring me out into the field and explain their rationale for why they were changing their varietals and clones.  After walking through the fields and their storage facilities with their estate Viognier and Pinot in hand, we finally got to the main tasting event inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/3-1050by788-8a2763.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/3-700by525-8a2763.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/3-675by506-8a2763.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/3-450by338-8a2763.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/3-525by394-8a2763.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/3-350by263-8a2763.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/3-350by263-8a2763.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;VSP&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A great example of a vine planted for vertical shoot positioning (VSP).  A branch from last year’s growth is preserved through the winter where new vines will grow vertically from.  They will be tied to the trellis wires (above) and trained upwards to ensure good sun exposure and space for wind to blow through (after rain and lingering fog.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or so I thought.  We were interrupted by the owner of the winery himself who heard that I was dropping wine knowledge to my cousin and her husband.  He introduced himself, asked how I heard about Cristom (blind Pinot Noir tasting with WSET students), and asked what I thought about their operation.  I forgot my resume at home, but needless to say that we got along swimmingly.  We even took a picture together (see below).  There was no pretentiousness at this winery whatsoever, which is not to say other places I visited were - it’s just that everyone felt so relaxed and happy just drinking the wine.  This was only possible because the wine was that good…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/4-1050by1400-5ab802.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/4-700by933-5ab802.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/4-675by900-5ab802.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/4-450by600-5ab802.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/4-525by700-5ab802.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/4-350by467-5ab802.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/4-350by467-5ab802.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Lucky Me!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I was lucky enough to run into the owner and winegrower of Cristom: Tom Gerrie.  We shared a conversation for 15 minutes on our obsession with wine, our respect for Burgundy, and our outsized expectations for Willamette Valley’s future.  As much as I love exploring new places, I will definitely be visiting Cristom again when I return to Oregon!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if this was the actual lineup, or I got a few extra bottles because of the picture above, but I got to taste basically the entire inventory that Cristom had available at the time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2016-Estate-Viognier&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Estate Viognier&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($30)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2016-Mt--Jefferson-Cuv-e-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Mt. Jefferson Cuvée Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($35)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2014-Estate-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Estate Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($50)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2015-Eileen-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Eileen Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($65)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/14-Louise-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir-750ml&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Louise Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($60)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/14-Jessie-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir-750ml&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Jessie Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($60)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2015-Marjorie-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Marjorie Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($70)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2014-Carter-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Carter Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2014-Hirschy-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Hirschy Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2014-Canary-Hill-Vineyard-Pinot-Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Canary Hill Vineyard Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($55)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cristomvineyards.com/product/2015-Estate-Syrah&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Estate Syrah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($50)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I lost a lot of tasting notes from my trip to Oregon this past year.  But my biggest regret is losing the tasting notes for Cristom, because the Pinot Noirs were all so wonderfully diverse.  The best were the four ladies - Eileen Vineyard, Jessie Vineyard, Louise Vineyard, and Marjorie Vineyard.  With vines that average over 20 years in age and are rooted in mostly 10M+ year old Basalt soils, there is just so much complexity that develops on the vines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combining that with whole-cluster fermentation techniques observed in Burgundy, the Pinot Noirs here have character that is unique in the Willamette Valley.  The flavors are more traditional (e.g. red fruit that is lighter than cherry, but not unripe by any means) but different compared to Burgundy (e.g. on one of the wines, I clearly observed tomato leaf as an aroma).  As someone who enjoys cerebral wines, this had me running around in circles.  Though I know others with an open mind could just enjoy the wines as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/5-1050by788-6a06f5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/5-700by525-6a06f5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/5-675by506-6a06f5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/5-450by338-6a06f5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/5-525by394-6a06f5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/5-350by263-6a06f5.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cristom/5-350by263-6a06f5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Lucky Me!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Obligatory picture of the beautiful vineyards.  Luckily, my cousin Jennifer was asking really good questions, which allowed me to hang back at points and just enjoy the experience.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wine &amp;amp; Spirits Magazine found that Cristom is the “#1 Pinot Noir on restaurant wine lists in America” for two years running.  I’m not lucky enough to have restaurants near me with this on the menu, but I do imagine they would be fun to pair foods with.  To be safe, I walked away with a case of their wine - choosing several bottles of the Jessie and one of each of the rest I liked.  If you are in the area, Cristom needs to be on your list of wineries to visit.  It may be 15-20min south of the larger group of wineries, but you need to make this trip.  If you do and enjoy the wines as much as I do, be sure to tell them that Jeremy sent you.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="oregon" /><category term="willamette-valley" /><category term="eola-amity-hills" /><summary type="html">There are many exciting wineries to visit in the Portland / Willamette Valley area. Although not as famous as Domaine Drouhin nor Argyle, Cristom is undoubtedly one of my favorites in the region, if not my absolute favorite. Everything about Cristom screams family – from the shape/structure of the tasting room, to their candor and joy while conducting their tastings, to the accessible prices of their wines and your ability to taste anything (with the right appointment), to even the way they named the winery (named after the co-owners - Christine and Thomas).</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/cristom/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Domaine Drouhin Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/10/domaine_drouhin_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Domaine Drouhin Public Tasting" /><published>2018-11-10T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/10/domaine_drouhin_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2018/11/10/domaine_drouhin_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Starting a new winery is hard.  There are so many things to do on the operations side such as clearing out the field, adjusting the soil, planting and caring for the vines, etc.  But just as important as making the product is building a brand and fostering a consumer base that will purchase your product.  This is even harder when you are entering an established market like Willamette Valley.  Thankfully for Domaine Drouhin, they had the branding piece covered already when they established the winery in 1987 and have continued to add to their reputation and legacy from Burgundy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/1-1050by788-8be9e2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/1-700by525-8be9e2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/1-675by506-8be9e2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/1-450by338-8be9e2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/1-525by394-8be9e2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/1-350by263-8be9e2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/1-350by263-8be9e2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;Doorway to France&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The doorway to Oregon soil and French Soul&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I visited their tasting room in Beaune, France (capital of the Burgundy area) last year and had a great time.  Their Clos de la Roche Grand Cru from a magnum was crazy good, but more on that in its own review, haha.  Needless to say, I left impressed with their wines.  So when I heard that they had a sister winery in Willamette, you know I had to visit.  I didn’t quite know what to expect as I was driving to the vineyard.  But when I saw the winery, I just shook my head and told myself “of course it would be like this”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/2-1050by788-65f21e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/2-700by525-65f21e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/2-675by506-65f21e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/2-450by338-65f21e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/2-525by394-65f21e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/2-350by263-65f21e.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-drouhin/2-350by263-65f21e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; title=&quot;A look to the vines&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Wine is only as good as the vines/soil they come from.  A view off the patio into some of their nearby vines&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Owner of 225 acres in the heart of the Dundee Hills area, the winery itself is surrounded by seemingly endless rows of vines with no other structures in sight besides the road you took.  Inside, the place was packed with people.  Many picking up their bottle allocations, many there to sample the wines, and more people than I expected just enjoying a day at the vineyard with their family.  The wines themselves were an interesting mix of new world power with old world flavor profiles and acidity.  This tasting was right after lunch, so my palate was a little off-center, but I would firmly place the tasting in the good category.  The tasting consisted of the following wines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.domainedrouhin.com/2016_Arthur_Chardonnay&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 DDO Chardonnay Arthur&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($35)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The white flowers, balanced body and solid acidity reminded me of Burgundian whites, but the fruit profile was definitely riper (e.g. stonefruit) than what you would find at their French estate.  Not too over-the-top, this is a nice Chardonnay to casually drink.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.domainedrouhin.com/2015_Roserock_Pinot_Noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Roserock Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($35)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Roserock covered a higher range of flavors than I normally encounter at this price point in America, meaning you can drink this young or let it evolve a bit with a few years of aging.  Though I wouldn’t wait more than 3 or so.  Balanced with structure and levity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.domainedrouhin.com/2015_Pinot_Noir_Dundee_HIlls&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 DDO Pinot Noir Dundee Hills&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($45)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;There is a noticeable difference of structure and intensity between the Roserock and DDO Dundee Hills.  More red fruit here that is still young in the bottle, balanced, and a noticeably longer finish.  Some wood spice character is also starting to come out - you can age this for 5 years if you wanted.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.domainedrouhin.com/2015_Roserock_Zephirine&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Roserock Zephirine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($60)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;While the previous wines focused on the balance and fruit, the Zephirine takes you on a bit of a turn towards more complexity, particularly terroir driven notes (more vivid floral notes, lighter red fruit, but some wood spice and just a hint of cacao.  This can age even longer than the Dundee Hills (up to 8-10).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://store.domainedrouhin.com/2015_Laurene&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 DDO Pinot Noir Laurene&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($70)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This is where the complexity hits its peak in the tasting.  To the floral, light red fruit, and light spice character, now add riper fruit (e.g. Cherry) and more dusty character from the terroir.  This felt like the best expression of French and Oregon flavors and concepts of the bunch.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of their French roots, if I my schedule had allowed, I would’ve really liked to have done the “French Soul, Oregon Soil” tasting ($40) instead.  Conducted only at 10AM, they taste wines from their French and Oregon Estates to compare and contrast the Chardonnay and Pinot Noir flavors and characteristics.  Looking back at the tastings, I personally still prefer their French wine - there’s just a level of nuance they achieve with those wines that make them that much more cerebral and enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the $15 fee is very reasonable - The membership pricing and benefits (20% off or free shipping on 6 or more bottles for new memeber) are also pretty solid.  I did not bring back any bottles with me since there are so many good wineries in the area and my luggage was only so big.  However, I encourage you to put this place in your Top 5 of wineries to visit when in the region.  They definitely provide a unique perspective of the terroir in the area and the views are too good to ignore.  Just be prepared to wade through a mass of humanity on the weekend, haha.  Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="oregon" /><category term="willamette-valley" /><category term="dundee-hills" /><summary type="html">Starting a new winery is hard. There are so many things to do on the operations side such as clearing out the field, adjusting the soil, planting and caring for the vines, etc. But just as important as making the product is building a brand and fostering a consumer base that will purchase your product. This is even harder when you are entering an established market like Willamette Valley. Thankfully for Domaine Drouhin, they had the branding piece covered already when they established the winery in 1987 and have continued to add to their reputation and legacy from Burgundy.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/domaine-drouhin/1.jpg" /></entry></feed>