<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-10-15T19:33:05+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Wines By Jeremy</title><subtitle>Wines by Jeremy offers an educative and enjoyable personalized wine experience. Located in the DC metro area, Wines by Jeremy provides a number of services including in-home exclusive tastings, highly curated event tastings, educational events, and wine cellar consulting.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Bjornson Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/10/12/bjornson_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bjornson Private Tasting" /><published>2019-10-12T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-12T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/10/12/bjornson_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/10/12/bjornson_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Bjornson may not be a winery you think of when you hear Eola Amity Hills, but it needs to be.  The wines and wine ambassadors are capable of entertaining both wine novices and afficionados.  This may be the winery my cousin and I enjoyed the most equally.  For me, I was intrigued by the odd varietals (e.g. Gamay, Auxerrois) and the differing styles of Pinot why my cousin and her husband enjoyed the stories behind the wines and found appreciation for each by connecting them to the stories.  Whichever side of the spectrum you fall on, I guarantee that you’ll find a good, educational time at Bjornson.  And if you get Coach Barb as your wine ambassador, consider yourself lucky.  She’s awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/1-1050by788-84fb5e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/1-700by525-84fb5e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/1-675by506-84fb5e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/1-450by338-84fb5e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/1-525by394-84fb5e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/1-350by263-84fb5e.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/1-350by263-84fb5e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Winery&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Bjornson Winery.  As you can see, it is Certified Sustainable and it’s building looks amazing from the outside.  I used to have a rock wall that my father and I made to separate our yard from our neighbor’s.  I’ve seen better looking rock walls, but to turn that concept into a building and a winery no less?  I am 100% on board with that.  Tell me that’s not a gorgeous building!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I head out wine tasting, I love co-locating my tastings to minimize the amount of driving.  Smart, right?  Visiting Bjornson Vineyards was a side-effect of that methodology; it was a Eola Amity Hills tasting day.  The nice thing about that style of tasting is that you get to stumble upon wineries you normally wouldn’t go out of your way to visit.  Bjornson was that winery on this day trip and I am glad it was.  It’s just north and a little east from other well-known wineries in the region (e.g. Cristom), but when you get there, it feels like a world away.  You literally can’t hear anything getting out of your car on the property.  And that is a great feeling…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/2-1050by788-baba7d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/2-700by525-baba7d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/2-675by506-baba7d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/2-450by338-baba7d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/2-525by394-baba7d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/2-350by263-baba7d.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/2-350by263-baba7d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Inside&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The inside of the winery.  I think it looked fine - it’s hard to make the interior live up to an exterior like that.  The wine ambassaors were fun an very knowledgable.  Ours, who is talking to my cousin and her husband, is a former college women’s basketball coach who has retired and move on to her second love in life: wine.  Her anecdotes and stories were hilarious and really interesting.  We all had a great time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bjornson Vineyards is a relatively new winery - it’s first official vintage release was in 2009.  The vines were planted a few years before that and were producing fruit before the winery building was built and opened.  But from the portfolio of wines on their order form, you’d think they’ve been around for 30+ years.  The tastings are good QPR value; I think their cheapest tasting option is 6 wines for $20.  I was able to taste a couple other wines as I went for the more expensive option, but I think you’ll be happy with the wines no matter your choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/3-1050by788-d591e1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/3-700by525-d591e1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/3-675by506-d591e1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/3-450by338-d591e1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/3-525by394-d591e1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/3-350by263-d591e1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bjornson/3-350by263-d591e1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Their Vineyards&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Their vineyards outside of the winery, just across the street from the parking lot.  You can see that it starts to slope down on the edge to the left.  But it was just gorgeous out here, off the main road a little bit.  You couldn’t hear anything out here.  That was the thing that struck me the most.  It was just dead quiet getting out of the car and walking through the vineyard…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always say that most important factor to a good tasting experience (besides the wine) is the quality of your wine ambassador.  And if I had a ranking system for them, Coach Barb would be near the top.  After a career coaching in Collegiate Women’s Basketball, Coach Barb moved to Portland and began working with her second love: wine.  I’m jealous of her career and the fact that she followed her heart afterwards.  But her stories, her energy, her love and care for the topic all made us that much more interested in the wines, their character, and yes we all bought a couple bottles to go home with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one thing I picked up from Coach Barb (and I believe it) is that when people come visit the winery and do a tasting with her, they 99% of the time fall into one or more of four categories of wine drinkers: (1) The socializers that are at the winery as a social activity rather than for the wine itself; (2) The learners that are engaged and inquisitive and ask tons of questions all over the map; (3) The technical wine drinkers who want all of the winemaking decisions and fact sheets, whether or not they are talented enough tasters to track those decision in the profile of the wines; and (4) The palate hunters that don’t want to talk or do anything except taste and decide if it’s good or bad.  I definitely fall into many/all of these categories, but it’s interesting to listen to how she handles and tailors the tasting to each type of person.  Another lesson on my road to (hopefully) a future wine ambassador.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winery’s descriptions of the wines can be found on Bjornson’s website &lt;a href=&quot;https://bjornsonwine.com/wines/&quot;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;.  My tasting notes are below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2018 Auxerrois&lt;/strong&gt; ($22)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fermented in Acacia barrels and described as “Chardonnay’s sassy, flirty sister”.  Lemon, lime, some heat with other lighter yellow fruit (apple) on the nose.  On the palate, mouthwatering medium(+) acidity that is forward on the tongue and some alcohol burn on the cheeks.  Flavors of zesty, ripe lemon, cooked yellow apple, and unripe green pear.  The wine finishes crisp/clean, but the rebound comes back and flirts with you.  A very interesting wine that could use some time for integration.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Family Cuvee Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt; ($29)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Vintage that was hot late in the season.  Light garnet in color.  Bright but rich red fruit flavors of ripe cranberry, ripe strawberry, and cranberry.  The generous, candied red cranberry opens up over time.  Medium(+) intensity with aromatic lift.  The palate has that red fruit in lower intensity, with earth, minerality, toast, and baking spices that is integrated with the alcohol providing most of the finish.  A lighter-bodied Pinot that will keep you warm on a cool spring day.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Bjornson Estate Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt; ($29)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Hottest vintage on record but with late rains that lightened the concentration of the fruit.  The intensity of the red fruit (especially the ripe/partially baked cranberry) and the light white spice is slightly more intense than the 2014 above, but not quite pronounced.  The red fruit and white spice is the dominant force on the palate, with the minerality and toast just beginning to show.  Medium(+) acidity with a medium(+) finish.  This wine may lack complexity now compared to the 2014, but I would bet that this will be the better wine in 3 years.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Bjornson Estate Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt; ($29)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Released April 2019.  Hot growing season with late rain right before harvest.  Brambly/Barnyard character that wasn’t there on the previous two.  This may be the least intense of the three, but may have must been the most cloying as well.  Red fruit, fleshy plum, white spice, and some ripe tomato on the nose, but all balanced and fairly well integrated already.  Bright medium(+) acidity, medium(-) finish but length that extends across the tongue.  This has a lot of potential, but I have no idea what it will look like in a few years.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Pinot Noir BW#21003&lt;/strong&gt; ($45)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The only wine they still co-ferment and cold soak.  The very first label they made in 2009 from their first block of vines with many different clones since they were still figuring it out (Pommard, Dijon, etc.).  They couldn’t agree on a name for the wine, so they used their bonded winery number since it shows the breadth of what they are going for.  They made this wine as early as they did to beat a law bill that would have restricted them from building a tasting room if they weren’t producing wine by a certain point.  There is a complexity and depth on the nose in this vintage that easily surpasses their Estate Pinot.  There are additional notes of black fruit like cherry and raspberry, but not fully ripe with baking spices, cedar, and toast also on the palate.  Medium(-) body, but with medium(+) acid and medium tannin providing structure.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Pinot Noir Magnus&lt;/strong&gt; ($60)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Made from the Top 5 barrels of the vintage.  If the winemaker doesn’t think the quality is up to par for the vintage, they won’t make the Magnus.  This is the only vintage during which they’ve made it (that I know of).  Similar depth on the nose as the BW#21003, but a bit brighter with its red and black fruit (mostly red).  The flavors cover the entire palate and focus on the red fruit, baking spices, and cedar notes, but should evolve over the next 5-10 years thanks to the medium(+) acid and tannin.  The palate doesn’t have the same depth as the nose, but I’m hoping the development of tertiary flavors will add to that.  The finish lasts for a decent 20-25 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Reserve Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt; ($35)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Reserve Chardonnay spends 9 months in neutral oak, 5 months in once-used lightly toasted oak, then in twice-used lightly toasted oak.  It is almost as if they are gently massaging the oak into the wine.  On the nose, bright yellow fruit that feels fresh and just hints of MLF (butter and cream).  The palate emphasizes the fruit, cream, but not much vanilla or other barrel notes.  I was surprised to learn that this was all wood aged since it’s fairly reductive and has bright yellow fruit flavors.  Not quite as concentrated or viscous as others, but very enjoyable.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Gamay Noir&lt;/strong&gt; ($29)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Strong cherry notes, raisins, baking spices, other bright red fruit on the nose.  No bubble gum makes me think that this is Cru Beaujolais in style and not carbonic maceration.  There is some underlying yeast and citrus notes along with the strong red fruit.  The yeast/brioche detracts from the theme of the wine though, clashing with the cranberry and light cherry on the palate.  Without the yeast and with slightly more vanilla to go with the toast this has, this could be very nice.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With affordable wines like these, I see no reason not to stop by when you are in the area.  I highly recommend you find a way to try the Magnus as it’s quite a wine that would rate comparably to the best of them in Willamette.  I certainly will be stopping by here again in the future (next time, not by chance) and I hope you do too!  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="oregon" /><category term="willamette-valley" /><category term="eola-amity-hills" /><summary type="html">Bjornson may not be a winery you think of when you hear Eola Amity Hills, but it needs to be. The wines and wine ambassadors are capable of entertaining both wine novices and afficionados. This may be the winery my cousin and I enjoyed the most equally. For me, I was intrigued by the odd varietals (e.g. Gamay, Auxerrois) and the differing styles of Pinot why my cousin and her husband enjoyed the stories behind the wines and found appreciation for each by connecting them to the stories. Whichever side of the spectrum you fall on, I guarantee that you’ll find a good, educational time at Bjornson. And if you get Coach Barb as your wine ambassador, consider yourself lucky. She’s awesome.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/bjornson/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Siltstone Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/10/05/siltstone_winery_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Siltstone Public Tasting" /><published>2019-10-05T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-05T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/10/05/siltstone_winery_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/10/05/siltstone_winery_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;When choosing wineries to enroll as a member, there are many factors to look at: the wine quality, prices, bottle minimums, membership benefits, etc.  The most important factor for me is simple: do they treat you like family?  If the answer is “yes”, everything else will work itself out.  In the case of Siltstone Wines, this is almost literally true for me as the owners and I share the same family name.  Even if we didn’t though, I would love this winery all the same.  A family starting the winery from nothing, growing the grapes themselves, making the wines themselves, and sharing the wines themselves.  It’s everything I want to do in the future.  On top of everything, there is an energy and happiness that pervades the place - it makes you want to spend your afternoon there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/1-1050by788-a1621a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/1-700by525-a1621a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/1-675by506-a1621a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/1-450by338-a1621a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/1-525by394-a1621a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/1-350by263-a1621a.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/1-350by263-a1621a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Tasting Room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Siltstone winery almost looks like a roadside diner when you drive by it on the highway.  It can be easy to miss and if you do, don’t brake hard to try to make the turn into the entrance.  Relax and take your time.  That phrase embodies this winery in that it feels home.  And for me, it very well may be (need to take that 23-and-me test).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/2-1050by788-3a7bc7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/2-700by525-3a7bc7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/2-675by506-3a7bc7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/2-450by338-3a7bc7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/2-525by394-3a7bc7.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/2-350by263-3a7bc7.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/2-350by263-3a7bc7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;It's small inside&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The inside of their tiny tasting room.  If you look in the mirror, you can see it only takes 6 people to make the tasting room feel packed.  That and how long my reach is in order to take pictures, haha.  Don’t worry, there is an outdoor patio in the back to enjoy the wines more easily.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Siltstone tasting room is located just right off the highway – you can literally see and/or hear the cars drive by while at the winery and it’s very easy to accidentally miss the entrance while driving to the winery.  Once you get over those two things, it’s smooth sailing from there as the winery itself is super laid back, but also filled with people who care about what they do since it truly is their livelihood.  And with the care that they show every customer, you truly do get the feel of family…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/3-1050by788-4692e1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/3-700by525-4692e1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/3-675by506-4692e1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/3-450by338-4692e1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/3-525by394-4692e1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/3-350by263-4692e1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/3-350by263-4692e1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;My cousin&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;My cousin Jennifer at our table on the back patio.  The facility may not be up to your normal standards, but the hospitality is second to none.  There is a meat-and-cheese table in the back that you can help yourself to, the wine ambassadors will come outside to your table to pour the next wine on the tasting list, and the atmosphere/conversation is very jovial.  The roof extension helps protect your from the summer sun and fall rains.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My brother happened to find Siltstone during his research for his honeymoon (he surprised his wife with a weekend in Willamette before heading to the Bahamas as they are both Pinot-philes).  After he gave me his impression of the place and a couple bottles of the J. Myers and Sons upon his return, I knew I had to stop by the next time I visited Portland.  I called ahead to schedule an appointment and let them know my availability like I normally do.  Once I explained the story of why I was visiting (my sister-in-law barely had time to take off her makeup from the wedding in Cleveland), the offered to open up the winery just for me.  Luckily, that wasn’t necessary after some schedule tweaking on my end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/4-1050by788-0eac8c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/4-700by525-0eac8c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/4-675by506-0eac8c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/4-450by338-0eac8c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/4-525by394-0eac8c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/4-350by263-0eac8c.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/4-350by263-0eac8c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Parking Lot&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;As you can see, the parking lot extends right up to the edge of the vines.  This is family winery that wasn’t founded with millions of dollars.  It was built from scratch to what it is today, so I can appreciate these small details.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I arrived, the first two things I noticed was that it was a really small place and it was crazy busy.  Though, everyone there seemed to be a local, rather than an out-of-towner.  The tasting room manager, Heather, had given birth only 10 days ago was already back pouring wines while her mother-in-law cared for her baby on the tasting patio (there was a mini-crowd around the baby).  The tasting room inside is small as you can see from my picture, but they had additional seats outside in the back.  You can choose to going inside every time you need another pour or they will walk around with bottles, check on everyone’s progress.  It just allows you to be very relaxed (lazy, even) and enjoy the wines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/5-1050by788-6a6661.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/5-700by525-6a6661.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/5-675by506-6a6661.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/5-450by338-6a6661.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/5-525by394-6a6661.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/5-350by263-6a6661.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/5-350by263-6a6661.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;First Person View&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A first-person view of the patio.  You can see the sign over the door that was made from the top of a barrel, the coal-fires outside to keep the patrons warm in the fall, and the fact that most of the tables were full (people seemed to know about this place).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Putting aside the ambiance of the place and looking at the vineyards, all of the Myers family vines are farmed Certified Sustainable. Joel Myers (why their Grand Vin is called J. Myers and Sons) first planted grapes in the 1960s by himself.  Today, the winery produces about 1,500 cases of wine (miniscule amount) under the Siltstone label from the Guadalupe Vineyard, Blacktail Vineyard, and Owl Ranch Vineyard.  A limited quantity of their premium Pinot noir label, J. Myers &amp;amp; Sons, is blended from select barrels after exceptional vintages (I only saw a 2012 and 2014 at the winery).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/6-1050by1400-4e25a1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/6-700by933-4e25a1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/6-675by900-4e25a1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/6-450by600-4e25a1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/6-525by700-4e25a1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/6-350by467-4e25a1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/siltstone/6-350by467-4e25a1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;With the Founder&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;With the man that started it all at Siltstone.  The Myers family owns and operates the winery, while the grand vin is named after him and the family: “J. Myers &amp;amp; Sons”.  It is a coincidence that my father’s name, my brother’s name, and my name is J. Myers, but it is a pretty amazing one.  Since the label seemed tailor-made for us, I bought a case to share with my family…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But wines need to be good to want to visit a winery right?  So let’s look at the wines!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Owl Ranch Sauvignon Blanc&lt;/strong&gt; ($15)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Smoke, flint, baked yellow apple, and cream on the nose.  Same notes on the palate with a bit more cream and sheep cheese funk.  It definitely feels like the wine underwent some MLF or at least had a good amount of time on the lees.  A unique style of Sauvignon Blanc that doesn’t align with any of the established styles - very interesting.  Probably not your crisp, cool wine on a hot day, but I could see this served a bit colder with dairy products.  Not my favorite, but could be a great fit for others that like their exotic cheeses.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Blacktail Pinot Gris&lt;/strong&gt; ($15)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Ripe green and yellow apple/pear on the nose with other citrus notes such as orange peel, orange blossom and ripe grapefruit.  Similar flavors appear on the palate, but the length doesn’t go past the mid-palate and has a medium finish with its green fruit.  This is a much easier-drinking wine than the Owl Ranch Sauvignon Blanc and has enough intensity initially to pair with some white-meat driven meals.  Serve chilled to maximize the acidity and leave your palate with a clean finish.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Willamette Valley Rose&lt;/strong&gt; ($11)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;100% Pinot Noir, picked early with a higher pH from the vineyard right behind the tasting room.  Direct press to steel tank and then into the bottle after fermentation.  Light aromas of cranberry and strawberry, but more pronounced were the notes of oranges, grapefruit, and some stonefruit character.  Medium(+) acidity with similar flavors as the nose, but they are all fairly integrated together and the medium(-) intensity makes it hard to pull them apart.  The pink grapefruit was the strongest among them.  Medium finish with integrated alcohol that added to the body.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Willamette Valley Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt; ($17)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Their easy-drinking table Pinot Noir.  Cranberry, cedar, mulch, white spice, and some bell pepper on the nose.  The palate also presents medium(+) intensity flavors of cranberry, cedar and white spice, though it’s starting to hint at black pepper.  Medium intensity with a medium finish, but a medium(-) body makes me imagine serving this a little chilled outside with hot dogs.  Not much green pepper on the palate, but I would recommend this to friends that want more spice in their Pinot than the traditional cherry-flavored, ripe Pinots.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Guadalupe Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt; ($30)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Riper cranberry than the Willamette Valley Pinot Noir, with notes of strawberry and cherry in there too.  On the palate, the fruit feels a bit more baked thanks to the medium acid, the medium(+) alcohol, and the baking spices on the palate.  There are tertiary notes of leather, cedar, and toast as well.  Even at 6 years, the wine already feels very integrated with both its flavors and tannin/alcohol.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2011 Guadalupe Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt; ($30)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is a bit more subdued than the 2013, likely due to the extra 2 years in age.  On the palate, although the intensity is medium, the length has increased on the palate and leaves you with a finish of cranberry, baking spices and a touch of cedar.  The medium(+) acid is well integrated with the brooding fruit, providing lift for its age and adding some brightness while not seeming over-the-top.  This wine is drinking very nicely right now, which leads me to believe the 2013 will continue to improve.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 J. Myers &amp;amp; Sons Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt; ($45)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;2x barrel select of the Guadalupe in only the best vintage years (50 cases a year when they make it).  2012 and 2014 are the only ones currently available.  Take the notes of the Guadalupe above and imagine an added richness, a bit more ripeness (some cherry and plum now too), an undertone of wet earth / mulch, and you get this wine.  Drinking wonderfully right now, this wine also shows good length, spice that is integrated with the core of the fruit, and a medium(+) finish.  If you like a tertiary character in your Pinot, this will be $40 well spent.  Though, I do own 1% of the 2012 and 2014 vintages now, haha.  So it may be hard to find!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want a place in Willamette that is popular to the locals and relatively unknown to the outsiders, I recommend stopping by Siltstone.  The wine quality will not be on the same level of Cristom or Beaux Freres, but the experience will be as good or better and the wines will be much more affordable.  Just be sure that you have enough self-control to not each everything at the charcuterie and cheese table, haha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you do stop by, say “hello” for me!  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="oregon" /><category term="willamette-valley" /><category term="dundee-hills" /><summary type="html">When choosing wineries to enroll as a member, there are many factors to look at: the wine quality, prices, bottle minimums, membership benefits, etc. The most important factor for me is simple: do they treat you like family? If the answer is “yes”, everything else will work itself out. In the case of Siltstone Wines, this is almost literally true for me as the owners and I share the same family name. Even if we didn’t though, I would love this winery all the same. A family starting the winery from nothing, growing the grapes themselves, making the wines themselves, and sharing the wines themselves. It’s everything I want to do in the future. On top of everything, there is an energy and happiness that pervades the place - it makes you want to spend your afternoon there.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/siltstone/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Evening Land Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/09/28/evening_lands_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Evening Land Private Tasting" /><published>2019-09-28T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-28T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/09/28/evening_lands_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/09/28/evening_lands_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;I strongly prefer tasting bottles at the winery rather than at in-town tasting rooms.  Unfortunately, I was in a bit of a rush, so I gladly made an exception here because when I think of Oregon Chardonnay, I think of Evening Springs.  If you’ve had a bottle of wine from Oregon (specifically around the Willamette Valley), chances are it was a Pinot Noir.  There are several other varietals grown in the region, but none are known for being as good a fit with the terroir as Pinot Noir.  However, once you taste the La Source here, you’ll be adding Chardonnay to that list.  I would confidently put La Source in a blind tasting against the best that America has to offer and it’s not even their best bottling (Summum).  I don’t care if you visit the tasting facility or not; just make sure to try these wines!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/1-1050by788-9d9cf1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/1-700by525-9d9cf1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/1-675by506-9d9cf1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/1-450by338-9d9cf1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/1-525by394-9d9cf1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/1-350by263-9d9cf1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/1-350by263-9d9cf1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Tasting Room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Their tasting room in Dundee, right off the main highway.  There are several winery tasting room located in the same building, so it’s not a bad idea to just setup tastings with all the wineries there over the course of the afternoon.  I’m sure the location in town helps generate foot traffic.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/2-1050by788-fd9d99.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/2-700by525-fd9d99.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/2-675by506-fd9d99.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/2-450by338-fd9d99.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/2-525by394-fd9d99.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/2-350by263-fd9d99.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/2-350by263-fd9d99.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Their room in the building&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The entrance to their room in the building.  They opened at 10am, so we needed to wait a bit before we were able to enter and start our tasting.  I’ll admit, waiting for them to open was tough, especially since you could see into the room and imagine yourself drinking wine inside it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first things you’ll notice when looking up Evening Springs is that they migrated up to Eola Amity Hills from Sonoma in 2007.  The fact that both locations both produce similar varietals (e.g. Pinot Noir, Chardonnay) gives you confidence that they know what they are doing, even if they were officially established only 10+ years ago.  And even for a winery so young, all of the grapes for their wines come from their Seven Springs Vineyards.  Though, not all of the grapes are up to their desired quality level, so they maintain a secondary label (Salem Wine Company) for their declassified grapes.  I respect wineries that are picky about their grapes and the quality of their wines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/3-1050by788-0010b8.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/3-700by525-0010b8.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/3-675by506-0010b8.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/3-450by338-0010b8.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/3-525by394-0010b8.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/3-350by263-0010b8.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/3-350by263-0010b8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;In at Last&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I not generally a fan of gray but the theme works very well inside this tasting room.  Like really, really well.  There was outdoor seating through the back if you prefer it, but I highly recommend staying in the tasting room…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a subscription to Wine Spectator, you may recognize the Evening Land label.  After all, the 2012 La Source Pinot Noir scored 98 points and landed as #3 on Wine Spectator’s World Top 100 wines in 2015.  And not criticize, but the two wines that ranked higher both received a lower score than the La Source and were more expensive than the La Source.  So in my book and maybe others’, the 2012 La Source was the best wine in 2015 according to Wine Spectator.  They don’t quite have the cult following, and therefore the high prices, of other wineries.  So this is your chance to get excellent quality wine at reasonable prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/4-1050by1400-ddbffe.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/4-700by933-ddbffe.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/4-675by900-ddbffe.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/4-450by600-ddbffe.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/4-525by700-ddbffe.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/4-350by467-ddbffe.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/4-350by467-ddbffe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;La Source Pinot&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The La Source Pinot Noir pictured here was really good, but it was the La Source Chardonnay that stole the show for me.  It could be that I just had a lot of good Pinot Noir from multiple producers over the weekend and this was the first surprising Chardonnay of them all.  But I don’t think you can go wrong between either of the Pinot or Chardonnay.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see from the pictures and my descriptions, I really liked their tasting room.  Clean, classic, good color scheme, and good background music choices.  As we started chatting with the wine ambassador, we learned that the winemaker felt the 2016s were the best chardonnays he has ever made.  That is a powerful statement and just made me thirstier.  Before we get to the tasting notes below, I do want to clarify that to have your tasting at their winery, you need to pay a $65 tasting fee per person and agree to a suggested 6-bottle purchase.  If someone does take the winery tour and enjoy it, please let me know and I may need to return!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/5-1050by1400-841503.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/5-700by933-841503.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/5-675by900-841503.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/5-450by600-841503.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/5-525by700-841503.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/5-350by467-841503.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/evening-land/5-350by467-841503.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Map on the Label&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I thought this was a pretty cool thing to do with their label.  They included a minature map of the Eola Amity Hills AVA region and marked the location of their vineyards.  It may take a bit of knowledge about the region to fully appreciate the information, but the label design just looks cool regardless.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the wines!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2018 Seven Springs Rose of Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt; ($28)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Made from younger vines in Eola Amity Hills.  Beautiful, clear pink color.  The nose is filled with aromas of unripe peaches, plum, and green apple.  The alcohol is present and blended with granny-smith apples as well as pink fruit on the palate.  The medium(+) acid provides structure and gradually builds on the palate.  Medium length finish of pink fruit with minerality and the acid providing a mouthwatering effect.  It’s what you look for in a rose.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eveninglandvineyards.com/product/2017-La-Source-Pinot-Noir-3-Pack&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 La Source Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pinot Noir from top of the vineyard hillside (350-650 ft in elevation).  Up there at the highest point, vines are stressed from the wind and the thin, rocky soil.  Because of the reduced yields, they produce only 350 cases of this wine a year.  30% Whole Cluster Fermentation, and 40% new French oak.  The nose is rich with strawberry and cranberry dominating, but also raspberry and cedar present.  Soft and smooth medium tannin, medium(+) acid, and medium(+) intensity of fresh, red fruit (ripe cranberry, lighter cherry).  You can feel the green on the palate from the whole cluster fermentation that also adds some complexity and depth on the finish.  Medium(-) body, but it has good medium(+) length.  A nice, lighter styled Pinot.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eveninglandvineyards.com/product/2018-Gamay-Noir-3-Pack&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Seven Springs Vineyard, Gamay Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($35)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The first cuttings of Gamay came over in the 1980s and were planted at Seven Springs in 2003.  They are aiming for the Cru Beaujolais style with this wine, though there are only 2 acres left due to phylloxera in the older vines.  Cranberry in color, the nose has notes of bright, unripe cranberry and some hints of terroir+funk, but the palate is more brooding in style with white pepper, wet earth, dried cranberry, and toast.  Medium(+) acidity balances the brooding style and makes this a very interesting wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eveninglandvineyards.com/product/2017-Seven-Springs-Chardonnay-3-Pack&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Seven Springs Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($35)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Chardonnay is 1/3 of their production.  They might even tell you that it’s their focus - they want to get their planting to 50/50 with Pinot Noir.  This wine is from 2013 vines, a young block.  Seven Springs aims for more acidity by picking grapes early, based on their acidity level.  For this wine, they use once-used barrels, 5L puncheons, MLF, and some lees aging with 1000 cases produced.  On the nose, yellow apple, brioche, cream, and butter leap out with pronounced intensity.  On the medium-bodied palate, that intensity continues with some popcorn and yellow pear also coming through with beautiful medium(+) acid that continues through the finish.  13.5% ABV, but provides some warmth on exhale.  This is a beautiful chardonnay that could be mistaken with Burgundy if there was a bit more minerality and length (it only makes it to the mid-palate).  But very impressive from vines so young.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Blanc de Blanc Sparkling Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt; ($65)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This Blanc de Blanc spent 33-36 months in tirage with no dosage in a Brut Nature style.  Pronounced nose of yellow apple and pear with medium(+) acidity, but not biting or tight at all – it’s actually rather soft.  They have a single foudre going that has different vintages in it and may eventually move to a Solera-like styled system.  I really liked the texture of the wine and bubbles, though this was opened yesterday, so that may have added to the softness.  The winemaker also wants the staff to start serving this after decanting as it changes the wine a lot.  Only 170 cases made.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eveninglandvineyards.com/product/2016-La-Source-Chardonnay-3-Pack-Copy&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 La Source Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;From near the top of the vineyard, the La Source Chardonnay comes from just below the Summum Chardonnay vines.  Up there, the grapes are very different, so the winemaker creates two different wines by tasting the grapes as they come in.  Once he’s sees a change in the character, that marks the cutoff for La Source.  The wine spends 12 months in 100% new Austrian puncheons that have a light toast.  Compared to the Seven Springs Chardonnay, this wine has a bit more reduction going on and a depth to the MLF/lees/toast notes.  You can spend minutes on the aromatics of this wine.  The reduction taps down any overbearing/unctuous fruit notes, but only works if the wines are less ripe and not overpowering already.  This wine was so impressive to me that I had to buy a bottle to bring back, along with the Seven Spring Chardonnay for comparison.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I brought back both a bottle of the La Source Chardonnay and the Seven Springs Chardonnay.  The La Source I want to blind taste with some more expensive bottles and friends.  The Seven Spring Chardonnay is a potential QPR darling.  But you may find that the La Source Pinot Noir is the crown jewel and that a case needs to go home with you.  The only way to tell is to visit yourself!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the next time you visit Willamette and find yourself in the town of Dundee, make sure to visit before grabbing that meal in town.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="oregon" /><category term="willamette-valley" /><category term="eola-amity-hills" /><summary type="html">I strongly prefer tasting bottles at the winery rather than at in-town tasting rooms. Unfortunately, I was in a bit of a rush, so I gladly made an exception here because when I think of Oregon Chardonnay, I think of Evening Springs. If you’ve had a bottle of wine from Oregon (specifically around the Willamette Valley), chances are it was a Pinot Noir. There are several other varietals grown in the region, but none are known for being as good a fit with the terroir as Pinot Noir. However, once you taste the La Source here, you’ll be adding Chardonnay to that list. I would confidently put La Source in a blind tasting against the best that America has to offer and it’s not even their best bottling (Summum). I don’t care if you visit the tasting facility or not; just make sure to try these wines!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/evening-land/3.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">King Family Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/09/21/kings_family_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="King Family Private Tasting" /><published>2019-09-21T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-21T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/09/21/kings_family_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/09/21/kings_family_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ll admit, when I heard of how King Family Vineyards got its start as a winery, I was hoping they wouldn’t be good.  But after tasting their wines and visiting their winery, I must admit that they are among the elite in Virginia, both in terms of their wine quality and the quality of their facilities/staff.  The wines were so good in fact that I left with a case…  If your budget allows for wines in the $30-$40 range and you can make a weekend trip to the Charlottesville area, King Family needs to be on your itinerary.  Just be prepared to taste wines that are almost Bordeaux-like in complexity, integration, and deliciousness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/1-1050by788-3333f1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/1-700by525-3333f1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/1-675by506-3333f1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/1-450by338-3333f1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/1-525by394-3333f1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/1-350by263-3333f1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/1-350by263-3333f1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Group Photo&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Group photo with the Shenendoah range in the background.  I must say, it was beautiful walking outside behind the winery and tasting room.  As you can see, King Family keeps everything well manicured, building upon the prestige of its wines.  Being at King Family makes you want to put on a seersucker suit and class it up.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/2-1050by788-25fc4e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/2-700by525-25fc4e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/2-675by506-25fc4e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/2-450by338-25fc4e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/2-525by394-25fc4e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/2-350by263-25fc4e.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/2-350by263-25fc4e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Walking the Vineyards&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Getting a tour and explanation of their vineyards.  As you can see, they use double guyot and vertical shoot positioning to both provide a little shade for the grapes and help air out the grapes after rains (prevent powdery mildew).  Because the vines group in a flat open area, they achieve riper flavors than other Virginia wineries.  Who knew that good Polo land could also make for good vineyard land?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I mentioned it in the intro, I feel like I need to elaborate.  Why didn’t I like King Family coming in?  Well, it was jealousy.  King Family Vineyards was established in 1998.  A little before then, the King family moved from Texas to Virginia, looking for a flat piece of land to purchase on which they could play Polo each week.  They had no intention of making wine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/3-1050by788-78425d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/3-700by525-78425d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/3-675by506-78425d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/3-450by338-78425d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/3-525by394-78425d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/3-350by263-78425d.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/3-350by263-78425d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Public Tasting Room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The public tasting room at King Family.  Again, that dark-brown wood, clean-but-classy theme really resonates with me.  There is a gift shop with lots of memorabilia to shop from as well.  If you get a tour-and-tasting package, you’ll get to experience a different part of the building.  And in case you are hungry, there is food for purchase as well.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The land that they purchased was covered in alfalfa originally.  Once they cleaned up the field and established their Polo stadium, a VA Tech alumnus from the wine program suggested that they try growing grapes with the rest of the land.  Soon after the suggestion, a terrible drought swept through Virginia and they family decided they needed to plant a crop that would withstand those conditions (perfect for grapes!).  To say that this decision worked out for them is an understatement.  Their land feels a bit like the Napa valley during the summer - there is plenty of sunshine and heat in this area next to the mountains that help the grapes achieve sugar and phenolic ripeness that surpasses most other wineries in the state.  Ripe for Virginia is still more like Bordeaux than Napa, but it’s enough to make wines that consistently end up in the Governor’s Case (the Top 12 wines of the VA Govenor’s Cup make it into the Govenor’s Case - it’s even more elite than a gold medal at the competition).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/4-1050by788-11e30d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/4-700by525-11e30d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/4-675by506-11e30d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/4-450by338-11e30d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/4-525by394-11e30d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/4-350by263-11e30d.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/4-350by263-11e30d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Backroom&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The private tasting room in the back of the winery.  If you are a larger group, I highly recommend doing the tour-and-tasting if only to enjoy your wine in peace and quiet.  You also can get your pours whenever you are ready and can revisit any wines that you would like.  There were multiple wines I got multiple pours of because they were so good…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They opened the winery in 2002, which at the time was a shack along the side of the road.  In 2019, they have 50 acres under management, which is just about the maximum they want to manage, so don’t be surprised when their production starts to level off.  Still, that’s 12,000 cases of wine a year that the world gets to enjoy.  Like most other wineries, they purchase some grapes as well in order to fulfill the demand they have - about 75% of the grapes are from their vineyards and 25% is purchased from other wineries in the Monticello AVA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/5-1050by788-e90270.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/5-700by525-e90270.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/5-675by506-e90270.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/5-450by338-e90270.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/5-525by394-e90270.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/5-350by263-e90270.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/king-family/5-350by263-e90270.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Their vault&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Their “vault” of previous vintages and special bottlings.  Luckily, I had a chance to walk in a pull a couple bottles.  The King Family catalog and history is more expansive than I thought.  I started a vault of their wines on my own (I purchased a case of wines).  The wines at the top are all medal winners from the VA Govenor’s Cup.  As you can see, they are well decorated…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, the two eldest son run the vineyards and the youngest son makes the wine.  But once a week on Sunday mornings, the family gets together and plays Polo (I think club members and family friends are invited to as well).  How does that sound for a Sunday?  Playing Polo in the morning and enjoying really good wine in the afternoon, staring at all of your wine awards…  Like I said, I’m jealous.  But there is just no denying the quality that’s coming out of this winery, as you’ll see below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.kingfamilyvineyards.com/product/Viognier-2018&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Viognier&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($27)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Medium intensity of peach, honeysuckle, and other stonefruit on the nose with some vanilla.  There’s also lemon and unripe yellow apple in the profile too.  On the palate, the ripe stonefruit flavors and pineapple/mango tropical fruit come through with pronounced intensity.  Medium finish with medium(+) body, acid, and alcohol.  This wine is very fresh and will warm you up gradually, making it a good summer AND spring/fall wine.  A very nice rendition of Viognier and no faults I can tell.  I made sure to grab 3 bottles, especially at the $27 price point…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.kingfamilyvineyards.com/product/Chardonnay-2018&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($28)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Medium(+) intensity of butter, cream, toast, green and yellow apple, lemon and yogurt.  On the palate, medium body and acid with pronounced intensity of lemon, toast, butter, cream, and yellow apple.  The medium length finish leaves you with a medium(+) alcohol heat, but it’s not unpleasant if you are in a cooler environment (Spring/Fall).  A solid Chardonnay that clearly displays the winemaker’s techniques without going too over-the-top.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.kingfamilyvineyards.com/product/Cros--2018&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2018 Crose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($21)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Medium salmon in color.  Medium(+) intensity aromas of cranberry, strawberry, red apple, peach, ripe pear, and a bit of honeysuckle.  On the palate, medium body, medium acid, and a phenolic bitterness / unripe lemon flavor pinches the jaw a bit.  Other flavors include unripe cranberry and strawberry at medium(+) intensity along with a few of the other notes found on the nose.  My least favorite of the wines, but apparently their biggest selling wine.  Am I the crazy one?  Or does everyone just need their Rose…?  Interesting to find a Merlot rose in Virginia though!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.kingfamilyvineyards.com/product/Merlot-2017&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Merlot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($28)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Deep ripe red fruit including cherry, cranberry, red currant, and even a bit of rhubarb with some baking spices and toast.  Even at a young age, the wine is showing good integration and complexity on the nose.  On the palate, medium body, high acid, medium(+) tannins that take time to build up, medium(+) alcohol, and bright (almost unripe) red fruit that is seen on the nose.  The nose is riper than the palate, and that difference will only be enhanced in the future when some of the tertiary character comes out more (you can already detect some forest floor coming).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.kingfamilyvineyards.com/product/Cabernet-Franc&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Small-Batch Cabernet Franc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($35)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose has a similar red fruit profile to the Merlot, but brighter with more ripe strawberry and even hints of kirsch and plum.  On the palate, the fruit profile is similar in intensity and ripeness (not fully ripe red fruit) to the nose.  The medium tannins are already so soft and the med(+) acid doesn’t pique too much.  The medium(+) finish is fantastic without pyrazine detractors but instead with herbal mint notes  and the medium(+) alcohol is well-integrated into the fruit.  I don’t know if you’ll believe me when I write that I could taste the whole-cluster fermentation impact on the flavors and texture of the wine.  You’ll just need to see for yourself.  A truly complex, cerebral, fine Cabernet Franc rendition.  I bought 3 bottles.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.kingfamilyvineyards.com/product/Meritage-2017&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Meritage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($36)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Their flagship wine.  The medium(-) intensity nose makes me think the wine is a little closed down early in its life or it needs to decant for a bit to open up.  The profile is a blend of the Cabernet Franc and Merlot described above (as you might expect from a blend of the actual two wines), with some tertiary hints already showing.  Smooth medium(+) tannins that take time to build up, medium(+) acid that is well integrated with the tannin and flavors that reveal themselves on the finish.  Very subtle, but there is depth and the medium(+) finish portends great things.  Such a pleasure to drink now, but I need to try and hold off and see how it evolves.  It will likely age the longest of all their wines as well.  I got 5 bottles of this to track it’s aging.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can tell from the tasting notes above, I was very impressed by not just the ripeness level the wines were able to achieve, but the complexity that came from deftly integrating the herbal notes into the profile.  If I took a group through the Charlotteville area again, this would need to be on the itinerary, but you don’t have to wait for me to experience the wines yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So take a weekend, enjoy Jefferson’s Estate at Monticello, then go have some excellent wine.  And if you have a horse and Polo gear, give them a call and ask if you can bring them too, haha.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="virginia" /><category term="monticello" /><category term="crozet" /><summary type="html">I’ll admit, when I heard of how King Family Vineyards got its start as a winery, I was hoping they wouldn’t be good. But after tasting their wines and visiting their winery, I must admit that they are among the elite in Virginia, both in terms of their wine quality and the quality of their facilities/staff. The wines were so good in fact that I left with a case… If your budget allows for wines in the $30-$40 range and you can make a weekend trip to the Charlottesville area, King Family needs to be on your itinerary. Just be prepared to taste wines that are almost Bordeaux-like in complexity, integration, and deliciousness.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/king-family/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Grace Estate Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/09/14/grace_estate_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Grace Estate Public Tasting" /><published>2019-09-14T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-14T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/09/14/grace_estate_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/09/14/grace_estate_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;The first review of a winery in my home state: Virginia.  Although I’ve never visited Grace Estate nor had their wine until this weekend, I’m glad this happened to be my first review.  There are two things I look for in wineries: (1) Is the wine quality on point? (2) Is it relatively off people’s radar?  If the answers to both are “yes”, you’ll have at least one intrigued customer coming to visit you.  Each one of the wines poured during the tasting at Grace Estate were unique, cerebral, and pretty good.  Combined with a nicely designed tasting room that feels like home rather than a Napa spaceship, I had a really nice time visiting for a couple hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/1-1050by788-cf0f71.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/1-700by525-cf0f71.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/1-675by506-cf0f71.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/1-450by338-cf0f71.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/1-525by394-cf0f71.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/1-350by263-cf0f71.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/1-350by263-cf0f71.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Group Picture!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The first stop of the day during our wine tour in Charlottesville.  On the weekdays, there are some places you can have to yourself and then there are some that will always be busy.  Although this was the former, we really enjoyed the tasting room and the wines.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/2-1050by788-14967d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/2-700by525-14967d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/2-675by506-14967d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/2-450by338-14967d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/2-525by394-14967d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/2-350by263-14967d.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/2-350by263-14967d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Close-up&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The close-up shot of our group.  Everyone had flown in from NYC the night before and spent the weekend at an AirBnB in Charlottesville.  They all agreed it was a beautiful weekend and that they had a lot of fun in Charlottesville.  I wonder how much traffic overall they get from NYC fliers…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many other wineries in Virginia, Grace Estate is a family-owned business.  But unlike many other Virginia wineries that purchase grapes to some degree to produce their wines, the wines of Grace Estate are 100% estate-grown and estate-bottled.  And we aren’t talking about a small amount of land or grapes either.  Grace Estate owns over 450 acres of land and 50 acres of it are visible from their Tasting room (Mt. Juliet Farm).  I also appreciate how the Grace Family’s residence is on the grounds - they live with their vines and wine.  If I owned a winery, I would certainly want to!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/3-1050by788-c5c208.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/3-700by525-c5c208.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/3-675by506-c5c208.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/3-450by338-c5c208.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/3-525by394-c5c208.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/3-350by263-c5c208.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/3-350by263-c5c208.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Tasting Room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I really likes the decor of the tasting room.  Clean, sophisticated, dark-brown color scheme, and true to southern style.  They have tables in all sizes, so if you are worried that they can’t sit 8+ people together, don’t be.  If you are 15-20+ people though, definitely make a reservation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/4-1050by788-bc3b2f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/4-700by525-bc3b2f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/4-675by506-bc3b2f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/4-450by338-bc3b2f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/4-525by394-bc3b2f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/4-350by263-bc3b2f.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/4-350by263-bc3b2f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Pouring Station&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A closer look at the wine bar itself.  Again, I really liked how clean the wine room was, even though the building itself showed sign of its age.  Here, you could order glasses or bottles of wine you like as well as charcuterie and other snacks.  One of the things I like about Virginia wineries - if you want to stay for half-a-day, they make it possible.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that the wine ambassador said to us that resonated with me was that Grace Estate Winery “embodies the true tradition of a Virginia farm winery”.  You can also find that phrase on their website.  Virginia is more like Oregon and Washington than Napa/Sonoma in that people can’t just spend a lot of money to buy land, build a sensational winery, produce wine, and become successful (there are always exceptions like RdV).  The differentiation between a lot of Virginia wineries are the stories and traditions that the wineries were built upon and the care they put into managing their crop.  After all, the land isn’t as diverse as Napa’s AVAs and they weather isn’t nearly as kind either (it’s very easy to lose your crop to frost, rain, mildew, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/5-1050by788-3e36dd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/5-700by525-3e36dd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/5-675by506-3e36dd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/5-450by338-3e36dd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/5-525by394-3e36dd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/5-350by263-3e36dd.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/grace-estate/5-350by263-3e36dd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Powerful New Yorkers&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;As you can imagine with important New Yorkers, everyone had an emergency or two to deal with over the weekend.  When they weren’t checking messages, they were always engaged in spirited debate on some deep topics.  Wine is good at enabling that.  I was quiet most of the trip - just taking these notes you are reading now, haha.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tasting through the wines, you could get a sense of the weather, land, and struggles of making wine in Virginia.  Though, the vines at Grace Estate are largely 20+ years old, so they are capable of complexity and depth, maybe moreso than other wineries in the region.  I wasn’t the biggest fan of the white wine, but all of the red wines were very interesting and beguiling to me.  I definitely recommend visiting and tasting these cerebral wines.  At the tasting’s price point, there is absolutely no reason not to visit if you are in the Charlottesville area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other interesting thing to me is that as these vines continue to age, the wines should continue to improve too.  So if you want to get on the ground floor of something potentially great one day…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what the wines are like today!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graceestate.orderport.net/product-details/0114/2017-Cuve&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Estate Le Gras Cuve&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($19)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is very perfumed with green and yellow apples, but simple in nature.  Medium(+) acidity, medium body, medium(+) intensity flavors with green/yellow apple and some bitter vegetal notes.  Pleasant to drink but not much complexity or length on the palate.  Medium length finish with the bitterness really emerging.  The round body and apple notes make this nice to drink on a hot day, but the Vidal Blanc could stand to be a bit riper.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graceestate.orderport.net/product-details/0082/2017-Long-Sword-Viognier&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Estate Viognier&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($29)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pronounced nose of yellow fruit, stonefruit (peach), and honeysuckle that is classic Viognier, but the blue cheese aroma is definitely different.  Medium(+) body, medium(+) alcohol, medium(+) acid, with ripe stonefruit flavors and bitter, unripe green flavors as well.  Probably means ripe and unripe grapes were crushed and blended together.   There is a brine that remains on the finish as well.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graceestate.orderport.net/product-details/0003/2016-Captain-John-Chardonnay&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Estate Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($26)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Med gold in appearance (like the Estate Le Gras Cuve).  Ripe/cooked flavors of yellow apple pie, vanilla, and some banana (likely from the volatile acid).  On the palate, the flavors lean closer to cooked rather than fresh yellow apple with some butter/cream flavors from the partial oak.  There’s bitterness on the finish that blends with the med(+) acidity that leaves your mouth watering.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graceestate.orderport.net/product-details/0092/2018-Rose&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Estate Le Gras Rose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($19)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The color of the wine is deeper than medium garnet, likely a byproduct of the extended maceration on the skins and a darker varietal (100% Malbec).  The nose has medium intensity aromas of ripe strawberries, cranberries, and some lighter cherry.  Medium(+) acid, low tannin, medium(-) bodied, with medium(+) flavors of tart cherry, cranberry and strawberry.  On exhale, it feels like medium(+) alcohol with a medium(-) finish.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graceestate.orderport.net/product-details/0049/2016-Earl-William-Cabernet-Franc&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Earl William Cabernet Franc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($34)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is really interesting.  Red cherry, cranberry, green pepper, and a pinch of asphalt (likely from the Pinotage).  High acid, medium bodied, medium, powdery tannin, medium(+) alcohol, with medium(+) intensity flavors of red cherry, cranberry, currant, green pepper (though lighter than the nose), with forest floor, coffee and a touch of wet straw.  Highly cerebral, but the finish is a little off-putting since it isn’t a continuation of the palate and feels like something else entirely.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graceestate.orderport.net/product-details/0112/2017-The-Count-Merlot&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Estate Merlot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($34)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Medium(+) intensity aromas of dried/cooked red fruit (cherry, strawberry, currant, hint of rhubarb), plum, baking spices.  Very integrated and deep on the nose.  On the palate, medium body, medium powdery tannin, medium acid, with medium intensity flavors of unripe cranberry/cherry/strawberry, baking spices, and some green, unripe vegetal notes, with a medium finish.  If not for that vegetal note at the end, this would be one of my favorite Virginia Merlots.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://graceestate.orderport.net/product-details/0085/2015-Colonel-Richard-Tannat&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Estate Tannat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($39)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is very ripe, rich red fruit, green pepper, rhubard, cocoa.  Softer, spicier, less ripe red fruit on the palate with medum(+) tannin, acid, and body.  The tannins are not harsh at all and is easy to drink right now.  I was genuinely surprised by how pleasant and interesting this wine was.  It’s also soft on the palate making this easy to drink alone or pair.  The earthiness and leather on the palate is also indicative of Tannat.  Nice…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the Viognier, Chardonnay and Cabernet Franc are normal to see in Virginia, the Merlot, Tannat and Malbec are less common.  Each of the wines showed some level of phenolic bitterness, but I feel the winery has done its best to incorporate those flavors into the style of the wine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that Grace Estate is worth a visit, especially since you could end up getting a tasting, a bottle, and some food for all under $50.  So be sure to give this place a look the next time you are in town.  Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="virginia" /><category term="monticello" /><category term="crozet" /><summary type="html">The first review of a winery in my home state: Virginia. Although I’ve never visited Grace Estate nor had their wine until this weekend, I’m glad this happened to be my first review. There are two things I look for in wineries: (1) Is the wine quality on point? (2) Is it relatively off people’s radar? If the answers to both are “yes”, you’ll have at least one intrigued customer coming to visit you. Each one of the wines poured during the tasting at Grace Estate were unique, cerebral, and pretty good. Combined with a nicely designed tasting room that feels like home rather than a Napa spaceship, I had a really nice time visiting for a couple hours.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/grace-estate/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bevan Cellars Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/09/07/bevan_cellars_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bevan Cellars Private Tasting" /><published>2019-09-07T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-07T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/09/07/bevan_cellars_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/09/07/bevan_cellars_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;I love hearing stories about how people entered the wine industry, especially those that had to start scrappy, rather than spending millions they earned in their previous life to fast track their way.  Maybe because if I’m ever going to have the opportunity myself, the path will look like the former, rather than the latter.  Russell Bevan and Victoria De Crescenzo of Bevan Cellars are the watermark for this category.  From enjoying blind tastings in the midwest to forming a wine lovers group in Minnesota, to trips and tastings in California with winemakers to risking it all and moving Napa on a dream.  Everything about their story resonates with me (and hopefully some of my friends, haha).  So it is only natural that I visit to taste their wines.  And wow, what a brand and catalog of wines they have built…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bevan-cellars/1-1050by788-42e35e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bevan-cellars/1-700by525-42e35e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bevan-cellars/1-675by506-42e35e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bevan-cellars/1-450by338-42e35e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bevan-cellars/1-525by394-42e35e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bevan-cellars/1-350by263-42e35e.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bevan-cellars/1-350by263-42e35e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;First or Last&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;You are either first or last.  In this case, I was first.  I really like the grounds at Brasswood Cellars - I’ll need to try their wines sometime as well.  Bevan Cellars does not have a tasting room, so they borrow a room from Brasswood to conduct their tastings.  Though at 9:30am, this large winery was eerily quiet…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing people tell me when planning a trip to Napa is that they are looking for QPR darlings.  “What are the tastings where I can get the most for my money?”  Bevan Cellars is my answer for the highest price/quality category; although the tasting fee is $100, the entire fee is applied to any Cabernet bottle(s) you purchase.  So if you are alright with buying one nice bottle for $200, you can get a free $100 tasting too of some very good wines.  And with wine quality as high as it is at Bevan Cellars, you’ll love the tasting and won’t have a hard time finding a bottle you want to buy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bevan-cellars/2-1050by788-d4fbe2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bevan-cellars/2-700by525-d4fbe2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bevan-cellars/2-675by506-d4fbe2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bevan-cellars/2-450by338-d4fbe2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bevan-cellars/2-525by394-d4fbe2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bevan-cellars/2-350by263-d4fbe2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bevan-cellars/2-350by263-d4fbe2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Winemakers Den&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Brasswood calls this room the Winemakers Den.  I don’t know why - maybe it’s because they let other winemakers use the room for events or meetings.  I felt like a rockstar tasting in this room alongside Bevan’s Wine Ambassador with people staring through the door at us…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, it’s shocking to me that you can go from selling dental equipment to producing some of the best wines in the valley.  But listening to the Wine Ambassador talk about their approach of paying attention to quality, all the way down handsorting each individual grape, you begin to understand the amount of work involved and why they’ve become successful.  It’s all about going further and doing what other people aren’t willing to do.  That type of attitude is important when you come into an industry where everyone else knows more than you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focusing back on the wines, the aspect that Bevan Cellars pays most attention to when making their wines is texture.  Texture is apparently an obsession for Russell Bevan in his wines.  And that’s something that’s obvious in not just his Cabernet Sauvignons, where high acid and tannin require that focus to make the wines approachable early in their life, but it’s also obvious in his Chardonnay and Pinot Noirs, where the larger textures give both varietals a presence that isn’t observed in wines from other producers.  And although they aren’t going for any certifications, they are moving towards more biodynamic / organic farming practices to continue increasing the quality of their grapes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bevan-cellars/3-1050by788-a35c6f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bevan-cellars/3-700by525-a35c6f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bevan-cellars/3-675by506-a35c6f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bevan-cellars/3-450by338-a35c6f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bevan-cellars/3-525by394-a35c6f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bevan-cellars/3-350by263-a35c6f.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bevan-cellars/3-350by263-a35c6f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Wines&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Normally, I like to ask a lot of questions during tastings, but during the Bevan Cellars tasting, both the wine ambassador and I were guilty of sniffing our glassese in silence, with unintelligible grunts and moans every once in a while to break the silence.  They wines were that good!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When emailing Bevan Cellars to coordinate your tasting, make sure that you write down the phone number of the wine ambassador you will be tasting with.  When you arrive at Brasswood Cellars for your tasting (Bevan doesn’t have it’s own winery / tasting room), there is no sign for Bevan Cellars or the Winemaker’s Den.  The pourers at Brasswood may also not know what you are talking about when you say you are there to taste another winery’s products.  You will likely need to call the phone number and ask that they look for you in the courtyard.  But once you find the room and settle in, be prepared to have a delicious hour of really good wines…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bevancellars.com/store/detail?item=2016-red-wine-ontogeny-napa-valley&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Ontogeny&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($95)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Ontogeny is a blend that got its name from how Russell Bevan approaches the wine.  Ontogenesis is the development of an organism from its early stages through maturity.  Similarly, he wanted to shape the wine so that year after year, you could see the change.  Sourced from Oakville, Stags Leap, Howell Mountain, and two other AVAs, the 2016 is composed of 76% Cabernet Sauvignon, 20% Merlot, and the rest Cabernet Franc and Petit Verdot.  Very pretty but powerful on the nose with white flowers, violets, and black fruit.  For the complexity of the blend, it’s surprising how much balance and texture this wine has.  A QPR darling and pretty close to being called a steal…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bevancellars.com/store/detail?item=2016-proprietary-red-wine-sugarloaf-mountain-napa-valley&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Proprietary Red Wine, Sugarloaf Mountain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($195)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Their 60% Merlot and 40% Cabernet Franc proprietary blend.  The Sugarloaf has a similar nose to the Ontogeny, but it’s a little less pretty, showing off a deeper richness instead.  On the palate, there is some much structure that seems built layer upon layer, almost like a deck of cards.  I cannot believe there isn’t any Cabernet Sauvignon in the wine; the high acidity and tannin trick you into believing otherwise.  The fruit focuses on the red spectrum moreso than the blue or black.  But this is a fantastic wine that leaves you wondering how it compares against the best of the Right Bank.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bevancellars.com/store/detail?item=2016-cabernet-sauvignon-wildfoote-vixen-stags-leap-district&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Wildfoote Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($195)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;100% Cabernet Sauvignon from Stags Leap, right next to Shafer.  The best way to describe this wine is a blueberry pie baked inside a french barrel…  This is the most fruit driven wine in the portfolio, according to the wine ambassador.  Sniffing the wine, it was incredible how pretty and how deep the aromas were.  Grown in volcanic soil with just two tons of fruit per acre harvested (that’s very low yielding), it’s like the wine itself is a concentrated/extracted version of a normal wine.  On the palate, there’s just so much depth and integration with the soil-attributable flavors.  It’s really hard to elaborate.  I felt that this wine was near perfect for me.  So much so that I bought multiple bottles.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bevancellars.com/store/detail?item=2016-bevan-cellars-tench-vineyard-cabernet-sauvignon-oakville&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Tench Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($195)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;According to Russell Bevan, Tench Vineyard (located in eastern Oakville) possesses a consistent reflection of “what is Oakville”.  Composed of 92% Cabernet Sauvignon and 8% Merlot, the wine has a pretty, elegant nose that reminds me of Beckstoffer Vineyards…  Although it isn’t as bright as the other wines, the nose has deep red fruit that is consistent through the palate as well.  But the showstopper here is the acid.  It’s as if there is a constant zap, like a tuning fork, hitting the back of the palate that just keeps stimulating you during each sip.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bevancellars.com/store/detail?item=2016-bevan-cellars-ee-red-wine&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Tench EE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($195)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This bottle is similar to the Tench, but the nose is a bit more reserved and the tannin is a bit more present.  This wine will require more aging than the Tench to achieve its full potential and may eventually have more potential than the Tench as well.  The fruit is also prettier and fresher than the Tench.  A fairly interesting combination, given that the wine is a blend of Cabernet Sauvignon, Cabernet Franc, and Merlot.  It seems as if the Cabrenet Franc provides that nose and the Merlot provides the richness on the palate.  Just give this wine a little time to round into form.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2011 Tench EE Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt; ($250)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I literally stopped in my tracks when I tasted this wine.  This was not a California wine.  This must be a Bordeaux 1st or 2nd growth.  The pyrazines from the Cab Franc are still there but it is very complementary to the wine; you can find it in the nose, but it matches the lighter aromas well.  This wine is such an outlier from the rest of the portfolio, yet so good in its own way.  I cannot believe this is from the same vineyard that produced the previous wine.  Out of a tough vintage like 2011, winemakers had to adapt to the fruit given to them.  And Russell Bevan did a magnificent job with this vintage.  I had to get a bottle of this wine to show other wine enthusiasts to see if I can trick them, haha.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can tell, I was very impressed with the entire portfolio of what I tasted - I’ll post another tasting note if I get to try their Chardonnay and Pinot Noir at the winery.  The wines are definitely larger and more brooding than many others in the valley, so make sure that’s the style you prefer before visiting.  As I mentioned earlier, I highly recommend tasting with Bevan Cellars, not just for the wine quality, but because of the refunded tasting fee with a purchase.  And although the price points of the bottles can seem scary, the quality is absolutely reflective of the quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So get out there and good luck finding your way to the Winemaker’s Den in Brasswood, haha.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="st-helena" /><summary type="html">I love hearing stories about how people entered the wine industry, especially those that had to start scrappy, rather than spending millions they earned in their previous life to fast track their way. Maybe because if I’m ever going to have the opportunity myself, the path will look like the former, rather than the latter. Russell Bevan and Victoria De Crescenzo of Bevan Cellars are the watermark for this category. From enjoying blind tastings in the midwest to forming a wine lovers group in Minnesota, to trips and tastings in California with winemakers to risking it all and moving Napa on a dream. Everything about their story resonates with me (and hopefully some of my friends, haha). So it is only natural that I visit to taste their wines. And wow, what a brand and catalog of wines they have built…</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/bevan-cellars/3.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Cliff Lede Backstage Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/31/cliff_lede_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cliff Lede Backstage Tasting" /><published>2019-08-31T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-31T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/31/cliff_lede_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/31/cliff_lede_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Christopher Tynan is one of the hottest winemakers in Napa Valley right now.  In addition to propelling wineries like Cliff Lede to centerstage in the wine world, he produces wines under his own label from sourced fruit that wine writers cannot stop gushing over (I think Jeb Dunnuck has given every one of his label’s wines 100pts each vintage).  He and Tony Arcudi are the two newer winemakers I am closely following.  So of course I had to take the opportunity to taste at Cliff Lede when I had the chance.  I thought Shafer and Stags Leap Wine Cellars were the two kings of the AVA.  But both of them better watch out because Cliff Lede is coming on very strong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/1-1050by788-aa284e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/1-700by525-aa284e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/1-675by506-aa284e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/1-450by338-aa284e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/1-525by394-aa284e.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/1-350by263-aa284e.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/1-350by263-aa284e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Facility&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Cliff Lede Winery looks like a normal house from the road in the Stags Leap District.  The wines are anything but normal though…  I’ve heard rumors and read the articles about Christopher Tynan, but I don’t think I was quite ready to taste these wines.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/2-1050by788-2055df.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/2-700by525-2055df.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/2-675by506-2055df.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/2-450by338-2055df.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/2-525by394-2055df.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/2-350by263-2055df.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/2-350by263-2055df.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The vineyards&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;From the parking lot, you have a great view to Stags Leap and can begin to understand what makes the wines so special.  I am also very jealous of the people that own the houses on the hillside, next to the plots where grapes for the Poetry come from.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than knowing of the winemaker, I had no background on Cliff Lede before the tasting.  I had neither read any articles about them nor tasted any of their wines before.  Even today, I can’t find much of their wines in DC/Virginia, even though I see bottles of the One Point Five (Shafer) and Artemis (SLWC) everywhere.  But now I am always paying attention to Cliff Lede’s website, waiting for the next sales on their Calistoga and Howell Mountain Cabernets as well as purchasing several bottles of their Beckstoffer To Kalon every new vintage.  That is how much things have changed for me in a year…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/3-1050by788-4aedc3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/3-700by525-4aedc3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/3-675by506-4aedc3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/3-450by338-4aedc3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/3-525by394-4aedc3.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/3-350by263-4aedc3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/3-350by263-4aedc3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Inside the Main Tasting Room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;If you sign up for the normal tasting, this is the area where it happens.  If you don’t make an appointment, you can still get a tasting from the standing bar, but if you do get one, you’ll have the chance to relax on some sofas inside or some chairs outside.  It was hot this day, so everyone wanted to stay inside.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/4-1050by788-79d8d4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/4-700by525-79d8d4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/4-675by506-79d8d4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/4-450by338-79d8d4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/4-525by394-79d8d4.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/4-350by263-79d8d4.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/4-350by263-79d8d4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Members Only&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;If you sign up for one of the special tasting experiences, they will take you to the members lounge in a building a short walk away.  The owners are very passionate about Rock and Roll and have pretty awesome memorabilia hanging up on the walls.  Sometimes during the year, they will also host art pieces at the front of the area as well.  I really liked the atmosphere and how everyone was enjoying themselves.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Driving up to the winery and entering the front-door, I didn’t really see much that would’ve made me think “Cliff Lede is a winery I need to follow”.  Their tasting list looked fairly average for a Napa Valley winery and the number of customers and ambiance were in line with that.  Luckily, I had signed up for their Backstage Tasting.  And as we entered the building behind the main tasting room, all of my perceptions changed.  The room was filled, the conversations were louder and more serious, people were laughing, and one of the workers was continuously collecting filled-out order and membership forms.  It was like I was at a different winery than before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/5-1050by788-7e5e87.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/5-700by525-7e5e87.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/5-675by506-7e5e87.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/5-450by338-7e5e87.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/5-525by394-7e5e87.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/5-350by263-7e5e87.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/5-350by263-7e5e87.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Wine Ambassador&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;My wine ambassador for the tasting, pouring me some of the FEL Chardonnay (their other label).  I came back a second time with another group of people where the wine wasn’t quite as good as this tasting, so sometimes it’s just luck regarding what type of experience you have.  Our tasting lineup was also a bit different.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I was a group of one (yes, it’s lonely), I got a seat at the bar in the back, setup my laptop, and proceeded to taste through 6 very good to outstanding wines.  I think the High Fidelity is not normally on their tasting menu, but some members had requested a taste earlier, so they were pouring the rest of the bottle for people until it ran out.  Good timing for me indeed.  I am still torn about not signing up for a membership here, but of the wines I were interested in, I’d have to purchase 6 of them each vintage and that would be tough, since I consider each of them special occasion wines (ie. ~$200-$300 a bottle).  Though, you can also sign up for a membership and receive their FEL or normal Cabernets instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/6-1050by1400-69a569.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/6-700by933-69a569.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/6-675by900-69a569.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/6-450by600-69a569.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/6-525by700-69a569.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/6-350by467-69a569.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/cliff-lede/6-350by467-69a569.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Beckstoffer&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Beckstoffer vineyards are famous in Napa.  In Napa, many times the vineyard will be more well-known than the producer and is one way different wineries will try to improve their visibility in the market (make a wine from a famous site).  I think this was more a clash of the superpowers that produced a 100pt wine…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of these wines were among the best of their varietal (or blend) category.  But that Beckstoffer left me dreaming of life 10-15 years from now.  Even now, I catch myself staring at the bottles in my wine fridge, wondering how well they will round into form.  Time will tell I guess…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ledefamilywines.com/product/2016-FEL-Chardonnay-Savoy-Vineyard&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEL Savoy Vineyard Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($48)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Light saline aromas on the nose paired with ripe lemon and lime on the palate (the wine was produced in steel tanks).  I’m guessing either none or very little MLF because of the lack of butter/cream notes, but in its place you have a very good medium(+) balanced acid.  This is a very easy drinking Chardonnay that is mellow and smooth.  I’d like a little more character, but besides complexity, there is nothing you could point to as a flaw or imbalance in this wine.  And if you like fruit flavors among all else, this will make you very happy…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 FEL Donnelly Creek Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt; ($38)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;From the Anderson Valley, so there is lots of maritime influence, meaning the weather/temperature is pretty constant where these grapes come from.  The first thing I thought of when I sniffed the wine was HdV (which sells its Pinots for $100+).  On the palate, this wine is very smooth…  Ripe fruit that isn’t candied, some degree of green that seems to be from whole cluster methods, great acidity, and smooth body.  This is for all of those cranberry loves out there that appreciates tingling acidity in their Pinot Noir.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cliffledevineyards.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/2010-Poetry.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2010 Cliff Lede Poetry Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($310)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;One of their two Platinum wines from Stags Leap (other is Songbook).  Ripe and cooked black/red fruit, a bit of green/pyrazine on the tasting profile, and very complex because of the blend percentages in this wine: 75% Cabernet Sauvignon, 16% Merlot, 5% Petit Verdot, 3% Cabernet Franc, and 1% Malbec.  Good structure from the Cab Sauv, tertiary character (espresso, chocolate) and integration from the age, and a long finish.  This is a very cerebral wine that has an expansive profile with tannin/acid levels that allow further aging.  I think it’s drinking perfectly right now, as are most 2010s.  This bottle is not for the traditional Cabernet drinker; this is a wine to ruminate on for an hour.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cliffledevineyards.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/2015-High-Fidelity.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 High Fidelity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($85)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;58% Merlot, 28% Cabernet Franc, 13% Cabernet Sauvignon, and the rest Petit Verdot.  The ripe black fruit, cocoa, espresso and dustiness come out right away from the glass.  There’s a spiciness at the end which is very interesting.  The tannin is very present and needs some time to loosen its grip, which is different for a Merlot-driven wine.  In fact, this bottle could compete with many flagship cabernets elsewhere!  Too bad Merlot gets a bad rap.  This is definitely a wine that could turn people around…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cliffledevineyards.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/2015-Moon-Fantasy.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Moon Fantasy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($110)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Each block of their vineyards is named after a Rock and Roll song rather than being numbered like most places.  Moon Fantasy is a blend of fruit from the “Dark Side of the Moon” plot in the Twin Peaks vineyard and the “Dear Mr. Fantasy” plot in the Poetry vineyard, hence the name Moon Fantasy.  Big, rich blue and black fruit with some dust dominate the nose.  The palate is more of the same with more perfumed fruit and big acid/tannin that could use some years of aging.  There is a dustiness/cocoa/terroir component that is just really smoothly integrated into the wine and added another layer of complexity and deliciousness.  If the High Fidelity shows the potential power of Merlot, this wine is about the big, brooding capability of Cabernet.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cliffledevineyards.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/2015-Cliff-Lede-CS-Beckstoffer-To-Kalon.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Beckstoffer To Kalon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($185)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If one considers the Moon Fantasy “brooding”, the Beckstoffer is a sleeping dragon.  I was almost afraid of swirling the wine for fear of what it might be when it woke up…  The wine explodes from the glass with perfumed blue/black fruit, white flowers, and cocoa.  The palate is just as intense as the nose and emphasizes the fruit and the cocoa.  This is just a brazen, out-of-control wine that needs to be drunk in the winter time.  Also, there is so much acid and tannin that allows for (I take that back – it needs!) 15-25 years of aging.  I don’t know if I can even call this a wine.  I dare not touch this for 10 years (and yes, I bought 5 bottles).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was struggling after this tasting as the Beckstoffer had consumed all of my taste buds.  Overall, this was a very solid tasting that showcased several above average wines and a couple showstoppers.  If you like dark, brooding wines like those of Mt. Veeder or other cult wines, you are really going to enjoy this tasting.  I wonder if it’s coincidence that the winery happens to be next to my favorite winery in Napa (Kapcsandy)…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next time you go out to Napa and think about tasting at Shafer and/or Stags Leap Wine Cellars, I ask that you consider including Cliff Lede as part of your itinerary.  I promise you that you will not be disappointed.  I for one was not…  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="stags-leap" /><summary type="html">Christopher Tynan is one of the hottest winemakers in Napa Valley right now. In addition to propelling wineries like Cliff Lede to centerstage in the wine world, he produces wines under his own label from sourced fruit that wine writers cannot stop gushing over (I think Jeb Dunnuck has given every one of his label’s wines 100pts each vintage). He and Tony Arcudi are the two newer winemakers I am closely following. So of course I had to take the opportunity to taste at Cliff Lede when I had the chance. I thought Shafer and Stags Leap Wine Cellars were the two kings of the AVA. But both of them better watch out because Cliff Lede is coming on very strong.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/cliff-lede/4.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Spire Collection Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/24/spire_collection_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spire Collection Private Tasting" /><published>2019-08-24T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-24T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/24/spire_collection_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/24/spire_collection_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;After my visit to Lokoya a couple years ago, I started following and tasting more of Chris Carpenter’s wines.  I would put him right beside Tony Arcudi as one of the winemakers I would love to work for and learn from.  I highly recommend you check out his podcast interview on “The Taste” with Doug Shafer to get a feel for his career and what’s shaped his style of winemaking.  One night, I happened upon his Mt. Brave and La Jota Cabernets and decided that I needed to taste the rest of the portfolio.  Luckily, each of the labels are all grouped under the Spire Collection brand and can be tasted together at their estate in Calistoga.  I recommend you find bottles sooner rather than later as the prices seem to rise every year…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/1-1050by788-e1003b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/1-700by525-e1003b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/1-675by506-e1003b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/1-450by338-e1003b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/1-525by394-e1003b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/1-350by263-e1003b.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/1-350by263-e1003b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The tasting builiding&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The tasting building for the Spire Collection.  It doesn’t look like much on the outside, but the inside with surprise and impress you.  But even better than the building is the views.  See below…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you visit Calistoga, I strongly recommend that you make an appointment with the Spire Collection.  Not only will you get to taste some excellent wines from the Napa Valley, but you’ll also get to sample great wines from other countries such as Australia, South Africa, Italy, France, etc.  Even better, you can email Spire ahead of time to let them know your preferences, the $$ you are willing to pay for the tasting, and they can adjust the wines they pour to fit what you’d like.  Most of the wines chosen for our tasting came from their international portfolio, while the rest were from Mt. Brave.  The tasting for those 6 wines came in at $75 per person, so that should give you an idea of what to expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/2-1050by788-a7fc10.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/2-700by525-a7fc10.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/2-675by506-a7fc10.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/2-450by338-a7fc10.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/2-525by394-a7fc10.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/2-350by263-a7fc10.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/2-350by263-a7fc10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The vines before trimming&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Not to toot my own horn, but I really like this picture.  You get a glimpse of the beautiful mountain views in the background, but also what the vines look like October, after harvest but before trimming all of the vines to start the winter hibernation.  Just gorgeous…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/3-1050by788-c62c6d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/3-700by525-c62c6d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/3-675by506-c62c6d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/3-450by338-c62c6d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/3-525by394-c62c6d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/3-350by263-c62c6d.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/3-350by263-c62c6d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;So bright...&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It was cold enough that you needed a heavy coat, but the morning sun was as strong as ever.  You also get a better view of the mountains in the background.  The one other thing you notice?  Not another winery in sight.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Putting aside the wines for just a moment, the presentation for the tasting is among the best I’ve experienced in the Napa Valley.  Driving to the tasting room, you drive parallel to the mountains and need to meander on a one lane road through the vines to get to your destination.  The only scary moment is when you arrive and see the building where the tasting is conducted.  It does not look like much from the outside, but once you make your way inside, everything changes.  The room is stylish, elegant, and the views of the mountains outside cannot be beat.  You can just stare at the mountainside while enjoying the wines and ignore everything else that is going on around you.  Though, if you love wine like I do, the view may actually be a distraction to enjoying the wine to their utmost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/4-1050by788-7cb309.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/4-700by525-7cb309.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/4-675by506-7cb309.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/4-450by338-7cb309.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/4-525by394-7cb309.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/4-350by263-7cb309.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/4-350by263-7cb309.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The tasting room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The beautiful tasting room.  Very elegant, lots of natural light (you’ll see why later), but that mirror betrays us, haha.  I loved thhe display of the different wines from the Spire Collection (though no Lokoya…).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/5-1050by788-7ab073.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/5-700by525-7ab073.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/5-675by506-7ab073.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/5-450by338-7ab073.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/5-525by394-7ab073.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/5-350by263-7ab073.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/5-350by263-7ab073.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;What do you think?&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;We had two wines to blind taste during the visit.  The first one gave us all some trouble as you can see by the thinking faces in the room.  Needless to say, we all got the wine origins wrong (the Spire Collection has wineries all over the world).  A very fun tasting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After taking some pictures and wandering the room a bit, it was time for our 10am tasting to begin.  Not only did I appreciate the lineup, but I appreciated the order in which we tasted the wines (the first thing you want to taste in the morning isn’t a Cabernet).  The Chardonnay was especially good, though my favorite had to be the Single Block Cabernet from Mt. Brave.  Just a singular wine that will continue to age well and is very good value at $125, compared to other wines in the same price category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/6-1050by788-0c8d4d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/6-700by525-0c8d4d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/6-675by506-0c8d4d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/6-450by338-0c8d4d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/6-525by394-0c8d4d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/6-350by263-0c8d4d.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/spire-collection/6-350by263-0c8d4d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The view outside&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I will admit to being distracted during the tasting.  This picture is the reason why…  You might think that having a beautiful view while tasting is always a plus, but I appreciate it as much as others.  I’d rather concentrate on the wine while tasting, then enjoy the views separately before/after the tasting.  What do you think?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the wines!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://p.widencdn.net/molqeq/CAP18_23014-15-Chard-WIS-Redesign_r5&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Capensis Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;From Stellenbosch, South Africa.  My first thought smelling this wine was “woah”.  The nose is very rich (like a Burgundian Meursault), but on the palate you can tell that the grapes are picked at a higher acid level.  It surprising to drink a South African Chardonnay that has both richness and structure.  The ripe yellow fruit flavors are pleasant but not too intense on the mid-palate and the salinity/minerality lasts through the finish (I wonder if it’s the effect of the Cape Doctor or reduction).  A very balanced wine that maintains the desired complexity of Chardonnay without overdoing the intensity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://embed.widencdn.net/pdf/plus/jfw/ahinjdwyzy/MGY_WIS_Afleet_2014+acclaim.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2011 Maggy Hawk Pinot Noir “Afleet”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;From the Anderson Valley, close to the ocean.  Each block of Maggy Hawk is dedicated to different clones of Pinot Noir.  Traditional red fruit on the nose (think earthy red cranberries) and some tertiary notes.  Afleet uses a Pommard clone, so mushroom notes are present, but the vibrant acidity covers the length of the palate.  I didn’t get much astringency, so this was picked right as the grapes were ready and still high in acid.  Very much varietally driven in structure and flavor.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://embed.widencdn.net/pdf/plus/jfw/vgob47ztzf/2010Arcanum,Toscana,CabernetFranc-basedblend&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blind Wine – 2011 Arcanum (Super Tuscan IGT)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($100)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The first wine we tasted blind (from a black wine glass).  High acid and medium(+) tannin that is well integrated together and has a heavy effect on the finish.  The nose had depth as it came across as mountain fruit.  Although the wine seemed young, the medium(-) body felt a little disconnected with the acid/tannin and the palate was restrained in intensity.  It did not surprise me that this was an italian wine, but I did not expect it to be 8-year-old Cabernet Franc (with 20% Merlot).  As the nose continues to open, there is more cooked fruit and a tiny bit of white spice on the profile, but nothing like what I would expect reading the label of the bottle..&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://embed.widencdn.net/pdf/plus/jfw/cptf1qn3ey/2014Mt.Brave,Mt.Veeder,CabernetSauvignon.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Mt. Brave Single Block Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($125)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;After being vexed from blind tasting the previous wine, I immediately regained my composure and good mood smelling and tasting this wine.  This wine is made from the highest block of Cabernet Sauvignon in the vineyard.  Crushed rocks, purple flowers, perfume, pretty red fruit, high acid and high tannin that isn’t rough, but very present in the wine.  This wine strikes me as a more elegant/feminine expression of Cabernet, yet contains massive structure that requires some aging.  I would be very comfortable calling this the younger brother of the Lokoya Mt. Veeder.  And at a third of the price…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://embed.widencdn.net/pdf/plus/jfw/porl6hsc80/2014Mt.Brave,Mt.Veeder,Malbec.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Mt. Brave Malbec&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mt. Brave grows some interesting varietals on Mt. Veeder: Cabernet Franc, Merlot, Syrah, etc.  We had the chance to taste the Malbec which really excited me because I’ve had world-class renditions from Argentina that had similar terroir.  The nose is explosive with bright red and blue candied fruit that leaps from the glass.  The tannins are not nearly as big as the previous Cabernet and the fruit just owns this glass of wine (there are some blackberries on the palate too, not just red/blue fruit).  Some crushed, powdered purple petals on the nose as well.  The palate goes from a boisterous symphony of bright/candied fruit to finishing a little too quickly…  Still, a huge Malbec that is fun to show off.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://embed.widencdn.net/pdf/plus/jfw/n7ptu6atzp/HCB17_877592015BrooksRoadWIS_Acclaim.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Hickinbotham Clarendon Vineyard Shiraz&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($75)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The last wine we tasted was also served blind.  This 100% Shiraz from the McLaren Vale is very reserved on the nose with a medium body that has grippy tannins.  The palate flavors are integrated and don’t really show that much uniqueness, which in itself is unique.  The cherry-cola flavor is a tell-tale sign of Shiraz, but this wasn’t your Barossa Valley (huge) Shiraz.  This was much more reserved and still closed down right now.  I would be interested to see this wine age for 5 years to see if it opens back up.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I had a fun time tasting the different wines and learning about the Jackson Family’s international estates.  I didn’t walk out with any bottles, but I later ordered the set of Mt. Brave wines from their website to do a tasting with since I think they are solid wines at their price point.  Maybe I can visit their winery up on Mt. Veeder someday…  Until then, I will gladly make do tasting their wines and reminiscing about the views.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="calistoga" /><summary type="html">After my visit to Lokoya a couple years ago, I started following and tasting more of Chris Carpenter’s wines. I would put him right beside Tony Arcudi as one of the winemakers I would love to work for and learn from. I highly recommend you check out his podcast interview on “The Taste” with Doug Shafer to get a feel for his career and what’s shaped his style of winemaking. One night, I happened upon his Mt. Brave and La Jota Cabernets and decided that I needed to taste the rest of the portfolio. Luckily, each of the labels are all grouped under the Spire Collection brand and can be tasted together at their estate in Calistoga. I recommend you find bottles sooner rather than later as the prices seem to rise every year…</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/spire-collection/5.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bennett Lane Reserve Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/17/bennett_lane_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bennett Lane Reserve Tasting" /><published>2019-08-17T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-17T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/17/bennett_lane_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/17/bennett_lane_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;The more wineries I visit in Calistoga, the more convinced I become that it’s the hidden value area of Napa.  Bennett Lane was not on my radar before I began planning an itinerary for the weekend; I just happened to notice that it was directly next to where the Spire Collection holds its tastings.  It isn’t as ostentatious as other wineries, but it makes solid wines that balance the fruit development with the weight and acidity on the palate.  And if you are a patient buyer, you may find discounted bottles on distribution sites, such as Vivino, and use the opportunity to stock up!  Having tasted at the winery and enjoyed several bottlings through online purchases, I highly recommend you visit and taste for yourself!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/1-1050by788-f9a7d2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/1-700by525-f9a7d2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/1-675by506-f9a7d2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/1-450by338-f9a7d2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/1-525by394-f9a7d2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/1-350by263-f9a7d2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/1-350by263-f9a7d2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Winery Entrance&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Bennett Lane is a no-frills winery deep into the Calistoga AVA.  It is located right across the street from the building used to taste the Spire Collection wines under the Jackson family.  If you sign up to taste the latter, this is a perfect pitstop right before or after lunch in the area.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/2-1050by788-fb13e6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/2-700by525-fb13e6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/2-675by506-fb13e6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/2-450by338-fb13e6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/2-525by394-fb13e6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/2-350by263-fb13e6.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/2-350by263-fb13e6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The tasting area&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It is a shame that Bennett Lane is not well known.  It has a refined interior, but again, they don’t go over the top.  The wine is on point as well.  Because we had the winery to ourselves on a Sunday afternoon, we were lucky to taste through some of the Reserve bottlings that aren’t normally available.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bennett Lane Winery’s beginnings follow that of many others - the owner(s) were influenced by wine or a wine region at some point in their life and realized that living that dream is the next step after accomplishing what they set out to do in business.  It certainly is my dream.  From both the architecture and their blends (the Maximus brand), you can tell that Italy was the main influence and it translates well to this property.  The pictures above and below hopefully give you some insight on what to expect in the tasting room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/3-1050by788-f0a471.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/3-700by525-f0a471.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/3-675by506-f0a471.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/3-450by338-f0a471.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/3-525by394-f0a471.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/3-350by263-f0a471.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/3-350by263-f0a471.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The tasting bar&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The 180 degree view from the picture above.  I have no idea what my friend Simon is looking at.  I’ve squinted at this picture several times and don’t see a tasting sheet on the bar.  Do you?  Perhaps he is deep in thought, getting ready for the wines to come.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/4-1050by1400-1682b0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/4-700by933-1682b0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/4-675by900-1682b0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/4-450by600-1682b0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/4-525by700-1682b0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/4-350by467-1682b0.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/4-350by467-1682b0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Chardonnay was good&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A picture with their 2016 Reserve chardonnay from the Sangiacomo Vineyard over in Carneros.  I remember being pleasantly surprised by the balance of the wine.  It was neither too heavy, nor too light, and with the right amount of acid.  The flavors between the fruit and wood melded together nicely as well.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to the winery itself, the wine ambassador was courteous and direct about the tasting.  We chose the reserve tasting (and that lineup is reflected below), but one may also choose the traditional tasting to get a better sense of the Maximus wines.  At a previous tasting, I heard about the high quality and decent prices for their Cabernets, but I would also love to visit again to taste their blend of Sauvignon Blanc, Chardonnay and Muscat Canelli (Maximus White) and their Bordeaux blend of Cabernet Sauvignon and Franc, Merlot, Syrah, and Petit Verdot (Maxiumus Red).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/5-1050by788-1183d6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/5-700by525-1183d6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/5-675by506-1183d6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/5-450by338-1183d6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/5-525by394-1183d6.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/5-350by263-1183d6.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/bennett-lane/5-350by263-1183d6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Soil Samples...&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Yes, I nerded out a bit discussing the different plots that the grapes were farmed from.  These aren’t the most recognizable plots from the Napa Valley, which means that there may be an opportunity to find a bottle that hits above its price range.  I think the Lewelling vineyard was my favorite plot from the tasting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did not spend much time discussing the owners’ nor winemakers’ backgrounds, so I recommend visiting their website if you are interested in learning more, as that will equal the knowledge I have access to.  Instead, we talked much more about the wines and what makes them different than others in the valley.  A summary on each of the available wines can also be found on the winery’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bennettlane.com/napa-valley-calistoga-wines-online-wine-shoping&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Reserve Chardonnay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($53)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Produced using sourced fruit from Carneros.  10% MLF allowed in order to round out the acid but keep the butter and cream notes as supporting character in the wine.  Fresh primary aromas of lemon and yellow apple.  The palate is medium body, medium(+) acid, and a touch of salinity that stimulates the palate before the crisp yellow apple, pear, vanilla, and hint of melon follows through.  Wine Advocate scored it 90pts (impressive for a white wine) and I’d agree.  The Chardonnay is for the crowd that doesn’t want the full, unctuous wines of Napa but rather a ripe representation of the varietal character.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2011 Cabernet Sauvignon Reserve&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($105)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This wine reminds me slightly of the Left-Bank as it has balanced deep red fruit, but also some green and tertiary notes on the nose.  You’ll want to decant this bottle for an hour or open-and-recork it and leave overnight.  The acid is more present than the tannin, which makes this very drinkable right now.  Medium(-) body with flavors that are a bit more earthy and feels like its at is optimum aging point.  Cherry, blackberry, cocoa and leather.  Again, it doesn’t feel underdeveloped, just very light for the Napa Valley (understandable considering the 2011 vintage).  Many places found it hard to produce wines in 2011 and this is pretty darn drinkable.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Cabernet Sauvignon Reserve&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($105)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Dark cherry, cassis, berries, mocha, cocoa, vanilla, and a caramel sensation on the nose.  Even with all of these aromas, the nose feels bright thanks to the acidity.  The palate is mellow and integrated but with lots of layers and decent complexity.  The 2012 has soft tannins, so it’s ready now, but they won’t hold on for too long - I recommend you finish the bottle the same day that you open it.  And I’m fine with that considering this lighter bodied, fruit-forward wine.  Just a darn good bottle of wine that is fairly rich but not too big.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Lynch Family Vineyard Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($125)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The gem of the lineup as it’s their only single vineyard Cabernet Sauvignon.  I know this sounds very strange, but there is a odd note on the nose that is reminiscent of Denorex Shampoo.  Almost like a herbal mint and caramel blended together.  Once you get past the semi-shock of the nose, the wine is very nice.  There is a cherry cola component that integrates well with the high acid/tannin and it has a medium(-) body that makes it dance across the palate.  Still, I’d describe this as an easy drinking wine (though a really nice one at that) which has a fair bit of complexity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($62)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;They were nice to let me try this wine outside of my tasting menu.  Cherry and cocoa on the nose with similar flavors on the palate.  Although it is less intense and concentrated than the Reserve, it isn’t short by much.  Although it’s a 2013, this is drinking very well right now and a good value buy (I purchased bottles of this to get my tasting free).  Soft and balanced, this wine is medium bodied, medium(+) tannin, and medium(+) acid that is integrated.  You could serve this wine no matter the food pairing at dinner.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Bennett Lane Winery isn’t my favorite winery for its wines, ambiance, nor presentation, it does a pretty solid job in all of the categories and should be a nice, quiet location to enjoy several glasses of wine.  The care and attention to detail are there without the price point nor the need to schedule a tasting in advance.  So meander on through the region and make this a pitstop to rehydrate!  Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="calistoga" /><summary type="html">The more wineries I visit in Calistoga, the more convinced I become that it’s the hidden value area of Napa. Bennett Lane was not on my radar before I began planning an itinerary for the weekend; I just happened to notice that it was directly next to where the Spire Collection holds its tastings. It isn’t as ostentatious as other wineries, but it makes solid wines that balance the fruit development with the weight and acidity on the palate. And if you are a patient buyer, you may find discounted bottles on distribution sites, such as Vivino, and use the opportunity to stock up! Having tasted at the winery and enjoyed several bottlings through online purchases, I highly recommend you visit and taste for yourself!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/bennett-lane/2.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hyde de Villaine Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/10/hyde_de_villaine_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hyde de Villaine Private Tasting" /><published>2019-08-10T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-08-10T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/10/hyde_de_villaine_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/08/10/hyde_de_villaine_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;What is in a name?  Well, for some it’s the most effective branding possible.  The name “Villaine” is enough to grab any wine collector’s attention.  Though, they normally associate it with a Burgundian winery that just happens to produce some of the most expensive wine on Earth (Aubert de Villaine of Domaine de la Romanee-Conti).  Though, that association is exactly what the owners don’t want, even though the winery is related to that Villaine!  The character of the terroir between the Cote de Nuit in Burgundy and Carneros in Napa are very different and you should expect very different wine because of that.  And while the wine isn’t as good as DRC, it also doesn’t cost $20K+ a bottle either.  I think what you do get with these wines is old world elegance, finesse, minerality, and a complexity that doesn’t over-index on the fruit character, thanks to the Burgundian traditions applied to Carneros fruit and terroir.  Do I recommend you visit?  You bet I do…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/1-1050by788-afcd6f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/1-700by525-afcd6f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/1-675by506-afcd6f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/1-450by338-afcd6f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/1-525by394-afcd6f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/1-350by263-afcd6f.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/1-350by263-afcd6f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Springtime&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A look at the vineyard before spring officially starts.  While it’s the mountains in the background that may grab your attention, just wait for these Chardonnay vines to bloom and grow their fruit.  These vines produce some of the best white wine in the Napa area today.  And don’t underestimate their red wines either…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The families of Villaine and Hyde each got their start in wine separately.  Larry Hyde has worked in the vineyards since the 70s and you can likely find multiple books on Aubert’s life story in Burgundy.  So what would bring two very different families together?  Love, of course!  Aubert married Larry’s cousin (Pamela Fairbanks) in 1970 and after 30 years of pursuing their own craft, Larry and Aubert decided to start a venture together in Carneros.  In 2002, they brought onboard their current winemaker (Stéphane Vivier) who studied at the the Université de Bourgogne.  And with a vision in mind, they built HdV!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/2-1050by788-000b44.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/2-700by525-000b44.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/2-675by506-000b44.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/2-450by338-000b44.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/2-525by394-000b44.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/2-350by263-000b44.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/2-350by263-000b44.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Not the Prettiest Building&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Never judge a book by its cover, especially in the wine world.  Similar to other great wineries like Kapcsandy, you won’t find a grand estate waiting for you at the property.  The facility is 100% tailored to making wine.  And when you are searching for the best wine, isn’t that what you want to see out of a winery?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HdV is primarily focused on Chardonnay which represents over 60% of their production.  Since the expertise of both Aubert and Stéphane lay in Burgundian wines, it makes sense that HdV is focused on the cooler Carneros, allowing them to produce higher acid wines that are similar to what is produced in Burgundy in contrast to the typical ripe Napa Chardonnay.  And because the Chardonnay is sourced from older-vine blocks at the Hyde Vineyard (30+ year old vines), each bottle contains character and concentration.  They produce a Merlot / Cabernet Sauvignon blend (Belle Cousine) and Syrah onsite as well.  It wasn’t until 2012 that they started making Pinot Noir here (remember, they don’t want that “diet-DRC” comparison), but the Burgundian winemaker wanted to make Pinot, so here we are!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/3-1050by788-ee6575.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/3-700by525-ee6575.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/3-675by506-ee6575.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/3-450by338-ee6575.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/3-525by394-ee6575.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/3-350by263-ee6575.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/3-350by263-ee6575.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;I Spy a Concrete Egg&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A look inside the facility.  Again, besides the office to the right of the concrete egg, everything in the place is for making wine.  It was hard to imagine how and where they move the tanks and barrels during harvest and crush.  Maybe some magical elves take care of everything?  That might explain why the Chardonnay is so delicious!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The funniest thing we talked about during the tasting was that Aubert didn’t take the idea of co-founding an American winery seriously until he participated in a blind tasting where one of the wines revealed was a Ramey Chardonnay that was made with fruit from the Hyde Vineyard.  After that tasting, he finally gave the co-venture some serious thought.  Since Aubert is half-the-world away running DRC, he doesn’t have much influence on the day-to-day.  He does make a couple trips to California each year where his biggest contribution is helping decide when to pick the grapes, since that is always the most important decision for a winery.  Where many wineries index on the brix (sugar) level of the grapes, HdV focuses on picking when the Total Acidity (TA) is just right.  And like Burgundy, there is no fining, filtration or additions to any of the wines, ever.  What the land offers is what they use in the winery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/4-1050by788-d6ca41.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/4-700by525-d6ca41.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/4-675by506-d6ca41.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/4-450by338-d6ca41.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/4-525by394-d6ca41.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/4-350by263-d6ca41.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/hyde-de-villaine/4-350by263-d6ca41.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Their Red Wines&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Most people are only familiar with the Chardonnay of HdV.  From the background of the co-owners, it is easy to see why.  But do not discount the red wines here.  The Syrahs were both very good and the Vine Cliff Cabernet was really special - it reminded me of the best French wines that have some Brett in their profile and are better / more complex wines for it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reservations are required for a tasting and just note that it’s pretty much a one man operation during most of the year - the one wine ambassador (Nate Olver) handles all of the phone calls, appointments, emails, etc.  This means that everything is done one customer at a time, including the tastings.  Though, they wouldn’t be able to fit more than one group of people in the office for a tasting anyways, haha.  NOTE: I don’t know if they normally pour this many wines for a tasting, so don’t overindex on the list below.  Though, if you show interest and appreciation for the wines, I wouldn’t be surprised if you had the opportunity to taste most of these wines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hdvwines.com/wines/detail?item=2016-le-debut&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Napa Valley Le Debut Carneros&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($50)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Even their young Chardonnay (Colera clone) has a rich minerality on the nose.  Limestone soil is very important for Burgundian Chardonnay, but there isn’t much of it in Napa (e.g. Mt. Harlan).  With the minerality, you also get very fresh ripe-but-light lemon and yellow apple.  The mouthfeel is the same way with really good harmony between the acid and ripeness thanks in part to the use of neutral oak.  No battonage in barrel and only one remuage.  For vines so young, they already display so much character in the wine…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hdvwines.com/wines/detail?item=15chy&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Napa Valley Chardonnay Carneros&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($70)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Their flagship wine as it represents 50% of their entire production.  The average vine age is around 30 years and they only use the Wente clone to enhance the minerality.  More butter on the profile, but still balanced with the acid and the fruit notes.  This wine is noticeably rounder and fuller bodied than the Le Debut.  I have no doubt this wine can age over a decade and can easily be paired with a meal.  I had to purchase a bottle to blind taste with the other greats of Napa.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2009 Napa Valley Chardonnay Hyde Vineyard&lt;/strong&gt; ($100)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It was fun to be able to taste their flagship 10 years into its life.  Still fresh on the nose with ripe lemon, butter, and a bit of nut, but not too oxidative.  It also sports a really nice golden color.  On the palate, the acid has settled down a bit, but the alcohol is 14.2% (it was a riper year), so there is some afterburn on the finish, making this an ideal fall/winter white wine.  There is still plenty of life in the bottle and could easily age another 5-10 years.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hdvwines.com/wines/detail?item=2016-hyde-pinot-noir&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Ygnacia Carneros Pinot Noir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($115)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fresh and fleshy red cranberry and strawberry that is not overly ripe/candied like many other Pinots from the valley.  20% new French Oak which gives it a hint of vanilla.  The balance between the tannin and body is nice with lift provided by the acidity.  This wine evokes a blend of Willamette and Burgundy Pinot, rather than RRV Pinot.  Easy drinking and complex thanks to the light earthiness in the wine.  I have no doubt that mushroom character will develop with age, making this really attractive.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hdvwines.com/wines/detail?item=11syrah&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2011 Californio Syrah Hyde Vineyard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($100)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A 12.5% ABV Syrah from the Napa Valley - I could hardly believe it…  Lots of fresh red fruit, some earthiness, and a hint of garrigue character on the nose.  The palate leans towards the garrigue character moreso than the red fruit (cranberry).  There is a balance between the complexity and integration of the wine, making it really appealing to wine nerds.  I must admit tasting this wine harkens me back to my travels in the Cote Rotie area.  I wouldn’t be surprised if the garrigue emphasis is due to the vintage conditions of 2011.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2007 Belle Cousine Hyde Vineyard&lt;/strong&gt; ($120)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;2007 was a great vintage for Napa and this blend of Merlot and Cabernet reflects that well.  Explosive nose of red fruit and tertiary character.  The acidity is still very bright, but the palate leans more towards the tertiary and is supported by the remaining red fruit.  I would not age this wine any longer - the balance is at its peak or slightly past it.  I really appreciate them opening this bottle for me though to show what I can expect when the wine is aging.  Sure to be a crowd-pleaser among the French lovers.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hdvwines.com/wines/detail?item=14syrah&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Californio Syrah Hyde Vineyard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What a difference three years and different vintage conditions can have.  Compared to the 2011, the 2014 has more white flowers, deeper red fruit and a perfume to the nose.  Those aromas carry straight through to the palate.  The structure of this wine is much bigger as well; the wine has smooth, ripe high tannin and medium(+) acid that are integrating nicely, but are still very noticeable.  It’ll take several years before the tertiary emerges to balance the fruit.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hdvwines.com/wines/detail?item=06827d8-14&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Belle Cousine Hyde Vineyard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($80)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Similarly, the 2014 Belle Cousine showed very differently compared to the 2007.  This wine is so pretty and feminine on the nose - ripe, developed red fruit that is very seductive and not candied.  The balance of tannin/acidity (more acid) leans to the French side and the tertiary notes are just getting started.  I think the optimal point for me will be after two more years, right before the tertiary notes stand out.  It’s really hard not to drink this wine right now though…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hdvwines.com/wines/detail?item=2014-vhr-vineyard-cabernet-sauvignon&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Cabernet Sauvignon Oakville Vine Hill Ranch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($195)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Only produced between 2013 and 2015 while they had access to the fruit.  100% Cabernet Sauvignon aged in 50% new oak.  This wine is just absolutely stunning.  The complexity is amazing for a wine this young.  The little bit of Brett and Pyrazines in the wine are masterfully done and well balanced with the fruit.  This is what good Brett in wine looks like; the French would be proud…  You can drink this right now and trick people into thinking that the wine is 10 years old.  Me, I would just sniff this wine for days…  It was $200 but I felt compelled to buy a bottle - that is how much this wine affected me.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for excellent Chardonnay and a French take on Napa fruit, you must visit HdV.  It’s rare to find a winery where every wine’s description contains the word “balance”, but that is what HdV offers those that visit.  If they serve you as many wines as they did me, the tasting fee will seem like a discounted amount.  HdV is also located very close to the town of Napa, so it is very easy to plan meals around the visit.  Just remember that this is not the place you want to take a group if you are looking for a winery tour or a place to relax outside for a couple hours.  Though the great thing about Napa is that there is a winery for every occasion, so just keep looking!  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="carneros" /><summary type="html">What is in a name? Well, for some it’s the most effective branding possible. The name “Villaine” is enough to grab any wine collector’s attention. Though, they normally associate it with a Burgundian winery that just happens to produce some of the most expensive wine on Earth (Aubert de Villaine of Domaine de la Romanee-Conti). Though, that association is exactly what the owners don’t want, even though the winery is related to that Villaine! The character of the terroir between the Cote de Nuit in Burgundy and Carneros in Napa are very different and you should expect very different wine because of that. And while the wine isn’t as good as DRC, it also doesn’t cost $20K+ a bottle either. I think what you do get with these wines is old world elegance, finesse, minerality, and a complexity that doesn’t over-index on the fruit character, thanks to the Burgundian traditions applied to Carneros fruit and terroir. Do I recommend you visit? You bet I do…</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/hyde-de-villaine/4.jpg" /></entry></feed>