<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-08-03T02:38:54+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Wines By Jeremy</title><subtitle>Wines by Jeremy offers an educative and enjoyable personalized wine experience. Located in the DC metro area, Wines by Jeremy provides a number of services including in-home exclusive tastings, highly curated event tastings, educational events, and wine cellar consulting.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Arcudi Wines Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/27/tony_arcudi_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Arcudi Wines Private Tasting" /><published>2019-07-27T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-27T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/27/tony_arcudi_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/27/tony_arcudi_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;This tasting wasn’t supposed to happen.  During a previous trip to Napa, my group and I happened to have the opportunity to try a bottle of Arcudi while at Fantesca because there wasn’t enough of their 2015 Spring Mountain Cabernet to serve for the tasting.  We found out Tony also produces Fantesca’s Pinot Noir and immediately signed up for his mailing list because both wines were delicious.  Soon after our first order, Tony reached out to personally thank us for the support and offered to host a visit whenever we were next in town.  I am sorry, but not sorry, to my friends because as soon as I found out he was recently hired as the consulting winemaker at Kapcsandy, I used any excuse to come to town and take him up on the offer, even if it was by myself…  Let’s just say, we need to make a second trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/1-1050by788-52a54a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/1-700by525-52a54a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/1-675by506-52a54a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/1-450by338-52a54a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/1-525by394-52a54a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/1-350by263-52a54a.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/1-350by263-52a54a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The House&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It is not uncommon for a winemaker to start a personal label while consulting for other wineries (see: Heidi Barrett, Thomas Rivers Brown, etc).  While others may be more established (e.g. larger/more diverse production, have deals to borrow tasting rooms), don’t expect Arcudi Wines to operate out of Tony’s house for long.  The wine is gorgeous and I have a feeling he’s going places…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But things did not start well.  Like a kid on Christmas Eve, I could not fall asleep in my Palo Alto hotel the night before.  I think I got 4 hours of sleep before picking up my rental car early at 7AM and arriving outside his house at 8:30AM.  And then I failed to nap for 90 minutes inside the car.  I’m surprised Tony let me in when I finally decided to knock on his door - I must have looked like a tired, wired, stressed, mess.  But let me in he did.  He sat me at his table, poured some wine, thanked me again for my patronage and then asked “What would you like to know?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/2-1050by1400-d4c34a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/2-700by933-d4c34a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/2-675by900-d4c34a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/2-450by600-d4c34a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/2-525by700-d4c34a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/2-350by467-d4c34a.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/2-350by467-d4c34a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Pour&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;During our talk, Tony was kind enough to offer me a pour of the newly minted 2015 Arcudi from the Black Sears Vineyard on Howell Mountain.  This wine was simultaneously monumental and elegant.  The quality of the grapes was striking, in addition to how  how well the wine was made.  I’d normally assume that 10+ years of aging is required to access this wine, but it was gorgeous and accessible at 4.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to deep dive on Tony’s life as I’m sure there are other resources that capture his history in more detail.  Actually, the real reason is because my attention was equally divided between the amazing wine in front of me and the amazing story I was listening to.  The wine was an absolute home run that lives up to and even surpasses its price tag.  You can read the tasting notes below, but just note that I met a wine ambassador from Black Sears Vineyard (where Tony gets the fruit for Arcudi wines) at the Howell Mountain Festival in Napa later that year and even he admitted that it was the best wine made from that vineyard.  That is really saying something…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/3-1050by788-e5dfbc.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/3-700by525-e5dfbc.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/3-675by506-e5dfbc.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/3-450by338-e5dfbc.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/3-525by394-e5dfbc.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/3-350by263-e5dfbc.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/3-350by263-e5dfbc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Talk&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Again, words cannot express how honored I was to sit down with Tony.  He opened his home to me at 10AM on a Saturday, poured a glass of $150 wine, and spent an hour discussing how he came to be a winemaker in Napa.  There are some parallels between us that made quite an impact on me.  I will get into the wine world one day…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I loved Tony’s story too.  He grew up in the Boston area (I went there for college); he enlisted in the Navy and became a missile navigation engineer (my father was an Army Ordnance Officer in Korea); he was a product manager in the tech sector (basically my current job); he loves Bruno Giacosa wines (also my favorite Italian wine); he worked at Maison M. Chapoutier (I loved visiting them in Hermitage); he works with Heidi Barrett (one of my all-time favorite winemakers); and he now consults at Kapcsandy (probably my favorite US winery).  I was speechless.  He did tell me of all the trials and tribulations it took to get to this point, but I wasn’t listening.  All that mattered at that moment was how can I get into this world?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/4-1050by1400-9da8c1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/4-700by933-9da8c1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/4-675by900-9da8c1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/4-450by600-9da8c1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/4-525by700-9da8c1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/4-350by467-9da8c1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/tony-arcudi/4-350by467-9da8c1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Store&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I’ve purchased a few bottles of his wines in the past, but after an experience like this, I couldn’t help but fill my wine suitcase with more.  I got a sneak peak at his personal tastes too (he is aging some great Italian wines).  There were quite a few bottles of King Richard’s Pinot Noir as well (the wine he makes for Fantesca).  I might put on a tasting of his wines one day since I have two complete verticals now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could not settle down at all through the tasting, which is why my tasting note on the wine seems less descript / more hand-wave-y than normal.  Maybe when I setup a vertical tasting of his wines, I’ll revist the tasting notes and fill in some vintages.  Til then, this will have to suffice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arcudiwines.com/wines/detail/?item=2016-cabernet-sauvignon-black-sears-vineyard&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Howell Mountain Cabernet Sauvignon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ($150)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pretty purple flowers, cocoa, and crushed, candied black fruit on the nose.  Although the palate has high tannin, high acid, and high alcohol, the wine already feels rounded and approachable at its young age.  I cannot understate the amazing texture - it feels weighty and elegant simultaneously, similar to Kapcsandy Cabernets.  The flavors are not as opulent as Cabernets from the valley floor, but it still has intense richness that unfolds over time.  I know it can age for 20+ years, but it’s so attractive right now, not unlike Heidi Barrett wines.  Bravo!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gone are the days where a winemaker works at winery they don’t own for their entire career.  Similar to free agency in sports, it’s important to note who the winemaker is as well as the estate a wine comes from.  Because variations between vintages may not just be influenced by the weather, but the qualities of the winemaker and their “style”.  Judging by the wines I’ve had so far, I know Tony Arcudi is someone I want to follow from now on, no matter who he’s making wine for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get the chance to have one of his wines, cheers to you!  If you are lucky enough to meet the man in person, an extra cheers for you.  I hope to visit him again soon and try his new Pritchard Hill release!  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="california" /><category term="napa" /><category term="howell-mountain" /><summary type="html">This tasting wasn’t supposed to happen. During a previous trip to Napa, my group and I happened to have the opportunity to try a bottle of Arcudi while at Fantesca because there wasn’t enough of their 2015 Spring Mountain Cabernet to serve for the tasting. We found out Tony also produces Fantesca’s Pinot Noir and immediately signed up for his mailing list because both wines were delicious. Soon after our first order, Tony reached out to personally thank us for the support and offered to host a visit whenever we were next in town. I am sorry, but not sorry, to my friends because as soon as I found out he was recently hired as the consulting winemaker at Kapcsandy, I used any excuse to come to town and take him up on the offer, even if it was by myself… Let’s just say, we need to make a second trip.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/tony-arcudi/3.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Clos du Mont-Olivet Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/20/clos_du_mont_olivet_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Clos du Mont-Olivet Public Tasting" /><published>2019-07-20T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-20T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/20/clos_du_mont_olivet_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/20/clos_du_mont_olivet_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve enjoyed several bottles of Clos du Mont Olivet in the past, so the trip to Châteauneuf wouldn’t have been complete without stopping by.  And without Google Maps, I never would have because this place is hard to find…  I don’t recall there being a clear sign outside directing visitors, but the door was branded in the same style as their wine labels, so I knew it was the right place when I knocked on the door.  Do not expect much in the way of aesthetics, but be prepared to taste solid wines that are steals at their price points.  And with a production of 50,000+ bottles a year, you should be able to find their wine back in the USA too.  So enjoy the irony between their office and quality/production while sipping on some serious wine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you drink Châteauneuf in the states and read publications like Jeb Dunnuck and his Rhone Report, you’ve likely heard of Clos du Mont Olivet before.  It isn’t in the same production category as Famille Perrin, but the quality and scores are right there.  I had one of their non-appellation wines at lunch in town on an earlier day which excited me even more (I remember it being surprisingly good for the price).  Similar to Pegau and other places in town, I was lucky that the advertising and storefront were subpar.  As you can see in the picture below, the room wouldn’t be able to accomodate more than one or two groups of visitors at a time and I wouldn’t have wanted to wait long for a tasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-du-mont-olivet/1-1050by788-3085be.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-du-mont-olivet/1-700by525-3085be.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-du-mont-olivet/1-675by506-3085be.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-du-mont-olivet/1-450by338-3085be.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-du-mont-olivet/1-525by394-3085be.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-du-mont-olivet/1-350by263-3085be.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-du-mont-olivet/1-350by263-3085be.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Tasting Room and Office&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;This is Clos du Mont Olivet!  I know, not much to look at - their office and tasting room are the same room after all.  Again, don’t let appearances deceive you.  Quality, price, and marketing are not always 100% correlated.  In this case, it works to the benefit of the consumer.  Out of the many wines I tried in Châteauneuf, I would pick their wine for my everyday table wine, considering the quality and price point.  And no matter your income level, everybody needs bottles like that…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my normal fashion, I introduced myself and gave glimpse of my background, especially why I was excited to be visiting with them.  They were going to start me directly on the Châteauneuf-du-Pape, but I asked to see their more affordable wines as well.  And it was a good thing I did.  The first two wines were quite surprising in quality for the prices.  I know I espoused the QPR of Domaine Durieu in an earlier post, but Clos du Mont Olivet may just be the steal of my Châteauneuf-du-Pape trip.  The style of the tasting was also very different - while the tasting at Domaine Durieu had 60s American rock music and energy, Clos du Mont Olivet played soothing string music and sounds, not unlike the music played during a massage.  As I was tasting by myself again, the music contributed to a relaxing experience that was interesting to reflect on.  Did the music make the wine more enjoyable?  Quite possibly.  If I run a winery one day, that might not be a bad idea for a private tasting room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like other great wineries, quality and care go into even their cheapest wines.  All of their non-appellation wines are grown and produced using similar methods as their highest rated wines.  For example, all of their vineyards are hand picked, pruned to low yields, sorted, etc.  One thing to note is that their white wine isn’t distributed yet to the USA as there is a name conflict with an American winery.  Once they change the name and I find out what it is, I will be sure to post it.  For now, it is referenced as “Vin de France Blanc” below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Vin de France Blanc&lt;/strong&gt; (9.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Ugni Blanc and Grenache Blanc from Lirac are blended together with second pressed juice from the Chateauneuf-du-Pape Blanc (Roussane, Bourboulanc and Clairette).  Very ripe and floral on the nose with notes of perfumed starfruit, ripe apricot, melon, and some MLF (butter/cream).  The wine has medium(+) acidity that balances the ripe fruit flavors, keeps the wine very fresh, light, and gives it a clean finish.  Though, that doesn’t impede the pronounced intensity on the palate one bit.  For the price point, this is an excellent wine, though I can see how it might be hard to drink more than two glasses in a sitting.  This wine will also be a bigger hit with California lovers than traditional French lovers.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.closmontolivet.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/20152.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 A Seraphin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (11.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Made from fruit grown 30 kilometers north of Châteauneuf-du-Pape.  Even though it doesn’t come from the AOC, that doesn’t mean the fruit quality poor in comparison.  A blend of 50% Grenache, 40% Syrah, and 10% old vine Carignan (45-60 years old).  Pronounced, ripe red fruit on the nose with a little bit of perfume and underlying spice.  The palate is not quite integrated yet - the light red fruit, spice and wood/earth character are all distinct.  The tannins are a bit rough at this stage of its life as well, so give it 2-3 years to integrate and soften.  I’m curious as to how the flavor profile will evolve during this time.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.closmontolivet.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/20163.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Châteauneuf-du-Pape&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (25.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A blend of 80% Grenache, 10% Syrah, 6% Mouvedre, and other varietals comprising the last 4%.  Served from a 375ml bottle as smaller bottles age faster and offer a look as to how the wines will develop.  Make no mistake, this cuvee is meant for aging and any attempts to enjoy it now will be like measuring the tip of an iceberg…  This wine is the face of their estate; 50,000 bottles are produced each year.  The red fruit is riper than their other wines with a slight candied quality.  The wine also displays undulating tertiary and spice notes in lower intensity.  The palate has medium(+) acid, high tannin, medium body, with flavors similar to the nose except the red fruit has a reduced intensity while the wood/earth come out more.  This wine is already pretty good but give this 4-5 years to start showing its true colors.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.closmontolivet.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/20162.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 La Cuvee du Papet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (45.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Only produced in the best vintages, this wine comes mostly from GSM vines that are all near ancient (80-100 years old).  The jamminess is accentuated on the nose of this wine and the complexity is higher than the Châteauneuf blend with better integration of flavors as well.  Medium(+) acid, high tannin, medium body, with flavors similar to the nose (the fruit is still jammy), but there is a spiciness that tickles the tongue at the end.  The tannins are smooth already and you could easily enjoy this now if you wanted to, though it will only get better.  I am confident that the fruit will hold strong in this wine through 10-15 years of aging.  I personally wouldn’t be able to hold onto the wine that long though, haha.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You never know where you will find great wines.  Luckily for me, I happened to know the quality and potential without having to rely on their branding or presence in town.  I highly recommend that you stop here for a tasting, if only to walk away with 10-25€ wines that you could happily enjoy over lunch or dinner.  If you want to find the Châteauneuf after tasting it for yourself, you shouldn’t have problems searching online, though as with all wines, there will be a markup from the shipping/distribution lifecycle.  So get out there and enjoy some great QPR wines.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="southern-rhone" /><category term="chateauneuf-du-pape" /><summary type="html">I’ve enjoyed several bottles of Clos du Mont Olivet in the past, so the trip to Châteauneuf wouldn’t have been complete without stopping by. And without Google Maps, I never would have because this place is hard to find… I don’t recall there being a clear sign outside directing visitors, but the door was branded in the same style as their wine labels, so I knew it was the right place when I knocked on the door. Do not expect much in the way of aesthetics, but be prepared to taste solid wines that are steals at their price points. And with a production of 50,000+ bottles a year, you should be able to find their wine back in the USA too. So enjoy the irony between their office and quality/production while sipping on some serious wine.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/clos-du-mont-olivet/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Domaine Durieu Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/13/domaine_durieu_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Domaine Durieu Public Tasting" /><published>2019-07-13T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-13T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/13/domaine_durieu_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/13/domaine_durieu_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;The tasting at Domaine Durieu provided a perfect foil to my tasting at Beaurenard in that it served as proof that the wine tasting experience can have as much impact on the customer as the quality of the wines themselves.  And nothing is more important to the wine tasting experience than the quality of the wine ambassador giving it.  It didn’t hurt either that he took me through their entire portfolio while rock music from the 60s set the mood in the background.  And at 20€ to 30€ a bottle, the wines were nice QPR darlings.  The 2012 Traditional CdP also provided a glimpse of what aging would do to these wines (spoiler alert: great times ahead).  Domaine Durieu is worth the stop while in town and may end up surprising you in a great way!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/1-1050by788-c67e12.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/1-700by525-c67e12.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/1-675by506-c67e12.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/1-450by338-c67e12.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/1-525by394-c67e12.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/1-350by263-c67e12.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/1-350by263-c67e12.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Storefront&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The entrance to Domaine Durieu’s tasting room in town and a very unflattering reflection of myself, haha.  It was amazing to me that Châteauneuf-du-Pape, the hub of amazing wines in the south-east of France, could have stores like this that were completely empty in the middle of the summer.  This area is under-appreciated as a wine tourism destination and one can only hope more people recognize that fact.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the majority of wineries in Châteauneuf, Domaine Durieu is family-owned and managed.  It was first started by the grandmother (Lucile Avril) and grandfather (Henri Duriel) several decades ago, but today boasts 40 hectares of land in Châteauneuf-du-Pape and 9 hectares in the greater Cotes du Pape.  Although they produced mostly strict AOC blends in the past, after the two brothers took over in 2004, Domaine Durieu began to produce other blends that are more accessible earlier in the life of the wine (ie. reduced harshness of tannins).  Even still, I’d like to give everyone of their wines a few more years in bottle…  And this is not to say they’ve completely overthrown tradition - they still produce a traditional blend each vintage for those that like to emphasize ageability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/2-1050by788-043cc9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/2-700by525-043cc9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/2-675by506-043cc9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/2-450by338-043cc9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/2-525by394-043cc9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/2-350by263-043cc9.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/2-350by263-043cc9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Tasting Room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Again, the wine tasting room wasn’t anything special.  I did like how the worn floor contrasted the clean walls and emaculate wine glasses.  You’ll notice that there were no spit buckets on the tasting table.  Instead, there were sinks built into the table where you could pour your wines out and it would drain into a container under the table.  But spitting was a dangerous game (#splashback).  I don’t know, I just really liked this space…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although their shop in town is quite small, the selection of wines is vast and goes back several vintages.  There is no need to make a reservation to stop by - just make sure that you go before lunch or wait until 2pm or so.  If you come with questions and curiosity, you will enjoy the tasting even more and the wine ambassador loves to talk and explain the wines.  Though if you are a white wine lover, this is not the place for you.  Like many wineries in the area, Domaine Durieu does not taste any of their white wines as they were either sold out or close to it.  Remember, 95% of the wines produced in Chateauneuf are red, so you really are in the wrong city in general for white wines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/3-1050by788-fcae24.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/3-700by525-fcae24.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/3-675by506-fcae24.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/3-450by338-fcae24.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/3-525by394-fcae24.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/3-350by263-fcae24.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-durieu/3-350by263-fcae24.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Wine Ambassador&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;My wine ambassador with his line-up of wines.  I appreciated that we tasted not only the current vintage, but also some past vintages to give the consumer an idea of how the wines will age.  I did pick up a bottle of the 2012 to bring back with me because it had already achieved a nice roundness to the wine with a fair amount of decanting.  It was unfair that all of the wines were so affordable - I had to think of excuses on the spot why I wasn’t buying one of each for my flight home…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some brief introductions, sharing our love of wine, American rock music, and a great discussion on science versus tradition in the “field” of wine, the wine ambassador poured me some wines and let me experience them at my own pace.  That may be what I loved most by this tasting.  Although I was the only patron in the shop, he could have rushed me through everything.  Instead, we enjoyed decent pours of each wine at a leisurely pace and he didn’t let me move on to the next wine until he was satisfied that I took away what I should from each of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.domainedurieu.fr/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/plandedieu.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Plan de Dieu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (9€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;70% Grenache, 10% each of Syrah, Cinsault, and Carignan.  Because of the Carignan, this cannot be classified as an AOC wine, hence the name.  There is a brooding, raisined fruit note blended with bright flowers on the nose with medium intensity.  Medium(+) acid, high tannin, medium body with a lighter intensity palate than the nose hints at.  Ripe, raisined red fruit, wood notes, light spice, and a hint of some unripened cranberry on the finish.  The wine is complex and interesting, though probably not for the easy drinking crowd.  At 9€ a bottle, that’s saying something…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.domainedurieu.fr/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/cdp.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Traditional Chateauneuf-du-Pape&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (19€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;80% Grenache, 10% Syrah, 5% Mouvedre, 3% Cinsault, and 2% Counoise.  Light red fruit and herbs on the nose.  It’s unfair to even attempt to drink this wine right now.  I wouldn’t even bother trying to decant it.  The screaming high, rough tannins make this wine hard to taste, not to mention hard to enjoy.  The red fruit seems to be big enough to stand up to the aging and hopefully evolves on the nose in the future.  The wine ambassador did warn me about this wine, but I wanted to taste it anyways because 2015 is such a heralded vintage…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.domainedurieu.fr/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/lucileavril.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Lucile Avril Chateauneuf-du-Pape&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (24€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;85% old vine Grenache, 10% old vine Mouvedre, and 5% Syrah.  We had an amazing discussion on how Duck Breast and Truffle Risotto would pair perfectly with this wine.  Not the usual conversation for a 24€ wine.  The red fruit is a bit sweeter than the traditional blend (candied cranberry) and the pepper is much more upfront.  Medium acid, high tannin, and medium bodied.  The palate still has the candied cranberry and while the tannin is high, it’s rounded enough to enjoy now.  Earth, spice and a very light wood undertone contribute to the wine feeling grounded.  I could easily drink more than a couple glasses of this wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.domainedurieu.fr/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/henridurieu.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Henri Durieu Plan de Dieu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (11€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;90% old vine Grenache and 5% each of Carignan and Mouvedre.  Even brighter red fruit than the last wine, but still a complex nose.  Feels lighter/brighter on the palate as well with high acid, high tannin but a medium(-) body.  It is harder to feel out more than red fruit of medium(-) intensity thanks to the tannin, medium(-) body, and the closed state of the wine.  As this wine ages (softens/integrates), I think you can expect this to become a complex wine that offers the red spectrum of flavors and maybe even dried fruits at a low intensity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Traditional Chateauneuf-du-Pape&lt;/strong&gt; (21€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Like the 2015, it feels like you can wait an additional 15 years on this wine if you wanted.  The red fruit is present, but there is an earthy perfume already present from aging (weirdly pleasant, almost like freshly shampoo-ed hair) with some spices.  Feels much better on the palate than the 2015 with a complex palate that is mostly tertiary driven, contrasting the nose.  There is enough fruit on the palate that you do not feel as if you are tasting earth and wood, but that is the dominant profile and it’s not unpleasant.  Definitely one of the more terroir-true wines I’ve had from Chateauneuf.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Lucile Avril Chateauneuf-du-Pape&lt;/strong&gt; (26€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This wine also has that weirdly pleasant “freshly shampoo-ed hair” aroma, but with a bit more bright cranberry behind it.  The tannins have softened to make this drinkable and the red fruit has begun to balance with the tertiary flavors as well.  I don’t know if this wine is lower intensity than the others or if the tertiary flavors just make the wine appear that way.  Still, another wine where you can easily drink multiple glasses.  Softest of the wines in the portfolio tasted thus far.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Tradition Chateauneuf-du-Pape&lt;/strong&gt; (30€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This wine was the star of the tasting.  Black plum, licorice, smoke, and black pepper on the nose in high intensity.  On the palate, this wine is incredible.  The secret to making the wine taste this great is opening the bottle and letting it sit overnight before drinking it.  That alone is enough to integrate the tannins even more and bring out the black plum flavor out to the extent that it is.  That flavor flows over the palate and there is a juiciness that supports and integrates with the tertiary flavors.  I had to get a bottle of this, even with my full suitcase.  It was that good and at only 30€…  I just hope I can replicate the process to make the wine open up.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see above, the wines in this lineup were very traditional and a little closed in the beginning.  If you purchase a Durieu wine, be prepared to wait on it until it is ready or to decant it like a Barolo.  But when it is ready, like the 2012 Traditional CdP, the result can be absolutely inspiring.  Even at a cost of 10-15€ a bottle, it may still be worth shipping a case back to the USA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you are in town and in the mood for more rustic Chateauneuf, make sure you stop by and ask them what the oldest vintage is that you are able to taste.  If you can go back further than the 2012, you know I’ll be jealous and asking your thoughts.  In the meantime, I’m going to let my bottle hit 10 years old and give it another go.  I just hope that I can find some more bottles in the US in the meantime…  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="southern-rhone" /><category term="chateauneuf-du-pape" /><summary type="html">The tasting at Domaine Durieu provided a perfect foil to my tasting at Beaurenard in that it served as proof that the wine tasting experience can have as much impact on the customer as the quality of the wines themselves. And nothing is more important to the wine tasting experience than the quality of the wine ambassador giving it. It didn’t hurt either that he took me through their entire portfolio while rock music from the 60s set the mood in the background. And at 20€ to 30€ a bottle, the wines were nice QPR darlings. The 2012 Traditional CdP also provided a glimpse of what aging would do to these wines (spoiler alert: great times ahead). Domaine Durieu is worth the stop while in town and may end up surprising you in a great way!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/domaine-durieu/3.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Domaine de Beaurenard Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/06/domaine_de_beaurenard_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Domaine de Beaurenard Public Tasting" /><published>2019-07-06T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-06T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/06/domaine_de_beaurenard_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/07/06/domaine_de_beaurenard_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Not every tasting experience is going to be amazing.  The positive way to look at it is that it helps to emphasize the other places that you did like…  All things considered, I think Domaine de Beaurenard was my least favorite tasting in Châteauneuf-du-Pape.  Granted, I did not make an appointment, but I was also the only visitor at the winery when I arrived.  There was a tasting tour group (one of those that you can purchase/schedule online that originates from Avignon) that came in 30 minutes after me, but even then the guide did most of the talking rather than the winery ambassador.  I learned more from him than I did from my tasting and the notes provided about the winery.  The wines were also a bit austere compared to others.  You win some, you lose some!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/1-1050by788-cbdf48.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/1-700by525-cbdf48.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/1-675by506-cbdf48.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/1-450by338-cbdf48.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/1-525by394-cbdf48.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/1-350by263-cbdf48.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/1-350by263-cbdf48.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Sign&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The sign and entrance to the winery.  I hope I caught the winery on an off day, but I honestly wouldn’t visit again to try and find out.  There are too many wineries in the area that blew me away to give other wineries a second shot.  This is very similar to how I feel about wineries in densely populated wine-producing regions in the USA.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Domaine de Beaurenard is right off one of the main streets that runs around Châteauneuf.  It runs south of the town and then east of it, up to Domaine Roger SABON and beyond.  It is also right next to the wine museum in town, so I would expect it to get decent foot and car traffic.  The wine museum was a bit underwhelming compared to those in other regions of France, so I would understand why people may not travel down this way much.  I had just finished reading up on some history of the area at the museum after lunch, so I was ready for more wine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/2-1050by788-a2f569.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/2-700by525-a2f569.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/2-675by506-a2f569.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/2-450by338-a2f569.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/2-525by394-a2f569.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/2-350by263-a2f569.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/beaurenard/2-350by263-a2f569.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Tasting Counter&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I don’t know if I was intimidating with my laptop and use of the spit bucket.  I like to think not.  The tasting counter at Beaurenard is rather small, but did not cause any sort of hindrance.  There is an open area to the right that is large enough to entertain groups.  It was funny how the tour guide went behind the counter grabbed bottles and just started pouring wine for his group, even though I know he didn’t work there, haha.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I visited and tasted through the wines, I was treated with a mild neglect, as each wine was poured without much explanation to the background of the wine, what the winery hoped to achieve with each one, and why each bottling was different/interesting.  I don’t think it was the language barrier either as I am pretty sure that the wine ambassador spoke English well.  I admit that if the wines were fantastic, then I would’ve been glad to be left to my own devices.  But while the blanc was entertaining, the other two reds felt too young, a bit austere, and not ready for tasting.  I understand the 2016 vintage was excellent and these two could be excellent in a few years, but I don’t think it was the best Châteauneuf-du-Pape has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Chateauneuf-du-Pape Blanc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (35€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Majority of Clairette and Rousanne but is blended with all 6 white varieties of the AOC.  On the nose, bright white peaches, white flowers, and some wood aromas as well.  The flavor profile on the palate emulated the aromas, except there was a zestiness present that seemed to come from the minerality.  Medium(+) acid with a shorter finish.  Nice to drink on a hot day, especially when paired with some food because of that zest, but seemed a little lacking on its own for the pricepoint.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Chateauneuf-du-Pape Rouge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (35€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;GSM majority blend with the rest of the 13 AOC-designate varieties appearing in lower quantities, similar to how Clos Des Papes includes the broad spectrum of varieties in their blends.  The grapes here come from clay/sand/stone terroirs that make biodynamic farming possible.  Give this wine at least 3 hours to breath or lay it down for 3-5 years.  Red fruit on the nose (cherry/strawberry) but medium intensity and medium brightness of fruit.  The palate has a lot of hard tannin making the flavors difficult to feel out, but the spice is more white and red than black pepper.  The high, rough tannin and lower intensity of flavors make this wine a little difficult to enjoy now, but it could definitely be interesting given that 3-5 years.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Chateauneuf-du-Pape Boisrenard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (55€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Low quantity production wine made from ancient vines over 100 years old.  The varietal composition is unknown because the vines were co-planted together in the vineyard in those days as a form a risk management to ensure there were at least some yields each year, no matter the conditions.  The nose is bigger, more complex and jammy than the CdP Rouge.  That impression carries over to the palate - more red fruit, but also more complexity from earth, old wood, thyme, and some light spice notes.  Like the first red, this wine needs time to round out and integrate more, but there is definitely potential, especially if you prefer lighter styled wines that reflect the terroir.  At this pricepoint, it was hard for me to take the leap of faith on a bottle without tasting older vintages so see how they’ve traditionally aged.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no doubt that the wines could become much more interesting and approachable in a few years, but it was a little difficult to enjoy them now.  If the wines sound interesting enough to try, please do!  If anyone has older vintages of this wine that have come around beautifully, I would love to know!  Tough in the meantime, I’ll likely stick to places closer aligned to my palate, preferences, and expectations of tasting hospitality.  Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="southern-rhone" /><category term="chateauneuf-du-pape" /><summary type="html">Not every tasting experience is going to be amazing. The positive way to look at it is that it helps to emphasize the other places that you did like… All things considered, I think Domaine de Beaurenard was my least favorite tasting in Châteauneuf-du-Pape. Granted, I did not make an appointment, but I was also the only visitor at the winery when I arrived. There was a tasting tour group (one of those that you can purchase/schedule online that originates from Avignon) that came in 30 minutes after me, but even then the guide did most of the talking rather than the winery ambassador. I learned more from him than I did from my tasting and the notes provided about the winery. The wines were also a bit austere compared to others. You win some, you lose some!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/beaurenard/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Domaine La Barroche Private Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/06/29/domaine_la_barroche_private_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Domaine La Barroche Private Tasting" /><published>2019-06-29T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-06-29T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/06/29/domaine_la_barroche_private_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/06/29/domaine_la_barroche_private_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;If there is one winery in Châteauneuf-du-Pape that reminds me of Napa Valley, it’s Domaine la Barroche.  And when I say “Napa Valley”, I don’t mean the large wineries that host hundreds of people for walk-in tastings each day.  I mean the top quality estates where you are the only people on the tour, everything about the winery is dedicated to making great wine, and the wine is fantastic…  In addition, the wine here is more fruit driven and pure than many other estates in the area, so it will greatly please the Napa lovers out there.  If Clos Des Papes was my favorite tasting experience, this may have been my favorite overall experience.  Do NOT miss Domaine la Barroche during your exploration of the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/1-1050by788-99cfb0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/1-700by525-99cfb0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/1-675by506-99cfb0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/1-450by338-99cfb0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/1-525by394-99cfb0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/1-350by263-99cfb0.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/1-350by263-99cfb0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The entrance to the winery&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The gate to the new wine facility for Domaine La Barroche.  After operating in their existing facility for decades, the owner decided to invest in a new winery to continue his crusade of making quality wines.  Their older winery continues to operate, but produces less volume than it used to as much of the harvest is brought here now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the early 1700s, the Barrot family have owned the land that the Domaine is built upon in Châteauneuf.  Passed down through the generations, it wasn’t until the late 19th century that plots would be chosen to plant vines.  The motto of the family has always been that of winegrowers - that wines are made in the vineyard, not in the winery.  Finally in 2015, they decided to invest in that part of the process too and opened a new state-of-the-art production facility.  Though, I admit, “state-of-the-art” is the lazy way to describe this winery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/2-1050by788-b0906b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/2-700by525-b0906b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/2-675by506-b0906b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/2-450by338-b0906b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/2-525by394-b0906b.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/2-350by263-b0906b.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/2-350by263-b0906b.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;A better view of the building&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A better view of the new facility.  You can tell how new it is by how clean the building and sign look.  This made it easy to spot the winery off the street.  It’s a reservation-only winery, so be sure to make one!  And I must say - I am so impressed by that rock wall.  I can only imagine how long it took to build, but it looks gorgeous walking by it…  Clean and rustic - a fair assessment of their wine as well.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the outside, it looks clean cut and simple except for the beautifully assembled stone walls on opposite sides of the main gate.  The inside reminds me of the best wineries that integrate class and function - everything has a purpose, is 100% geared toward making wine, but organized in such a way that it looks like art.  For example, they use gravity flow for moving the grapes, must and eventually wine to their destinations.  Each level has its own feel - the top floor is steel and white, with the next level a darker tan with barrels lined against the walls.  But each step is seamlessly connected to ensure a smooth production process.  This is the type of winery that everyone wants to copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/3-1050by788-f50c4f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/3-700by525-f50c4f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/3-675by506-f50c4f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/3-450by338-f50c4f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/3-525by394-f50c4f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/3-350by263-f50c4f.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/3-350by263-f50c4f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Where we had the tasting&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;We conducted the tasting 1-on-1 in the cellar of their winery.  That table you see is not a table - it’s actually an authentic well that’s been there since before they built the new winery.  It was a little cool down here, but the experience was fantastic and it was fun walking through, seeing the bottles for sale and this year’s harvest in barrels.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their oldest vintage in the new facility is 2016, so all vintages before that are from the other facility.  I personally thought it was fun to compare and contrast the 2015 and 2016.  Both vintages are rated highly with the 2016 scoring slightly better, but I was convinced that the 2016 had a bit more precision to it (or maybe I talked myself into it?).  The price point on their wines is very reasonable; even their best wine (Pure) is under 80 Euros.  Though, make sure you purchase the wines at the winery as the markup is considerable back in the states where high scores and ratings drive up the price of the Pure to ~$150.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/4-1050by788-890b2a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/4-700by525-890b2a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/4-675by506-890b2a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/4-450by338-890b2a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/4-525by394-890b2a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/4-350by263-890b2a.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-la-barroche/4-350by263-890b2a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The vats!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A picture of the wine ambassador with a bottle of Pure while in front of their giant concrete foudres.  I cannot overstate how gorgeous and pristine it was inside the winery.  It would appeal to anyone’s wine and/or architectural sense.  It was also surreal to be at the winery by ourselves.  They opened up just for me - they had no other visitors that day.  Knowing how much Pure goes for in the states, I was foolish not to fill my suitcase with it on the spot…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with other winery tours, we spent time talking about the vines (they have some ancient vine Grenache on the property), their wine production process with the gravity flow, and the style of wines the proprietors hope to achieve.  After walking around their cellar and admiring the collection of Pure on the shelves, we opened a few bottles to taste.  You can find their wine catalog &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.domainelabarroche.com/our-wines/?lang=en&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.domainelabarroche.com/libertyEN.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Vin de France Liberty&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (19€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A blend of Grenache, Syrah, Mouvedre (GSM) with Cinsault and Carignan.  On the nose, violets and a combination of deep red and black fruit.  Because the grapes come from just outside Châteauneuf-du-Pape and the wine has some Carignan, it cannot be an AOC designate wine.  The palate has intensity and is mainly fruit driven and bright, making it drinkable without any aging required to enjoy it.  This wine is for those that like their Châteauneuf a little juicy with slightly less black pepper.  It still has some tertiary flavors towards the finish that will come out more with time, but why wait?  Very nice for the price point…&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Chateauneuf-du-Pape Signature – Julien Barrot&lt;/strong&gt; (35€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Poured from a 375ml bottle.  GSM blend with some Cinsault.  Bright and fresh on the nose with seemingly equal amounts of red/blue/black fruit, though not much tertiary influence.  The palate is medium(+) acid, high ripe tannin, medium body, with flavors of fresh black fruit (blackberry.  Although the tannins are ripe, they still need just a year or two more to smooth out even more.  On the finish, the depth of the fruit becomes more apparent, but it’s too easy to fall in love with the freshness on the nose/palate.  Very clean for a Châteauneuf and an upgrade over the Liberty in its balance, depth, and aging potential.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.domainelabarroche.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/SIGNATURE_UK.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Chateauneuf-du-Pape Signature&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (35€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Jammy and cooked fruit flavors on the nose with black pepper being a significant part of the profile.  Medium acid, high tannin, and medium body with flavors of raisined red fruit, kirsch, black pepper, and some black fruit.  The tannins dry out your mouth on the finish, but I’d still consider it having bright red fruit at the end.  This one will definitely require more aging or decanting than the 2016 and is definitely more for those that like a little more “brooding” in their wine.  The 2016 is just so bright and balanced by comparison.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.domainelabarroche.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/FIANCEE_UK.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Fiancee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (55€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Blend of 40% old vine Grenache and 60% young Syrah.  The nose is very pretty thanks to the Syrah - bright red fruit that’s less ripe than cherry but also a bit candied.  Medium acid, high tannin, medium body, with flavors of young, fresh riper-than-cranberry red fruit and some spice.  The tannins are grippy in this young wine and will obviously round out with age.  I’d love to see this wine in 3-5 years when the tannins mellow into the body.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.domainelabarroche.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/PURE_UK.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Pure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (78€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;100% ancient vine (100+ years old) Grenache that comes from a fine-grained sand plot in the northeast of the appellation, right next to Chateau Rayas (cult-status Châteauneuf).  Aged in Foudre, which prevents oxidation of the Grenache while minimize oak flavors.  Great depth on the nose with red (kirsch) and black fruit coming out and light baking spice tickling the nose at the end.  Medium+ acid and tannin with a medium body.  The flavors are ripe, nearly reaching raisined character, and span the breadth of the red/black spectrum with not too much tertiary character yet.  The tannins are very fine but present which makes the wine appear very elegant at a young age.  It’s inspiring how much character is in this single varietal wine.  Bravo!  Best drinking window is 7-9 years according to the wine ambassador running the tasting.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was disappointed that I didn’t get to taste the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.domainelabarroche.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/PURE_blancUK.pdf&quot;&gt;2016 Pure Blanc&lt;/a&gt; because it sold out upon release,  But it is 55€, an 800 bottle production, and scored very well - I think I saw it being resold in the states for $150 as well.  This wine emulates the Pure Rouge in that it is a 100% varietal wine (Clairette) and evidently displays similar complex character.  I was encouraged to track down a bottle to try it, so track it down I will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must say I was extremely impressed how approachable their wines were at such a young age.  The fineness of the tannins were immediately noticeable and are likely a result of their precises winemaking practices.  I purchased a half-case of their Signature Chateauneuf-du-Pape and a few bottles of the Pure Rouge when I returned the states and am very happy with that decision.  If you’d like to track down bottles for yourself, you can try contacting their distributor in the states (David Bowler Wine - bowlerwine.com).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t wait to share these wines with friends in a blind tasting and hope that you get an opportunity to enjoy them too.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="southern-rhone" /><category term="chateauneuf-du-pape" /><summary type="html">If there is one winery in Châteauneuf-du-Pape that reminds me of Napa Valley, it’s Domaine la Barroche. And when I say “Napa Valley”, I don’t mean the large wineries that host hundreds of people for walk-in tastings each day. I mean the top quality estates where you are the only people on the tour, everything about the winery is dedicated to making great wine, and the wine is fantastic… In addition, the wine here is more fruit driven and pure than many other estates in the area, so it will greatly please the Napa lovers out there. If Clos Des Papes was my favorite tasting experience, this may have been my favorite overall experience. Do NOT miss Domaine la Barroche during your exploration of the area.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/domaine-la-barroche/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Boutique Famille Perrin Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/06/22/famille_perrin_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Boutique Famille Perrin Public Tasting" /><published>2019-06-22T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-06-22T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/06/22/famille_perrin_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/06/22/famille_perrin_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I was not able to visit the Beaucastel Estate, even though I tried to make a reservation…  So if anyone reading this article does manage to make it onsite and get the full treatment, please send me some pictures and let me know how it was!  If you are told to visit their wine shop in Châteauneuf-du-Pape instead, you’ll likely experience something similar to me!  Luckily, finding the Famille Perrin wine shop in town is not hard.  In fact if you head to the circle in the city center, you cannot miss it.  The shop is literally right next to one of the main restaurants there and is open most of the day (except during lunch time).  Since they taste more than just their Beaucastel label, it’s worth dropping by to experience parts of their vast portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To provide a little background, Chateau Beaucastel is one of the premium brands of Châteauneuf that you can find at boutique wine shops in the USA.  On a quality and price level, they are on par with brands such as Domaine du Pegau and Domaine Roger SABON.  Unlike Pegau though, the production, distribution, and number of brands of Famille Perrin (which owns the Beaucastel label), is very large.  This means that given access to their full catalog, one should be able to find a bottle at the price point they desire.  Even someone like myself has trouble finding those other brands in the USA, so I had to pounce at the chance to taste these wines, even if they did not come with a tour or talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/famille-perrin/1-1050by788-4c759d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/famille-perrin/1-700by525-4c759d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/famille-perrin/1-675by506-4c759d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/famille-perrin/1-450by338-4c759d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/famille-perrin/1-525by394-4c759d.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/famille-perrin/1-350by263-4c759d.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/famille-perrin/1-350by263-4c759d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The storefront&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The storefront for the Famille Perrin Wines.  NOTE: It does carry more than just the Chateau Beaucastel wines - these are the wines you’ve most likely encountered in the USA before.  The store also carries most of the wines produced by the Famille Perrin brand.  You may find some of those other wines to be cheaper but as high quality as the Beaucastel wines.  They just don’t have the brand recognition in the USA…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The selection within the store is pretty broad and most of the wines are of very good quality, meaning you can find some interesting wines for great prices if you don’t need your wine to have international branding or acclaim.  Of note too is the fact that while they do serve the Chateau Beaucastel rouge as part of the tasting, the menu is predominantly geared toward exposing the consumer to other wines within the family’s portfolio.  This is exactly what I was hoping for…  Just note that the store and the two people running it can normally handle only two tasting groups at a time near the counter.  So be prepared to window shop for a few minutes if others are in line to taste before you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://m.familleperrin.com/8W92WE/web&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Chateauneuf-Du-Pape AOC White&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;80% Roussane with the other 20% coming from three other white varietals.  There’s a hint of MLF on the nose (ie. some popcorn) with mellow stonefruit.  Structure of medium(+) acid and medium body.  The palate had medium(+) intensity flavors of yellow fruit, popcorn, butter, and minerality that tingles the edge of the tongue on the finish.  The finish is nice and long with well integrated alcohol providing weight on the palate and a warming sensation.  This is a big white that can compete with Napa Valley Chardonnays in a blind tasting.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://m.familleperrin.com/FM9LVE/web&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Coudoulet de Beaucastel AOC Red&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (21€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Their Cotes du Rhone table wine.  The nose was a little closed but displayed some lighter red fruit notes with black pepper.  High acid, high chewy tannins, a medium body.  The flavors on the palate are pretty clear: cranberry, black pepper, and a slight garrigue character.  The acid is mouthwatering and the fruit flavor isn’t quite as ripe as I was expecting, but for the 20€ price range, that’s about what you would expect.  I prefer the Paul Jaboulet Aine, but would be happy with this at my table.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lesalexandrins.com/en/wine/?vincod=9A7V7E&amp;amp;winecolor=&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Hermitage Maison Les Alexandrins&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (38€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Medium(+) acid, medium(-) body, and high tannins.  This wine already has a well integrated nose with dried red fruit, garrigue, and black pepper on the nose in medium(-) intensity.  The tannins are still present on the finish, but the intensity of flavors on the palate makes it work.  This wine needs a year or two to round everything out and to allow the tertiary character to emerge and balance the red fruit.  Still, this wine is already drinking pretty well.  I’m surprised how light this wine was considering 2015 was a ripe harvest.  One of the rare 2015s that offers more balance than weight and power.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://m.familleperrin.com/HGKBKE/web&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2010 Les Chapouins Veilles Vignes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Chateauneuf-du-Pape AOC wine.  100% old vine Grenache aged for 5 years in large, neutral oak foudres.  Medium(+) acid, medium body, and medium(+) tannins.  For a single variety wine, it has really good complexity with tertiary flavors already integrated with the red fruit.  The finish goes on for 30+ seconds and the tannins are fairly smooth.  Value wise, I think this wine was the best I tasted at the shop (I purchased a bottle) and should be drunk within the next 3 years.  The earth and cedar show more than the pepper, which is a twist I liked.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://m.familleperrin.com/517LSE/web&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Chateau de Beaucastel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (69€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The flagship GSM blend.  The nose is less bright and a little deeper than its Cote du Rhone brethren, but it still emphasizes its red fruit.  The palate leans toward the tertiary flavors at this point (earth, wood, black pepper) with dried red fruit layered underneath.  It’s still full bodied and could age a fair number of years, but I think it’s just about at its peak.  Serve this wine a little cool to accentuate the acid a bit.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the interesting this about the store is how the wines are transported in and eventually put on sale.  Most of the pricier wines (e.g. the 2010 Les Chapouins Veilles Vignes that I purchased) are shipped to the store in the 6-pack OWC (Original Wood Case) from the winery.  When the store sells the wine in increments other than 6, they must break open the OWC (ie. remove the nails with a hammer), to take out the bottles they sell and give it to the consumer.  This was very different to see as someone who is always used to the bottles being out of the OWC in wineries/stores in the USA.  It adds additional labor, but I think its a nice show to put on for customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gentlemen running the store were helpful but also aggressive about making the sale for wines.  Luckily, I had a wine that I liked and was happy to purchase, but if you get a tasting at the store, be prepared to receive the full court press!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I would have much preferred to get a tour and tasting at the Chateau Beaucastel Estate, I am also happy that I got to try some of the other wines from the Famille Perrin portfolio and even found one I liked enough to stash in my suitcase for my travel back to the states.  If you are in Châteauneuf-du-Pape, there is no good reason not to visit Boutique Famille Perrin before or after grabbing lunch in town.  So skip the wines at lunch and enjoy!  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="southern-rhone" /><category term="chateauneuf-du-pape" /><summary type="html">Unfortunately, I was not able to visit the Beaucastel Estate, even though I tried to make a reservation… So if anyone reading this article does manage to make it onsite and get the full treatment, please send me some pictures and let me know how it was! If you are told to visit their wine shop in Châteauneuf-du-Pape instead, you’ll likely experience something similar to me! Luckily, finding the Famille Perrin wine shop in town is not hard. In fact if you head to the circle in the city center, you cannot miss it. The shop is literally right next to one of the main restaurants there and is open most of the day (except during lunch time). Since they taste more than just their Beaucastel label, it’s worth dropping by to experience parts of their vast portfolio.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/famille-perrin/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Domaine Roger SABON Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/06/15/roger_sabon_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Domaine Roger SABON Public Tasting" /><published>2019-06-15T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-06-15T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/06/15/roger_sabon_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/06/15/roger_sabon_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;If you were in Châteauneuf for only a day, Roger SABON needs to be on that list of three wineries to visit.  The wines served aren’t as pricey as Clos Des Papes and others, but you will have a fantastic experience with the tour, the different varietals, and the styles of wine they have on their menu.  You should absolutely make a reservation here to guarantee an English-speaker for your guide.  And if you are lucky like me, you’ll have the winemaker himself showing you around the facility, explaining what he aimed for when he made each of the wines, and answering any/all questions you may have.  As a wine student, this was definitely my most educational tasting in Châteauneuf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/1-1050by1400-4134dd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/1-700by933-4134dd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/1-675by900-4134dd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/1-450by600-4134dd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/1-525by700-4134dd.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/1-350by467-4134dd.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/1-350by467-4134dd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Their sign outside the winery&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I don’t know why, but I really liked the way they did their sign.  As you can see, it is going nowhere in a hurry, even in the sometimes tempestual winds that Châteauneuf endures.  This is an easy marker to spot from the road.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/2-1050by788-932f1c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/2-700by525-932f1c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/2-675by506-932f1c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/2-450by338-932f1c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/2-525by394-932f1c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/2-350by263-932f1c.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/2-350by263-932f1c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Entrance&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It was only after I discovered their sign above did I notice that their building also bears their name.  That is their winemaking facility, while the stone building next to it is the actual entrance / tasting room.  Now I know why my AirBnB hosts said this place would be hard to miss.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember having a bottle of the 2012 Secret de Sabon about 2 years ago during a tasting and really liking it.  Little did I know how much that bottle cost and that I would ever need to recall its name.  It is a surreal experience each time I visit a winery that produces wines I’ve enjoyed at home, at a wine bar, or in a restaurant.  The website recommended that I make a reservation and since practically no other winery requested/required one, I made sure to get this done.  When I arrived at the winery, the hostesses seemed confused, like I was lost.  I explained that I had made a reservation and that I was here for a tour and tasting.  I guess they expected it to be a group of people, not just me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/3-1050by788-af879f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/3-700by525-af879f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/3-675by506-af879f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/3-450by338-af879f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/3-525by394-af879f.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/3-350by263-af879f.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/3-350by263-af879f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The foudre room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view inside their foudre room.  Most wineries in the area have decades old barrels and have worn out the interiors of their buildings.  Compared to them, this place is emaculate.  I don’t know if it’s related, but there is a purity of fruit in their wines and in the wines of Domaine la Barroche, which also has a pristine facility.  Just interesting to note.  I would have loved to have tasted the wines at that center table…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They asked me to wait as one of them fetched a man out of the winemaking pad in the building next door.  He was covered in grape must, smelled like (bad) wine, and was a bit out of breath.  I thought he was just one of their crushpad workers that spoke English.  After some introductions and light conversation, it dawned on me that this guy really knew what he was talking about and that he might be someone important.  It turns out, I was getting a private tour and tasting from the Roger SABON’s winemaker.  How cool is that?  And Roger SABON is not a small production shop - they send wine all over the world and this was the man responsible.  I hate to admit that my attitude changed (I don’t want to be that wine snob), but his words seemed to carry more weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/4-1050by788-b74c57.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/4-700by525-b74c57.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/4-675by506-b74c57.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/4-450by338-b74c57.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/4-525by394-b74c57.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/4-350by263-b74c57.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/4-350by263-b74c57.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Soil Samples&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A look at the different soil types from their various parcels of land.  Like many other great wine regions, Châteauneuf has many different soil types within a small area, meaning that you’ll harvest grapes with different character and can blend them into complex wines (like they do here) or you can turn them into single site wines (like Napa does).  Both methods have their merits.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we walked through the winery and discussed the appellation as a whole, the different terroirs, their varietals, picking schedules (I had just interrupted a crush session during their harvest), and winemaking choices.  I was delighted to discover that Roger SABON in fact owns 80 hectares of vines on 14 different plots.  That is massive for a producer in this town.  Despite their production levels, they still take the same care that they always have with their wines.  They continue to macerate the red wines for about a month, age them in three different sized barrels (foudre, barrel, and giant neutral oak tanks) for various periods, and then blend them back together.  They normally bottle the wines a year after blending to allow them adequate time to integrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/5-1050by788-7ba0a1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/5-700by525-7ba0a1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/5-675by506-7ba0a1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/5-450by338-7ba0a1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/5-525by394-7ba0a1.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/5-350by263-7ba0a1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/5-350by263-7ba0a1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The man himself&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Didier, the man himself, holding a bottle of Secret des Sabon.  Roger SABON was one of the only places in Châteauneuf where I made a reservation (their website asks that you do).  While their tasting counter is open to walk-in visitors, if you make a reservation, they can make sure an English-speaker is present to take you on a tour.  Turns out that person was their winemaker!!  Oh man, did we have a good time talking about the wines…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As intriguing as the wine production discussion was, I was more interested in Didier’s story (the winemaker who was showing me around).  He played it coy with me and instead talked about the winery’s history.  Domaine Roger SABON was founded in 1952 by the father and later had the support of his three sons.  Like many other family wineries, once all of the sons came of age, the youngest two left home and started other wineries in the region while the eldest eventually took over the reigns at Roger SABON.  They all still enjoy close relationships and even help each other out when needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I knew it, wine had appeared in my hand and I was drinking it at Didier’s behest:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.domainerogersabon.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/FICHE-TECHNIQUE-RENAISSANCE.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Renaissance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (27€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;White Chateauneuf blend of Clairette, Bourboulenc, Grenache Blanc, and Roussane.  White flowers, lemon, cream, and yogurt on the nose.  The wine was very bright for having been aged on the lees.  Medium(+) acid, medium body with flavors in sync with the aromas, with an additional bit of melon.  It finishes a little hot because of the alcohol, but this was just released, so I would expect a couple years in bottle may help round that out.  Still, a very nice wine all the way through the palate.  For the price point, I’d definitely get some bottles had I the suitcase room.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.domainerogersabon.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/FICHE-TECHNIQUE-LIRAC-ENGLISH.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Lirac&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (9.80€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Red Chateauneuf blend of Grenache, old vine Carignan, Syrah, and Mouvedre.  Bright red cherries-n-crème and violets on the nose.  Structurally, the wine had medium(+) acid, high grippy tannins, and a medium(-) body.  The cherries-n-crème flavor dominate the palate with the tannins gripping a bit on the finish.  The flavors are there, but the imbalance of the lighter body and grippy tannins make this seem like a 10€ wine.  Assuming the fruit holds up well and the tannins/body integrate, I wouldn’t be surprised if this drank like a 20€-30€ bottle in a few years.  Everything just needs to round out a little and the tertiary character needs to work with the fruit.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.domainerogersabon.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/FICHE-TECHNIQUE-OLIVETS-ENGLISH.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Les Olivets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (17.90€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;80/10/10 proportional blend of Grenache, Syrah, and Mouvedre (GSM) respectively.  There’s a complicated blend of aromas on the nose.  It’s integrated but young enough that you can still feel out the 4-5 distinct aromas (red currant, cherry, black cherry, and light spice).  High acid, high grippy tannins and medium body.  The intensity and flavors of the fruit are harder to suss out on the palate with the tannins as high and rough as they are, but they are mostly in the primary fruit category, though not as ripe as the nose.  This wine needs at least 3 years to settle down before you can really evaluate it without a food pairing to counter the tannins.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.domainerogersabon.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/FICHE-TECHNIQUE-RESERVE-ENGLISH.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Reserve&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (23.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;GSM blend (Grenache dominant) in a more rustic style than the previous wines.  You can smell the tertiary component on the nose with more dried red fruit.  Medium(+) acid, high grippy tannins, and a medium body.  The intensity of the fruit is a bit more apparent on the palate, but the tannins interfere with the taste.  Didier (the winemaker) said to decant this wine for 1 hour to open the the aromatics and soften the tannins to make this more approachable.  I would do it for the Les Olivets too.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.domainerogersabon.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/FICHE-TECHNIQUE-PRESTIGE-ENGLISH.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Prestige&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (35.50€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Deeper and riper red fruit, even more so than the Reserve.  There’s also an underlying hint of baking spice that blends well with the high alcohol.  Medium(+) acid, high grippy tannin, and medium body.  Though, the flavor intensity is pronounced enough that you can clearly taste the red fruit through the tannins.  Red cranberry/cherries are the dominant flavors, though they are very light and bright on the palate.  Again though, the wine will be at its best in a few years or after an hour or two of decanting.  No alcoholic bite to the wine - it is well integrated.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.domainerogersabon.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/FICHE-TECHNIQUE-SECRET-ENGLISH.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Secret des Sabon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (90€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Less powerful than 2015/2016 and more of a burgundy style.  Nearly 100% Grenache from two fabulous old vine plots to showcase the grape’s complexity, varietal character, and the uniqueness of their terroir.  The bottle I tasted from had been opened for 3 days, so there was a little oxidation because it is Grenache.  The depth and complexity on the nose are pretty incredible considering it’s a single varietal.  Fresh and dried red fruit with a little thyme.  The tannins are fine enough to drink this right now and are balanced with the acidity.  The finish goes on for 20 seconds and ends cleanly.  Thanks to the oxidation, I could feel the start of the tertiary character, but it’s a supporting piece to a puzzle that’s predominantly complex fruit.  This will age beautifully thanks to the surprising amount of ripe, smooth tannin in this wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/6-1050by788-d0def0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/6-700by525-d0def0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/6-675by506-d0def0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/6-450by338-d0def0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/6-525by394-d0def0.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/6-350by263-d0def0.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/roger-sabon/6-350by263-d0def0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Obligatory Selfie&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I know it’s getting old, but I love taking selfies in front of vineyards that the wineries own.  The views are gorgeous and I travel alone, which made it hard to get picture of myself in most places.  At least here, there was no one around to criticize my selfie-skillz.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t had their wines before, I highly recommend tracking it down at your local wine shop.  Their distributor in the USA is European Cellars, which is based out of Charlotte, NC.  I have already picked up a bottle of Prestige and a couple of Secret des Sabon from the 2015/2016 vintages, though I know that I’ll need to wait a while in order to enjoy them at their fullest.  Again, if you find yourself in Chateauneuf, you need to stop by and have a great conversation.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="southern-rhone" /><category term="chateauneuf-du-pape" /><summary type="html">If you were in Châteauneuf for only a day, Roger SABON needs to be on that list of three wineries to visit. The wines served aren’t as pricey as Clos Des Papes and others, but you will have a fantastic experience with the tour, the different varietals, and the styles of wine they have on their menu. You should absolutely make a reservation here to guarantee an English-speaker for your guide. And if you are lucky like me, you’ll have the winemaker himself showing you around the facility, explaining what he aimed for when he made each of the wines, and answering any/all questions you may have. As a wine student, this was definitely my most educational tasting in Châteauneuf.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/roger-sabon/1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Clos Des Papes Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/06/08/clos_des_papes_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Clos Des Papes Public Tasting" /><published>2019-06-08T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-06-08T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/06/08/clos_des_papes_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/06/08/clos_des_papes_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;Clos Des Papes was my favorite wine tasting in Châteauneuf-du-Pape.  If you trust me at all, that should be enough to get you to put it at the top-of-your-list.  But in case you don’t trust me, trust the wine critics.  Jeb Dunnuck cannot stop talking about their wines (scored the 2016 rouge 100PTS) and Wine Advocate also continues to rate it highly.  But best of all, it’s free to taste (though I would expect them to start charging soon), they normally pour the current vintage and the one previous, and they also have their white wines to taste!  When I visited, I couldn’t believe it.  I spent more time here than I intended tasting the wines and speaking with their wine ambassador.  But I have no regrets and enjoyed every minute of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/1-1050by788-d45266.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/1-700by525-d45266.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/1-675by506-d45266.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/1-450by338-d45266.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/1-525by394-d45266.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/1-350by263-d45266.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/1-350by263-d45266.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The entrance to the best tasting in Châteauneuf&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It took me a while to find the place and that was while using Google Maps on my phone.  Hopefully this picture will help in that you now know what you are looking for when you are walking along the street.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the tasting room for Clos Des Papes is based out of a large house that doubles as their winery, it is actually quite easy to miss.  In fact, I missed it a couple times until I saw their sign on the gate to the house (see above).  As you walk up the driveway, it’s still pretty easy to think that you are in the wrong place and are in fact trespassing on someone’s private property.  Once you make it to the building though, there are signs with the Clos Des Papes brand and operating hours posted that reassure you.  You can head inside for a tasting once you have had your fill of staring at the vines (see my selfie at the bottom).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/2-1050by788-183e98.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/2-700by525-183e98.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/2-675by506-183e98.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/2-450by338-183e98.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/2-525by394-183e98.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/2-350by263-183e98.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/2-350by263-183e98.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The Tasting room&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Unlike some other wineries in Châteauneuf, their tasting room is nothing special.  What it lacks in aesthetics though, it makes up in the number of wines to taste, the quality of the wines, the price to taste, and the well-versed wine ambassador who will guide your tasting.  Since there were other guests, I made myself comfortable at her desk in the corner.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see above, their tasting room is a little underwhelming compared to some of the other wineries I’ve written about in Châteauneuf.  Have no fear.  The first thing you’ll notice besides the look of the room is the temperature - they keep it at a cool 65 degrees, hence why their wine ambassador is wearing a sweater even though it’s 95 outside.  The second is that there are several bottles of wine on the table and some interesting artwork nearby as well.  If you’re like me, you’ll take a minute to compose yourself from the heat outside.  Next, you’ll walk right up to the table and confidently ask for a tasting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/3-1050by788-d01518.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/3-700by525-d01518.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/3-675by506-d01518.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/3-450by338-d01518.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/3-525by394-d01518.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/3-350by263-d01518.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/3-350by263-d01518.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Wine and Wine Ambassador&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;After the other two gentlemen left, I had the tasting room all to myself.  As I mentioned earlier, I did linger and take my time evaluating the wines (she even brought me some 2014 that they had open in the back).  We both talked about our journey through the world of wine (her English was very good) and what we look for when we explore new regions.  I am still kicking myself for not asking to buy a case of wine on the spot - it was all really good and better than market price.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back on the experience, I know that I was a bit star-struck when I realized the wine ambassador was going to pour me two vintages each of the blanc and the rouge.  You might be thinking “oh, they didn’t pour you their special cuvee.”  You would be half right and half wrong.  That is because there is no special cuvee!  Each vintage, Clos Des Papes only produces their blanc and their rouge.  All of their fruit (including their best) goes into their one red and their one white, or else it gets sold off to other wineries.  It’s a bit awe-inspiring how much they let their vines dictate what their wines are going to taste like each vintage.  And who am I to argue?  Each one was delicious!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that I wasn’t able to try Châteauneuf Blancs in many places and I got to try it from one of the best producers in the area, I can’t help but consider myself lucky.  Even more special, I got an extra pour (the 2014 rouge).  It was a great start to the morning, let me tell you…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Clos Des Pape Blanc&lt;/strong&gt; (52€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Their Blanc uses 6 of the 7 white varietals allowed in CdP (equal percentage of Grenache Blanc, Roussane, Clairette, Bourboulenc, Picpoul, and Picardin).  The nose is mellow and soft, predominantly with yellow fruit notes.  The structure of the wine is high alcohol, medium(+) body, and medium(+) acidity, which I was not expecting.  The bottle was served at room temperature, so some of the alcohol burn came out on the finish.  Although there are so many varietals in here, the palate feels like a smooth, integrated wine (I couldn’t pick out more than lemon, white peach, and orange zest).  But I know how complicated this wine is and what it might develop into with more time.  You might think $60 is expensive for a white wine.  This is one of those wines where you throw preconceptions like that out the window.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Clos Des Pape Blanc&lt;/strong&gt; (54€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Same varietals and blending percentage in this wine as the 2017.  Doing that year after year is not as simple as that sounds as mother nature demands constant change.  Just smelling the wine, you get a sense the ‘16 and ‘17 are two totally different wines because the nose feels much more defined for the 2016.  I wonder if that is indicative of the vintage or the extra year of aging.  On the nose, you get white spice, ripe yellow fruit, even more zest, and orange fruit comes out in greater intensity.  The white spice and minerality is stronger on the palate too, but with a lighter body.  There is so much harmony though - there’s got to be some magic in the winery for them to use the same percentage of grapes for the blend each year, yet allow them to be adaptable to what fruit comes in.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Clos des Papes Rouge&lt;/strong&gt; (62€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This wine is already displaying such integration and depth, but also acidity and brightness with a 75/25 red-to-black fruit ratio on the nose (mostly strawberry and light cherry).  The palate has medium(+) acid, medium(+) but fine tannin, with a nice clean finish and red fruit lingering.  The wine is lighter in its spice profile than others in the area and also shows off brighter, lighter red fruit.  But there is an undercurrent of tertiary character (wood, earth) that is present and starting to creep in.  Not quite as integrated as the other vintages, but one to three years of aging will fix that.  This wine just feels different from other reds in the area, especially with its distinctive baking spice character.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Clos des Papes Rouge&lt;/strong&gt; (64€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The nose is so evolved on the 2015.  I cannot believe this is the same wine and has only aged for an additional year.  The red fruit feels more cooked (2015 was a hot vintage), but the wood spice, black pepper, cedar, and forest floor come out so much more on this nose.  Though, if you asked me, I would still call this a bright wine.  Structurally, you have medium(+) acid, high but very fine tannin, and a medium body.  On the palate and finish, the dried cranberry and baking spice are dominant, but the tertiary notes already possess good length.  I love how it’s baking spices and not black pepper that’s the dominant spice here.  It integrates with the tertiary character very well and makes me yearn for red meat.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 Clos des Papes Rouge&lt;/strong&gt; (59€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I’ve said so much already about the ‘15/’16 that it’s hard to come up with something new to say.  The nose builds on the 2015, except a little less intensity and a little more integration of aromas.  Dried/cooked red fruit and baking spices continue to dominate.  Structurally, this wine has high acid, medium(+) tannin, and a medium body.  The flavors align with the aromas, though I might be starting to feel a little garrigue, but I’m unsure.  The dried (ripe cranberry/raspberry) red fruit come out so nicely on the nose and feels like there is a bouquet of flowers integrated within.  I spent more time smelling this wine than the others and it makes me giddy that I have bottles stored away, waiting for me.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must say, the dried/cooked red fruit plus baking spice character is so distinctive in their red wines that I think I can pick it out of a Châteauneuf-du-Pape lineup.  And I do not type those words lightly…  Yet another reason that I am drawn to this wine.  Afterwards, I had to go clear my head outside in the vineyards (see below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/4-1050by788-7ae775.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/4-700by525-7ae775.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/4-675by506-7ae775.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/4-450by338-7ae775.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/4-525by394-7ae775.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/4-350by263-7ae775.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/clos-des-papes/4-350by263-7ae775.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The clos-des-papes vineyards!&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;After the tasting was over, I meandered outside and made sure to take a selfie with their vines.  I don’t remember if these are the red or white varietals, but I do remember that they are co-planted, which is why you get all of the varietals in each blend - they literally take what the land gives them.  And since co-planting was originally done to protect against the elements and disease a long time ago, you can imagine how old the vines are.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to visit Clos Des Papes because the bottle I had from them was delicious and I knew their wines scored well.  I thought I would get a similar tasting experience as Domaine du Pegau.  I never expected all of this.  If you ever happen to visit Châteauneuf-du-Pape, you need to make this your first stop.  Also, their wines are hard to come by in the USA and are usually priced around $100+ per bottle of rouge.  Buying a case may save you $20-$30 a bottle, provided you have a means of shipping the wine out of the country cheaply (aka: room in the luggage).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do bring some back and have second thoughts, invite me over and I’ll help with that dilemma, haha.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="southern-rhone" /><category term="chateauneuf-du-pape" /><summary type="html">Clos Des Papes was my favorite wine tasting in Châteauneuf-du-Pape. If you trust me at all, that should be enough to get you to put it at the top-of-your-list. But in case you don’t trust me, trust the wine critics. Jeb Dunnuck cannot stop talking about their wines (scored the 2016 rouge 100PTS) and Wine Advocate also continues to rate it highly. But best of all, it’s free to taste (though I would expect them to start charging soon), they normally pour the current vintage and the one previous, and they also have their white wines to taste! When I visited, I couldn’t believe it. I spent more time here than I intended tasting the wines and speaking with their wine ambassador. But I have no regrets and enjoyed every minute of it.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/clos-des-papes/3.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Famille Mayard Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/06/01/famille_mayard_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Famille Mayard Public Tasting" /><published>2019-06-01T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-06-01T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/06/01/famille_mayard_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/06/01/famille_mayard_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;With enough money, you could build one of the most gorgeous wineries in the world.  But try to build a winery into the hill that your town sits on and make it beautiful, rustic, classy and have it work as a functioning winery.  That takes a great deal of patience, care, and skill.  That is exactly what Famille Mayard has done with the construction of their winery / tasting room.  The entrance doesn’t seem like much when looking at it from the street.  But once you head inside, it feels like you have been transported to someone’s cellar, because that is exactly what it looks like.  Match that with great wines and you have a hidden oasis in the bustling town of Châteauneuf-du-Pape.  Like other small places I love, you want to see them succeed and have plenty of customers, but sometimes, you also want the winery all to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winery is on the outskirts of town, but still on the slopes of the hill.  There are several other wineries you will pass by walking to Famille Mayard from Châteauneuf-du-Pape, after lunch in the center of town.  Most of them will have plently of people visiting and will have large signs or buildings.  And while I encourage you to visit and support all wineries, make sure you have enough of your palate left to visit Famille Mayard.  You will not be disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/famille-mayard/1-1050by788-4b5347.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/famille-mayard/1-700by525-4b5347.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/famille-mayard/1-675by506-4b5347.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/famille-mayard/1-450by338-4b5347.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/famille-mayard/1-525by394-4b5347.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/famille-mayard/1-350by263-4b5347.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/famille-mayard/1-350by263-4b5347.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The back bar area&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;The view of the winery as you look to your right upon entering.  Just beautiful with the sun shining into the room from the windows above.  I wish I had a better camera to take advantage of the unique view.  The back bar was unoccupied as I was the only visitor at the time, but it’s easy to imagine when full with people.  I should probably go leave a comment on TripAdvisor, like they requested…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not quite sure, but I think that their wines are distributed in the USA and that is why the name sounded familiar to me.  When you are in a foreign town with over 30 wineries to visit, sometimes a name or a label/crest are all that you have to go by in choosing which places to visit.  Thankfully, my luck was strong while I was visiting in Châteauneuf.  As they say, trust your gut on food and wine choices, especially since it’s the organ that is going to have to bear the brunt of the consequences of those choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/famille-mayard/2-1050by788-09f21c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/famille-mayard/2-700by525-09f21c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/famille-mayard/2-675by506-09f21c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/famille-mayard/2-450by338-09f21c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/famille-mayard/2-525by394-09f21c.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/famille-mayard/2-350by263-09f21c.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/famille-mayard/2-350by263-09f21c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;The front bar area&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;If you didn’t believe me when I said this was a functioning winery, I hope you do now as you can see the bottles of wine sprawled everywhere, waiting to be shipped to customers.  This picture doesn’t quite do the scene justice, but it was a beautiful sight.  Because it was similar to a wine cave, the temperature was at least 20-30 degrees cooler than outside.  I feel bad that I didn’t purchase any bottles because I had a lovely time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really did enjoy having the tasting in their beautiful cellar area.  It’s really ingenious - save money by combining the storage cellar, wine bar, and shipping areas.  Add some windows (away from the storage area), put up some decorations, and you get something that is smart and tasteful.  I admit that this place had an outsized impact in my own future designs (once I can afford to do something about them, haha).  Alright then, time to talk about the wines.  NOTE: Only 5% of their production is white wine, which means there’s none available in the tasting room for visitors (it sells out every year).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vignobles-mayard.fr/fr/nos-cuvees/clos-du-calvaire/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016 Clos du Calvaire&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (26€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Their table wine blend of Grenache, Syrah, and Cinsault.  Instead of wood, this wine spends 12 months in concrete vats.  On the nose, this wine has more violets and bright red/black fruit than other Châteauneufs I’ve had from the area.  Structurally, you get high acid, high tannin and a medium body.  The palate consists of sweet raisins mixed into the fruit character from the nose.  This wine is very smooth and drinkable right now, even with its high tannins.  This wine will make Tawny Port lovers happy with its tasting profile, but won’t feel as heavy.  Serve a little chilled.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vignobles-mayard.fr/fr/nos-cuvees/domaine-du-pere-pape/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2013 Domaine du Pere Pape&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (33€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This wine is similar in style to the Clos du Calvaire, except this wine spends 12 months in oak vats (not concrete vats) and has some Mouvedre blended in.  Bright with acid on the nose, though the aromas alternate between ripe citrus and ripe cherry notes.  The palate is a bit more traditional, but there is a little banana in there (esther) and the black pepper is still a little reserved.  Still, the fruit is strong, deep, and just a bit stewed, but not in a bad way.  This is another very agreeable wine that has a different profile but is just as ready to drink.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vignobles-mayard.fr/fr/nos-cuvees/la-crau-de-ma-mere-rouge/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 La Crau de ma Mere&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (39€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This is their rockstar wine.  Made from 100 year old Grenache vines that grow on 3 meters of rock.  You could say that these vines have shared some struggles (and grow fantastic grapes because of it).  This wine is a straight GSM (Grenache, Syrah, Mouvedre) blend that spends 15 months in oak vats.  Bright red fruit (cherry, cranberry) permeates the nose with white and black pepper blended with floral notes.  It has a medium body, high tannins, medium(+) acid, with a flavor profile that is consistent with the nose.  There’s an unspoken complexity thanks to the old vines.  The tannins are very fine, so it’s definitely drinkable right now.  You could say this wine is somewhat similar to the first wine, but with more complexity and balance.  I would gladly pay 40 Euros for this wine.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to many wineries in the area, this winery has no tasting fee nor reservations required.  And since it is literally the family running the store, giving the tastings and shipping the wines, I felt bad that I walked away without purchasing a bottle (my suitcase has limits!).  So if you decide to drop by and partake in a tasting, can you grab a bottle of the La Crau de ma Mere?  I will enjoy it vicariously through you, haha.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="southern-rhone" /><category term="chateauneuf-du-pape" /><summary type="html">With enough money, you could build one of the most gorgeous wineries in the world. But try to build a winery into the hill that your town sits on and make it beautiful, rustic, classy and have it work as a functioning winery. That takes a great deal of patience, care, and skill. That is exactly what Famille Mayard has done with the construction of their winery / tasting room. The entrance doesn’t seem like much when looking at it from the street. But once you head inside, it feels like you have been transported to someone’s cellar, because that is exactly what it looks like. Match that with great wines and you have a hidden oasis in the bustling town of Châteauneuf-du-Pape. Like other small places I love, you want to see them succeed and have plenty of customers, but sometimes, you also want the winery all to yourself.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/famille-mayard/2.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Domaine du Pegau Public Tasting</title><link href="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/05/25/domaine_du_pegau_public_tasting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Domaine du Pegau Public Tasting" /><published>2019-05-25T19:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-25T19:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/05/25/domaine_du_pegau_public_tasting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/2019/05/25/domaine_du_pegau_public_tasting.html">&lt;p&gt;The 2012 Domaine du Pegau was one of the first bottles that truly opened my eyes to the possibilities of the world of wine.  Up until that point, I had mostly tasted fruit driven (American) wines, wines with both fruit and terroir influence (Bordeaux), and those that were driven by wood and age (Spanish).  Never would I have thought that a wine could taste like a rare roast beef with crackling black pepper.  That was my introduction to the garrigue character of French Syrah from the Rhone.  Afterthat wine, I remember wanting to explore more wines from more areas to see what exotic flavor profiles were out there.  It’s strange to look back on that experience today now that I am a WSET Diploma student preparing for my Unit #3 exam.  Time does truly fly and I am very appreciative of the wines that first piqued my curiosity.  You can definitely count Domaine du Pegau among them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/1-1050by788-3d4fd5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/1-700by525-3d4fd5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/1-675by506-3d4fd5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/1-450by338-3d4fd5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/1-525by394-3d4fd5.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/1-350by263-3d4fd5.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/1-350by263-3d4fd5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Google was Wrong&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;If you want to visit Domaine du Pegau during your journey to Châteauneuf-du-Pape as well, be warned.  Do not follow Google Maps.  Instead, ask around town for the correct location for their storefront and most people will be glad to point you in the right direction.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So of course, when preparing my itinerary for the Châteauneuf-du-Pape area, I had to make sure I went and paid homage.  The first thing I did when I set out for the morning (as I do every morning when visiting wineries) was plug in the name into Google Maps and follow the directions.  You can see in the picture above, I was rather surprised to find that Google led me to the end of a street where vines were growing in a field.  I never figured out if those vines belonged to Domaine du Pegau because I was a little embarrassed to ask once I arrived at their storefront in town, but I suspect they did.  I’m pretty sure that if you look at some other results in Google Maps when looking up the winery, there is one that will seem like a store - that is the place you want to head towards.  As you can see below, I was rather happy to find it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/2-1050by788-528eb2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/2-700by525-528eb2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/2-675by506-528eb2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/2-450by338-528eb2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/2-525by394-528eb2.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/2-350by263-528eb2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/2-350by263-528eb2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Finally found it&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;It took a little more effort than I had hoped, but I finally found my destination.  You can tell I was very happy and proud of myself.  I was also confused too.  Why would a place like Domaine du Pegau, with the international brand that it has, be so quiet during the middle of the day on a weekend.  I was fine with the fact that it just meant more attention for me…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/3-1050by788-94d2a9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/3-700by525-94d2a9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/3-675by506-94d2a9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/3-450by338-94d2a9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/3-525by394-94d2a9.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/3-350by263-94d2a9.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/3-350by263-94d2a9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Happy to see me&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Although their tasting room and experience (only two wines to taste) is fairly simple, it is still worth spending 30 minutes to stop by while you are in town.  The tasting is free, so what have you got to lose?  The worst thing that can happen is that you fall in love with the wines and debate whether to ship a case back home or whether you have the patience to find a store that has enough bottles to satisfy you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both from the street and inside the store, Domaine du Pegau isn’t going to win any architectural design awards.  This is not the place to lounge for a day, drinking wines.  Though in the last picture, you can see there is an inner section to enjoy a bottle if you wanted to.  This is just an efficient, low cost way of allowing people that already know of Domaine du Pegau to taste the current vintage and to taste a bottle that is harder to come by on the market: the Cuvee Laurence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wine ambassador was surprised to see me, even though it was 11AM on a Saturday; I guess I was the first visitor of the day and they are not used to many.  I relayed my story about Pegau’s impact on my wine journey and he said “Say no more!”  He poured me two (generous) glasses of the wines below, poured himself much smaller quantities, and we tasted the wines together:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pegau.com/crbst_5.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015 Cuvee Reservee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (55€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;80,000 bottles produced each vintage.  This was everything that I remember about this wine.  Jammy red fruit (2015 was a warm vintage), black pepper, cinnamon, and the garrigue character.  The wine was very well balanced and integrated while sporting high-but-smooth tannins and medium(+) acidity.  The flavors on the palate matched the nose with similar notes.  But the smooth mouthfeel and the 20+ second finish are what really held my attention.   Many people prefer this style to the more expensive Laurence as it’s more rustic and traditional.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pegau.com/crbst_8.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2012 Cuvee Laurence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (65€)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The best cask (8,000 bottles) in a vintage may be chosen from the Cuvee Reservee to make into the Cuvee Laurence.  The Laurence spends four years in cask versus two years for the Cuvee Reservee.  There is a little more age on the nose (e.g. the fruit is a little deeper/dried), the pepper is better integrated, and some tertiary notes have started to develop.  The fruit pulls back a bit on the palate, but this is already tasting great like a fine, older wine.  Seemless black pepper, garrigue, forest floor, and cedar integrate with the red fruit - this wine relies on integration and elegance rather than intensity.  I think this is slightly more complex than the Reservee and worth the extra 10€, especially since it’s much harder to find in the US than the Cuvee Reservee.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/4-1050by1400-8af93a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/4-700by933-8af93a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/4-675by900-8af93a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/4-450by600-8af93a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/4-525by700-8af93a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/4-350by467-8af93a.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/4-350by467-8af93a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;I need that wine in my collection&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;What you see here are the best bottles in their collection.  Past vintages of their Laurence, Cuvee de Capo (their Creme de la Creme produced in select years), and special bottlings produced only during the years when the owners gave birth to their children.  That’s definitely one way to make your kids famous.  Sadly, these were outside of my price range and definitely were not going to be served at a tasting like this…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in one of the captions above, there is no reason not to stop by Domaine du Pegau.  It’s right in town, does not require a reservation, does not require a tasting fee, and will likely be higher quality than many of the wines you will find in town.  There’s also a very good chance you could find their Cuvee Reservee in stores back in the USA if you wanted to buy bottles in the future.  I only wish they made more wines and had their Blanc available to taste - the Cuvee Reservee Blanc is produced in very small quantities (4200 bottles a year) and sells out quickly each vintage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/5-1050by788-2c4a9a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 40em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/5-700by525-2c4a9a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 40em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/5-675by506-2c4a9a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em) and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-width: 30em) and (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/5-450by338-2c4a9a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(min-width: 30em)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/5-525by394-2c4a9a.jpg&quot; media=&quot;(-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 1.5), (min-resolution: 144dpi)&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/5-350by263-2c4a9a.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/assets/images/domaine-pegau/5-350by263-2c4a9a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;For those that do buy a bottle...&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Caption Title:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;If you do choose to buy a bottle at the store and want to enjoy it immediately, there is a common room a bit further back in the cave.  It’s nice and cool compared to the likely temperature outside and is therefore very tempting.  Since I was traveling alone and in a hurry to try as many wines as possible, I didn’t have a chance to relax here.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding the rest of their portfolio, the Cuvee Da Capo is their top wine and only produced in the best vintages (e.g. 2010, 2015, 2016).  Even then, only 5000 bottles are produced, making it a collector’s item.  Pegau does not make the Cuvee Laurence and the Da Capo during the same vintage, meaning the Cuvee Laurence is basically the Da Capo, though just slightly lesser in quality.  Another reason to grab the Laurence if you can.  But even rarer than the Da Capo is the Cuvee a Tempo - only 1200 bottles are produced during special vintages.  It is the biodynamic, white wine version of the Da Capo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a lot of fun here and can’t wait to talk about Pegau the next time I open one of their bottles.  Cheers!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeremy Myers</name></author><category term="review" /><category term="winery" /><category term="tasting" /><category term="france" /><category term="southern-rhone" /><category term="chateauneuf-du-pape" /><summary type="html">The 2012 Domaine du Pegau was one of the first bottles that truly opened my eyes to the possibilities of the world of wine. Up until that point, I had mostly tasted fruit driven (American) wines, wines with both fruit and terroir influence (Bordeaux), and those that were driven by wood and age (Spanish). Never would I have thought that a wine could taste like a rare roast beef with crackling black pepper. That was my introduction to the garrigue character of French Syrah from the Rhone. Afterthat wine, I remember wanting to explore more wines from more areas to see what exotic flavor profiles were out there. It’s strange to look back on that experience today now that I am a WSET Diploma student preparing for my Unit #3 exam. Time does truly fly and I am very appreciative of the wines that first piqued my curiosity. You can definitely count Domaine du Pegau among them.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.winesbyjeremy.com/domaine-pegau/3.jpg" /></entry></feed>